<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="dita-insert-conref">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150617T113134+0300" comment="Merged content with &quot;Creating a DITA Content Reference&quot; and now this one is no longer needed."?>Insert
    a Direct Content Reference<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Reuse<indexterm>insert a direct content reference</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>You can use the same content in multiple topics by inserting a DITA content reference
      to that content. The following steps describe the procedure of inserting a DITA content
      reference:</context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Position your cursor inside the element that you want to reference and in the <xref
            href="../../topics/attributes-panel.dita#attributes-panel"
              ><uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view</xref> enter a value in the
            <uicontrol>ID</uicontrol> field.</cmd>
        <info>If you want to reuse just a part of the content of an element, select the content with
          your cursor, press <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> and in the proposals list select
            <codeph>ph</codeph>. This encapsulates your content inside a
            <codeph>phrase(&lt;ph>)</codeph> element, allowing you to set an ID and then reference
          it. </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Open the topic where you want to insert the reference to this element.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select <uicontrol><image href="../../img/Conref20.png" id="image_gmv_hrx_xr"/>Insert
            Content Reference</uicontrol> on the main toolbar (or from the
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu).</cmd>
        <stepresult>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog box is
          displayed.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> field of the <uicontrol>Insert Content
            Reference</uicontrol> dialog box, select the topic that holds the element you want to
          reference.</cmd>
        <stepresult>In the <uicontrol>Target ID</uicontrol> section of the <uicontrol>Insert Content
            Reference</uicontrol> dialog box, <ph keyref="product"/> presents the elements that you
          can reference.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the ID of the element you want to reference, then click
          <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.</cmd>
        <info>If you select an interval of elements, the <uicontrol>Conrefend</uicontrol> field is
          filled with the <codeph>id</codeph> value of the element that ends the selected
          interval.</info>
        <stepresult>A reference to the selected element is inserted at the cursor
          position.</stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>