<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="new-dialog-eclipse">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20160301T155424+0200" comment="converted to topic (same id) and moved to not_used"?><ph><ph
        keyref="product"/> New Document Wizard</ph>
    <?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <taskbody>
    <context> The <uicontrol>New Document</uicontrol> wizard only creates a skeleton document. It
      contains the document prolog, a root element, and possibly other child elements depending on
      the options specific for each schema type. <ph product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">To
        generate full and valid XML instance documents based on an XML Schema, use the <xref
          href="../topics/xml-schema-instance-generator.dita">XML instance generation
        tool</xref>.</ph><p> The <ph keyref="product"/> installs a series of Eclipse wizards for
        easy creation of documents. If you use these wizards, <ph keyref="product"/> automatically
        completes the following details:<ul id="ul_z2v_mlk_bg">
          <li>The system ID, or schema location of a new XML document.</li>
          <li>The minimal markup of a DocBook article, or the namespace declarations of a Relax NG
            schema. </li>
        </ul></p></context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>To create a document, either select <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Other</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol keyref="product"/>
          </menucascade> or click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/EclipseNew.png"
              id="image_nbd_fkf_wr"/>New </uicontrol> button on the toolbar.</cmd>
        <stepresult>The <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> file wizard is displayed.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select a document type. You can also select <xref
            href="creating-from-templates.dita#creating-from-templates"><uicontrol>New from
              Templates</uicontrol></xref> to create a document based upon predefined templates or
          custom templates.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <stepresult>For example, if XML was selected the <uicontrol>Create an XML
            Document</uicontrol> wizard is started. <p>The <uicontrol>Create an XML
              Document</uicontrol> dialog box enables definition of an XML Document Prolog using the
            system identifier of an XML Schema, DTD, Relax NG (full or compact syntax) schema, or
            NVDL (Namespace-based Validation Dispatching Language) schema. As not all XML documents
            are required to have a Prolog, you can choose to skip this step by clicking
              <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. If the prolog is required, complete the fields as described
            in the subsequent steps.</p></stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Type a name for the new document and press the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>
          button.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>If you select <uicontrol>Customize</uicontrol>, <ph keyref="product"/> opens the
          following dialog box. You can customize various options, depending on the document type
          you select.</cmd>
        <itemgroup>
          <fig>
            <title>New XML Document Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_create_new_xml_dialog.png"/>
          </fig>
          <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> - Specifies the path to the schema file. When you select
              a file, <ph keyref="product"/> analyzes its content and tries to fill the rest of the
              dialog box.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Schema type</uicontrol> - Allows you to select the schema type. The
              following options are available: XML Schema, DTD, RelaxNG XML syntax, RelaxNG compact
              syntax, and NVDL.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Public ID</uicontrol> - Specifies the PUBLIC identifier declared in the
              document prolog.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol> - Specifies the document namespace.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Prefix</uicontrol> - Specifies the prefix for the namespace of the
              document root.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Root Element</uicontrol> - Populated with elements defined in the
              specified schema, enables selection of the element used as document root.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> - A small description of the selected document
              root.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Add optional content</uicontrol> - If you select this option, the
              elements, and attributes defined in the XML Schema as optional, are generated in the
              skeleton XML document.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Add first Choice particle</uicontrol> - If you select this option, <ph
                keyref="product"/> generates the first element of an <codeph>xs:choice</codeph>
              schema element in the skeleton XML document. <ph keyref="product"/> creates this
              document in a new editor panel when you click <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>.</li>
          </ul>
          <fig>
            <title>New XSL Document Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_create_new_xsl_dialog.png"/>
          </fig>
          <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Stylesheet version</uicontrol> - Allows you to select the Stylesheet
              version number. You can select from: 1.0, 2.0, and 3.0. </li>
            <li><uicontrol>Add documentation annotations</uicontrol> - Adds annotation for XSL
              components.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Open file for editing when done</uicontrol> - Specifies whether or not
              you want to open the newly created file in the editor.</li>
          </ul>
          <fig>
            <title>New XML Schema Document (XSD) Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_create_new_xsd_dialog.png"/>
          </fig>
          <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Default XML Schema version</uicontrol> - Uses the XML Schema version
              defined in the  <xref keyref="options_preferences"><uicontrol>XML Schema</uicontrol>
                preferences page</xref>.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>XML Schema 1.0</uicontrol> - Sets the <codeph>minVersion</codeph>
              attribute to <varname>1.0</varname> and the <codeph>maxVersion</codeph> attribute to
                <varname>1.1</varname>.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>XML Schema 1.1</uicontrol> - Sets the <codeph>minVersion</codeph>
              attribute to <varname>1.1</varname>.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Target namespace</uicontrol> - Specifies the schema target
              namespace.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Namespace prefix declaration table</uicontrol> - Contains namespace
              prefix declarations. To manage table information, use the <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
              and <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> buttons.<note type="tip"
                product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">For further details on how you can set the
                version of an XML Schema, go to <xref
                  href="../topics/set-xml-schema-version.dita#set-xml-schema-version">Setting the
                  XML Schema Version</xref>.</note></li>
          </ul>
          <fig>
            <title>New Schematron Document Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_create_new_schematron_dialog.png"/>
          </fig>
          <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Schematron version</uicontrol> - Specifies the Schematron version.
              Possible options: 1.5 and ISO.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Open file for editing when done</uicontrol> - Specifies whether or not
              you want to open the file for editing purposes.</li>
          </ul>
        </itemgroup>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
