<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="configure-marklogic-connection">
  <title>How to Configure a MarkLogic Connection</title>
  <taskbody>
    <prereq>Available in the Enterprise edition only.<note><ph keyref="product"/> supports MarkLogic
        version 4.0 or later.</note></prereq>
    <context>The steps for configuring a connection to a MarkLogic database are the
      following:</context>
    <steps>
      <step conref="configure-berkeley-connection.dita#configure-berkeley-connection/step1"
        conrefend="configure-berkeley-connection.dita#configure-berkeley-connection/step4">
        <cmd/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Fill-in the connection details. </cmd>
        <substeps>
          <substep>
            <cmd>The host name or IP address of the installed MarkLogic engine in the
                <uicontrol>XDBC Host</uicontrol> field.</cmd>
            <info><ph keyref="product"/>
              uses XCC connector to interact with MarkLogic XDBC server and requires the basic
              authentication schema to be set. Starting with version MarkLogic 4.0 the default
              authentication method when you create a HTTP or WebDAV Server is digest, so make sure
              to change it to basic.</info>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd>Set the port number of the MarkLogic engine in the <uicontrol>Port</uicontrol>
              field. A MarkLogic XDBC application server must be configured on the server on this
              port. This XDBC server will be used to execute XQuery expressions against the server.
              Later on, if you want to change the XDBC server, instead of editing the configuration
              just use the <xref
                href="../topics/marklogic-connection.dita#marklogic-connection/use-it-to-execute-queries"
                  ><uicontrol>Use it to execute queries</uicontrol></xref> action from Data Source
              Explorer.</cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd>Set the user name to access the MarkLogic engine in the <uicontrol>User</uicontrol>
              field.</cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd>Set the password to access the MarkLogic engine in the
                <uicontrol>Password</uicontrol> field.</cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd>Optionally set the URL used for browsing the MarkLogic database in the
                <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view in the <uicontrol>WebDAV
                URL</uicontrol> field.</cmd>
            <info>The <uicontrol>Database</uicontrol> field specifies the database over which the
              XQuery expressions are executed. In case you set this option to default, the database
              associated to the application server of the configured port is used.</info>
          </substep>
        </substeps>
      </step>
      <step conref="configure-berkeley-connection.dita#configure-berkeley-connection/step6">
        <cmd/>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
