<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="dg-customize-default-CSS">
  <title>Customizing the Main CSS of a Document Type</title>
  <taskbody>
    <!--Proofed-->
    <context>The easiest way to customize the <term>main</term> CSS stylesheet of a document type is
      to create a new CSS stylesheet, save it in the same folder as the other <term>main</term> CSS
      files for that particular document type, and then select it from the
        <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down menu in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. <p>For
        example, suppose that you want to customize the <term>main</term> CSS for DITA documents. To
        do this, follow these steps: </p></context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>First, create a new CSS stylesheet and save it in the folder
            <filepath>[OXYGEN_DIR]/frameworks/dita/css_classed</filepath> (where the default
            <term>main</term> stylesheet named <filepath>dita.css</filepath> is located).</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To add the new stylesheet as a <term>main</term> CSS stylesheet for DITA documents, <ph
            conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>. Select the DITA document type and press the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
          button. Then, go to the <uicontrol>CSS</uicontrol> subtab of the
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab.</cmd>
        <info>
          <fig>
            <title>CSS Subtab of the Document Type Association Author Tab</title>
            <image href="../img/author_css_subtab.png"/>
          </fig>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Add16.png" id="image_frk_fjp_bs"
            />Add</uicontrol> button to open a dialog box that allows you to specify the URI and
          Title for your newly created stylesheet. Leave the <uicontrol>Alternate</uicontrol> option
          unchecked to define it as a <term>main</term> stylesheet.</cmd>
        <info>
          <fig id="fig_r2h_3lp_bs">
            <image href="../img/css_chooser_dialog_box.png" id="image_thc_4lp_bs"/>
          </fig>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Press <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> in all the dialog boxes to validate the changes.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select your newly created CSS stylesheet from the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol>
          drop-down menu on the toolbar in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</cmd>
        <stepresult>You can now edit DITA documents based on the new CSS stylesheet. You can also
          edit the new CSS stylesheet itself and see its effects on rendering DITA documents in the
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode by using the <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/Refresh16.png" id="image_bbb_bmp_bs"/>Refresh</uicontrol> action that is
          available on the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> toolbar and in the
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu.</stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <link
      href="../references/selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles.dita#selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles"
    />
  </related-links>
</task>
