<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="dg-customize-default-CSS">
  <title>Customizing the Default CSS of a Document Type</title>
  <taskbody>
    <!--Proofed-->
    <context>The easiest way to customize the default CSS stylesheet of a document type is to create
      a new CSS stylesheet, save it in the same folder as the default CSS, and set the new
      stylesheet as the default CSS for the document type. <p>For example, to customize the default
        CSS for DITA documents by changing the background color of the <i>task</i> and <i>topic</i>
        elements to red, follow the following steps: </p></context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>First, create a new CSS stylesheet named <filepath>my_dita.css</filepath> and save it
          in the folder <filepath>[OXYGEN_DIR]/frameworks/dita/css_classed</filepath>, where the
          default stylesheet named <filepath>dita.css</filepath> is located. The new stylesheet
            <filepath>my_dita.css</filepath> contains:</cmd>
        <info>
          <codeblock outputclass="language-css">@import "dita.css";
    
task, topic{
    background-color:red;
}
</codeblock>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To set the new stylesheet as the default CSS stylesheet for DITA documents, <ph
            conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>. Select the DITA document type and press the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
          button. In the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab, change the URI of the default CSS
          stylesheet from <codeph>${framework}/css_classed/dita.css</codeph> to
            <codeph>${framework}/css_classed/my_dita.css</codeph>.</cmd>
        <info>
          <fig>
            <title>Set the location of the default CSS stylesheet</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_dita_default_css_location.png"/>
          </fig>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Press <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> in all the dialogs to validate the changes. You can now
          edit DITA documents based on the new CSS stylesheet. You can also edit the new CSS
          stylesheet itself and see its effects on rendering DITA XML documents in the
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode by running the <i>Refresh</i> action that is
          available on the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> toolbar and in the
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
