<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="dg-configure-toolbar">
  <title>Configuring the Toolbars</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Settings<indexterm>toolbars<indexterm>configure
            toolbar</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>Now that you have defined the <b><xref
            href="../tasks/dg-insert-section-action.dita#dg-insert-section-action" format="dita"
            >Insert Section</xref></b> action and the <b><xref
            href="../tasks/dg-insert-table-action.dita#dg-insert-table-action" format="dita">Insert
            Table</xref></b> action, you can add them to the toolbar. You can configure additional
        toolbars on which to add your custom actions.</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Open the Document Type edit dialog for the <b>SDF</b> framework and select on the
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab. Next click on the <uicontrol>Toolbar</uicontrol>
          label.</cmd>
        <info>
          <fig product="editor author authorSDK">
            <title>Configuring the Toolbar</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_dg_configuring_toolbar.png"/>
          </fig>
          <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
            <title>Configuring the Toolbar</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_dg_configuring_toolbar.png"/>
          </fig>
          <p>The panel is divided in two sections: the left side contains a list of actions, while
            the right one contains an action tree, displaying the list of actions added in the
            toolbar. The special entry called <i>Separator</i> allows you to visually separate the
            actions in the toolbar.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Insert section</uicontrol> action in the left panel section and
          the <uicontrol>Toolbar</uicontrol> label in the right panel section, then press the <uicontrol>
            <image href="../img/AddAsChild16.png"/>Add as child</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Insert table</uicontrol> action in the left panel section and the
            <uicontrol>Insert section</uicontrol> in the right panel section. Press the <uicontrol>
            <image href="../img/AddAsSibling16.png"/>Add as sibling</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>When opening a <b>Simple Documentation Framework</b> test document in
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the toolbar below will be displayed at the top of
          the editor.</cmd>
        <info><fig>
            <title>Author Custom Actions Toolbar</title>
          </fig><image href="../img/bt_dg_author_custom_actions_toolbar.png"/><p>
            <note type="tip">If you have many custom toolbar actions, or want to group actions
              according to their category, add additional toolbars with custom names and split the
              actions to better suit your purpose. In case your toolbar is not displayed when
              switching to the <b>Author</b> mode, right click the main toolbar and make sure the
              entry labeled <uicontrol>Author custom actions 1</uicontrol> is enabled.</note>
          </p></info>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
