<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="dg-insert-section-action">
  <title>Creating the Insert Section Action</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Settings<indexterm>actions<indexterm>insert
            section</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>This section presents all the steps that you need to follow, to define the
          <uicontrol>Insert Section</uicontrol> action. We assume the icon files <image
          href="../img/bt_section16.png"/> (<filepath>Section16.png</filepath>) for the menu item
        and <image href="../img/bt_section20.png"/> (<filepath>Section20.png</filepath>) for the
        toolbar, are already available. Although you could use the same icon size for both menu and
        toolbar, usually the icons from the toolbars are larger than the ones found in the menus.
        These files should be placed in the <filepath>frameworks / sdf</filepath> directory.</p>
      <fig product="editor author authorSDK">
        <title>The Action Dialog</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_dg_edit_action_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
      <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
        <title>The Action Dialog</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_dg_edit_action_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set the <b>ID</b> field to <b>insert_section</b>. This is an unique action
          identifier.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set the <b>Name</b> field to <b>Insert Section</b>. This will be the action's name,
          displayed as a tooltip when the action is placed in the toolbar, or as the menu item
          name.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set the <b>Menu access key</b> to <b>i</b>. On Windows, the menu items can be accessed
          using (ALT + <keyword>letter</keyword>) combination, when the menu is visible. The
            <keyword>letter</keyword> is visually represented by underlining the first letter from
          the menu item name having the same value.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set the <b>Description</b> field to <b>Insert a section at caret position</b>. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set the <b>Large icon (20x20)</b> field to<b> ${frameworks} / sdf / Section20.png</b>.
          A good practice is to store the image files inside the framework directory and use <xref
            href="../topics/editor-variables.dita#editor-variables">editor variable</xref>
          <filepath>${framework}</filepath> to make the image relative to the framework
          location.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>If the images are bundled in a jar archive together with some Java operations
            implementation for instance, it might be convenient for you to refer the images not by
            the file name, but by their relative path location in the class-path.</p>
          <p>If the image file <filepath>Section20.png</filepath> is located in the <b>images</b>
            directory inside the jar archive, you can refer to it by using
              <b>/images/Section20.png</b>. The jar file must be added into the
              <uicontrol>Classpath</uicontrol> list.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set the <b>Small icon (16x16)</b> field to <b>${frameworks} / sdf /
          Section16.png</b>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the text field next to <b>Shortcut key</b> and set it to <b>Ctrl (Meta on Mac
            OS)+Shift+S</b>. This will be the key combination to trigger the action using the
          keyboard only.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The shortcut is enabled only by <xref
              href="dg-configuring-author-menu.dita#dg-configuring-author-menu">adding the action to
              the main menu of the Author mode</xref> which contains all the actions that the author
            will have in a menu for the current document type.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>At this time the action has no functionality added to it. Next you must define how this
          action operates. An action can have multiple operation modes, each of them activated by
          the evaluation of an XPath version 2.0 expression. The first enabled action mode will be
          executed when the action is triggered by the user. The scope of the XPath expression must
          be only element nodes and attribute nodes of the edited document, otherwise the expression
          will not return a match and will not fire the action. For this example we'll suppose you
          want allow the action to add a section only if the current element is either a
            <codeph>book</codeph>, <codeph>article</codeph> or another
          <codeph>section</codeph>.</cmd>
        <substeps id="substeps_fafb419f-187b-4bbf-8986-48ee0120f0b0">
          <substep>
            <cmd>Set the XPath expression field to:</cmd>
            <stepxmp>
              <codeblock>local-name()='section' or local-name()='book' or 
 local-name()='article'</codeblock>
            </stepxmp>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd>Set the <b>invoke operation</b> field to <apiname>InsertFragmentOperation</apiname>
              built-in operation, designed to insert an XML fragment at caret position. This belongs
              to a set of built-in operations, a complete list of which can be found in the <xref
                href="../topics/dg-default-author-operations.dita#dg-default-author-operations"
                format="dita">Author Default Operations</xref> section. This set can be expanded
              with your own Java operation implementations. </cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd>Configure the arguments section as follows:</cmd>
            <stepxmp>
              <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;section xmlns=
"http://www.oxygenxml.com/sample/documentation"&gt;
     &lt;title/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</codeblock>
              <p><apiname>insertLocation</apiname> - leave it empty. This means the location will be
                at the caret position.</p>
              <p><apiname>insertPosition</apiname> - select "<b>Inside</b>".</p>
            </stepxmp>
          </substep>
        </substeps>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
