<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="dita-insert-conref">
  <title>Insert a Direct Content Reference</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Reuse<indexterm>insert a direct content reference</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>You can use the same content in multiple topics by inserting a DITA content reference
      to that content. The following steps describe the procedure of inserting a DITA content
      reference:</context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Position your caret inside the element that you want to refer and in the <xref
            href="../topics/attributes-panel.dita#attributes-panel"
              ><uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view</xref> enter a value in the
            <uicontrol>ID</uicontrol> field.</cmd>
        <info>In case you want to reuse just a part of the content of an element, select the content
          with your cursor, press <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> and in the proposals list select
            <codeph>ph</codeph>. This encapsulates your content inside a
            <codeph>phrase(&lt;ph>)</codeph> element, allowing you to set an ID and then refer it.
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Open the topic where you want to insert the reference to this element.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_conref.png"/> Insert a DITA Content
            Reference</uicontrol> on the main toolbar.</cmd>
        <stepresult>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog is
          displayed.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog, from the
            <uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> field, navigate to the topic that holds the element you want
          to refer.</cmd>
        <stepresult>In the <uicontrol>Target ID</uicontrol> section of the <uicontrol>Insert Content
            Reference</uicontrol> dialog <ph keyref="product"/> presents the elements that you can
          refer.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the ID of the element you want to refer, then click
          <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.</cmd>
        <info>In case you select an interval of elements, the <uicontrol>Conrefend</uicontrol> field
          is filled with the <codeph>id</codeph> value of the element that ends the selected
          interval.</info>
        <stepresult>A reference to the selected element is inserted at the caret position.<note
            id="search-content-references">To search for references made through a direct content
            reference of a topic, paragraph, list item and so on, use the <uicontrol>Search
              References</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu.</note></stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>