<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="eppo-create-book-map">
  <title>Creating a Book in DITA</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>If you want to create a traditional book in DITA, you can use a book map to organize your
        topics into a book. A DITA book map is a specialized type of map, intended for creating
        output that is structured like a book. A book map allows you to add book-specific elements
        such as <codeph>frontmatter</codeph>, <codeph>part</codeph>, <codeph>chapter</codeph>,
          <codeph>appendix</codeph>, and <codeph>backmatter</codeph> to the map. How these
        book-specific elements are processed for publication is up to the processing script for each
        media. See the <xref href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.2/os/spec/DITA1.2-spec.html"
          format="html" scope="external">DITA documentation</xref> for details. </p>
      <p>You can find additional support for creating books in DITA in the DITA for Publishers
        plugin, which is included with <ph keyref="product">.</ph></p>
      <p>To create a book in DITA using a book map:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Create a new book map. <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>New...</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> DITA Map</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>map</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Bookmap</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Create the structure of your book by adding the appropriate book sections and defining
          containers for chapters and any appendices. To add sections to a book map, or children to
          a section, right-click on the book map or section icon and choose <uicontrol>Append
            child</uicontrol>. The selections offered in the <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol>Insert After</uicontrol> menus will adjust depending on the element they are
          applied to. Consult the DITA documentation to fully understand the structure of a DITA
          book map and where to create each element. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Create special elements like an <xref keyref="dita.index">index</xref> and a <xref
            keyref="dita.table-of-contents">table of contents</xref>. The index and table of
          contents will be generated by the build process, based on the content of the map and the
          topics it points to. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd><xref keyref="dita.add-topic-to-map">Add topics</xref> to your chapters to add content
          to your book. You may find it easier to manage if you <xref keyref="dita.submaps">use
            sub-maps</xref> to create the content of your chapters. This keeps your book map from
          becoming long and difficult to manage. </cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
