<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="eppo-creating-reusable-content">
  <title>Creating a Reusable Content Component</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>Almost any content element in DITA can be made reusable simply by adding an
          <codeph>id</codeph> attribute to it. The DITA content reference (<codeph>conref</codeph>)
        mechanism can reuse any element with an <term>id</term>. However, it is considered best
        practice not to reuse arbitrary pieces of text out of arbitrary topics due to the management
        overhead this creates, and the possibility of authors deleting or changing content that is
        reused in other topics without being aware that the content is reused. Instead, create and
        manage a separate set of topics that contain topics designed specifically for reuse. </p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> makes it easy to create reusable content components from existing
        topic content.</p>
      <note>
        <p>To ensure that the topic file that contains the reusable component is a valid container
          for just the reusable content component, without having to include the other elements
          required by a standard topic type, <ph keyref="product"/> creates a specialized topic type
          on the fly. This specialization is designed to make sure that the content is compatible
          with the topic type from which it is created. </p>
      </note>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the content you want to make into a reusable component.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Choose <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Create Reusable Component...</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</cmd>
        <stepresult>The <wintitle>Create Reusable Component</wintitle> dialog box is
          displayed.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Reuse Content</uicontrol> field, select the scope of the content to
          be made reusable. The choices presented are each of the container elements of the current
          caret position, allowing you to select how much of the current content you want to make
          reusable.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Add a description. This becomes the title of the topic that contains the reusable
          component, but is not part of the reusable content. It is just to help you identify the
          reusable content. It will not become part of your output.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select whether you want the current content to be replaced by the reusable component.
          This is recommended, since the point of reuse is to maintain only one copy of the content.
        </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select a file name and location to save the topic containing the reusable component and
          click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. It is considered best practice to save or store
          reusable components in an area set aside for that purpose.</cmd>
        <stepresult>If you selected to have your current content replaced by the reusable component,
            <ph keyref="product"/> replaces the current content with a content reference. The
          content of the content reference will be shown in your current topic, but it will no
          longer be editable. To see the source of the reusable component, click on the
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/link.png" id="image_mt1_mjf_wr"/>Link</uicontrol> icon
          at the beginning of the inserted content. </stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>You now have a reusable component that you can include in other topics using a <xref
          href="../topics/eppo-create-conref.dita#eppo.dita.create-conref">content reference</xref>
        or a <xref href="../topics/eppo-create-conkeyref.dita#eppo.dita.create-conkeyref">content
          key reference</xref>.</p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
