<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="eppo-relationship-table-linking">
  <title>Linking with Relationship Tables in DITA</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Linking<indexterm>Relationship
          tables</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Relationship tables</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>A relationship table is used to express relationships between topics outside of the topics
        themselves. The DITA publishing scripts can then create links between related topics when
        the content is published.</p>
      <p>The reason for using a relationship table is to help make topics easier to reuse. If a
        topic links directly to another topic, this creates a dependency between the topics. If one
        topic is reused in a publication where the other is not used, the link is broken. By
        defining relationships between topics in a relationship table, you avoid creating this
        dependency. </p>
      <p>To create an appropriate set of links between topics in multiple publications, you can
        create a separate relationship table for each publication. If you are creating multiple
        publications by applying profiling conditions to a single map, you can also profile your
        relationship table.</p>
      <p>To create a relationship table, follow these steps :</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>If the map is currently open in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>,
          double-click the map icon (<image href="../img/TreeMode16.png" id="image_qsq_cbm_1q"/>) to
          open the map in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. If it opens in
            <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, click <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> at the bottom left
          to switch to <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Move the insertion point inside the <term>map</term> root element (usually
            <codeph>map</codeph>, but it might be <codeph>bookmap</codeph>, or another
          specialization of the <codeph>map</codeph> element). The easiest way to do this is to
          click below the title of the map in the editor and then press the up arrow once. Confirm
          that you are inside the <term>map</term> root element by checking the breadcrumbs at the
          top left of the editor window. You should only see the name of the <term>map</term> root
          element.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol><image href="../img/RelTable16.gif" id="image_fqg_5rx_sr"/>Insert
            Relationship Table</uicontrol> action on the toolbar or from the <uicontrol>Relationship
            Table</uicontrol> submenu of the contextual menu.</cmd>
        <stepresult>The <uicontrol>Insert Relationship Table</uicontrol> dialog box is
          displayed.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set the number of rows, the number of columns, a table title (optional), and select
          whether or not you want a table header. Click <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Enter the type of the topics in the header of each column.</cmd>
        <info>The header of the table (the <codeph>relheader</codeph> element) already contains a
            <codeph>relcolspec</codeph> element for each table column. You should set the value of
          the attribute <codeph>type</codeph> of each <codeph>relcolspec</codeph> element to a value
          such as <i>concept</i>, <i>task</i>, or <i>reference</i>. When you click in the header
          cell of a column (that is a <codeph>relcolspec</codeph> element), you can see all the
          attributes of that <codeph>relcolspec</codeph> element, including the
            <codeph>type</codeph> attribute in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view. You can
          edit the attribute type in this view.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To insert a topic reference in a cell, place the cursor in a table cell and select
            <xref href="create-topic-in-map.dita#create-topic-in-map"><uicontrol><image
                href="../img/Topicref16.png" id="image_k22_dvx_sr"/>Insert
            Reference</uicontrol></xref> from the contextual menu or the <uicontrol>DITA
            Map</uicontrol> toolbar.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To add a new row to the table or remove an existing row use <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/RelTableRow16.gif" id="image_qhv_d5x_sr"/>Insert Relationship
            Row</uicontrol>/<uicontrol><image href="../img/RelDeleteRow16.gif" id="image_s3c_d5x_sr"
            />Delete Relationship Row</uicontrol> from the contextual menu or the <uicontrol>DITA
            Map</uicontrol> toolbar.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To add a new column to the table or remove an existing column, use <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/RelTableColumn16.gif" id="image_ls3_25x_sr"/>Insert Relationship
            Column</uicontrol>/<uicontrol><image href="../img/RelDeleteColumn16.gif"
              id="image_df5_25x_sr"/>Delete Relationship Column</uicontrol> contextual menu or the
            <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol> toolbar. If you double-click the relationship table (or
          select it and press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>, or choose
            <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> from the contextual menu) the <term>DITA map</term> is
          opened in the editor with the cursor positioned inside the corresponding relationship
          table.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To add topic references to your relationship table, drag and drop topics from the
            <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> or the <xref
            href="../topics/using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view"><uicontrol
              product="author editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
              product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</uicontrol></xref> view into the
          appropriate cell in the relationship table.</cmd>
        <info>See the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/dita/1.3/specs/langRef/base/reltable.html" format="html"
            scope="external">DITA documentation</xref> for a full explanation of the relationship
          table format and its options. Note that you can change all the selections that you make
          here later by using the actions on the toolbar (or in the <uicontrol>Relationship
            Table</uicontrol> submenu of the contextual menu) or by editing the underlying XML in
            <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Save the <term>DITA map</term>.</cmd>
        <stepresult>Relationship tables are also displayed in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
            Manager</uicontrol> view, along with the other elements in its <term>DITA map</term>. <p>
            <fig>
              <title>Relationship Table</title>
              <image href="../img/sa_reltable_ditamap.png" id="image_pxv_njx_sq"/>
            </fig>
          </p><p>You can open the DITA map to edit the relationship table by doing one of the
              following:<ul id="ul_npp_trx_sq">
              <li>Double-click the appropriate relationship table in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                  Manager</uicontrol>.</li>
              <li>Select the relationship table in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> and
                press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>.</li>
              <li>Select <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> from the contextual menu of the relationship
                table in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>.</li>
            </ul></p></stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
