<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="task_wsh_tnd_xp">
    <title>Linking with Relationship Tables in DITA</title>
    <shortdesc/>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>A relationship table is used to express relationships between topics outside of the
        topics themselves. The DITA publishing scripts can then create links between related topics
        when the content is published. Links are generally created at the end of each topic, though
        this is up to the publishing scripts. </p>
      <p>The reason for using a relationship table is to help make topics easier to reuse. If a
        topic links directly to another topic, this creates a dependency between the topics. If one
        is reused in a publication where the other is not used, the link will be broken. By defining
        relationships between topics in a relationship table, you avoid creating this dependency. </p>
      <p>To create an appropriate set of links between topics in different publications, you can
        create a separate relationship table for each publication. If you are creating different
        publications by applying profiling conditions to a single map, you can also profile your
        relationship table.</p>
      <p>To create a relationship table.</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>A relationship table is created in a map. Open the map you want to use in the
            <xref keyref="mode.author">Author mode</xref>. (If the map is currently open in the DITA
          Maps Manager, double click the map icon <image href="../img/TreeMode16.png"
            id="image_qsq_cbm_1q"/> to open the map in the editor. If it opens in <xref
            keyref="mode.text">Text mode</xref>, click <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> at the bottom
          left to switch to Author mode.)</cmd>
            </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Move the insertion point inside the map root element (generally <codeph>map</codeph>,
          but it might be <codeph>bookmap</codeph>, or another specialization of the
            <codeph>map</codeph> element). The easiest way to do this is to click below the text of
          the map and then press the up arrow once. Confirm that you are inside the root element by
          checking the breadcrumbs at the top left of the editor window. You should see just the
          name of the root element.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Hit Enter to display the content completion assistant. Choose
          <codeph>reltable</codeph>. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Insert a DITA reltable</uicontrol> button <image
            href="../img/RelTable20.gif" id="image_x52_bgm_1q"/> on the DITA Maps Toolbar. The
            <wintitle>Insert Relationship Table</wintitle> dialog is displayed. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Make the appropriate selections in the <wintitle>Relationship Table</wintitle> dialog.
          See the DITA documentation for a full explanation of the relationship table format and its
          options. Note that you can change all the selections you make here later using the buttons
          on the DITA Maps Toolbar or by editing the underlying XML.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To add topic references to your relationship table, drag and drop topics from the
            <wintitle>DITA Maps Manger</wintitle> or the <wintitle>Project</wintitle> view into the
          appropriate cell in the relationship table.</cmd>
      </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
