<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="executing-sql-statements">
    <title>Executing SQL Statements</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
      <p>The steps for executing an SQL statement on a relational database are as follows:</p>
    </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
        <cmd>Configure a <xref href="../concepts/transformation-scenario.dita">transformation
            scenario</xref> using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/TransformConfig16.png"
              id="image_qxr_1wv_sr"/>Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> action from
          the toolbar or the <menucascade product="author developer editor">
            <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Transformation</uicontrol>
          </menucascade><uicontrol product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
            >XML</uicontrol> menu.</cmd>
        <info>A SQL transformation scenario needs a database connection. You can configure a
          connection using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Options16.png"
            />Preferences</uicontrol> button from the SQL transformation dialog box.</info>
        <stepresult>The dialog box contains the list of existing scenarios that apply to SQL
          documents.</stepresult>
      </step>
            <step>
        <cmd>Set parameter values for SQL placeholders using the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol>
          button from the SQL transformation dialog box.</cmd>
        <info>For example, in <codeph>SELECT * FROM `test`.`department` where DEPT = ? or DEPTNAME =
            ?</codeph> the two parameters can be configured for the place holders (?) in the
          transformation scenario.<p>When the SQL statement is executed, the first placeholder is
            replaced with the value set for the first parameter in the scenario, the second
            placeholder is replaced by the second parameter value, and so on.<note
              type="restriction">When a stored procedure is called in an SQL statement executed on
              an SQL Server database, mixing inline parameter values with values specified using
              the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> button of the scenario dialog box is not
              recommended. This is due to a limitation of the SQL Server driver for Java
              applications. An example of stored procedure that is not recommended: <codeph>call
                dbo.Test(22, ?)</codeph>.</note></p></info>
      </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Execute the SQL scenario by clicking the <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol>Apply associated</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
                <stepresult>
                    <p>The result of a SQL transformation is <xref
              href="../topics/results-view.dita#results-view" format="dita">displayed in a
              view</xref> at the bottom of the <ph keyref="product"/> window.</p>
                </stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>View more complex return values of the SQL transformation in a separate editor
                    panel.</cmd>
                <info>A more complex value returned by the SQL query (for example, an
            <term>XMLTYPE</term> or <term>CLOB</term> value) cannot be displayed entirely in the
          result table.</info>
                <substeps>
                    <substep>
            <cmd>Right-click the cell containing the complex value.</cmd>
          </substep>
                    <substep>
                        <cmd>Select the action <uicontrol>Copy cell</uicontrol> from the contextual
              menu.</cmd>
                        <stepresult>The action copies the value in the clipboard.</stepresult>
                    </substep>
                    <substep>
                        <cmd>Paste the value into an appropriate editor.</cmd>
            <info>For example, you can paste the value in an opened XQuery editor panel of <ph
                keyref="product"/>.</info>
                    </substep>
                </substeps>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task>
