<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="import-text">
  <title>Import from Text Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Importing Data<indexterm>from text files</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>The steps for importing a text file into an XML file are the following:</context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Go to menu <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Text File... </uicontrol>
          </menucascade>
        </cmd>
        <stepresult>The <uicontrol>Select text file</uicontrol> dialog box is
          displayed.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the URL of the text file.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the encoding of the text file.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <stepresult>
          <p>The <uicontrol>Import Criteria</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed:</p>
          <fig product="editor developer">
            <title>Import from text file</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_import_text.png"/>
          </fig>
          <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
            <title>Import from text file</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_import_text.png"/>
          </fig>
          <p>The input data is displayed in a tabular form. The <uicontrol>XML Import
              Preview</uicontrol> panel contains an example of what the generated XML document looks
            like. The names of the XML elements and the transformation of the first five lines from
            the text file are displayed in the <uicontrol>Import settings</uicontrol> section. All
            data items in the input are converted by default to element content, but this can be
            overridden by clicking the individual column headers. Clicking once a column header
            causes the data from this column to be used as attribute values of the row elements.
            Click the second time and the column's data is ignored when generating the XML file. You
            can cycle through these three options by continuing to click the column header. The
            following symbols decorate the column header to indicate the type of content that column
            is converted to:<ul id="ul_132_krd_ff">
              <li><i>&lt;&gt;</i> symbols for data columns converted to element content</li>
              <li><i>=</i> symbol for data columns converted to attribute content</li>
              <li><i>x</i> symbol for ignored data</li>
            </ul></p>
        </stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the field delimiter for the import settings:</cmd>
        <choices>
          <choice>Comma;</choice>
          <choice>Semicolon;</choice>
          <choice>Tab;</choice>
          <choice>Space;</choice>
          <choice>Pipe.</choice>
        </choices>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Set other optional settings of the conversion.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The dialog offers the following settings:</p>
          <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>First row contains field names</uicontrol> - If the option is enabled,
              you will notice that the table has moved up. The default column headers are replaced
              (where such information is available) by the content of the first row. In other words,
              the first row is interpreted as containing the field names. The changes are also
              visible in the preview of the XML document. To return to default settings (where the
              first row is interpreted as containing data and not fields names), simply uncheck the
              option.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change labels</uicontrol> -This button opens a new dialog, allowing you
              to edit the names of the root and row elements, change the XML name and the conversion
                criterion.<p>The XML names can be edited by double-clicking the desired item and
                entering the required label. The conversion criterion can also be modified by
                selecting one of the drop-down list options: <uicontrol>ELEMENT</uicontrol>,
                  <uicontrol>ATTRIBUTE</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>SKIPPED</uicontrol>.</p></li>
            <li product="editor developer"><uicontrol>Open in editor</uicontrol> - If checked, the
              new XML document created from the imported text file is opened in the editor.</li>
            <li product="editor developer"><uicontrol>Save in file</uicontrol> - If checked, the new
              XML document is saved at the specified path.<note>If only <uicontrol>Open in
                  editor</uicontrol> is checked, the newly created document is opened in the editor,
                but as an unsaved file.</note></li>
            <li product="editorEclipse developerEclipse"><uicontrol>Output file</uicontrol> - Allows
              you to select the output XML file.</li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
