<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="import-db-table-content-to-xml">
  <title>Import Table Content as XML Document</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Importing Data<indexterm>from a database<indexterm>table content as XML
              document</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>The steps for importing the data from a relational database table are the
      following:</context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd><ph product="editor developer">Go to menu <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Database Data...</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></ph><ph product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">Go to menu <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>oXygen / Database Data</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</ph></cmd>
        <stepresult>
          <p>Clicking this action opens a dialog with all the defined database connections:</p>
          <fig product="editor developer">
            <title>Select Database Table Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_select_database_table.png"/>
          </fig>
          <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
            <title>Import From Database Data Wizard</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_select_database_table.png"/>
          </fig>
        </stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the connection to the database that contains the data. </cmd>
        <info>Only connections configured on relational data sources can be used to import
          data.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>If you want to edit, delete or add a data source or connection click on the
            <uicontrol>Configure Database Sources</uicontrol> button. </cmd>
        <stepresult>The <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>/<uicontrol>Data Sources</uicontrol>
          option page is opened.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>From the catalogs list, click on a schema and choose the required table.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <stepresult>
          <p>The <uicontrol>Import Criteria</uicontrol> dialog opens next, with a default query
            string in the <uicontrol>SQL Query</uicontrol> pane:</p>
          <fig product="editor developer">
            <title>Import from Database Criteria Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_import_criteria_db.png"/>
          </fig>
          <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
            <title>Import from Database Criteria Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_import_criteria_db.png"/>
          </fig>
          <p>The dialog contains the following items:</p>
          <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>SQL Preview</uicontrol> - If the <uicontrol>SQL Preview</uicontrol>
              button is pressed, it shows the labels that are used in the XML document and the first
              five lines from the database into the <uicontrol>Import settings</uicontrol> panel.
              All data items in the input are converted by default to element content, but this can
              be overridden by clicking the individual column headers. Clicking once on a column
              header (ex <uicontrol>Heading0</uicontrol>) causes the data from this column to be
              used as attribute values of the row elements. Click a second time and the column's
              data is ignored when generating the XML file. You can cycle through these three
              options by continuing to click the column header. The following symbols decorate the
              column header to indicate the type of content that column is converted to:<ul
                id="ul_132_krd_ff">
                <li><i>&lt;&gt;</i> symbols for data columns converted to element content</li>
                <li><i>=</i> symbol for data columns converted to attribute content</li>
                <li><i>x</i> symbol for ignored data</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change labels</uicontrol> - This button opens a new dialog, allowing you
              to edit the names of the root and row elements, change the XML name and the conversion
              criterion. The XML names can be edited by double-clicking the desired item and
              entering the required label. The conversion criterion can also be modified by
              selecting from the drop-down list <uicontrol>ELEMENT</uicontrol>,
                <uicontrol>ATTRIBUTE</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>SKIPPED</uicontrol>.</li>
            <li product="editor developer"><uicontrol>Open in editor</uicontrol> - If checked, the
              new XML document created from the imported text file is open in the editor.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Save in file</uicontrol> - If checked, the new XML document is saved at
              the specified path.<note>If only <uicontrol>Open in editor</uicontrol> is checked, the
                newly created document is open in the editor, but as an unsaved file.</note></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Generate XML Schema</uicontrol> - Allows you to specify the path of the
              generated XML Schema file.</li>
          </ul>
        </stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>SQL Preview</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The <uicontrol>SQL Query</uicontrol> string is editable. You can specify which fields
            are considered.</p>
        </info>
        <stepxmp>
          <p>Use aliases if the following are true:<ul id="ul_f4h_yrd_ff">
              <li>the query string represents a join operation of two or more tables</li>
              <li>columns selected from different tables have the same name</li>
            </ul></p>
          <p>The use of aliases avoids the confusion of two columns being mapped to the same name in
            the result document of the importing operation.</p>
          <codeblock>
  select s.subcat_id,
        s.nr as s_nr,
        s.name,
        q.q_id,
        q.nr as q_nr,
        q.q_text
    from faq.subcategory s,
            faq.question q
    where  ...</codeblock>
        </stepxmp>
        <stepresult>The input data is displayed in a tabular form in the <uicontrol>Import
            Settings</uicontrol> panel. The <uicontrol>XML Import Preview</uicontrol> panel contains
          an example of what the generated XML looks like.</stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>