<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="synchronize-branch">
  <title>Synchronize a Branch</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Branches/Tags<indexterm>merging<indexterm>synchronize branch</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>While working on your own branch, other people on your team continue to make important
      changes in it's parent branch (which can be the <term>trunk</term> itself or any other
      branch). It's in your best interest to replicate those changes to your branch, to make sure
      they mesh well with your changes. This is done by performing a <term>synchronize merge</term>,
      that will bring your branch up-to-date with any changes made to its ancestral parent branch,
      since your branch was created. Subversion is aware of the history of your branch and knows
      when it split away from the parent branch.<p>Frequently keeping your branch in sync with the
        parent branch helps you prevent "surprise" conflicts when the time comes for you to hold
        your changes back into the parent. The synchronization uses merge tracking to skip all those
        revisions that have already been merged, so a sync merge can be repeated periodically to
        fetch all the parent's latest changes, in order to stay up-to-date with it.</p><p>
        <note type="important">It is recommended to synchronize the whole working copy of the child
          branch (the root of the working copy), not just a part of it.</note>
      </p><p>After running the prior example, your branch working copy now contains new local
        modifications, and these edits are duplications of all of the changes that have happened on
        the trunk since you first created your branch:</p><p>At this point, your private branch is
        now "in sync" with the trunk, so you can rest easier knowing that as you continue to work in
        isolation, you're not drifting too far away from what everyone else is doing. </p></context>
    <steps id="steps_ejx_brz_h4">
      <step conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/start-wizard">
        <cmd/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Synchronize branch</uicontrol> option.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/merge_wizard_second_page">
        <cmd/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <b>Parent branch (URL)</b> field enter the URL of the branch from which you
          created your branch. This means that the URL must belong to the same repository as your
          working copy from the child branch.</cmd>
        <info>
          <ph
            conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/merge_browse_source_repository"/>
          <note><ph
              conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/merge-source-peg-revision"/>
            The peg revision specifies both the peg revision of the URL and the latest revision that
            will be considered for merging. By default, the <codeph>HEAD</codeph> revision is
            assumed.</note></info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Press the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <stepresult><ph conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/options-set-result"
              /><note><uicontrol>Ignore ancestry / Disable merge tracking</uicontrol> is not
            available for this merge type, since a synchronization merge should always be recorded
            in the destination branch.</note></stepresult>
      </step>
      <step conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/perform-merge">
        <cmd/>
      </step>
      <step conref="resolve-merge-conflicts.dita#resolve-merge-conflicts/resolve-conflicts">
        <cmd/>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/merge-result"/>
    <postreq conref="merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range/merge-postreq"/>
  </taskbody>
</task>
