<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic-1">
    <title>Chrysanthemum</title>
    <body>
        <p><i>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia.</i></p>
        <p><b>Chrysanthemums</b><indexterm>flowers<indexterm>autumn<indexterm>chrysanthemums</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>,
            often called 'mums', are a <xref keyref="flowers.genus" format="dita">genus</xref>
                (<b>Chrysanthemum</b>) of about 30 species of <xref keyref="flowers.perennial"
                format="dita">perennial</xref> flowering plants in the family Asteraceae, native to
            Asia and northeastern Europe.</p>
        <p><image href="../../images/Chrysanthemums.jpg" scale="200"/></p>
        <p class="- topic/p ">(Edit file)The genus once included many more species, but was split
            several decades ago into several genera; the naming of the genera has been contentious,
            but a ruling of the International Code of Botanical Nomenclature in 1999 resulted in the
            defining species of the genus being changed to <b>Chrysanthemum indicum</b>, thereby
            restoring the economically important florist's chrysanthemum to the genus
                <b>Chrysanthemum</b>. These species were, after the splitting of the genus but
            before the ICBN ruling, commonly treated under the genus name <b>Dendranthema</b>.</p>
        <p><b>Chrysanthemums</b> were cultivated in China as a flowering herb as far back as the
            15th century BC. An ancient Chinese city was named Ju-Xian, meaning "<i>chrysanthemum
                city</i>". The plant is particularly significant during the Double Ninth Festival.
            The flower was introduced into Japan probably in the 8th century AD, and the Emperor
            adopted the flower as his official seal. There is a "<i>Festival of Happiness</i>" in
            Japan that celebrates the flower.</p>
        <p>The flower was brought to Europe in the 17th century. Linnaeus named it from the Greek
            word <i>chrysous</i>, golden (the colour of the original flowers), and -<i>anthemon</i>,
            meaning flower.</p>
        <p><b>Chrysanthemums</b> are broken into two basic groups, Garden Hardy and Exhibition.
            Garden hardy mums are perennials capable of being wintered over in the ground in most
            northern latitudes. Exhibition varieties are not usually as sturdy. Garden hardies are
            defined by their ability to produce an abundance of small blooms with little if any
            mechanical assistance (ie. staking) and withstanding wind and rain. Exhibition varieties
            on the other hand require staking, over-wintering in a relatively dry cool environment,
            sometimes with the addition of night lights.</p>
    </body>
    <related-links>
        <link href="salvia.dita#topic-1"/>
    </related-links>
</topic>
