<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD LW DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_ej5_fbv_mv">
  <title>oXygen XML Editor</title>
  <shortdesc>The Complete XML Development &amp; Authoring Solution!</shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <data name="source" value="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor.html"/>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section id="section_ssk_vbx_mv">
      <title>XML Editor</title>
      <p>oXygen XML Editor is the complete XML editing solution, both for XML developers and content
        authors. It provides must have tools for XML editing, covering most XML standards and
        technologies. oXygen XML Editor includes all the features of oXygen XML Developer and
        Author. </p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/mb_editor.png"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_asm_1cx_mv">
      <title>Features &amp; Technologies</title>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_single_source_publishing.png"/></p>
      <p><b>Single-Source Publishing</b></p>
      <p>The XML Editor offers preset and configurable scenarios that are one click away, allowing
        you to produce outputs in PDF, ePUB, HTML, and many other formats using the same source.</p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/oxygen_single_source_publishing.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_structured_editing.png"/></p>
      <p>
        <b>Structured XML Editing</b></p>
      <p>The most intuitive XML editing features and a user-friendly interface, helping you to
        improve the results of your work with oXygen XML Editor.</p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/intelligent_xml_editing.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_publishing_framework.png"/></p>
      <p><b>XML Publishing Frameworks</b></p>
      <p>oXygen XML Editor includes ready-to-use support for DITA, DocBook, XHTML, and TEI
        frameworks. </p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/WYSIWYG_Editors.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_extensibility.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>Extensibility</b></p>
      <p>Take advantage of unmatched extensibility support and enhance the built-in XML publishing
        frameworks of the XML Editor, or even create your own frameworks. </p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/extensible_xml_editor_frameworks.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_connectivity.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>Connectivity</b></p>
      <p>The powerful connectivity support of the XML Editor allows you to interact with the
        majority of XML databases, content management systems, and WebDAV.</p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/native_xml_databases.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_collaboration.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>Collaboration</b></p>
      <p>oXygen allows you to collaborate with other authors more efficient than ever using the XML
        Editor's tracking tools, subversion repository client, and compare and merge solutions.</p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/change_tracking_and_review.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_intelligent_xml.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>Intelligent XML Editor</b></p>
      <p>XML editing is more effective than ever with the help of intelligent actions and features
        designed to be intuitive, responsive, and easy to use. </p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/intelligent_xml_editing.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_xml_validation.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>XML Validation</b></p>
      <p>Make sure your XML documents are "well-formed" and valid, using as-you-type validation
        support and context-sensitive editing capabilities of the XML Editor.</p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/validation.html" format="html" scope="external"
          >Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_xml_db.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>XML Databases Support</b></p>
      <p>oXygen XML Editor can perform XQuery and XPath queries against a native XML database,
        through a connection to the database server. A dedicated collection of database exploring
        views are grouped together in a database perspective layout.</p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/native_xml_databases.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_xml_standards.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>All XML Standards Support</b></p>
      <p>Take advantage of the dedicated editors that oXygen XML Editor offers, covering all XML
        standards. The specialized views and operations of each editor offer support to edit XML
        Schemas, XSLT stylesheets, WSDL, RelaxNG, and XQuery files.</p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_xslt_xq_debugger.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>XSLT &amp; XQuery Debugging</b></p>
      <p>The XML Editor offers a powerful XSLT and XQuery debugger that provides full control over
        the debugging process. Two dedicated perspectives are available, one for XSLT and one for
        XQuery debugging. Both offers specialized views and actions that allow you to troubleshoot
        and perfect your documents.</p>
      <p><xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/xslt_debugger.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Read more</xref></p>
      <p><image href="http://oxygenxml.com/img/kf_web_services.png"/>
      </p>
      <p><b>Web Services Support in oXygen XML Editor</b></p>
      <p>The advanced WSDL editor helps you edit WSDL documents offering content completion
        capabilities, a specialized Outline view, and support for generating documentation. You can
        easily verify if the defined SOAP messages are accepted by the remote Web Services server
        using the XML editor's WSDL SOAP Analyzer integrated tool.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
