<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="accessibility">
  <title>Accessibility Support in Oxygen</title>
  <body>
    <p>Our company is dedicated to developing software products that are usable for everyone,
      including those with physical challenges and disabilities. <b>Oxygen XML</b> was designed to
      adhere to the U.S. Government Section 508 accessibility standards: <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/xml_editor/section508.html" format="html" scope="external"
      /></p>
    <p>As a Java application, <b>Oxygen</b> works and is periodically tested on Windows using the
      JAWS screen reader: <xref href="http://www.freedomscientific.com/Products/Blindness/JAWS"
        format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
    <p>You first need to enable the Java access bridge in <b>Oxygen</b> in order for JAWS to work:
        <xref
        href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/technotes/guides/access/enable_and_test.html"
        format="html" scope="external"/></p>
    <p>As <b>Oxygen</b> comes bundled with its own Java VM, you need to open a console in the
        <filepath>jre</filepath> folder bundled with <b>Oxygen</b> and run the following
      command:</p>
    <codeblock outputclass="language-ini">D:\PATH\TO\OXYGEN_INSTALLATION_FOLDER\jre>bin\jabswitch -enable</codeblock>
    <p>You will receive a notification in the console that the access bridge has been enabled.</p>
    <p>Once the Java access bridge is enabled, if the JAWS narrator is active, when <b>Oxygen</b>
      starts, the narrator will start reading content from <b>Oxygen</b> you can interact with the
      application, read menus, content from opened XML documents, and UI components from dialog
      boxes and side views.</p>
    <p>Here are a few hints for using <b>Oxygen</b> if you are visually impaired:<ul
        id="ul_owd_cv5_xcb">
        <li>The top main menu should contain most of the actions that you need to open, save, and
          close documents, switch between opened documents, or switch between the various editing
          modes for XML documents that are already opened.<ul id="ul_hyq_hv5_xcb">
            <li>The <uicontrol>File</uicontrol> menu contains actions to open, save, or close the
              currently edited XML document.</li>
            <li>The <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> menu contains actions to undo/redo or cut/copy/paste
              content. They also have the usual shortcuts that can be used instead of directly
              invoking the actions from the menu.</li>
            <li>The <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol> menu contains an action to show the
                <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> dialog box. Sometimes the <b>JAWS</b> narrator
              overloads the <b>CTRL-F</b> shortcut and presents its own find/replace window but the
                <b>Oxygen's</b>
              <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> dialog box provides the ability to perform complex
              find/replace operations in the opened file.</li>
            <li>In the <b>Options</b> menu, you have access to the <b>Preferences</b> dialog box
              that contains global application settings and access to the <b>Menu Shortcut Keys</b>
              table where you can configure shortcuts for the most commonly used actions.</li>
            <li>The <b>Window</b> menu includes actions to switch between opened XML documents.
              Also, you can use the <b>Show view</b> submenu open a particular side view and move
              the focus to that view.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li>An opened XML document can be edited with accessibility support either in the
            <b>Text</b> editing mode (where the XML tags are accessible in the edited content) or in
          the visual <b>Author</b> editing mode (where the XML tags are hidden and only the text
          content is shown). You can switch between these editing modes by using the <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Edit Mode</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> menu.<ul id="ul_jgk_nk1_ycb">
            <li><b>Text</b> mode provides access to the entire source document with all of its
                <b>XML</b> content, just like you have in any text editing application. In addition,
              using the <menucascade>
                <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol>Show view</uicontrol>
              </menucascade> submenu, you can change focus to the <b>Attributes</b>,
              <b>Elements</b>, or <b>Outline</b> view. The <b>Attributes</b> view presents the
              existing and possible attributes that can be inserted in an XML tag. The
                <b>Elements</b> view shows you the list of XML elements that can be inserted at
              cursor position (also, pressing F2 on a selected element presents its annotation). The
                <b>Outline</b> view shows the current path in the XML structure.</li>
            <li><b>Author</b> mode is useful for reviewing written XML content because it has
              support for change tracking and for adding comments. Editing in the <b>Author</b>
              visual editing mode, you have access only to the text content in the XML document.
              Pressing <b>Shift-F2</b> will read to you the location in the XML structure. Again,
              you can also use the <b>Outline</b> view for this. In the <b>Author</b> editing mode,
              you can also use the <b>Attributes</b> and <b>Elements</b> views similar to using them
              in the <b>Text</b> editing mode. Pressing <b>ENTER</b> in the <b>Author</b> visual
              editing mode can also be used to present a list of allowed elements at the current
              position.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
