<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="account_management">
    <title>Account Management</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Account management</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Reviewer Guide<indexterm>Account management</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Account management</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <section id="sign_up">
      <title>Sign Up</title>
      <p>If this is your first time using <ph keyref="product"/>, you need to create an account by
        following these steps:<ol>
          <li>If you have an active GitHub or Google account, you can simply click either of those
            two buttons and allow <ph keyref="product"/> to use those credentials. Otherwise,
            proceed to the next step.</li>
          <li>Click on <uicontrol>SIGN UP</uicontrol> and enter your name, a valid email address,
            and a password.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>I'm not a robot</uicontrol> checkbox.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Sign Up</uicontrol> button at the bottom.</li>
          <li>Open the email that is sent to the email address you entered and use the link to
            verify your email address.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol> to finalize the account creation process.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="login">
      <title>Login</title>
      <p>If you signed up using your GitHub or Google account, simply press either of those two
        buttons to login. Otherwise, enter your email address and password.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="forgot_your_password">
      <title>Forgot Your Password</title>
      <p>To reset your password, click the <uicontrol>Forgot Your Password</uicontrol> link at the
        bottom of the Login page. You will be directed to a page where you can enter your email
        address and you will receive an email with a link to reset your password.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="profile_page">
      <title>Profile Page</title>
      <p>To view your profile information, click on your user name in the top-right corner of the
          <ph keyref="product"/> interface and select <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol>. This opens
        your profile information page that displays your name, email, avatar, and allows you to
        delete your profile.</p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
