<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="add-syntax-highlights-codeblocks">
  <title>Adding Syntax Highlights for Codeblocks in the Output</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Output<indexterm>Syntax highlights in
            codeblocks</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Syntax highlights in codeblocks</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><term>Syntax Highlighting</term> makes it easier to read the semantics of the structured
      content by displaying each type of code (language) in different colors and fonts. <ph
        keyref="product"/> provides the ability to add syntax highlights in codeblocks for DITA to
      PDF or HTML-based output through the use of the <xmlatt>outputclass</xmlatt> attribute and a
      variety of predefined values are available.</p>
    <p>To provide syntax highlighting in the codeblocks that appear in the output, add the
        <xmlatt>outputclass</xmlatt> attribute on the <xmlelement>codeblock</xmlelement> element and
      set its value to one of the predefined language values. The <uicontrol>Content Completion
        Assistant</uicontrol> offers a list of the possible values when adding the
        <xmlatt>outputclass</xmlatt> attribute in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode but there are
      also two very simple ways to set the value in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode:<ul>
        <li>Select the <xmlelement>codeblock</xmlelement> element in the editor and in the
            <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view, click on the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> cell
          for the <codeph>outputclass</codeph> attribute and select one of the predefined values
          (for example, <codeph>language-xml</codeph>).</li>
        <li>Select the <xmlelement>codeblock</xmlelement> element in the editor and use the
            <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_enter"/> keyboard shortcut to
          open the in-place attributes editor window. Then select one of the predefined values from
          the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> drop-down menu.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The predefined values that can be selected are:<ul
        conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/ul-output-class-values">
        <li/>
      </ul></p>
    <note type="attention">It is recommended that you do not add inline elements in the codeblocks
      when using this <xmlatt>outputclass</xmlatt> attribute, as it may lead to improper
      highlighting.</note>
    <p><b>Example:</b></p>
    <p>This
      codeblock:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;codeblock outputclass="language-xml">
 &lt;p>This code is an example of how to use a coderef.&lt;/p>
   &lt;codeblock>&lt;coderef href="MyExternalCode.xsl"/>&lt;/codeblock>
&lt;/codeblock></codeblock></p>
    <p>would look like this in the output:</p>
    <image href="../img/codeblock-example.png"/>
  </body>
</topic>
