<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="add-resources-working-copy">
  <title>Add Resources to Version Control</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Working Copy Resources<indexterm>add resources to version
          control</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To share new files and folders (created in your working copy), add them to version control
      using the <uicontrol>Add to version control</uicontrol> option from the <xref
        href="working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref>. </p>
    <p>You can easily spot resources not under version control by the <image
        href="../img/sa_svn_wc_unversioned.png"/> (<term>unversioned</term>) icon displayed in the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNLocalContentStatusColumnHeader.png"/> Local file
        status</uicontrol> column. Resources scheduled for addition (<term>added</term>) are
      displayed with this icon <image href="../img/sa_svn_wc_added.png"/> in the <uicontrol>Working
        Copy</uicontrol> view and are added in the repository after you commit them. <note>Do not
        make a confusion between <image href="../img/SVNWCAddedWithHistory10.png"/> and <image
          href="../img/sa_svn_wc_added.png"/> icons. The former icon stands for resources that are
        actually copies of resources already committed in the repository, meaning they are
          <i>scheduled for addition with history</i>.</note></p>
    <p>When you use the <uicontrol>Add to version control</uicontrol> option on a directory, its
      entire structure is scanned and all the resources that can be added under version control are
      presented.</p>
    <p>Though it is not mandatory to add resources under version control explicitly, it is
      recommended. If you forgot to add a resource, when you <xref href="send-changes.dita">commit
        your changes</xref>, the resource is presented in the commit dialog, but not selected. When
      you commit and <term>unversioned</term> resource, it is automatically added under version
      control before starting the commit operation.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>"Add to version control" <uicontrol>dialog</uicontrol> box</title>
        <image href="../img/svn-add-to-version-control-dialog-box.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <note><term>Ignored</term> (<image href="../img/SVNWCIgnored10.png"/>) items can also be added
        under version control.</note>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Depth</uicontrol> column is displayed only when directories are also presented
      in the dialog. For any directory, you can use one of the available values to instruct
      Subversion to limit the scope of the operation to a particular tree depth.<note>The initial
        value of the <uicontrol>Depth</uicontrol> field can have the following values, depending on
        the <xref href="working-copy-settings.dita#working-copy-settings/view-mode">listing mode of
          the items in the working copy view</xref>:<ul>
          <li><i>infinity</i> - when the working copy items are presented as a tree;</li>
          <li><i>files</i> - when the working copy items are presented compressed;</li>
          <li><i>empty</i> - when the working copy items are presented flat.</li>
        </ul>When you add unversioned or ignored directories, the initial value of the
          <uicontrol>Depth</uicontrol> field also depends on the state of the <uicontrol>Show
          unversioned directories content</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Show ignored directories
          content</uicontrol> options. In case these options are enabled, the value is based on the
        listing mode of the items in the working copy view. When they are disabled, the value is
          <i>empty</i> .</note></p>
    <p>The following options are available in this dialog box:<ul>
        <li>
          <p id="enable-auto-properties"><uicontrol>Enable auto-properties</uicontrol> or
              <uicontrol>Disable auto-properties</uicontrol> - enables or disables automatic
            property assignment (per runtime configuration rules), overriding the
              <codeph>enable-auto-props</codeph> runtime configuration directive, defined in the
              <codeph>config</codeph> file of the Subversion configuration directory.<note>
              <p>This option is available only when there are defined properties to be applied
                automatically for resources newly added under version control. You can define these
                properties in the <codeph>config</codeph> file of the Subversion configuration
                directory, in the <codeph>auto-props</codeph> section.</p>
              <p>Based on the value of the <codeph>enable-auto-props</codeph> runtime configuration
                directive, the presented option is either <uicontrol>Enable
                  auto-properties</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Disable
                auto-properties</uicontrol>.</p>
            </note></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p id="no-ignore"><uicontrol>No ignore</uicontrol> - when you enable this option,
            file-name patterns defined to ignore <term>unversioned</term> resources do not apply.
            Resources that are located inside an <term>unversioned</term> directory selected for
            addition, and match these patterns, are also scheduled for addition in the repository.<note>
              <p>This option is available only when directories are also presented in the
                dialog.</p>
              <p>You can define file-name patterns to ignore <term>unversioned</term> resources in
                one of the following locations:<ul>
                  <li>in the <codeph>config</codeph> file of the Subversion configuration directory
                    (the <codeph>global-ignores</codeph> option from the <codeph>miscellany</codeph>
                    section);</li>
                  <li>in the <ph keyref="product"/> options: <menucascade>
                      <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol>SVN</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol>Working copy</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol> Application global ignores</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade>.</li>
                </ul></p>
            </note></p>
        </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>Each of the above two options is activated only when you select an item for which the option
      can be applied.</p>
  </body>
</topic>