<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ant-component-dependencies">
  <title>Ant Component Dependencies View</title>
    <body>
      <p>The Component Dependencies view allows you to see the dependencies for a selected Ant
      component. You can open the view from <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Component Dependencies</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu.</p>
      <p>If you want to see the dependencies of an Ant component, select the desired component in
      the editor or <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view and choose the <b>Component Dependencies</b>
      action from the contextual menu. The action is available for the following components:
      properties, targets (including extension points), and task or types references (those that
      have an id set). </p>
      <p>In the Component Dependencies view there are available the following toolbar actions:<ul
        id="ul_ggx_gfv_5n">
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_refresh.png" id="image_lhx_gfv_5n"/></uicontrol> -
          Refreshes the dependencies structure.</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_stop.png" id="image_mhx_gfv_5n"/></uicontrol> - Stops
          the dependencies computing.</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_configureSearchScope.png" id="image_nhx_gfv_5n"
            /></uicontrol> - Allows you to configure a search scope to compute the dependencies
          structure. You can decide to use automatically the defined scope for future operations by
          checking the corresponding checkbox.</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_history.png" id="image_ohx_gfv_5n"/></uicontrol> -
          Allows you to repeat a previous dependencies computation.</li>
      </ul></p>
      <p>The following actions are available on the contextual menu:<ul id="ul_phx_gfv_5n">
          <li>
            <p>
              <b>Go to First Reference</b> - Selects the first reference of the referred component
              from the current selected component in the dependencies tree.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>
              <b>Go to Component</b> - Shows the definition of the current selected component in the
              dependencies tree.</p>
          </li>
        </ul></p>
      <note type="tip">
        <p>If a component contains multiple references to another, these references are listed in a
        table displayed at the bottom of <uicontrol>Component Dependencies</uicontrol> view.</p>
        <p>When a recursive reference is encountered, it is marked with a special icon <image
            href="../img/Cycle8.png" id="image_q3x_gfv_5n"/>.</p>
      </note>
    </body>
    <related-links>
      <link href="search-refactor-scope.dita">
        <desc>Search and Refactor Operations Scope</desc>
      </link>
    </related-links>
</topic>
