<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ant-transformation-options-tab">
  <title>The Options Tab</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> tab contains the following options:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Working directory</uicontrol> - path of the current directory of the Ant
        external process. An <xref href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables" format="dita"
          >editor variable</xref> can be inserted in this text box using the small green arrow
        button (<image href="../img/InsertEditorVariables12.gif" id="image_yy5_1lz_3d"/>);</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Build file</uicontrol> - ant script file that is the input of the Ant external
        process. An <xref href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables" format="dita">editor
          variable</xref> can be inserted in this text box using the small green arrow button
          (<image href="../img/InsertEditorVariables12.gif" id="image_nrh_1lz_3d"/>);</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Build target</uicontrol> - optionally a build target from the Ant script file
        can be specified. If no target is specified, the Ant target that is specified as default in
        the Ant script file is executed;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Additional arguments</uicontrol> - additional command-line arguments to be
        passed to the Ant transformation (for example <parmname>-verbose</parmname>);</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ant Home</uicontrol> - path to the Ant installation to run the transformation.
          <ph product="author developer editor">By default it is the path configured in the <xref
            href="ant-preferences.dita#ant-preferences">Ant preferences page</xref>. A custom value
          can also be set;</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Java Home</uicontrol> - the path to the Java Virtual Machine that runs the Ant
        transformation. By default it is the Java Virtual Machine that is bundled with <ph
          keyref="product"/>. A custom Java virtual
        machine can also be set;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>JVM Arguments</uicontrol> - this parameter allows you to set specific
        parameters to the Java Virtual Machine used by Ant. By default it is set to
          <parmname>-Xmx384m</parmname> which means the transformation process is allowed to use 384
        megabytes of memory. Sometimes, when performing a large DITA map transformation you may want
        to increase the memory allocated to the Java Virtual Machine from the default value (384 MB)
        to a higher value, like 512 MB. In this way, you can avoid running out of memory
          (<uicontrol>OutOfMemoryError</uicontrol>) when running an Ant process;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Libraries</uicontrol> - this button allows adding to the classpath of the Ant
        process any external libraries that are not bundled with Ant (that is they are not built-in
        Ant libraries).</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
