<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="apply-profiling-attributes">
  <title>Apply Profiling Attributes</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Apply profiling attributes</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Apply profiling
              attributes</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Apply profiling attributes in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Profiling attributes are applied on element nodes. You can apply profiling attributes on a
      text fragment (it will automatically be wrapped into a phrase-type element), on a single
      element, or on multiple elements in the same time. If there is no selection in your document,
      the profiling attributes are applied on the element at the cursor position.</p>
    <p>To profile a fragment from your document, select the fragment in the
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing mode and follow these steps:<ol>
        <li>Invoke the <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> action from the contextual
          menu in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.<p><b>Step Result:</b> The <uicontrol>Edit
              Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed and shows all the profiling
            attributes and their values, as defined for the particular document type (framework). If
            you have a large list of profiling attributes, you can use the text filter field to
            search for attributes or values, and you can expand or collapse attributes by using the
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/ExpandAll16.png"/>Expand All/<image
                href="../img/CollapseAll16.png"/>Collapse All</uicontrol> buttons to the right of
            the text filter or the arrow button to the left of the profiling attribute
            name.</p><p>The attributes and values that appear in the dialog box are determined as
              follows:<ul id="ul_bsp_5sd_bq">
              <li product="author editor">If you have <xref
                  href="profiling-attributes-management.dita#profiling-attributes-management"
                  >defined profiling attribute values</xref> for the DITA document type in the <xref
                  href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                    ><uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> and
                you store them at <xref keyref="glossentry_project-options">project-level</xref>,
                those values are displayed in the dialog box.</li>
          <li product="author editor">If you have <xref
              href="profiling-attributes-management.dita#profiling-attributes-management">defined
              profiling attribute values</xref> for the DITA document type in the <xref
              href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                ><uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> and you
            store them at <xref href="preferences-storing.dita#preferences-storing/global_options"
              >global-level</xref>, those values are displayed in the dialog box.</li>
          <li product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">If you have <xref
              href="profiling-attributes-management.dita#profiling-attributes-management">defined
              profiling attribute values</xref> for the DITA document type in the <xref
              href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                ><uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>, those
            values are displayed in the dialog box.</li>
              <li>Otherwise, a generic default set of profiling attributes and values are
                available.</li>
            </ul></p><p>
            <fig id="edit-profiling-image">
              <title>Edit Profiling Attributes Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/edit-profiling-attributes-dialog.png" id="image_dkz_hsd_bq"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
        <li>In the <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> dialog box, select the
          checkboxes that correspond to the attribute values you want to apply on the <xref
            keyref="glossentry_document-fragment"><term>document fragment</term></xref>.</li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to finish the profiling configuration.<p><b>Result:</b>
            The attribute names and values selected in the <uicontrol>Edit Profiling
              Attributes</uicontrol> dialog box are set on the elements contained in the profiled
            fragment. If you only select a fragment of content (rather than the entire element),
            this fragment is wrapped in phrase-type elements in which the profiling attributes are
            set.</p><p>If the <uicontrol>Show Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> option (available in
            the <xref format="dita"
              href="../topics/profiling-conditional-text-menu.dita#profiling-conditional-text-menu"
                  ><uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar16.png" id="image_v2c_s4f_wr"
                  placement="inline"/>Profiling / Conditional Text</uicontrol> toolbar menu</xref>)
            is selected, a green border is painted around profiled text in the
              <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. Also, all profiling attributes set on the current
            element are listed at the end of the highlighted block and in its tooltip message. To
            edit the attributes of a profiled fragment, click one of the listed attribute values. A
            form control pops up and allows you to add or remove attribute values.</p><p>
            <fig>
              <title>Profiling Attribute Value Form Control Pop Up</title>
              <image href="../img/profiling_form_control.png" placement="inline"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
      </ol></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="customize-profiling-conditions.dita#customize-profiling-conditions"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
