<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="apply-styles">
  <title>Apply Profiling Colors and Styles</title>
  <body>
    <p>Applying profiling colors and styles allows you to customize the Author editing area to mark
      profiled content so you can instantly spot different variants of the output. </p>
    <image href="../img/profiling-styles-sample.png" id="image_xvp_2q4_5n"/>
    <p>Choosing the right style for a specific profiling attribute is a matter of personal taste,
      but you should keep in mind that:<ul id="ul_ixz_gm4_5n">
        <li>if the same block of text is profiled with two or more profiling attributes, their
          associated styles combine. Depending on the styling, this might result in an excessively
          styled content that may prove difficult to read or work with;</li>
        <li>profile only differences. There is no need to profile common content, since excessive
          profiling can visually pollute the document;</li>
        <li>a mnemonic associated with a style will help you spot instantly different types of
          content. </li>
      </ul>To set colors and styles to profiling attribute values:<ul id="ul_vsg_rn4_5n">
        <li>enable the <uicontrol>Show Profiling Colors and Styles</uicontrol> option from the <xref
            href="../topics/profiling-conditional-text-menu.dita#profiling-conditional-text-menu"
            format="dita"><uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar20.png"
                id="image_hxp_kms_n2"/> Profiling / Conditional Text</uicontrol> toolbar
          menu</xref>;</li>
        <li>go to <uicontrol>Profiling Settings</uicontrol> from the <xref
            href="../topics/profiling-conditional-text-menu.dita#profiling-conditional-text-menu"
            format="dita"><uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar20.png"
                id="image_hxp_kms_n3"/> Profiling / Conditional Text</uicontrol> toolbar
          menu</xref>. This is a shortcut to the <xref
            href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#profiling.conditions"
              ><uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> options page</xref>. Select the
            <xref href="colors-and-styles-preferences.dita#colors-and-styles-preferences"
              ><uicontrol>Colors and Styles</uicontrol> options page</xref>;</li>
        <li>set a style to a profiling attribute value.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>Note that the styling is now applied in the Author editor, the Outline view and DITA Maps
      Manager view. Also, to help you identify more easily the profiling you want to apply in the
      current context, the styling is applied in the <uicontrol>Edit Profiling
        Attributes</uicontrol> dialog and in the inline form control that allows you to quickly set
      the profiling attributes.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
