<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="apply-all-default-quick-fixes-in-scope">
  <title>Applying All Default Quick Fix Proposals</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Apply all default quick fix proposals</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_w2w_fb1_p1c">The <uicontrol>Apply all default quick fix proposals</uicontrol> tool can
      be used to apply quick fix proposals for all reported validation errors in one or more
      documents when one or more quick fix proposals have been detected for reported validation
      errors. If multiple quick fixes are available for the same validation error, the default quick
      fix defined in the Schematron validation schema using the <codeph>sqf:default-fix</codeph>
      attribute is automatically selected to be applied. If no default quick fix is explicitly
      specified, the first quick fix proposal in the list is considered. All quick fix proposals are
      then automatically executed in bulk, one after the other.<note id="note_pdd_kb1_p1c"
        type="other" othertype="Important Notes to Consider">
        <ul id="ul_afw_fb1_p1c">
          <li id="li_bfw_fb1_p1c">To maintain the accuracy of the initially calculated error
            validation ranges, the quick fix proposals are applied in the reverse order of their
            selection.</li>
          <li id="li_cfw_fb1_p1c">If two or more quick fixes act on the same "area" within the
            document, only one is applied (no changes can be made to changes already made).</li>
          <li id="li_dfw_fb1_p1c">Quick fixes that involve "user-entered values" that normally
            present a dialog box to facilitate data entry will not be executed (the automatic
            process of applying all selected quick fixes cannot be interrupted by the presence of
            the respective dialog boxes).</li>
        </ul>
      </note></p>
    <p id="p_eqn_4ln_lbc">The <uicontrol>Apply all default quick fix proposals</uicontrol> tool can
      be accessed from the following interface locations:<ul id="ul_lbp_dmn_lbc">
        <li id="li_jl1_lmn_lbc"><b>[Single Document]</b> The contextual menu when you right-click
          anywhere in <ph product="json"><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode</ph><xref
            href="text-mode-actions.dita"
            product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
              ><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode</xref><ph
            product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> or <xref
              href="author-contextual-menu.dita"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode</xref></ph> when
          there is a detected quick fix proposal in the current document.</li>
        <li id="li_mbp_dmn_lbc"><b>[One or More Documents]</b> The <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
          menu.</li>
        <li id="li_bwx_fmn_lbc"><b>[One or More Documents]</b> The
            <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu when you right-click one or more files in the
            <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita"><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol>
          view</xref>.</li>
        <li id="li_vdv_4nn_lbc" product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"><b>[One or More
            Documents]</b> The <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu when you right-click one
          or more files in the <xref href="dita-maps-manager.dita"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
              Manager</uicontrol> view</xref>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p id="p_yr5_5yz_jbc">Invoking the tool opens the <uicontrol>Apply all default quick fix
        proposals</uicontrol> dialog box where you can choose the scope for the operation and
      optionally specify a filter to narrow the scope. </p>
    <p id="p_f3w_bgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_n32_1xg_wr">
        <title>Apply All Default Quick Fix Proposals Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/Apply-all-default-qf.png" id="image_pg4_pxg_wr"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_g3w_bgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> section allows you to choose from the
      following scopes:</p>
    <ul id="ul_mbw_tvg_wr">
      <li id="li_nrx_mzz_jbc"><uicontrol>Current File</uicontrol> - The quick fix proposals are
        applied on the current file only.</li>
      <li id="li_ejf_qzz_jbc"><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> - The quick fix proposals are applied
        on the current project. </li>
      <li id="li_k3w_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Selected project resources</uicontrol> - The quick fix
        proposals are applied on the selected files from the current project.</li>
      <li id="li_h3w_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>All opened files</uicontrol> - The quick fix proposals are
        applied on all opened files.</li>
      <li id="li_i3w_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Entire DITA map hierarchy</uicontrol> (for DITA documents)
        - The quick fix proposals are applied on current DITA map along with all of its referenced
        topics and submaps (and topics referenced in those submaps).</li>
      <li id="li_j3w_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Working sets</uicontrol> - The quick fix proposals are
        applied on a user-defined set of resources, referred to as a <xref
          keyref="glossentry_working-set"><term>working set</term></xref>.</li>
    </ul>
    <p id="p_m3w_bgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Include files</uicontrol> option in the
        <uicontrol>Filters</uicontrol> section can be used to narrow the scope of the operation by
      filtering the selected resources using a file pattern. For example, to restrict the operation
      to only parse and update XML documents from the selected files, you could use
        <codeph>{*}.xml</codeph> for the file pattern.</p>
    <p id="p_ffw_fb1_p1c">You can click the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> button to see a
      comparison preview that provides an overview of the content changes that will be made,
      according to the quick fixes that will be applied. <ph
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">You can preview the changes in
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. </ph>The comparison
      panel also informs you of any problems encountered. While previewing the changes, you can also
      choose to exclude certain files from having the quick fixes be applied if you do not agree
      with the changes for the particular files. If you agree with the changes presented, click
        <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol> to trigger the quick fixes and update the content.</p>
    <note id="note_dqg_bpn_lbc" type="trouble">If a quick fix did not apply, a notification with
      some information about the error will be displayed in the <uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> view
      at the bottom of the application.</note>
    <note id="note_k2k_fpn_lbc" type="tip">If the operation takes longer than expected, you can use
      the <uicontrol>Stop</uicontrol> button in the progress bar to cancel the operation.</note>
    <section id="section_xqr_cpr_fdc">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p id="p_yqr_cpr_fdc">For more information about the <uicontrol>Apply all default quick fix
          proposals</uicontrol> tool, see our video: <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/apply_qf.html" format="html" scope="external"
          >Introducing the Apply All Default Quick Fix Proposals Tool</xref>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
