<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="assign_task_to_new_owner">
  <title>Adding a New Owner to a Task</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Assign task to new owner</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Assign task (Content Author)</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Review tasks that are created by the <b>Content Author</b> are automatically assigned to that
        <b>Content Author</b> as the task owner. It is possible to add additional owners to an
      existing task so that more than one <b>Content Author</b> can manage the task or merge the
      changes in <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>.</p>
    <p>To add an additional owner to a review task:</p>
    <p>
      <ol>
        <li>Open the task in a browser (click on name of the task in the <uicontrol>Content Fusion
            Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view).</li>
        <li>In the task <uicontrol>Details</uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>ASSIGN</uicontrol>
              button.<p><b>Step Result:</b> This opens a dialog box where you can add additional
            owners to the task.</p><p>
            <fig>
              <title>Assign New Owner Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/cf_assign_owner.png"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
        <li>Start typing a name or email in the <uicontrol>Add new owner</uicontrol> field and the
          system will search for assignable users that can be selected from a drop-down
            menu.<note>The assignable users are based upon validated email addresses for each <ph
              keyref="cfEnterprise"/> installation. If you need to limit the assignable users to a
            particular department within your organization (for example), it is recommended to have
            a separate <ph keyref="cfEnterprise"/> installation for each department.</note></li>
        <li>Select a new owner and click the <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> button to assign the task
          ownership to the new owner.</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
    <p><b>Result:</b> The new owner is now assigned as one of the owners of the task. The task is
      now listed as one of the <uicontrol>Review tasks owned by me</uicontrol> in the <xref
        href="content_fusion_user_interface_author.dita#content_fusion_user_interface_author/my-tasks"
          ><uicontrol>My Tasks</uicontrol> screen</xref> and the task is also added in the
        <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view for the new owner.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
