<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="associating-schema-directly">
  <title>Associating a Schema Directly in XML Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Associate schema directly in XML
          documents</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Associate schema directly in XML documents</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The schema used by the <xref keyref="glossentry_content-completion-assistant"><term>Content
          Completion Assistant</term></xref> and document validation engine can be directly
      associated with the current document by using the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/AssociateSchema16.png" id="image_lgf_ng3_5r"/>Associate Schema</uicontrol>
      action. For most of the schema types, it uses the <xref
        href="https://www.w3.org/TR/xml-model/#the-xml-model-processing-instruction" format="html"
        scope="external"><i>xml-model</i> processing instruction</xref>, with the exceptions of:<ul>
        <li><b>W3C XML Schema</b> - The <codeph>xsi:schemaLocation</codeph> attribute or
            <codeph>xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation</codeph> attribute is used.</li>
        <li><b>DTD</b> - The <codeph>DOCTYPE</codeph> declaration is used.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The association can specify a relative file path or a URL of the schema. The advantage of
      relative file path is that you can configure the schema at file level instead of <xref
        keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>framework</term></xref> level.</p>
    <p>To associate a schema to the current document, follow these steps:<ol>
        <li>Select the <uicontrol><image href="../img/AssociateSchema16.png" id="image_f4c_lg3_5r"
            />Associate Schema</uicontrol> action from the toolbar (or <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Schema</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> menu).<p><b>Step Result:</b> The <uicontrol>Associate Schema</uicontrol>
            dialog box is displayed:</p><p>
            <fig>
              <title>Associate Schema Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/sa_associate_schema_dialog.png"/>
            </fig>
          </p><p>This dialog box contains the following options:<ul>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> - Allows you to specify or select a URL for the schema.
                It also keeps a history of the last used schemas. The URL must point to the schema
                file that can be loaded from the local disk or from a remote server through HTTP(S),
                  FTP(S)<ph product="editor developer"> or a <xref
                    href="howto-custom-protocol-plugin.dita#howto-custom-protocol-plugin"
                    format="dita">custom protocol</xref></ph>.</li>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>Use path relative to file location</uicontrol> - Select this option if
                the XML instance document and the associated schema contain relative paths. The
                location of the schema file is inserted in the XML instance document as a relative
                file path. This practice allows you, for example, to share these documents with
                other users without running into problems caused by multiple project locations on
                physical disk.</li>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>Schema type</uicontrol> - Select a possible schema type from this combo
                box that is populated based on the extension of the schema file that was entered in
                the <uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> field. The possible schema types are: XML Schema,
                DTD, Relax NG, Relax NG Compact, Schematron, or NVDL.</li>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>Add additional association for embedded Schematron rules</uicontrol> - If
                you have selected XML Schema or Relax NG schemas with embedded Schematron rules and
                you want to use those embedded rules, select this option.</li>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>Public ID</uicontrol> - Allows you to specify a public ID if you have
                selected a DTD.</li>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>Keep existing schema associations</uicontrol> - Select this option to use
                the existing schema associations of the currently edited document. </li>
            </ul></p></li>
        <li>Select the schema that will be associated with the XML document and configure the rest
          of the options according to your preferences.</li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <p><b>Result:</b> The schema association is created based upon the specified type.<ul>
        <li><b>XML Schema</b> - The association with an XML Schema is added as an attribute of the
          root element with one of the following:<ul>
            <li><codeph>xsi:schemaLocation</codeph> attribute, if the root element of the document
              is in the namespace.</li>
            <li><codeph>xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation</codeph> attribute, if the root element is not
              in the namespace.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b>DTD</b> - The association with a DTD is added as a <codeph>DOCTYPE</codeph>
          declaration.</li>
        <li><b>Other</b> - The association with a Relax NG, Schematron, or NVDL schema is added as
          an <xref href="https://www.w3.org/TR/xml-model/#the-xml-model-processing-instruction"
            format="html" scope="external"><i>xml-model</i> processing instruction</xref>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>
      <note type="tip"><ph conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/open-schema-ph"/></note>
    </p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="validating-XML-documents.dita#validating-XML-documents"/>
      <link href="streamline-with-content-completion.dita#streamline-with-content-completion"/>
      <link href="content-completion-author-mode.dita#content-completion-author-mode"
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
