<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/concept.dtd">
<topic id="attributes-panel">
  <title>The Attributes View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing XML Documents<indexterm>streamline with content completion<indexterm>the
              Attributes view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150812T151050+0300" comment="All of this can be referenced"?>The
        <uicontrol>Attributes View</uicontrol> presents all possible attributes of the current
      element determined by the schema of the document.  </p>
    <p>The attributes are rendered differently depending on their state:<ul>
        <li>The names of the attributes with a specified value are rendered with a bold font, and
          their value with a plain font.<note>The names of the attributes with an empty string value
            are also rendered bold. </note></li>
        <li>Default values are rendered with a plain font, painted gray.</li>
        <li>Empty values display the text "[empty]", painted gray.</li>
        <li>Invalid attributes and values are painted red.</li>
      </ul>Double-click a cell in the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column to edit the value of the
      corresponding attribute. If the possible values of the attribute are specified as
        <codeph>list</codeph> in the schema of the edited document, the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol>
      column acts as a combo box that allows you to insert the values in the document.</p>
    <p>You can sort the attributes table by clicking the <uicontrol>Attribute</uicontrol> column
      header. The table contents can be sorted as follows: <ul>
        <li>By attribute name in ascending order.</li>
        <li>By attribute name in descending order.</li>
        <li>Custom order, where the used attributes are displayed at the beginning of the table
          sorted in ascending order, followed by the rest of the allowed elements sorted in
          ascending order.<?oxy_comment_end?></li>
      </ul></p>
    <fig product="editor author developer">
      <title>The Attributes View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_attributes_panel.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Attributes View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_attributes_panel.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150812T151103+0300" comment="Leave"?>The
      following actions are available in the contextual menu of the
        <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view when editing in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode:<?oxy_comment_end?><dl>
        <?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150812T151121+0300" comment="This &apos;dlentry&apos; is only for this topic"?>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Add</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to insert a new attribute. Adding an attribute that is not in the list of
            all defined attributes is not possible when the <xref
              keyref="options_editor_edit-modes_author_schema-aware">Allow only insertion of valid
              elements and attributes</xref> schema aware option is enabled.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <?oxy_comment_end?>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150812T151135+0300" comment="All this can be referenced"?><uicontrol>Set
              empty value</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Specifies the current attribute value as empty.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Removes the attribute (action available only if the attribute is specified). You can
            invoke this action by pressing the <uicontrol><shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol>
            or <uicontrol><shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> keys.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copies the <codeph>attrName="attrValue"</codeph> pair to the clipboard. The
              <codeph>attrValue</codeph> can be: <ul>
              <li>The value of the attribute.</li>
              <li>The value of the default attribute, if the attribute does not appear in the edited
                document.</li>
              <li>Empty, if the attribute does not appear in the edited document and has no default
                value set.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Depending on the content of the clipboard, the following cases are possible: <ul>
              <li>If the clipboard contains an attribute and its value, both of them are introduced
                in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view. The attribute is selected and its
                value is changed if they exist in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view.</li>
              <li>If the clipboard contains an attribute name with an empty value, the attribute is
                introduced in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view and you can start editing
                it. The attribute is selected and you can start editing it if it exists in the
                  <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view.</li>
              <li>If the clipboard only contains text, the value of the selected attribute is
                modified. <?oxy_comment_end?></li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
