<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-elements-view">
  <title>Elements View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>elements view</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Elements</uicontrol> view presents a list of all defined elements that you can
      insert in your document. All elements from a sequence are presented but the invalid proposals
      (which cannot be inserted in the current context) are grayed-out. The upper part of the view
      features a combo box that contains the current element's ordered ancestors. Selecting a new
      element in this combo box updates the list of the allowed elements in
        <uicontrol>Before</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>After</uicontrol> tabs.</p>
    <fig id="figure-author-elements-view-oxygen" product="editor author">
      <title>The Elements View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_elements_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="figure-author-elements-view-oxygenEclipse" product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title>The Elements View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_author_elements_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>Three tabs present information relative to the caret location:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Caret</uicontrol> - Shows a list of all the elements allowed at the current
        caret location. Double-clicking any of the listed elements inserts that element at the caret
        position.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Before</uicontrol> - Shows a list of all elements that can be inserted before
        the element selected in the combo box. Double-clicking any of the listed elements inserts
        that element before the element at the caret position.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>After</uicontrol> - Shows a list of all elements that can be inserted after the
        element selected in the combo box. Double-clicking any of the listed elements inserts that
        element after the element at the caret position.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Double clicking an element name in the list surrounds the current selection in the editor
      panel with the start tags and end tags of the element. If there is no selection, just an empty
      element is inserted in the editor panel at the cursor position.</p>
  </body>
</topic>