<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-editing-tables">
  <title>Table Layout and Operations</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides support for
      editing data in a tabular form. The following operations are available:<ul id="ul_zn2_xvn_2g">
        <li>Adjusting column width:<p>You are able to manage table width and column width
            specifications from the source document. These specifications are supported both in
            fixed and proportional dimensions. The predefined frameworks (DITA, DocBook, and XHTML)
            also support this feature. The layout of the tables for these document types takes into
            account the table width and the column width specifications particular to them. To
            adjust the width of a column or table, drag the border of the column. The changes you
            make to a table are committed into the source document.</p></li>
      </ul></p>
    <fig>
      <title>Resizing a Column in <ph keyref="product"/> Author Editor</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_resize_column.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>
      <ul id="ul_sns_c5m_2g">
        <li>Column and row selection:<p>To select a row or a column of a table, place the mouse
            cursor above the column or in front of the row you want to select, then click. When
            hovering the mouse cursor in front of rows or above column headers, the cursor changes
            to <image href="../img/RowSelection.png"/> for row selection and to <image
              href="../img/ColumnSelection.png"/> for column selection and that specific row or
            column is highlighted.</p></li>
        <li>Cell selection:<p>To select a cell in a table, press and hold the
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol> key and click anywhere inside the
            cell. You can use this action to select one or more cells, and also to deselect cells
            from a selection. Alternatively, you can click one of the left corners of a cell (right
            corners in case you are editing a RTL document). The cursor changes to <image
              href="../img/CellLtrUpSelection.png" id="image_yr3_2zr_4n"/> when it hovers over the
            corners of the cell.</p></li>
      </ul>
      <ul id="ul_mr3_cgn_2g">
        <li>Drag and drop:<p>You can use the drag and drop action to edit the content of a table.
            You are able to select a column and drag it to another location in the table you are
            editing. When you drag a column and hover the cursor over a valid drop position, <ph
              keyref="product"/> decorates the target location with bold rectangles. The same drag
            and drop action is also available for rows. </p></li>
        <li>Copy-paste and cut for columns and rows:<p>In <ph keyref="product"/>, you are able to
            copy entire rows or columns of the table you are editing. You can paste a copied column
            or row both inside the source table and inside other tables. The cut operation is also
            available for rows and columns. You can use the cut and the copy-paste actions for
            tables located in different documents as well.</p><p>When you paste a column in a
            non-table content, <ph keyref="product"/> introduces a new table which contains the
            fragments of the source column. The fragments are introduced starting with the header of
            the column. When you copy a column of a CALS table, <ph keyref="product"/> preserves the
            width information of the column. This information is then used when you paste the column
            in another CALS table.</p></li>
        <li>Content deletion:<p>To delete only the content of a table, select a row or column and
            press either <uicontrol><shortcut>Delete</shortcut></uicontrol>, or
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Backspace</shortcut></uicontrol> on your keyboard. To delete an
            entire row or column, use <uicontrol><image id="image_ty2_txn_2g"
                href="../img/bt_delete_table_row.png"/>Delete a table row</uicontrol> or
                <uicontrol><image id="image_313_wxn_2g" href="../img/bt_delete_table_column.png"
              />Delete a table column</uicontrol>. </p></li>
      </ul>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>