<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-customize-smart-paste">
  <title>Customizing Smart Paste Support</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Document Type Association (Framework)<indexterm>Customizing Smart Paste
            mapping</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <term>Smart Paste</term> feature preserves certain style and structure information when
      copying content from some of the most common applications and pasting into <xref
        href="smart-paste-support.dita#smart-paste-support/doc-types-sp-p">document types that
        support Smart Paste</xref> in <ph keyref="product"/>. For other document types, the default
      behavior of the paste operation is to keep only the text content without the styling.</p>
    <p>The style of the pasted content can be customized by editing an XSLT stylesheet for a
      particular document type (framework). The XSLT stylesheet must accept an XHTML flavor of the
      copied content as input, and transform it to the equivalent XML markup that is appropriate for
      the target document type of the paste operation.</p>
    <section id="how_to_customize_the_smart_paste_mapping">
      <title>How to Customize the Smart Paste Mapping</title>
      <p>To customize the mapping between the markup of the copied content and the markup of the
        pasted content for a particular document type, follow these steps:<ol>
          <li>Make sure the particular framework contains a folder named
              <filepath>resources</filepath> in the following path
            structure:<codeblock><filepath><term conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"/>/frameworks/[Document Type]/resources</filepath></codeblock></li>
          <li>Create an XSLT file named <filepath>xhtml2content.xsl</filepath> and save it in the
              <filepath>resources</filepath> folder for the particular
            framework.<codeblock>For example: <filepath><term conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"/>/frameworks/dita/resources/xhtml2content.xsl</filepath>.</codeblock></li>
          <li>Add your customized styling in the XSLT file.</li>
          <li>You can test modifications done in the stylesheet by pasting content without having to
            restart <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
        </ol></p>
      <p><b>Result:</b> When you paste content from external applications (such as a web browser or
        and Office document) to a document that is opened in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, and
        that matches the particular framework, the styling from the
          <filepath>xhtml2content.xsl</filepath> stylesheet will be applied on the clipboard
        contents.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="smart-paste-support.dita#smart-paste-support"/>
    <link href="http://blog.oxygenxml.com/2015/10/how-special-paste-works-in-oxygen.html"
      format="html" scope="external">
      <linktext>oXygen XML Blog: How Special Paste Works in oXygen</linktext>
    </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>
