<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-dita-extensions">
    <title>DITA Author Extensions</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>DITA Topics Document Type<indexterm>Author extensions</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>The specific actions for a DITA topic are:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_bold.png"/>Bold</uicontrol> - surrounds the
        selected text with a <codeph>b</codeph> tag;</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_italic.png"/>Italic</uicontrol> - surrounds the
        selected text with an <codeph>i</codeph> tag;</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_underline.png"/>Underline</uicontrol> - surrounds
        the selected text with a <codeph>u</codeph> tag;<note>
          <p><uicontrol>Bold</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Italic</uicontrol>, and
              <uicontrol>Underline</uicontrol> are toggle actions.</p>
          <p>For all of the above actions, if there is no selection in the document, then a new
            specific tag is inserted. These actions are available in any document context.</p>
        </note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Style Guide</uicontrol> - opens the <b>DITA Style Guide Best Practices for
          Authors</b> in your browser and presents the description of the element at the caret
        position. This action is available in the contextual menu of the editing area (when editing
        DITA documents), in the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu, and in the documentation tip
        displayed by the <uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol>;</li>
            <li><ph id="browse_ref_manual"><uicontrol>Browse reference manual</uicontrol> - opens in
          your web browser of choice a reference to the documentation of the XML element closest to
          the caret position;</ph></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Cross Reference</uicontrol> - inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element
        with the value of the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set to <codeph>dita</codeph>. The
        target of the <codeph>xref</codeph> element is selected in a dialog box that lists all the
        IDs extracted from the selected file. When you select an ID, you can preview the content in
        the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> tab or the XML source in the
          <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> tab. In case you have a large number of IDs in the target
        document, use the <uicontrol>Filter</uicontrol> field to search through the IDs.<fig
          product="editor author">
          <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_xref.png"/>
        </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
          <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
          <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_xref.png"/>
        </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The dialog is
          closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Key Reference</uicontrol> - inserts a user specified element with the
        value of the <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set to a specific key name. As stated in the
        DITA 1.2 specification, keys are defined at map level and referenced afterwards. You are
        able to select the target of the <codeph>keyref</codeph> element in the <uicontrol>Insert
          Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog box;<note>The <uicontrol>Insert Key Reference</uicontrol>
          dialog box presents the list of keys available in the current DITA Map. If the DITA Map is
          not opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view, the <uicontrol>Insert Key
            Reference</uicontrol> dialog does not display any keys.</note><p>You can also reference
          elements at sub-topic level by pressing the <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol> button and
          choosing the target.</p>All keys which are presented in the dialog are gathered from the
        current opened DITA map. Elements which have the <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set are
        displayed as links. The current opened DITA map is also used to resolve references when
        navigating <codeph>keyref</codeph> links in the Author mode. Image elements which use key
        references are rendered as images.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>File Reference</uicontrol> - inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element
        with the value of attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>xml</codeph>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Web Link</uicontrol> - inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element with the
        value of attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph>, and
          <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Related Link to Topic</uicontrol> - inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
        element inside a <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Related Link to File</uicontrol> - inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
        element with the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set to <codeph>xml</codeph> inside a
          <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Related Link to Web Page</uicontrol> - inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
        element with the attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph> and
          <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph> inside a
          <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent;<note>The actions for inserting references described
          above are grouped in the <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Link</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> menu.</note>
      </li>
            <li><uicontrol>Paste as content reference</uicontrol> (available on the contextual menu
        of Author editor for any topic file) - inserts a content reference (a DITA element with a
          <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute) to the DITA XML element from the clipboard. An entire
        DITA XML element with an ID attribute must be present in the clipboard when the action is
        invoked. The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute will point to this ID value;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Paste as content key reference</uicontrol> - allows you to indirectly refer
        content using the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute. When the DITA content is processed,
        the key references are resolved using key definitions from DITA maps. To use this action, do
        the following:<ul>
          <li>set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element holding the content you want to
            refer;</li>
          <li>open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view;</li>
          <li>right click the topic that holds the content you want to refer, select <uicontrol>Edit
              Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol>
            field;</li>
          <li>make sure the DITA Map remains open in the DITA MAPS Manger View. </li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>paste as link</uicontrol> (available on the contextual menu of Author editor
        for any topic file) - inserts a <codeph>link</codeph> element or an <codeph>xref</codeph>
        one (depending on the location of the paste) that points to the DITA XML element from the
        clipboard. An entire DITA XML element with an ID attribute must be present in the clipboard
        when the action is invoked. The <codeph>href</codeph> attribute of
          <codeph>link</codeph>/<codeph>href</codeph> will point to this ID value;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Paste as link (keyref)</uicontrol> - inserts a link to the element that you
        want to refer. To use this action, do the following:<ul>
          <li>set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element that you want to refer;</li>
          <li>open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view;</li>
          <li>right click the topic that holds the content you want to refer, select <uicontrol>Edit
              Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol>
            field;</li>
          <li>make sure the DITA Map remains open in the DITA MAPS Manger View. </li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_section.png"/>Insert Section /
          Step</uicontrol> - inserts a new section / step in the document, depending on the current
        context. A new section will be inserted in either one of the following contexts:<ul>
          <li>section context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the current
            element or one of its ancestors contains <codeph>topic</codeph> or
              <codeph>section</codeph>.</li>
          <li>topic's body context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
            current element contains <codeph>topic/body</codeph>.</li>
        </ul><p>A new step will be inserted in either one of the following contexts:</p><ul>
          <li>task step context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the current
            element or one of its ancestors contains <codeph>task/step</codeph>.</li>
          <li>task steps context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the current
            element contains <codeph>task/steps</codeph>.</li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_dita_insert_concept.png"/>Insert
          Concept</uicontrol> - inserts a new concept. Concepts provide background information that
        users must know before they can successfully work with a product or interface. This action
        is available in one of the following contexts:<ul>
          <li>concept context, one of the current element ancestors is a <codeph>concept</codeph>.
            In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be inserted after the current
              <codeph>concept</codeph>.</li>
          <li>concept or DITA context, current element is a <codeph>concept</codeph> or
              <codeph>dita</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be inserted
            at current caret position.</li>
          <li>DITA topic context, current element is a <codeph>topic</codeph> child of a
              <codeph>dita</codeph> element. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
            inserted at current caret position.</li>
          <li>DITA topic context, one of the current element ancestors is a DITA
              <codeph>topic</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
            inserted after the first <codeph>topic</codeph> ancestor.</li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_dita_insert_task.png"/>Insert Task</uicontrol> -
        inserts a new task. Tasks are the main building blocks for task-oriented user assistance.
        They generally provide step-by-step instructions that will enable a user to perform a task.
        This action is available in one of the following contexts:<ul>
          <li>task context, one of the current element ancestors is a <codeph>task</codeph>. In this
            case an empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted after the last child of the first
              <codeph>concept</codeph>'s ancestor.</li>
          <li>task context, the current element is a <codeph>task</codeph>. In this case an empty
              <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted at current caret position.</li>
          <li>topic context, the current element is a <codeph>dita</codeph>
            <codeph>topic</codeph>. An empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted at current caret
            position.</li>
          <li>topic context, one of the current element ancestors is a <codeph>dita</codeph>
            <codeph>topic</codeph>. An empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted after the last
            child of the first ancestor that is a <codeph>topic</codeph>.</li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_dita_insert_ref.png"/>Insert Reference</uicontrol>
        - inserts a new reference in the document. A reference is a top-level container for a
        reference topic. This action is available in one of the following contexts:<ul>
          <li>reference context - one of the current element ancestors is a
              <codeph>reference</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>reference</codeph> will be
            inserted after the last child of the first ancestor that is a
            <codeph>reference</codeph>.</li>
          <li><codeph>reference</codeph> or <codeph>dita</codeph> context - the current element is
            either a <codeph>dita</codeph> or a <codeph>reference</codeph>. An empty
              <codeph>reference</codeph> will be inserted at caret position.</li>
          <li>topic context - the current element is <codeph>topic</codeph> descendant of
              <codeph>dita</codeph> element. An empty <codeph>reference</codeph> will be inserted at
            caret position.</li>
          <li>topic context - the current element is descendant of <codeph>dita</codeph> element and
            descendant of <codeph>topic</codeph> element. An empty <codeph>reference</codeph> will
            be inserted after the last child of the first ancestor that is a
            <codeph>topic</codeph>.</li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_graphic.png"/>Insert image
              reference</uicontrol> - <xref href="author_adding_images.dita#author_adding_images" format="dita"
          product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">inserts an image reference</xref><ph
          product="authorSDK">inserts an image reference</ph> at the caret position. Depending on
        the current context, an image-type DITA element is inserted. Also you can use this action to
          <xref href="working-with-mathml.dita#working-with-mathml" format="dita"
          product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">refer MathML files</xref><ph
          product="authorSDK">refer MathML files</ph>;</li>
            <li id="dita-insert-content-reference">
                <p><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_conref.png"/>Insert DITA Content
            Reference</uicontrol> - inserts a content reference at the caret position.</p>
                <p>The DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of
                    content fragments. The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute stores a reference to
                    another element and is processed to replace the referencing element with the
                    referenced element. The element containing the content reference acts as a
                    placeholder for the referenced element. The identifier for the referenced
                    element must be either absolute or resolvable in the context of the referencing
                    element. See <xref
                        href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.0/archspec/conref.html"
                        scope="external" format="html">here</xref> for more details.</p>
                <p><ph keyref="product"/>
                    <xref href="author-displaying-referred-content.dita"
                        product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">displays the referred
                        content</xref><ph product="authorSDK">displays the referred content</ph> of
                    a DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid resource. If you
                    have URI's instead of local paths in the XML documents and your DITA OT
                    transformation needs an XML catalog to map the URI's to local paths you have to
                        <xref href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita"
                        product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">add the catalog to <ph
                            keyref="product"
                        /></xref><ph product="authorSDK">add the catalog to <ph
                            keyref="product"/></ph>.
                    If the URI's can be resolved the referred content will be displayed in Author
                    mode and in the transformation output.</p>
                <p>A content reference is inserted with the action <uicontrol>Insert a DITA Content
                        Reference</uicontrol> available on the toolbar <uicontrol>Author custom
                        actions</uicontrol> and on the menu <menucascade>
                        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
                        <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade>.</p>
                <fig product="editor author">
                    <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
                    <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conref.png"/>
                </fig>
                <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
                    <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
                    <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conref.png"/>
                </fig>
        <note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The dialog is
          closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note>
                <p>In the URL chooser you set the URL of the file from which you want to reuse
                    content. Depending on the <uicontrol>Target type</uicontrol> filter you will see
                    a tree of elements which can be referred (which have ID's). For each element the
                    XML content is shown in the preview area. The <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol>
                    value is computed automatically for the selected tree element. After pressing
                        <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> an element with the same name as the target
                    element and having the attribute <codeph>conref</codeph> with the value
                    specified in the <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> value field will be inserted at
                    caret position.</p>
                <p>According to the DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute
                    can be used to specify content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature
                    when referencing multiple consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple
                    contiguous sibling selection the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be
                    set to the value of the last selected ID path. <ph
                        keyref="product"/> will
                    present the entire referenced range as read-only content.</p>
            </li>
            <li id="dita-insert-content-key-reference"><uicontrol><image
            href="../img/bt_insert_conkeyref.png"/>Insert Content Key Reference</uicontrol> -
        inserts a content key reference at the caret position;<p>As stated in the DITA 1.2
          specification the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of
          content fragments similar with the <codeph>conref</codeph> mechanism. Keys are defined at
          map level which can be referenced using <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>. The
            <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute contains a key reference to another element and is
          processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The element
          containing the content key reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced element. The
          identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable in the context
          of the referencing element.</p><p><ph keyref="product"/>
          <xref href="author-displaying-referred-content.dita"
            product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">displays the key referred
            content</xref><ph product="authorSDK">displays the key referred content</ph> of a DITA
            <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid resource in the context of
          the current opened DITA map.</p><p>A content key reference is inserted with the action
            <uicontrol>Insert a DITA Content Key Reference</uicontrol> available on the toolbar
            <uicontrol>Author custom actions</uicontrol> and on the menu <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</p><fig product="editor author">
          <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conkeyref.png"/>
        </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
          <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog</title>
          <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conkeyref.png"/>
        </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The
          dialog is closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note><p>To
          reference target elements at sub-topic level just press the
            <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol> button and choose the target.</p><p>According to the
          DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute can be used to specify
          content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature when referencing multiple
          consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple contiguous sibling selection for IDs
          at sub-topic level the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be set to the value of
          the last selected ID path. <ph keyref="product"/> will present the entire referenced range
          as read-only content.<note type="important">All keys which are presented in the dialog are
            gathered from the current opened DITA map. Elements which have the
              <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed by default with the target
            content expanded. The current opened DITA map is also used to resolve references when
            navigating <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> links in the Author mode.</note></p></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Replace conref / conkeyref reference with content</uicontrol> - replaces
        the content reference fragment or the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> at caret position with the
        referenced content. This action is useful when you want to make changes to the content but
        decide to keep the referenced fragment unchanged;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Insert Equation</uicontrol> - allows you to insert an MathML equation.
          <ph product="editor author">For more information, see section <xref
            href="author-editing-mathml.dita#author-editing-mathml" format="dita">Editing MathML
            Notations</xref></ph>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Create Reusable Component</uicontrol> - creates a reusable component from
        a selected fragment of text. For more information, see <xref
          href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita"
          product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">Reusing Content</xref><xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/#topics/dita-reusing-content.html"
          format="html" scope="external" product="authorSDK">Reusing Content</xref>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Insert Reusable Component</uicontrol> - inserts a reusable component at
        cursor location. For more information, see <xref
          href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita"
          product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">Reusing Content</xref><xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/#topics/dita-reusing-content.html"
          format="html" scope="external" product="authorSDK">Reusing Content</xref>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Remove Content Reference</uicontrol> - removes the
          <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute of an element. For more information, see <xref
          href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita"
          product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">Reusing Content</xref><xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/#topics/dita-reusing-content.html"
          format="html" scope="external" product="authorSDK">Reusing Content</xref>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Add/Edit Content Reference</uicontrol> - add or edit the
          <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute of an element. For more information, see <xref
          href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita"
          product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">Reusing Content</xref><xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/#topics/dita-reusing-content.html"
          format="html" scope="external" product="authorSDK">Reusing Content</xref>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteAsConref16.png"/> Paste as Content
          Reference</uicontrol> - pastes the content of the clipboard as a content reference. Note
        that the copied element must have the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute set;</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteAsLink16.png"/> Paste as Link</uicontrol> -
        pastes the content of the clipboard as a link. Note that the copied element must have the
          <codeph>id</codeph> attribute set;<p>
          <ul conref="author_actions.dita#author_actions/list_editing_actions" id="ul_sdb_dkb_fg">
            <li/>
          </ul>
        </p></li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <ul conref="author_actions.dita#author_actions/table_editing_actions"
                        id="ul_rsl_bkb_fg">
                        <li/>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>The following options are available for customizing the frame of a table:<ul>
                    <li><codeph>none</codeph> - the table has no frame;</li>
                    <li><codeph>all</codeph> - the table has top, bottom and side borders;</li>
                    <li><codeph>top</codeph> - the table has a top border;</li>
                    <li><codeph>topbot</codeph> - the table top and bottom borders;</li>
                    <li><codeph>bottom</codeph> - the table has a bottom border;</li>
                    <li><codeph>sides</codeph> - the table has side border;</li>
                    <li><codeph>-dita-use-conref-target</codeph> - it indicates that when the
                        element uses <term>conref</term> to pull in content, the attribute with a
                        value of <uicontrol>-dita-use-conref-target</uicontrol> should also be
                        pulled in from the target; </li>
                    <li><codeph>unspecified</codeph> - if you select this option, when you insert
                        the table, the frame attribute is not inserted. </li>
                </ul></li>
        </ul>
        <note>DITA supports the CALS table model similar with DocBook document type in addition to
            the <codeph>simpletable</codeph> element specific for DITA.</note>
        <note type="caution">Column specifications are required for table actions to work
            properly.</note>
        <ul>
            <li id="generate-ids">
        <p><ph id="action-generateID"><uicontrol>Generate IDs</uicontrol> - Available in the
            contextual menu, this action allows you to generate an unique ID for the element at
            caret position. If the element already has an ID set, it is preserved.</ph>
        </p>
        <p>Further options are offered in the <uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol> dialog, available in
          the document type specific main menu. The configurable ID value pattern can accept most of
          the application supported <xref href="editor-variables.dita">editor variables</xref>. You
          can also specify the elements for which <ph keyref="product"/> generates an ID if the
            <uicontrol>Auto generate ID's for elements</uicontrol> is enabled. </p>
        <p>If you want to keep an already set element ID's when copying content in the same
          document, make sure the <uicontrol> Remove ID's when copying content in the same
            document</uicontrol> option is not checked.</p>
      </li>
        </ul>
    <ul id="ul_cbc_b51_md">
      <li><uicontrol>Search References</uicontrol> - Finds the references to the <codeph>id</codeph>
        attribute value of the selected element in all the topics from the current DITA map (opened
        in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view). The default shortcut of the action is
          <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_g"/> and
        can be changed in the <uicontrol>DITA Topic</uicontrol> document type.</li>
    </ul>
        <p>All actions described above are available in the contextual menu, the
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> submenu of the main menu or in the <uicontrol>Author custom
        actions</uicontrol> toolbar.</p>
        <p id="drag-and-drop-from-project-to-author-dita-topic">A drag and drop with a file from
                <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
                product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">the
                    <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref><ph product="authorSDK">the
                    <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</ph> or from <xref
                href="editing-dita-maps.dita#editing-dita-maps" format="dita"
                product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                    Manager</uicontrol> view</xref><ph product="authorSDK">the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                    Manager</uicontrol> view</ph> to a DITA topic document that is edited in Author
            mode will create a link to the dragged file (the <codeph>xref</codeph> DITA element with
            the <uicontrol>href</uicontrol> attribute) at the drop location. A drag and drop with an
            image file from the default file system application (Windows Explorer on Windows, Finder
            on Mac OS X, etc) will insert an image element (the <codeph>image</codeph> DITA element
            with the <codeph>href</codeph> attribute) with the location of the dragged file at the
            drop location, like the <uicontrol>Insert Graphic</uicontrol> toolbar action.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
