<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-contextual-menu">
  <title>Contextual Menu</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>contextual menu</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>More powerful support for editing the XML markup is offered via actions included in the
      contextual menu. Two types of actions are available: <b>generic actions</b> (actions that not
      depends on a specific document type) and <b>document type actions</b> (actions that are
      configured for a specific document type).</p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>Contextual menu</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_contextual_menu_generic.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title>Contextual menu</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_author_contextual_menu_generic.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The generic actions are:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Edit Attributes</uicontrol> - A pop-up window is displayed allowing you to
        manage the element attributes;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol> - The element from the caret position can be renamed quickly
        using the content completion window. If the <xref href="preferences-schema-aware.dita">Allow
          only insertion of valid elements and attributes</xref> schema aware option is enabled only
        the proposals from the content completion list are allowed, otherwise a custom element name
        can also be provided;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol> -
        Common edit actions with the same functionality as those found in the text editor;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Paste As XML</uicontrol> - Similar to <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol> operation,
        except that the clipboard's content is considered to be XML;</li>
      <li id="edit_profiling_attributes"><uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> - Allows
        you to select the profiling attributes;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Select</uicontrol> - Contains the following actions:<ul>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Select</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Select Element</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Selects the entire element at the current caret position;</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Select</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Select Content</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Selects the entire content of the element at the current caret
            position, excluding the start and end tag. Performing this action repeatedly will result
            in the selection of the content of the ancestor of the currently selected element
            content;</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Select</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Select Parent</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Selects the parent of the element at the current caret position;</li>
        </ul><note>You can select an element by triple clicking inside its content. If the element
          is empty you can select it by double clicking it.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> - Contains the following actions:<ul id="ul_ckk_ftc_gd">
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>To Lower Case</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Converts the selection content to lower case characters;</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>To Upper Case</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Converts the selection content to upper case characters;</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Capitalize Sentences</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Converts to upper case the first character of every selected
            sentence;</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Capitalize Words</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Converts to upper case the first character of every selected word;</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Count Words</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Counts the number of words and characters (no spaces) in the entire
            document or in the selection for regular content and read-only content;<note>The content
              marked as deleted with track changes is ignored when counting words.</note></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> - Contains a series of actions designed to alter the
        document's structure:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Toggle Comment</uicontrol> - Encloses the currently selected text in an XML
            comment, or removes the comment if it is commented;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Move Up</uicontrol> - Moves the current node or selected nodes in front of
            the previous node;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Move Down</uicontrol> - Moves the current node or selected nodes after the
            successive node;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Split Element</uicontrol> - Splits the content of the closest element that
            contains the caret's position. Thus, if the caret is positioned at the beginning or at
            the end of the element, the newly created sibling will be empty;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Join Elements</uicontrol> - Joins two adjacent elements that have the same
            name. The action is available only when the caret position is between the two adjacent
            elements. Also, joining two elements can be done by pressing the Delete or Backspace
            keys and the caret is positioned between the boundaries of these two elements;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Surround with Tag...</uicontrol> - Selected text in the editor is marked
            with the specified start and end tags;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Surround with '&lt;Tag name&gt;'</uicontrol> - Selected text in the editor
            is marked with start and end tags used by the last '<uicontrol>Surround with
              Tag...</uicontrol>' action;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Rename Element</uicontrol> - The element from the caret position and the
            elements that have the same name as the current element can be renamed according with
            the options from the <uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol> dialog;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Delete Element Tags</uicontrol> - Deletes the tags of the closest element
            that contains the caret's position. This operation is also executed if the start or end
            tags of an element are deleted by pressing the <uicontrol>
              <shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol> or <uicontrol>
              <shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> keys;</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> - Provides access to <xref
          href="author-managing-changes.dita#author-managing-changes" format="dita">Track
          Changes</xref> and Manage Comments actions;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Manage IDs</uicontrol> - Provides access to <xref
          href="search-refactor-operations-xml-id-idrefs.dita#search-refactor-operations-xml-id-idrefs"
          >searching and refactory actions for ID/IDREFS</xref>;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Insert Entity</uicontrol> - Allows the user to insert a predefined entity or a
        character entity. Surrogate character entities (range #x10000 to #x10FFFF) are also
        accepted. Character entities can be entered in one of the following forms:<ul>
          <li>#<i>&lt;decimal value&gt;</i> - e. g. #65;</li>
          <li>&amp;#<i>&lt;decimal value&gt;</i>; - e. g. &amp;#65;</li>
          <li>#x<i>&lt;hexadecimal value&gt;</i> - e. g. #x41;</li>
          <li>&amp;#x<i>&lt;hexadecimal value&gt;</i>; - e. g. &amp;#x41;</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Open File at Caret</uicontrol> - Opens in a new editor panel the file with the
        path under the caret position. If the path represents a directory path, it will be opened in
        system file browser. If the file does not exist at the specified location, the error dialog
        that is displayed contains a <uicontrol>Create new file</uicontrol> action which displays
        the <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> file dialog. This allows you to choose the type or the
        template for the file. If the action succeeds, the file is created with the referred
        location and name and is opened in a new editor panel. This is useful when you decide first
        on the file name and after that you want to create it in the exact location specified at the
        current cursor position;</li>
      <li product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> - Opens
        the <xref href="preferences-author.dita#preferences-author" format="dita">Author options
          page</xref>.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Document type actions are specific to some document type. Examples of such actions can be
      found in the <xref href="../concepts/doc-type.dita">Predefined document types</xref>
      section.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
