<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-change-tracking">
  <title>Reviewing Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>change tracking</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit Menu <indexterm>Review</indexterm><indexterm>Track
          Changes</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a variety of helpful review tools that improve your ability
      to collaborate with other members of your team, track changes, mark content for various
      reasons, add comments in your content, and to manage the review features.</p>
    <section id="change-tracking">
      <title>Tracking Document Changes</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> feature is a way to keep track of the changes you
        make in a document. <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> highlights changes that you make to
        the content in a document, as well as changes to attributes. The types of tracked changes include:<ul>
          <li>Inserting, deleting content (text or elements)</li>
          <li>Drag and drop content (text or elements)</li>
          <li>Cutting or pasting content (text or elements)</li>
          <li>Inserting, deleting, and changing the structure of tables</li>
          <li>Inserting and editing lists and their content</li>
          <li>Inserting and deleting entities</li>
          <li>Inserting and deleting element tags</li>
          <li>Editing attributes</li>
          <li>Performing a <b>Split</b> operation</li>
          <li>Performing a <uicontrol>Surround with</uicontrol> operation</li>
          <li>Changes in referenced content (for example, XInclude fragments or DITA conrefs)</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>The changes are stored in the document source code as processing instructions and they do
        not interfere with validating and transforming it. For each change, the author name and the
        modification time are preserved.</p>
      <p><b>Example - Insertion Change:</b> The following processing instruction is an example of
        how an <term>insertion</term> change is stored in a
        document:<codeblock><codeph>&lt;?oxy_insert_start author="John Doe" timestamp="20090408T164459+0300"?>all&lt;?oxy_insert_end?></codeph></codeblock></p>
      <p><b>Example - Deletion Change:</b> The following processing instruction is an example of how
        a <term>deletion</term> change is stored in a
        document:<codeblock><codeph>&lt;?oxy_delete author="John Doe" timestamp="20090508T164459+0300" content="belong"?></codeph></codeblock></p>
    </section>
    <p>
      <note type="important">If you copy content in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode that contains
        tracked changes, the changes will automatically be accepted prior to the content being
        copied to the clipboard. This filtering is performed only if the selection is not entirely
        inside a tracked change. </note>
    </p>
    <section id="author-comments"><title>Adding Comments in Documents</title><p>You can associate a
        comment to a selected area of content. Comments can highlight virtually any content from
        your document, except <i>read-only</i> text. The difference between using comments and
        change tracking is that a comment can be associated to an area of text without modifying or
        deleting the text. </p>Comments are presented in <xref
        href="author-callouts.dita#author-callouts">callouts</xref> with persistent highlights and a
      colored background. The background color is assigned automatically by the application, but it
      can also be customized from the <xref keyref="options_track-changes"
          ><uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>.<p>The comments are stored in the
        document source code as processing instructions that contain information about the author
        name and the comment time:
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;?oxy_comment_start author="John Doe" timestamp="20090508T164459+0300" comment="Do not change this content"?>
    Important content
&lt;?oxy_comment_end?></codeblock></p></section>
    <section>
      <title>Highlighting Content</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/>
        include<?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>s a highlighting
        feature<?oxy_custom_end?> that allows you to create digital markers to emphasise important
        fragments of your documents. This is especially useful when you want to mark content that
        needs additional work or the attention of others.</p>
      <p>The highlights are stored in the document as processing instructions that contain
        information about the author name and the comment time: </p>
    </section>
    <section id="review_view"
        ><title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20160406T163255+0300" comment="edit"?>Using
        the Review View<?oxy_comment_end?></title>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view is also
      useful for managing tracked changes and comments. In this view, the edits are presented in a
      compact form, in the order they appear in the document and each edit is marked with a
      type-specific icon.</section>
  </body>
</topic>

