<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-dita-extensions">
    <title>DITA Author Mode Actions</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>DITA Topics Document Type<indexterm>Author extensions</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>A variety of actions are available in the DITA framework that can be added to the
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu, the <uicontrol>Author custom actions</uicontrol> toolbar,
      the contextual menu, and the <uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol>.</p>
    <section id="dita-toolbar-actions-section"><title>DITA Toolbar Actions</title>The following
      default actions are readily available on the <uicontrol>DITA (Author Custom
        Actions)</uicontrol> toolbar when editing in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode (by default,
      most of them are also available in the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu and in various
      submenus of the contextual menu):<dl>
        <dlentry id="bold-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Bold16.gif" id="image_tys_tjx_sr"
            />Bold</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Surrounds the selected text with a <codeph>b</codeph> tag. You can use this action on
            multiple non-contiguous selections.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="italic-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Italic16.png" id="image_kbn_3xx_sr"
            />Italic</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Surrounds the selected text with an <codeph>i</codeph> tag. You can use this action on
            multiple non-contiguous selections.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="underline-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Underline16.gif" id="image_hr3_vxx_sr"
              />Underline</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Surrounds the selected text with a <codeph>u</codeph> tag. You can use this action on
            multiple non-contiguous selections.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/LinkDrop.png" id="image_rng_tkx_sr"/>Link</uicontrol>
            Actions Drop-Down Menu</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The following link actions are available from this menu:<dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Cross Reference</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Depending on the context where it is invoked, the action inserts one of the
                    following two elements:<ul id="ul_tx4_ggb_2r">
                      <li><codeph>xref</codeph> - With the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set to
                          <codeph>dita</codeph>.</li>
                      <li><codeph>fragref</codeph> - A specialization of the <codeph>xref</codeph>
                          element.<note>Both elements point to their target using the
                            <codeph>href</codeph> attribute</note></li>
                    </ul>The referenced target is selected in a dialog box that lists all the IDs
                    extracted from the selected file. When you select an ID, you can preview the
                    content in the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> tab or the XML source in the
                      <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> tab. If you have a large number of IDs in the
                    target document, use the <uicontrol>Filter</uicontrol> field to search through
                    the IDs. <fig product="editor author" id="fig_ux4_ggb_2r">
                      <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
                      <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_xref.png" placement="inline"
                        id="image_ibp_ggb_2r"/>
                    </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_xbp_ggb_2r">
                      <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
                      <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_xref.png" placement="inline"
                        id="image_nfp_ggb_2r"/>
                    </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog box is not modal.
                      The dialog box is closed automatically if you switch to a different
                      editor.</note></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Key Reference</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Inserts a user specified element with the value of the <codeph>keyref</codeph>
                    attribute set to a specific key name. As stated in the DITA 1.2 specification,
                    keys are defined at map level and referenced afterwards. You are able to select
                    the target of the <codeph>keyref</codeph> element in the <uicontrol>Insert Key
                      Reference</uicontrol> dialog box. <note>The <uicontrol>Insert Key
                        Reference</uicontrol> dialog box presents the list of keys available in the
                      current DITA Map. If the DITA Map is not opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                        Manager</uicontrol> view, the <uicontrol>Insert Key Reference</uicontrol>
                      dialog box does not display any keys. </note><p>You can also reference
                      elements at sub-topic level by pressing the <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol>
                      button and choosing the target.</p>All keys which are presented in the dialog
                    box are gathered from the current opened DITA map. Elements which have the
                      <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed as links. The current
                    opened DITA map is also used to resolve references when navigating
                      <codeph>keyref</codeph> links in the Author mode. Image elements which use key
                    references are rendered as images.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>File Reference</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element with the value of attribute
                      <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>xml</codeph>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Web Link</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element with the value of attribute
                      <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph>, and
                      <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Related Link to Topic</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph> element inside a
                      <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Related Link to File</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph> element with the <codeph>format</codeph>
                    attribute set to <codeph>xml</codeph> inside a <codeph>related-links</codeph>
                    parent.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Related Link to Web Page</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph> element with the attribute
                      <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph> and
                      <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph> inside a
                      <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent. </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-image-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Image16.gif" id="image_lqj_f1z_tr"/>Insert
              Image</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens the <xref href="eppo-adding-images.dita#eppo-adding-images"><uicontrol>Insert
                Image</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> that allows you to configure the properties of
            an image to be inserted into a DITA document at the caret position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertSectionDrop.png" id="image_i2d_31z_tr"/>Insert
              Section</uicontrol> Drop-Down Menu</dt>
          <dd>The following insert actions are available from this menu:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Section16.gif" id="image_btp_v1z_tr"/>Insert
                    Section</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>section</codeph> element in the document, depending on the
                  current context.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertConcept16.gif" id="image_qxk_qcz_tr"
                    />Insert Concept</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>concept</codeph> element, depending on the current
                  context. Concepts provide background information that users must know before they
                  can successfully work with a product or interface.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertTask16.gif" id="image_hg5_qcz_tr"/>Insert
                    Task</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>task</codeph> element, depending on the current context.
                  Tasks are the main building blocks for task-oriented user assistance. They
                  generally provide step-by-step instructions that will enable a user to perform a
                  task.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertTopic16.gif" id="image_d1z_fbz_tr"/>Insert
                    Topic</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>topic</codeph> element, depending on the current context.
                  Topics are the basic units of DITA content and are usually organized around a
                  single subject.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertRef16.gif" id="image_rhf_rcz_tr"/>Insert
                    Reference</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>reference</codeph> element, depending on the current
                  context. A reference is a top-level container for a reference topic.</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-para-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Paragraph16.png" id="image_glk_4lw_5r"/>Insert
              Paragraph</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new paragraph at current cursor position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dita-insert-content-reference">
          <dt><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150707T104530+0300" comment="This section will need to be updated once EXM-32714 is done.  Also, I should condense the info here and link it to a topic that provides even more info."?><uicontrol><image
                href="../img/Conref16.png" id="image_h2y_rwx_sr"/>Insert Content
              Reference</uicontrol><?oxy_comment_end?></dt>
          <dd>
            <p>Opens the <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you
              to insert a content reference at the caret position. You can also use this dialog box
              to insert a content key reference.</p>
            <p>The DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of content
              fragments. The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute stores a reference to another element
              and is processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The
              element containing the content reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced
              element. The identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or
              resolvable in the context of the referencing element. See <xref
                href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.0/archspec/conref.html" scope="external"
                format="html">here</xref> for more details.</p>
            <p><ph keyref="product"/>
              <xref href="author-displaying-referenced-content.dita">displays the referenced
                content</xref> of a DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid
              resource. If you have URI's instead of local paths in the XML documents and your DITA
              OT transformation needs an XML catalog to map the URI's to local paths you have to
                <xref href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita">add the catalog to <ph keyref="product"
                /></xref>. If the URI's can be resolved the referenced content will be displayed in
              Author mode and in the transformation output.</p>
            <fig product="editor author" id="fig_usp_ggb_2r">
              <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conref.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_jwp_ggb_2r"/>
            </fig>
            <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_ywp_ggb_2r">
              <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conref.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_ebq_ggb_2r"/>
            </fig>
            <note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog box is not modal. The
              dialog box is closed automatically if you switch to a different editor.</note>
            <p>In the URL chooser you set the URL of the file from which you want to reuse content.
              Depending on the <uicontrol>Target type</uicontrol> filter you will see a tree of
              elements which can be referenced (which have ID's). For each element the XML content
              is shown in the preview area. The <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> value is computed
              automatically for the selected tree element. After pressing
                <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>, an element with the same name as the target element
              and having the attribute <codeph>conref</codeph> with the value specified in the
                <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> value field will be inserted at caret position.</p>
            <p>According to the DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute can
              be used to specify content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature when
              referencing multiple consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple contiguous
              sibling selection the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be set to the value
              of the last selected ID path. <ph keyref="product"/> will present the entire
              referenced range as read-only content.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-list-item-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ListItem16.gif" id="image_r15_fl1_5r"/>Insert step or
              list item</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new list or step item in the current list type.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-ul-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-ol-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
      </dl><dl>
        <dlentry conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/sort-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
      </dl><dl conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/table_editing_actions">
        <dlentry>
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
    <section><title>DITA Menu Actions</title>In addition to the <xref
        href="#author-dita-extensions/dita-toolbar-actions-section" format="dita">DITA toolbar
        actions</xref>, the following default actions are available in the
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu when editing in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode:<dl>
        <dlentry id="push-element-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Push Current Element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens the <xref href="conref-push-mechanism.dita#conref-push-mechanism"
                ><uicontrol>Push current element</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> that allows content
            from a source topic to be inserted into another topic without any special coding in the
            topic where the content will be re-used.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="add-edit-conref-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Add/Edit Content Reference</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Add or edit the <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute of an element. For more information,
            see <xref href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
              Content</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="replace-ref-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Replace Reference with content</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Replaces the content reference fragment at the caret position with the referenced
            content. This action is useful when you want to make changes to the content but decide
            to keep the referenced fragment unchanged.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="remove-conref-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove Content Reference</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Removes the <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute of an element. For more information, see
              <xref href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
              Content</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="create-reusable-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Create Reusable Component</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Creates a reusable component from a selected fragment of text. For more information,
            see <xref href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
              Content</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-reusable-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert Reusable Component</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a reusable component at cursor location. For more information, see <xref
              href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
              Content</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteSpecialDITA16.png" id="image_cf2_csh_ps"/>Paste
              special</uicontrol> submenu</dt>
          <dd>This submenu includes the following special paste actions that are specific to the
            DITA framework:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as content reference</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a content reference (a DITA element with a <codeph>conref</codeph>
                  attribute) to the DITA XML element from the clipboard. An entire DITA XML element
                  with an ID attribute must be present in the clipboard when the action is invoked.
                  The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute will point to this ID value.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as content key reference</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Allows you to indirectly reference content using the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>
                  attribute. When the DITA content is processed, the key references are resolved
                  using key definitions from DITA maps. To use this action, do the following:<ol
                    id="ol_rby_rhn_ps">
                    <li>Set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element holding the content you
                      want to reference.</li>
                    <li>Open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and
                      make sure that the <uicontrol>Root map</uicontrol> combo box points to the
                      correct map that stores the keys.</li>
                    <li>Right click the topic that holds the content you want to reference, select
                        <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the
                        <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> field.</li>
                  </ol></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as link</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph> element or an <codeph>xref</codeph> (depending
                  on the location of the paste operation) that points to the DITA XML element from
                  the clipboard. An entire DITA XML element with an ID attribute must be present in
                  the clipboard when the action is invoked. The <codeph>href</codeph> attribute of
                    <codeph>link</codeph>/<codeph>href</codeph> will point to this ID value.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as link (keyref)</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a link to the element that you want to reference. To use this action, do
                  the following:<ol id="ol_jt2_13n_ps">
                    <li>Set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element that you want to
                      reference.</li>
                    <li>Open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and
                      make sure that the <uicontrol>Root map</uicontrol> combo box points to the
                      correct map that stores the keys.</li>
                    <li>Right click the topic that holds the content you want to reference, select
                        <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the
                        <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> field.</li>
                  </ol></dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Table</uicontrol> submenu</dt>
          <dd>In addition to the table actions available on the toolbar, the following actions are
            available in this submenu:<dl>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-row-above-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-rows-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-column-before-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-columns-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/Equation16.gif" id="image_v53_g4z_vr"/>Insert
                Equation</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>XML Fragment Editor</uicontrol> that allows you to insert and
              <xref href="../topics/author-editing-mathml.dita">edit MathML notations</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/ID-options-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry
          conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/generate-ids-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Style Guide</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens the <b>DITA Style Guide Best Practices for Authors</b> in your browser and
            displays a topic that is relevant to the element at the caret position. When editing
            DITA documents, this action is available in the contextual menu of the editing area
            (under the <uicontrol>About Element</uicontrol> sub-menu), in the
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu, and in some of the documentation tips that are
            displayed by the <uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry
          conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/refresh-references-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry
          conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/tags-display-mode-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry
          conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/profiling-text-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
    <section><title>DITA Contextual Menu Actions</title>In addition to many of the <xref
        href="#author-dita-extensions/dita-toolbar-actions-section" format="dita">DITA toolbar
        actions</xref> and the <xref href="author-contextual-menu.dita#author-contextual-menu"
          ><i>general</i>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode contextual menu actions</xref>, the following DITA
      framework-specific actions are also available in the contextual menu when editing in
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteSpecialDITA16.png" id="image_us5_53h_ps"/>Paste
              special</uicontrol> submenu</dt>
          <dd>This submenu includes the following special paste actions that are specific to the
            DITA framework:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as content reference</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a content reference (a DITA element with a <codeph>conref</codeph>
                  attribute) to the DITA XML element from the clipboard. An entire DITA XML element
                  with an ID attribute must be present in the clipboard when the action is invoked.
                  The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute will point to this ID value.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as content key reference</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Allows you to indirectly reference content using the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>
                  attribute. When the DITA content is processed, the key references are resolved
                  using key definitions from DITA maps. To use this action, do the following:<ol
                    id="ol_yq4_rjn_ps">
                    <li>Set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element holding the content you
                      want to reference.</li>
                    <li>Open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and
                      make sure that the <uicontrol>Root map</uicontrol> combo box points to the
                      correct map that stores the keys.</li>
                    <li>Right click the topic that holds the content you want to reference, select
                        <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the
                        <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> field.</li>
                  </ol></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as link</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph> element or an <codeph>xref</codeph> (depending
                  on the location of the paste operation) that points to the DITA XML element from
                  the clipboard. An entire DITA XML element with an ID attribute must be present in
                  the clipboard when the action is invoked. The <codeph>href</codeph> attribute of
                    <codeph>link</codeph>/<codeph>href</codeph> will point to this ID value.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Paste as link (keyref)</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts a link to the element that you want to reference. To use this action, do
                  the following:<ol id="ol_zq4_rjn_ps">
                    <li>Set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element that you want to
                      reference.</li>
                    <li>Open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and
                      make sure that the <uicontrol>Root map</uicontrol> combo box points to the
                      correct map that stores the keys.</li>
                    <li>Right click the topic that holds the content you want to reference, select
                        <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the
                        <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> field.</li>
                  </ol></dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Table</uicontrol> submenu</dt>
          <dd>In addition to the table actions available on the toolbar, the following actions are
            available in this submenu when the contextual menu is invoked on a table:<dl>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-row-above-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-rows-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-column-before-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry
                conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/insert-columns-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/Equation16.gif" id="image_b3h_vjn_ps"/>Insert
                Equation</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>XML Fragment Editor</uicontrol> that allows you to insert and
              <xref href="../topics/author-editing-mathml.dita">edit MathML notations</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry
          conref="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/generate-ids-dlentry">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Reuse</uicontrol> submenu</dt>
          <dd>This submenu includes the following actions in regards to reusing content in DITA:<dl>
              <dlentry conref="#./push-element-dlentry" conrefend="#./insert-reusable-dlentry">
                <dt/>
                <dd/>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SearchReferences16.png" id="image_d3f_2kn_ps"/>Search
              References</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Finds the references to the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute value of the selected
            element in all the topics from the current DITA map (opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
              Manager</uicontrol> view). The default shortcut of the action is <uicontrol
              conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_g"/> and can be
            changed in the <uicontrol>DITA Topic</uicontrol> document type.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>About Element</uicontrol> submenu</dt>
          <dd>This submenu includes the following actions:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Style Guide</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Opens the <b>DITA Style Guide Best Practices for Authors</b> in your browser and
                  displays a topic that is relevant to the element at the caret position. When
                  editing DITA documents, this action is available in the contextual menu of the
                  editing area (under the <uicontrol>About Element</uicontrol> sub-menu), in the
                    <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu, and in some of the documentation tips that are
                  displayed by the <uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol>.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/BrowseReferenceManual16.png"
                      id="image_ixj_qkn_ps"/>Browse reference manual</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Opens a reference to the documentation of the XML element closest to the caret
                  position in a web browser.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowDefinition16.png" id="image_rgn_4wp_zr"/>Show
                    Definition</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Moves the cursor to the definition of the current element.</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
    <section>
      <title>DITA Drag/Drop Actions</title>
      <p id="drag-and-drop-from-project-to-author-docbook4">Dragging a file from <xref
          href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita">the
            <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref> or <xref keyref="dita_edit-maps"
          format="dita"><uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view</xref> and dropping it into a
        DITA document that is edited in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, creates a link to the
        dragged file (the <codeph>xref</codeph> DITA element with the <codeph>href</codeph>
        attribute) at the drop location. Dragging an image file from the default file system
        application (Windows Explorer on Windows or Finder on Mac OS X, for example) and dropping it
        into a DITA document inserts an image element (the <codeph>image</codeph> DITA element with
        the <codeph>href</codeph> attribute) at the drop location.</p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
