<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-attributes-view">
  <title>Attributes View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>attributes view</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view presents all the attributes of the current element
      determined by the schema of the document. It allows you to insert attributes in the current
      element or change the value of the attributes already inserted. The attributes are rendered
      differently depending on their state:<ul>
        <li>the names of the attributes with a specified value are rendered with a bold font, and
          their value with a plain font;<note>The names of the attributes with an empty string value
            are also rendered bold. </note></li>
        <li>default values are rendered with a plain font, painted gray;</li>
        <li>empty values display the text "[empty]", painted gray;</li>
        <li>invalid attributes and values are painted red;</li>
      </ul>Double-click a cell in the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column to edit the value of the
      corresponding attribute. In case the possible values of the attribute are specified as list in
      the schema of the edited document, the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column acts as a combo box
      that allows you to insert the values in the document. </p>
    <p>You can sort the attributes table by clicking the <uicontrol>Attribute</uicontrol> column
      header. The table contents can be sorted as follows: <ul>
        <li>by attribute name in ascending order;</li>
        <li>by attribute name in descending order;</li>
        <li>custom order, where the used attributes are displayed at the beginning of the table
          sorted in ascending order, followed by the rest of the allowed elements sorted in
          ascending order.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>The Attributes View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_attributes_panel.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title>The Attributes View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_author_attributes_panel.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>A combo box located in the upper part of the view allows you to edit the attributes of the
      ancestors of the current element.</p>
    <p>The following actions are available in the contextual menu:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> - allows you to insert a new attribute. Adding an attribute
          that is not in the list of all defined attributes is not possible when the <xref
            href="preferences-schema-aware.dita">Allow only insertion of valid elements and
            attributes</xref> schema aware option is enabled;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Set empty value</uicontrol> - Specifies the current attribute value as
          empty;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> - Removes the attribute (action available only if the
          attribute is specified). You can invoke this action by pressing the
              <uicontrol><shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol> or
              <uicontrol><shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> keys;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> - copies the <codeph>attrName="attrValue"</codeph> pair to
          the clipboard. The <codeph>attrValue</codeph> can be:<ul>
            <li>the value of the attribute;</li>
            <li>the value of the default attribute, in case the attribute does not appear in the
              edited document;</li>
            <li>empty, in case the attribute does not appear in the edited document and has no
              default value set.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol> - this action is available in the contextual menu of the
            <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view, in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> modes. Depending on the content of the clipboard, the
          following cases are possible:<ul>
            <li>in case the clipboard contains an attribute and its value, both of them are
              introduced in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view. The attribute is selected
              and its value is changed if they exist in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol>
              view;</li>
            <li>in case the clipboard contains an attribute name with an empty value, the attribute
              is introduced in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view and you can start editing
              it. The attribute is selected and you can start editing it if it exists in the
                <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view;</li>
            <li>in case the clipboard only contains text, the value of the selected attribute is
              modified. </li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To edit in place the attributes of an element in the editor panel, select the attribute and
      press <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_enter"/> on your
      keyboard. This shortcut pops up a small window with the same content of the
        <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view. The default form of the pop-up window presents the
        <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> fields, with the list of all
      the possible attributes collapsed.</p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>Edit attributes in place</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_edit_attributes_in_place.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title>Edit attributes in place</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_author_edit_attributes_in_place.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The small right arrow button expands the list of possible attributes allowed by the schema of
      the document as in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view.</p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>Edit attributes in place - full version</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_edit_attributes_in_place_full_version.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title>Edit attributes in place - full version</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_author_edit_attributes_in_place_full_version.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> field auto-completes the name of the attribute: the complete
      name of the attribute is suggested based on the prefix already typed in the field as the user
      types in the field.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
