<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-outline-view">
  <title>Outline View in Author Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Outline view</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Outline
            view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Outline view in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode displays a
      general tag overview of the currently edited XML Document. When you edit a document, the
        <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view dynamically follows the changes that you make,
      displaying the node that you modify. This functionality gives you great insight on the
      location of your modifications in the current document. It also shows the correct hierarchical
      dependencies between elements. This makes it easy for you to be aware of the document
      structure and the way element tags are nested.</p>
    <section id="outline_view_features">
      <title>Outline View Features</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view allows you to:<ul>
          <li>Quickly navigate through the document by selecting nodes in the
              <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree.</li>
          <li>Insert or delete nodes using contextual menu actions.</li>
          <li>Move elements by dragging them to a new position in the tree structure.</li>
          <li>Highlight elements in the editor area. It is synchronized with the editor area, so
            when you make a selection in the editor area, the corresponding nodes are highlighted in
            the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view, and vice versa.</li>
          <li>View document errors, as they are highlighted in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol>
            view. A tooltip also provides more information about the nature of the error when you
            hover over the faulted element.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="outline_view_interface">
      <title>Outline View Interface</title>
      <p>By default, it is displayed on the left side of the editor. <ph
          conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/reopen-view"/></p>
      <p conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/outliner-filter-box"/>
      <p>It also includes a <ph product="editor author"><uicontrol><image
              href="../img/Settings16.png"/>Settings</uicontrol> menu</ph><ph
          product="editorEclipse authorEclipse"><uicontrol>View menu</uicontrol></ph> in the
        top-right corner that presents a variety of options to help you filter the view even
        further.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="drop_and_drop_actions_in_the_outline_view">
      <title>Drop and Drop Actions in the Outline View</title>
      <p>Entire XML elements can be moved or copied in the edited document using only the mouse in
        the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view with drag-and-drop operations. Several drag and drop
        actions are possible:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>If you drag an XML element in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view and drop it on
          another node, then the dragged element will be moved after the drop target element.</li>
        <li>If you hold the mouse pointer over the drop target for a short time before the drop then
          the drop target element will be expanded first and the dragged element will be moved
          inside the drop target element after its opening tag.</li>
        <li>You can also drop an element before or after another element if you hold the mouse
          pointer towards the upper or lower part of the targeted element. A marker will indicate
          whether the drop will be performed before or after the target element.</li>
        <li>If you hold down the <uicontrol><shortcut>(Ctrl (Command on OS
            X))</shortcut></uicontrol> key after dragging, a copy operation will be performed
          instead of a move.</li>
      </ul>
      <note type="tip" product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">You can select and drag
        multiple nodes in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view when editing in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</note>
    </section>
    <p>
      <fig id="figure-author-outline-view-oxygen" product="editor author">
        <title>Outline View</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_author_outliner_panel.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <fig id="figure-author-outline-view-oxygenEclipse" product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
        <title>Outline View</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_author_outliner_panel.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
