<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-display-markup">
    <title>Displaying the Markup</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>navigation<indexterm>display the
                        markup</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>In the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, you can control the amount of displayed markup
      using the following dedicated actions from the <uicontrol><image href="../img/TagsDrop.png"
          id="image_pmr_mhm_1s"/>Tags display mode</uicontrol> drop-down menu that is available on
      the toolbar:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/FullTagsWithAttrs16.png" id="image_gmv_lrm_wr"/>Full Tags
            with Attributes</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Displays full tag names with attributes for both block level and in-line level
          elements.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/FullTags16.png" id="image_y33_mrm_wr"/>Full
            Tags</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Displays full tag names without attributes for both block level and in-line level
          elements.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/BlockTags16.png" id="image_rcr_mrm_wr"/>Block
            Tags</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Displays full tag names for block level elements and simple tags without names for
          in-line level elements.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InlineTags16.png" id="image_usz_mrm_wr"/>Inline
            Tags</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Displays full tag names for inline level elements, while block level elements are not
          displayed.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/PartialTags16.png" id="image_qsh_nrm_wr"/>Partial
            Tags</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Displays simple tags without names for in-line level elements, while block level
          elements are not displayed.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/NoTags16.png" id="image_ucq_nrm_wr"/>No
          Tags</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>No tags are displayed. This is the most compact mode and is as close as possible to a
          word-processor view.</dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
        <p>To set a default mode of the tags mode, go to <xref href="preferences-author.dita">Author
        preferences page</xref> and configure the <uicontrol>Tags display mode</uicontrol> options.
      However, if the document opened in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode editor does not have an
      associated CSS stylesheet, then the <uicontrol>Full Tags</uicontrol> mode will be used.</p>
        <p>Block-level elements are those elements of the source document that are formatted
      visually as blocks (for example, paragraphs), while the inline level elements are distributed
      in lines (for example, emphasizing pieces of text within a paragraph, inline images, etc). The
      graphical format of the elements is controlled from the CSS sources via the
        <codeph>display</codeph> property.</p>
    </body>
</topic>