<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-outline-popup-menu">
  <title>The Contextual Menu of the Outline Tree</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XML Outline View<indexterm>contextual menu</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree contains the following
      actions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Edit attributes</uicontrol> - A dialog is presented allowing the user to see and edit the attributes of the selected node.</li>
      <li>The <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Insert before</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>Insert after</uicontrol> submenus allow to quickly insert new tags in the
        document at the place of the element selected in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree.
        The <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol> submenu lists the names of all the elements which
        are allowed by the schema associated with the current document as child of the current
        element. The effect is the same as typing the '&lt;' character and selecting an element name
        from the popup menu offered by <xref href="streamline-with-content-completion.dita">the
            <uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol>.</xref> The <uicontrol>Insert
          before</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Insert after</uicontrol> submenus list the elements
        which are allowed by the schema associated with the current document as siblings of the
        current element inserted immediately before respectively after the current element.</li>
      <li>The <uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> actions execute <ph product="editor author">
          <xref href="copying-and-pasting-text.dita">the same actions as the
              <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> menu items with the same name</xref> on the elements
          currently selected in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree.</ph>
        <ph product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">the same actions as the
            <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> menu items with the same name on the elements currently
          selected in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree (<uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol>,
            <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol>).</ph></li>
      <li>You can insert a well-formed element before, after or as a child of the currently selected
        element by accessing the <uicontrol>Paste before</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Paste
          after</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Paste as Child</uicontrol> actions.</li>
      <li>The <uicontrol>Toggle Comment</uicontrol> item encloses the currently selected element of
        the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree in an XML comment, if the element is not commented,
        or removes the comment if it is commented.</li>
      <li>Using the <uicontrol>Rename Element</uicontrol> action the element from the caret position
        and the elements that have the same name as the current element can be renamed according
        with the options from the <uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol> dialog.</li>
      <li product="editor author editorEclipse authorEclipse">
        The <uicontrol product="editor author">Expand More / Collapse All</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">Expand All / Collapse All</uicontrol>
        actions expand / collapse the selection and all its children.</li>
    </ul>
    <note type="tip">You can copy, cut or delete multiple nodes in the
        <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> by using the contextual menu after selecting multiple nodes
      in the tree.</note>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="author-attributes-view.dita"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
