<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="author_actions">
  <title>Author Actions</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides the following
      actions in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry id="bold-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_bold.png" placement="inline" id="image_cx4_ggb_2r"
            />Bold</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Surrounds the selected text with a <codeph>b</codeph> tag.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="italic-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_italic.png" placement="inline" id="image_dx4_ggb_2r"
            />Italic</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Surrounds the selected text with an <codeph>i</codeph> tag.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="underline-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_underline.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_sx4_ggb_2r"/>Underline</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Surrounds the selected text with a <codeph>u</codeph> tag. </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt id="link-action-dt"><uicontrol><image href="../img/Link20.png" id="image_tnf_phb_2r"
            />Link</uicontrol> Actions Drop-Down List</dt>
        <dd>
          <p>The following link actions are available from this list:<ul id="ul_kqs_bhb_2r">
              <li><uicontrol>Cross Reference</uicontrol> - Depending on the context where it is
                invoked, the action inserts one of the following two elements:<ul id="ul_tx4_ggb_2r">
                  <li><codeph>xref</codeph> element, with the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set
                    to <codeph>dita</codeph></li>
                  <li><codeph>fragref</codeph> element, which is a specialization of the
                      <codeph>xref</codeph> element<note>Both elements point to their target using
                      the <codeph>href</codeph> attribute</note></li>
                </ul>The referenced target is selected in a dialog box that lists all the IDs
                extracted from the selected file. When you select an ID, you can preview the content
                in the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> tab or the XML source in the
                  <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> tab. In case you have a large number of IDs in the
                target document, use the <uicontrol>Filter</uicontrol> field to search through the
                IDs. <fig product="editor author" id="fig_ux4_ggb_2r">
                  <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
                  <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_xref.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_ibp_ggb_2r"/>
                </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_xbp_ggb_2r">
                  <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
                  <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_xref.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_nfp_ggb_2r"/>
                </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The
                  dialog is closed automatically in case you switch to a different
                editor.</note></li>
              <li><uicontrol>Key Reference</uicontrol> - Inserts a user specified element with the
                value of the <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set to a specific key name. As stated
                in the DITA 1.2 specification, keys are defined at map level and referenced
                afterwards. You are able to select the target of the <codeph>keyref</codeph> element
                in the <uicontrol>Insert Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog box. <note>The
                    <uicontrol>Insert Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog box presents the list of keys
                  available in the current DITA Map. If the DITA Map is not opened in the
                    <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view, the <uicontrol>Insert Key
                    Reference</uicontrol> dialog does not display any keys. </note><p>You can also
                  reference elements at sub-topic level by pressing the
                    <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol> button and choosing the target.</p>All keys
                which are presented in the dialog are gathered from the current opened DITA map.
                Elements which have the <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed as
                links. The current opened DITA map is also used to resolve references when
                navigating <codeph>keyref</codeph> links in the Author mode. Image elements which
                use key references are rendered as images.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>File Reference</uicontrol> - Inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element
                with the value of attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to
                <codeph>xml</codeph>.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Web Link</uicontrol> - Inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element with
                the value of attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph>, and
                  <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph>.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Related Link to Topic</uicontrol> - Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
                element inside a <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Related Link to File</uicontrol> - Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
                element with the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set to <codeph>xml</codeph>
                inside a <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Related Link to Web Page</uicontrol> - Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
                element with the attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph> and
                  <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph> inside a
                  <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent. </li>
            </ul></p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="insert-image-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_graphic.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_ekg_v2b_2r"/>Insert image reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd><xref href="author_adding_images.dita#author_adding_images" format="dita">Inserts an
            image reference</xref> at the caret position. Depending on the current context, an
          image-type DITA element is inserted. Also you can use this action to <xref
            href="working-with-mathml.dita#working-with-mathml" format="dita">reference MathML
            files</xref>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Insert Section</uicontrol> Drop-Down List</dt>
        <dd>The following link actions are available from this list:<ul id="ul_a21_13b_2r">
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_section.png" placement="inline"
                  id="image_nfp_13b_2r"/>Insert Section</uicontrol> - Inserts a new section / step
              in the document, depending on the current context. A new section will be inserted in
              either one of the following contexts: <ul id="ul_ikp_ggb_2r">
                <li>section context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element or one of its ancestors contains <codeph>topic</codeph> or
                    <codeph>section</codeph>.</li>
                <li>topic's body context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element contains <codeph>topic/body</codeph>. </li>
              </ul><p>A new step will be inserted in either one of the following contexts: </p><ul
                id="ul_inp_ggb_2r">
                <li>task step context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element or one of its ancestors contains <codeph>task/step</codeph>.</li>
                <li>task steps context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element contains <codeph>task/steps</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_dita_insert_concept.png" placement="inline"
                  id="image_vtb_d3b_2r"/>Insert Concept</uicontrol> - Inserts a new concept.
              Concepts provide background information that users must know before they can
              successfully work with a product or interface. This action is available in one of the
              following contexts: <ul id="ul_czr_d3b_2r">
                <li>concept context, one of the current element ancestors is a
                    <codeph>concept</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
                  inserted after the current <codeph>concept</codeph>.</li>
                <li>concept or DITA context, current element is a <codeph>concept</codeph> or
                    <codeph>dita</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
                  inserted at current caret position.</li>
                <li>DITA topic context, current element is a <codeph>topic</codeph> child of a
                    <codeph>dita</codeph> element. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph>
                  will be inserted at current caret position.</li>
                <li>DITA topic context, one of the current element ancestors is a DITA
                    <codeph>topic</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
                  inserted after the first <codeph>topic</codeph> ancestor.</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_dita_insert_task.png" placement="inline"
                  id="image_prp_ggb_2r"/>Insert Task</uicontrol> - Inserts a new task. Tasks are the
              main building blocks for task-oriented user assistance. They generally provide
              step-by-step instructions that will enable a user to perform a task. This action is
              available in one of the following contexts: <ul id="ul_qrp_ggb_2r">
                <li>task context, one of the current element ancestors is a <codeph>task</codeph>.
                  In this case an empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted after the last child
                  of the first <codeph>concept</codeph>'s ancestor.</li>
                <li>task context, the current element is a <codeph>task</codeph>. In this case an
                  empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted at current caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context, the current element is a <codeph>dita</codeph>
                  <codeph>topic</codeph>. An empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted at current
                  caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context, one of the current element ancestors is a <codeph>dita</codeph>
                  <codeph>topic</codeph>. An empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted after the
                  last child of the first ancestor that is a <codeph>topic</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150223T113801+0200" comment="Insert content, image, etc."?><uicontrol>Insert
                Topic</uicontrol> - <?oxy_comment_end?></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_dita_insert_ref.png" placement="inline"
                  id="image_dsp_ggb_2r"/>Insert Reference</uicontrol> - Inserts a new reference in
              the document. A reference is a top-level container for a reference topic. This action
              is available in one of the following contexts: <ul id="ul_esp_ggb_2r">
                <li>reference context - one of the current element ancestors is a
                    <codeph>reference</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>reference</codeph>
                  will be inserted after the last child of the first ancestor that is a
                    <codeph>reference</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph>reference</codeph> or <codeph>dita</codeph> context - the current
                  element is either a <codeph>dita</codeph> or a <codeph>reference</codeph>. An
                  empty <codeph>reference</codeph> will be inserted at caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context - the current element is <codeph>topic</codeph> descendant of
                    <codeph>dita</codeph> element. An empty <codeph>reference</codeph> will be
                  inserted at caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context - the current element is descendant of <codeph>dita</codeph>
                  element and descendant of <codeph>topic</codeph> element. An empty
                    <codeph>reference</codeph> will be inserted after the last child of the first
                  ancestor that is a <codeph>topic</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></li>
          </ul></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="insert-para-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_para.png" id="image_jm4_mb2_fr"/>Insert a new
            paragraph</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Insert a new paragraph at current cursor position.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="dita-insert-content-reference">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_conref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_tsp_ggb_2r"/>Insert DITA Content Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>
          <p>Inserts a content reference at the caret position.</p>
          <p>The DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of content
            fragments. The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute stores a reference to another element
            and is processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The
            element containing the content reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced
            element. The identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable
            in the context of the referencing element. See <xref
              href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.0/archspec/conref.html" scope="external"
              format="html">here</xref> for more details.</p>
          <p><ph keyref="product"/>
            <xref href="author-displaying-referenced-content.dita">displays the referenced
              content</xref> of a DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid
            resource. If you have URI's instead of local paths in the XML documents and your DITA OT
            transformation needs an XML catalog to map the URI's to local paths you have to <xref
              href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita">add the catalog to <ph keyref="product"/></xref>. If
            the URI's can be resolved the referenced content will be displayed in Author mode and in
            the transformation output.</p>
          <p>A content reference is inserted with the action <uicontrol>Insert a DITA Content
              Reference</uicontrol> available on the toolbar <uicontrol>Author custom
              actions</uicontrol> and on the menu <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</p>
          <fig product="editor author" id="fig_usp_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conref.png" placement="inline" id="image_jwp_ggb_2r"
            />
          </fig>
          <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_ywp_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conref.png" placement="inline" id="image_ebq_ggb_2r"
            />
          </fig>
          <note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The dialog
            is closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note>
          <p>In the URL chooser you set the URL of the file from which you want to reuse content.
            Depending on the <uicontrol>Target type</uicontrol> filter you will see a tree of
            elements which can be referenced (which have ID's). For each element the XML content is
            shown in the preview area. The <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> value is computed
            automatically for the selected tree element. After pressing
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>, an element with the same name as the target element and
            having the attribute <codeph>conref</codeph> with the value specified in the
              <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> value field will be inserted at caret position.</p>
          <p>According to the DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute can be
            used to specify content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature when referencing
            multiple consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple contiguous sibling
            selection the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be set to the value of the last
            selected ID path. <ph keyref="product"/> will present the entire referenced range as
            read-only content.</p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="dita-insert-content-key-reference">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_conkeyref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_tbq_ggb_2r"/>Insert Content Key Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a content key reference at the caret position. <p>As stated in the DITA 1.2
            specification the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of
            content fragments similar with the <codeph>conref</codeph> mechanism. Keys are defined
            at map level which can be referenced using <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>. The
              <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute contains a key reference to another element and
            is processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The element
            containing the content key reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced element.
            The identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable in the
            context of the referencing element.</p><p><ph keyref="product"/>
            <xref href="author-displaying-referenced-content.dita">displays the key referenced
              content</xref> of a DITA <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid
            resource in the context of the current opened DITA map.</p><p>A content key reference is
            inserted with the action <uicontrol>Insert a DITA Content Key Reference</uicontrol>
            available on the toolbar <uicontrol>Author custom actions</uicontrol> and on the menu <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</p><fig product="editor author" id="fig_ubq_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conkeyref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_jfq_ggb_2r"/>
          </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_zfq_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conkeyref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_ojq_ggb_2r"/>
          </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal.
            The dialog is closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note><p>To
            reference target elements at sub-topic level just press the
              <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol> button and choose the target.</p><p>According to the
            DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute can be used to specify
            content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature when referencing multiple
            consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple contiguous sibling selection for
            IDs at sub-topic level the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be set to the
            value of the last selected ID path. <ph keyref="product"/> will present the entire
            referenced range as read-only content.<note type="important">All keys which are
              presented in the dialog are gathered from the current opened DITA map. Elements which
              have the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed by default with the
              target content expanded. The current opened DITA map is also used to resolve
              references when navigating <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> links in the Author
            mode.</note></p></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Sort16.png" id="image_msv_5c2_fr"/>Sort</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Sorts a table selection.</dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
    <p>Table editing actions:<dl id="table_editing_actions">
        <dlentry id="table_editing_actions_insert_table">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_table.png" id="image_ny1_ty5_2g"
                placement="inline"/>Insert Table</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog that allows you to configure and insert a table. You can generate a
            header and footer, set the number of rows and columns of the table and decide how the
            table is framed.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_new_table_row.png" id="image_4y1_ty5_2g"
                placement="inline"/>Insert Row</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new table row with empty cells. This action is available when the caret is
            positioned inside a table.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_new_table_column.png" id="image_py1_ty5_2g"
                placement="inline"/>Insert Column</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new table column with empty cells after the current column. This action is
            available when the caret is positioned inside a table.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_new_table_cell.png" id="image_qy1_ty5_2g"
                placement="inline"/>Insert Cell</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new empty cell depending on the current context. If the caret is positioned
            between two cells, <ph keyref="product"/> a new cell at caret position. If the caret is
            inside a cell, the new cell is created after the current cell.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_delete_table_column.png" id="image_ry1_ty5_2g"
                placement="inline"/>Delete Column</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Deletes the table column located at caret position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_delete_table_row.png" id="image_sy1_ty5_2g"
                placement="inline"/>Delete Row</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Deletes the table row located at caret position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_properties.png" id="image_on2_nd2_fr"/>Edit
              Table Properties</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Table properties</uicontrol> dialog that allows you to configure
            properties of a table (such as frame borders).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Table Join/Split</uicontrol> Drop-Down List</dt>
          <dd>The following link actions are available from this list:<ul id="ul_kyv_1kb_2r">
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_join_table_row_cells.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_jbz_dkb_2r"/>Join Row Cells</uicontrol> - Joins the content of the
                selected cells. The operation is available if the selected cells are from the same
                row and they have the same row span. The action is also available when the selection
                is missing, but the caret is positioned between two cells.</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_join_above.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_axz_fkb_2r"/>Join Cell Above</uicontrol> - Joins the content of the
                cell from the current caret position with the content of the cell above it. This
                action works only if both cells have the same column span.</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_join_below.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_acz_dkb_2r"/>Join Cell Below</uicontrol> - Joins the content of the
                cell from the current caret position with the content of the cell below it. This
                action works only if both cells have the same column span.<note>When you use
                      <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_join_above.png" placement="inline"
                      id="image_bcz_dkb_2r"/>Join Cell Above</uicontrol> and <uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/bt_table_join_below.png" placement="inline" id="image_pcz_dkb_2r"
                    />Join Cell Below</uicontrol>, <ph keyref="product"/> deletes the source row is
                  case it remains empty. The cells that span over multiple rows are also
                  updated.</note></li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_split_left.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_qcz_dkb_2r"/>Split Cell To The Left</uicontrol> - Splits the cell from
                the current caret position in two cells, inserting a new empty table cell to the
                left. This action works only if the current cell spans over more than one column.<ph
                  keyref="product"/> decreases the column span of the source cell with one.</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_split_right.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_rcz_dkb_2r"/>Split Cell To The Right</uicontrol>- Splits the cell from
                the current caret position in two cells, inserting a new empty table cell to the
                right. This action works only if the current cell spans over more than one
                  column.<ph keyref="product"/> decreases the column span of the source cell with
                one.</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_split_above.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_cqk_kkb_2r"/>Split Cell Above</uicontrol> - Splits the cell from
                current caret position in two cells, inserting a new empty table cell above. This
                action works only if the current cell spans over more than one row. <ph
                  keyref="product"/> decreases the column span of the source cell with one.</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_table_split_below.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_qwr_lkb_2r"/>Split Cell Below</uicontrol> - Splits the cell from
                current caret position in two, inserting a new empty table cell below. This action
                works only if the current cell spans over more than one row. <ph keyref="product"/>
                decreases the column span of the source cell with one.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl><dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/insert_row_above.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_pq4_dvf_fr"/>Insert Row Above</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a row above the current one.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertRow20.gif" id="image_qq4_dvf_fr"/>Insert Row
              Below</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a row below the current one.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert Rows...</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog that allows you to insert any number of rows and specify the position
            where they will be inserted (<uicontrol>Above</uicontrol> or
              <uicontrol>Below</uicontrol> the current row).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/insert_column_before.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_rq4_dvf_fr"/>Insert Column Before</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a column before the current one.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertColumn20.gif" id="image_sq4_dvf_fr"/>Insert
              Column After</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a column after the current one.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert Columns...</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog that allows you to insert any number of columns and specify the
            position where they will be inserted (<uicontrol>Above</uicontrol> or
              <uicontrol>Below</uicontrol> the current column).</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
      <p>List editing actions:<dl id="list_editing_actions">
        <dlentry id="list_editing_actions_insert_step">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_list_item.png" id="image_xlq_qc1_fg"
                placement="inline"/>Insert a step or list Item</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new step or list item in the current list type.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_itemized_list.png" id="image_nmq_qc1_fg"
                placement="inline"/>Insert an unordered list at the caret position</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts an itemized list. A child list item is also automatically inserted by
            default.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="list_editing_actions_insert_ordered_list">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_ordered_list.png" id="image_mmq_qc1_fg"
                placement="inline"/>Insert an ordered list at the caret position</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts an ordered list. A child list item is also automatically inserted by
            default.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
