<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-navigate-document-content">
  <title>Navigating the Document Content</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Author
          Editor<indexterm>navigation</indexterm><indexterm>breadcrumb</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>Using the Keyboard</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to quickly navigate through a document using <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/tab"/> to go to the next XML node
        and <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/shift_tab"/> to go
        to the previous one. The caret is moved to the next / previous editable position. When your
        caret is positioned in a space preserve element, press a key on your keyboard and then use
          <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/tab"/> to arrange the
        text. You can also arrange the text using <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/tab"/> if you position the cursor
        in a space preserve element using your mouse. In case you encounter a space preserve element
        when you navigate through a document and you press no other key, the next <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/tab"/> continues the navigation. </p>
      <p>To navigate one word forward or backwards, use <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_right_arrow"/>, and
          <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_left_arrow"/>,
        respectively. Entities and hidden elements are skipped.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Using the Navigation Toolbar</title>The locations of selected text are stored in
      an internal list which allows you to navigate between them with the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/bt_go_back.png"/>Back</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/previous-edited-text"/>) and
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_go_forward.png"/>Forward</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/next-edited-text"/>) buttons from
      the <uicontrol>Navigation</uicontrol> toolbar. The <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/bt_go_to_last_modification.png"/> Last Modification</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_alt_g"/>) button automatically
      takes you to the latest edited text.</section>
    <section>
      <title>Using the Breadcrumb Helpers </title>
      <p>A left-hand side stripe paints a vertical thin light blue bar indicating the span of the
        element found at caret position. Also a top stripe called <i>breadcrumb</i> indicates the
        path from document root to the current element.</p>
      <fig>
        <title>The breadcrumb in Editor view</title>
        <image href="../img/bt_author_top_stripe.png"/>
      </fig>
      <p>The last element is also highlighted by a thin light blue bar for easier identification.
        Clicking one element from the top stripe selects the entire element in the editor view.</p>
      <p>The tag names displayed in the breadcrumb can be customized with an Author extension class
        that implements <apiname>AuthorBreadCrumbCustomizer</apiname>. See the <xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/developer.html" scope="external" format="html">Author
          SDK</xref> for details about using it.</p>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Insert before</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>Insert after</uicontrol> submenus of the top stripe popup menu allow you to
        insert new tags in the document at the place of the selected element. The <uicontrol>Append
          child</uicontrol> submenu lists the names of all the elements which are allowed by the
        schema associated with the current document as child of the current element. The effect is
        the same as typing the '&lt;' character and selecting an element name from the popup menu
        offered by <xref href="streamline-with-content-completion.dita">the content completion
          assistant.</xref> The <uicontrol>Insert before</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Insert
          after</uicontrol> submenus list the elements which are allowed by the schema associated
        with the current document as siblings of the current element inserted immediately before
        respectively after the current element.</p>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol>
        and <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> items of the popup menu execute <ph
          product="editor author">
          <xref href="copying-and-pasting-text.dita">the same actions as the
              <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> menu items with the same name</xref> on the elements
          currently selected in the stripe.</ph>
        <ph product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">the same actions as the
            <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> menu items with the same name on the elements currently
          selected in the stripe (Cut, Copy, Paste, Delete).</ph> The <uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> operations (like the <codeph>display:block</codeph> property
        or the tabular format of the data from a set of table cells) preserve the styles of the
        copied content. The <uicontrol>Paste before</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Paste after</uicontrol>
        and <uicontrol>Paste as Child</uicontrol> actions allow the user to insert an well-formed
        element before, after or as a child of the currently selected element.</p>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Toggle Comment</uicontrol> item of the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree
        popup menu encloses the currently selected element of the top stripe in an XML comment, if
        the element is not commented, or removes the comment if it is commented.</p>
      <p>Using the <uicontrol>Rename Element</uicontrol> action the selected element and the
        elements that have the same name as the current element can be renamed according with the
        options from the <uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol> dialog.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Using the Folding Support</title>When working on a large document, the
        <b>folding support</b> can be used to collapse some elements content leaving in focus only
      the ones you need to edit. Foldable elements are marked with a small triangle painted in the
      upper left corner. Hovering with the mouse pointer over that marker, the entire content of the
      element is highlighted by a dotted border for quick identification of the foldable area. The
      following actions are available in the contextual menu, <uicontrol>Folding</uicontrol> sub-menu:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_toggle_fold.png"/> Toggle Fold</uicontrol> - toggles
          the state of the current fold;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_close_other_folds.png"/> Close Other Folds</uicontrol>
            (<uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_numpad_slash"
          />)- folds all the elements except the current element;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_collapse_child_folds.png"/> Collapse Child
            Folds</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_numpad_dot"/>) - folds the
          elements indented with one level inside the current element; </li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_expand_child_folds.png"/> Expand Child
            Folds</uicontrol>- unfolds all child elements of the currently selected element; </li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ExpandAll16.png"/> Expand All</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_numpad_asterisk"/>) -
          unfolds all elements in the current document.</li>
      </ul></section>
    <section>
      <title>Using the Linking Support</title>
      <p>When working on a suite of documents that refer to one another (references, external
        entities, XInclude, DITA conref, etc), the <b>linking support</b> is useful for navigating
        between the documents. In the predefined customizations that are bundled with <ph
          keyref="product"/> links are marked with an
        icon representing a chain link: <image href="../img/author_link.png"/>. When hovering with
        the mouse pointer over the marker, the mouse pointer changes its shape to indicate that the
        link can be followed and a tooltip presents the destination location. Click a followable
        link to open the referred resource in an editor. The same effect can be obtained by using
        the action <uicontrol>Open file at caret</uicontrol> when the caret is in a followable link
        element.</p>
      <p>To position the cursor at the beginning or at the end of the document you can use
          <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_home"/>, and
          <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_end"/>
        respectively.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>