<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-customize-smart-paste">
  <title>Customizing Smart Paste Support</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Customize Smart Paste</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <term>Smart Paste</term> feature preserves certain style and structure information when
      copying content from some of the most common applications and pasting into <xref
        href="smart-paste-support.dita#smart-paste-support/doc-types-sp-p">document types that
        support Smart Paste</xref> in <ph keyref="product"/>. For other document types, the default
      behavior of the paste operation is to keep only the text content without the styling.</p>
    <p>The style of the pasted content can be customized by editing an XSLT stylesheet for the
      particular document type. The XSLT stylesheet must accept an XHTML flavor of the copied
      content as input, and transform it to the equivalent XML markup that is appropriate for the
      target document type of the paste operation.</p>
    <p>A default XSLT stylesheet that can be edited to customize the mapping between the markup of
      the copied content and the markup of the pasted content is included the following directory
      for each supported document type: <filepath>[OXYGEN INSTALLATION
        DIRECTORY]/frameworks/[Document Type]/resources</filepath>. The name of this default XSLT
      file begins with <filepath>xhtml2</filepath>, followed by the document type (for example,
        <filepath>xhtml2dita.xsl</filepath> for the DITA document type). </p>
    <example>
      <title>The Default Stylesheet for DITA Document Type</title>
      <p>To customize the mapping for a DITA topic, edit the <filepath>[OXYGEN INSTALLATION
          DIRECTORY]/frameworks/dita/resources/xhtml2dita.xsl</filepath> stylesheet. To test the
        modifications done in the stylesheet, you can start pasting content without having to
        restart <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
    </example>
    <p>
      <note><ph keyref="product"/> implements the Smart Paste feature by <xref
          keyref="customize_extensions-bundle" format="dita">setting up</xref> a stylesheet which is
        obtained by <ph keyref="product"/> from the <apiname>getImporterStylesheetFileName</apiname>
        method. This method is available in an instance of <xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Editor/SDK/javadoc/ro/sync/ecss/extensions/api/AuthorExternalObjectInsertionHandler.html"
          format="html" scope="external">the <apiname>AuthorExternalObjectInsertionHandler</apiname>
          class</xref>, which is returned by the
          <apiname>createExternalObjectInsertionHandler</apiname> method of <xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Editor/SDK/javadoc/ro/sync/ecss/extensions/api/ExtensionsBundle.html"
          format="html" scope="external">the <apiname>ExtensionsBundle</apiname> instance</xref> of
        the target document type.</note>
    </p>
  </body>
  <related-links product="editor author authorEclipse editorEclipse">
    <link href="smart-paste-support.dita#smart-paste-support"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
