<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-devel-guide-intro">
  <title>Author Developer Guide</title>
  <body>
    <p>The Author editor of <ph keyref="product"/> was
      designed to bridge the gap between the XML source editing and a friendly user interface. The
      main achievement is the fact that the Author combines the power of source editing with the
      intuitive interface of a text editor. </p>
    <p>This guide is targeted at advanced authors who want to customize the Author editing
      environment and is included both as a chapter in the <ph keyref="product"/> user manual and as a
      separate document in <xref
        href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen_sdk.html#XML_Editor_Authoring_SDK" format="html"
        scope="external">the Author SDK</xref>.</p>
    <fig product="editor author authorSDK">
      <title><ph keyref="product"/> Author Visual
        Editor</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_perspective.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title><ph keyref="product"/> Author Visual
        Editor</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_author_frame.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>Although <ph keyref="product"/> comes with
      already configured frameworks for DocBook, DITA, TEI, XHTML, you might need to create a
      customization of the editor to handle other types of documents. The common use case is when
      your organization holds a collection of XML document types used to define the structure of
      internal documents and they need to be visually edited by people with no experience in working
      with XML files.</p>
    <p>There are several ways to customize the editor:</p>
    <ol>
      <li>Create a CSS file defining styles for the XML elements the user will work with, and create
        XML files that refer the CSS through an <codeph>xml-stylesheet</codeph> processing
        instruction.</li>
      <li>Fully configure a document type association. This involves putting together the CSSs, the
        XML schemes, actions, menus, etc, bundling them and distributing an archive. The CSS and the
        GUI elements are settings of the <ph
          keyref="product"/> Author. The other
        settings like the templates, catalogs, transformation scenarios are general settings and are
        enabled whenever the association is active, no matter the editing mode (Text, Grid or
        Author).</li>
    </ol>
    <p>Both approaches will be discussed in the following sections.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
