<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-change-tracking">
  <title>Review</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>change tracking</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section id="change-tracking">
      <title>Tracking Document Changes</title>
      <p><uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> is a way to keep track of the changes you make to a
        document. To activate track changes for the current document, either choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> or click the <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> button on the
          <uicontrol>Author Review</uicontrol> toolbar. When <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> is
        enabled, your modifications are highlighted using a distinctive color. The name of the
        author who is currently making changes and the colors can be customized from the <xref
          href="preferences-track-changes.dita">Review</xref> preferences page.</p>
      <fig>
        <title>Change Tracking in Author Mode</title>
        <image href="../img/author_track_changes.png"/>
      </fig>
      <p>When hovering a change the tooltip displays information about the author and modification
        time.  </p>
      <p><uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> highlights textual changes and also changes that you
        make to the attributes in a document. The following table offers you a detailed view of the
        tracked and untracked changes:</p>
      <simpletable frame="all" relcolwidth="1.0* 1.0*">
        <sthead>
          <stentry>Tracked Changes</stentry>
          <stentry>Untracked Changes</stentry>
        </sthead>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Inserting, deleting content (text or elements)</stentry>
          <stentry>Performing a <b>Split</b> operation</stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Drag and drop content (text or elements)</stentry>
          <stentry>Performing a <uicontrol>Surround with</uicontrol> operation</stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Cutting, or pasting content (text or elements)</stentry>
          <stentry/>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Inserting, deleting and changing the structure of tables </stentry>
          <stentry/>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Inserting and editing lists and their content</stentry>
          <stentry/>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Inserting and deleting entities</stentry>
          <stentry/>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Deleting element tags</stentry>
          <stentry/>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry>Editing attributes</stentry>
          <stentry/>
        </strow>
      </simpletable>
      <p>If the selection in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> contains track changes and you are
        copying it, the clipboard contains the selection with all the <i>accepted</i> changes. This
        filtering is performed only if the selection is not entirely inside a tracked change. The
        changes are stored in the document as processing instructions and they do not interfere with
        validating and transforming it. For each change the author name and the modification time
        are preserved. The following processing instructions are examples of storing
          <term>insert</term> and <term>delete</term> changes in the document: <ul
          id="ul_5b2_vdm_gd">
          <li><codeph>&lt;?oxy_insert_start author="John Doe"
              timestamp="20090408T164459+0300"?>all&lt;?oxy_insert_end?></codeph></li>
          <li><codeph>&lt;?oxy_delete author="John Doe" timestamp="20090508T164459+0300"
              content="belong"?></codeph></li>
        </ul></p>
      <note>The <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view is synchronized with the <uicontrol>Track
          Changes</uicontrol>. Deleted content is rendered with a strike through in the
          <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view. </note>
    </section>
    <section id="author-comments">
      <title>Adding Document Comments</title>
      <p>You can associate a note or a comment to a selected area of content. Comments can highlight
        virtually any content from your document, except <i>read-only</i> text. The difference
        between such comments and change tracking is that a comment can be associated to an area of
        text without modifying or deleting the text. </p>
      <p>The actions for managing comments are <uicontrol>Add Comment</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Edit
          Comment</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Delete Comment</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Manage
          Comments</uicontrol> and are available on the <uicontrol>Author Review</uicontrol> toolbar
        and on the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> submenu of the contextual menu of Author
        editor.</p>
      <note type="tip">The comments are stored in the document as processing instructions containing
        information about the author name and the comment time:
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;?oxy_comment_start author="John Doe" timestamp="20090508T164459+0300" comment="Do not change this content"?>
    Important content
&lt;?oxy_comment_end?></codeblock></note>
      <p>Comments are persistent highlights with a colored background. The background color is
        customizable or can be assigned automatically by the application. This behavior can be
        controlled from the <xref href="preferences-track-changes.dita#preferences-track-changes"
          format="dita">Review preferences page</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <note><ph keyref="product"/> presents the tracked changes in DITA conrefs and XInclude
      fragments.</note>
  </body>
</topic>

