<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-displaying-referenced-content">
  <title>Displaying Referenced Content</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Displaying referenced
          content</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Displaying referenced content in Author mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The references to entities, XInclude, and DITA conrefs are expanded by default in
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and the referenced content is displayed. You can control
      this behavior from the <xref href="preferences-author.dita">Author preferences page</xref>.
      The referenced resources are loaded and displayed inside the element or entity that refers
      them, however the displayed content cannot be modified directly.</p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editor author">
        <title>XInclude reference</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_author_expanded_xinclude.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editor author">
        <title>External entity reference</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_author_expanded_external_entity.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>When the referenced resource cannot be resolved, an error will be presented inside the
      element that refers them instead of the content.</p>
    <p>If you want to make modifications to the referenced content, you must open the referenced
      resource in an editor. The referenced resource can be opened quickly by clicking the link
      (marked with the <image href="../img/link.png" id="image_epw_jjf_wr"/> icon) that is displayed
      before the referenced content or by using the <uicontrol>Edit Reference</uicontrol> action
      from the contextual menu (in this case the cursor is placed at the precise location where the
      action was invoked in the main file). The referenced resource is resolved through the <xref
        keyref="glossentry_xml-catalog"><term>XML Catalog</term></xref> set in
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The referenced content is refreshed:<ul>
        <li>Automatically, when it is modified and saved from <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
        <li>On demand, by using the <xref href="author-editing-refreshing.dita">Refresh references
            action</xref>. Useful when the referenced content is modified outside the <ph
            keyref="product"/> scope.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
