<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-displaying-referred-content">
  <title>Displaying Referred Content</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>external references</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The references to entities, XInclude, and DITA conrefs are expanded by default in Author mode
      and the referred content is displayed. You can control this behavior from the <xref
        href="preferences-author.dita">Author preferences page</xref>. The referred resources are
      loaded and displayed inside the element or entity that refers them, however the displayed
      content cannot be modified directly.</p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>XInclude reference</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_expanded_xinclude.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>External entity reference</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_expanded_external_entity.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>When the referred resource cannot be resolved, an error will be presented inside the element
      that refers them instead of the content.</p>
    <p>If you want to make modifications to the referred content, you must open the referred
      resource in an editor. The referred resource can be opened quickly by clicking the link
      (marked with the icon <image href="../img/author_link.png"/> ) which is displayed before the
      referred content or by using the <uicontrol>Edit Reference</uicontrol> action from the
      contextual menu (in this case the caret is placed at the precise location where the action was
      invoked in the main file). The referred resource is resolved through the XML Catalog set in
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The referred content is refreshed:<ul>
        <li>automatically, when it is modified and saved from <ph
            keyref="product"/>;</li>
        <li>on demand, by using the <xref href="author-editing-refreshing.dita">Refresh references
            action</xref>. Useful when the referred content is modified outside the <ph
            keyref="product"/> scope.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
