<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-callouts">
  <title>Author Callouts</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>change
            tracking<indexterm>callouts</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>A <term>callout</term> is a vertical stripe, with a balloon-like look, that <ph
        keyref="product"/> displays in the right side
      of the editing area. Callouts are decorated with a colored border and also have a colored
      background. A horizontal line, which has the same color as the border, connects text fragments
      with their corresponding callouts. <ph
        keyref="product"/> assigns an individual
      color for the callouts depending on the user who is editing the document. To customize the
      list of these colors, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Edit Modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Review</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. You are able to add, edit, or remove colors in this list. You can choose to
      use the same color for any user who modifies the content or inserts a comment. To do this,
      select the <uicontrol>fixed</uicontrol> option and choose a color from the color box. Once you
      set a fixed color for a user you are able to edit it. Press the color box and select a
      different color from the <uicontrol>Choose color</uicontrol> dialog box.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> uses callouts to
      provide an enhanced view of the changes you, or other authors make to a document. They hold
      specific information depending on their type. In addition, <ph
        keyref="product"/> uses callouts to display
        <term>comments</term> that you associate with fragments of the document you are editing. For
      more information about editing comments, go to <xref
        href="author-managing-comments.dita#author-managing-comments" format="dita">Managing
        Comments</xref>. To enable callouts, go to <xref href="callouts-preferences-page.dita"
        format="dita"><menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Edit Modes</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Author</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Review</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Callouts</uicontrol>
        </menucascade></xref>. Enable the following options:<ul id="ul_cnh_fzl_xf">
        <li><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> - <ph
            keyref="product"/> displays comment
          callouts when you insert a comment. You can use two types of comments in <ph
            keyref="product"/>:<ul id="ul_kyg_yyf_2g">
            <li>author review comments: comments that you associate with specific fragments of text; </li>
            <li>change comments: comments that you add in an already existing insertion or deletion
              callout. </li>
          </ul> By default, the fragment of text that you comment is highlighted and a horizontal
          line connects it with the comment callout. A comment callout contains the name of the
          author who inserts the callout and the comment itself. To customize the content of a
          comment callout and display the date and time of its insertion, go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Edit Modes</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Author</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Review</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Callouts</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> and enable <uicontrol>Show review time</uicontrol>;</li>
      </ul><fig>
        <title>Comment Callouts</title>
        <image id="image_t1m_4km_zf" href="../img/comment_callout.png"/>
      </fig><ul id="ul_ns4_w3m_zf">
        <li><uicontrol>Track Changes deletions</uicontrol> - <ph
            keyref="product"/> displays deletion
          callouts when you delete a fragment of text. By default, a deletion callout contains the
          type of callout (<term>Deleted</term>) and the name of the author that makes the deletion.
          You are able to customize the content of a deletion callout to display the date and time
          of the deletion and the deleted fragment itself. To do this, go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Edit Modes</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Author</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Review</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Callouts</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> and enable <uicontrol>Show review time</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Show
            deleted content in callout</uicontrol>;</li>
      </ul><fig>
        <title>Deletion Callouts</title>
        <image id="image_phx_rkm_zf" href="../img/deletion_callout.png"/>
      </fig><ul id="ul_4dd_qkm_zf">
        <li><uicontrol>Track Changes insertions</uicontrol> - <ph
            keyref="product"/> displays insertion
          callouts when you insert a fragment of text. By default, an insertion callout contains the
          type of callout (<term>Inserted</term>) and the name of the author that makes the
          insertion. You are able to customize the content of an insertion callout to contain the
          date and time of the insertion and the inserted fragment itself. To do this, go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Edit Modes</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Author</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Review</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Callouts</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> and enable <uicontrol>Show review time</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Show
            inserted content in callout</uicontrol>.</li>
      </ul><fig>
        <title>Insertion Callouts</title>
        <image id="image_5x2_t4m_zf" href="../img/insertion_callouts.png"/>
      </fig></p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Multiple Authors Callouts</title>
        <image id="image_p4h_wqm_2g" href="../img/multiple_authors_callouts.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p><note><ph keyref="product"/> displays callouts only if <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/TrackChangesFinalWithChanges20.png" id="image_n4k_ksp_yf"/>View All
          Changes/Comments</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>View Only Changes/Comments by</uicontrol> is
        selected. <ph keyref="product"/> does not display callouts in <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/TrackChangesFinal20.png" id="image_3c4_4sp_yf"/>View Final</uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/TrackChangesOriginal20.png" id="image_sk2_psp_yf"/>View
          Original</uicontrol> modes. </note>To select a callout, either click the callout or its
      source. Selected callouts have a more intense background and a bold border. The connecting
      line between the source and the callout is also rendered in bold font. If you select a
      fragment of text which is associated with one or more callouts, the callouts are
      highlighted.</p>
    <p>
      <note type="important">The callouts are displayed in the right side of the editing area.
        However, in some cases, the text you are editing can span into the callouts area. For
        example, this situation can appear for callouts associated with wide images or
        space-preserve elements (like <term>codeblock</term> in DITA or <term>programlisting</term>
        in DocBook) which contain long fragments. To help you view the text under the covered area,
          <ph keyref="product"/> applies transparency to these callouts. When the caret is located
        under a callout, the transparency is enhanced, allowing you to both edit the covered content
        and access the contextual menu of the editing area.<fig>
          <title>Transparent Callout</title>
          <image href="../img/transparent_callout.png"/>
        </fig></note>
    </p>
    <p>
      <note><ph keyref="product"/> does not display
        callouts located in folded areas of the edited document.</note>
    </p>
    <p>The following actions are available in the contextual menu of an insertion, or deletion
      callout: <ul id="ul_smd_d1g_2g">
        <li><uicontrol>Accept Change</uicontrol> - select this option to accept the changes you or
          other authors make to a document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Reject Change</uicontrol> - select this option to reject the changes you or
          other authors make to a document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Comment Change</uicontrol> - select this option to comment an existing change
          in your document. You are also able to add a comment to a change from the
            <uicontrol>Comment Change<image id="image_jjy_lcg_2g" href="../img/comment_change.png"
            /></uicontrol> button available on the <uicontrol>Author Review</uicontrol> toolbar; </li>
        <li><ph id="edit-reference-callout"><uicontrol>Edit Reference</uicontrol> - in case the
            fragment that contains callouts is a reference, use this option to go to the reference
            and edit the callout</ph>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Callouts Options</uicontrol> - select this option to open the <xref
            href="callouts-preferences-page.dita#callouts-preferences-page">preferences page</xref>
          of the callouts. </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The following options are available in the contextual menu of the comment callouts:<ul
        id="ul_kh2_wcg_2g">
        <li><uicontrol>Edit Comment</uicontrol> - select this option to modify the content of a
          comment callout;<note>The text area is disabled if you are not the author which inserted
            the comment. </note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove Comment</uicontrol> - select this option to remove a comment
          callout;</li>
        <li><ph conref="#author-callouts/edit-reference-callout"/>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Callouts Options</uicontrol> - select this option to open the <xref
            href="callouts-preferences-page.dita#callouts-preferences-page">preferences page</xref>
          of the callouts. </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>When you print a document from <ph keyref="product"/>, all callouts you, or other authors
      added to the document are printed. For a preview of the document and its callouts, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Print preview...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the Callouts support, go to <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/CalloutsSupport.html" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://oxygenxml.com/demo/CalloutsSupport.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
