<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-editing-markup">
  <title>Editing the XML Markup</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>edit
    markup</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>One of the most useful feature in Author editor is the content completion support. The
      fastest way to invoke it is to press <uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/enter"/> or <uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_space"/> in the editor
      panel.</p>
    <p>Content completion window offers the following types of actions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>inserting allowed elements for the current context according to the associated schema, if
        any;</li>
      <li>inserting element values if such values are specified in the schema for the current
        context;</li>
      <li>inserting new undeclared elements by entering their name in the text field;</li>
      <li>inserting CDATA sections, comments, processing instructions;</li>
      <li>inserting <xref href="../topics/code-templates.dita#code-templates" format="dita">code
          templates</xref>.</li>
      <li>if the <uicontrol>Show all possible elements in the content completion list</uicontrol>
        option from the <xref href="preferences-schema-aware.dita">Schema aware preferences
          page</xref> is enabled, the content completion pop-up window will present all the elements
        defined by the schema. When choosing an element from this section, the insertion will be
        performed using the schema aware smart editing features.</li>
    </ul>
    <fig>
      <title>Content completion window</title>
      <image href="../img/bt_author_content_completion.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>If you press <uicontrol>
        <shortcut>(Enter)</shortcut></uicontrol> the displayed content completion window will
      contain as first entries the <uicontrol>Split &lt;Element name&gt;</uicontrol> items. Usually
      you can only split the closest block element to the caret position but if it is inside a list
      item, the list item will also be proposed for split. Selecting <uicontrol>Split &lt;Element
        name&gt;</uicontrol> splits the content of the specified element around the caret position.
      Thus, if the caret is positioned at the beginning or at the end of the element, the newly
      created sibling will be empty.</p>
    <p>If the caret is positioned inside a space preserve element the first choice in the content
      completion window is <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> which inserts a new line in the content of
      the element. If there is a selection in the editor and you invoke content completion, a
        <uicontrol>Surround with</uicontrol> operation can be performed. The tag used will be the
      selected item from the content completion window.</p>
    <p>By default you are not allowed to insert element names which are not defined by the schema.
      This can be changed by unchecking the <uicontrol>Allow only insertion of valid elements and
        attributes</uicontrol> check box from the <xref href="preferences-schema-aware.dita">Schema
        aware preferences page</xref>.<note>The content completion list of proposals contains
        elements depending on the elements inserted both before and after the caret position.
      </note></p>
    <p><b>Joining two elements</b> - You can choose to join the content of two sibling elements with
      the same name by using the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>contextual menu</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Join elements</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action.</p>
    <p>The same action can be triggered also in the next situations:<ul>
        <li>The caret is located before the end position of the first element and <uicontrol>
            <shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
        <li>The caret is located after the end position of the first element and <uicontrol>
            <shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
        <li>The caret is located before the start position of the second element and <uicontrol>
            <shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
        <li>The caret is located after the start position of the second element and <uicontrol>
            <shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>In either of the described cases, if the element has no sibling or the sibling element has a
      different name, <uicontrol>Unwrap</uicontrol> operation will be performed automatically.</p>
    <p><b>Unwrapping the content of an element</b> - You can unwrap the content of an element by
      deleting its tags using the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Delete element tags</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action from the editor contextual menu.</p>
    <p>The same action can be triggered in the next situations: </p>
    <ul>
      <li>The caret is located before the start position of the element and <uicontrol>
          <shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
      <li>The caret is located after the start position of the element and <uicontrol>
          <shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
      <li>The caret is located before the end position of the element and <uicontrol>
          <shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
      <li>The caret is located after the end position of the element and <uicontrol>
          <shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed.</li>
    </ul>
    <p><b>Removing all the markup of an element</b> - You can remove the markup of the current
      element and keep only the text content with the action <uicontrol>
        <image href="../img/bt_remove_all_markup.png"/>Remove All Markup </uicontrol> available on
      the submenu <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> of the contextual menu and on the toolbar
        <uicontrol>XML Refactoring</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>When you press <uicontrol>
        <shortcut>(Delete)</shortcut></uicontrol> or <uicontrol>
        <shortcut>(Backspace)</shortcut></uicontrol> in the presented cases the element is unwrapped
      or it is joined with its sibling. If the current element is empty, the element tags will be
      deleted.</p>
    <p>When you click on a marker representing the start or end tag of an element, the entire
      element will be selected. The contextual menu displayed when you right-click on the marker
      representing the start or end tag of an element contains <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>,
        <uicontrol>Insert Before</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Insert After</uicontrol> submenus as
      first entries.</p>
  </body>
</topic>