<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author_adding_images">
  <title>Inserting Images</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Inserting images</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Inserting
              images</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Insert images in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To insert an image in a document while editing in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, use one
      of the following methods:<ul>
        <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Image16.gif" id="image_gqz_lzy_tr"/>Insert
            Image</uicontrol> action from the toolbar. This opens a dialog box that allows you to
          choose the image file you want to insert and configure some properties. <ph
            keyref="product"/> tries to reference the image with a path that is relative to that of
          the document you are currently editing. For example, if you want to add the
            <codeph>file:/C:/project/xml/dir/img1.jpg</codeph> image into the
            <codeph>file:/C:/project/xml/doc1.xml</codeph> document, <ph keyref="product"/> inserts
          a reference to <codeph>dir/img1.jpg</codeph>. This is useful when multiple users work on a
          common project and they have it stored in multiple locations. <note>The <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/Image16.gif" id="image_wr2_mzy_tr"/>Insert Image</uicontrol> action is
            available for the following document types: DITA, DocBook, TEI, XHTML, JATS.</note></li>
        <li>Drag an image from other application and drop it in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
          editing mode. If it is an image file, it is inserted as a reference to the image file. For
          example, in a DITA topic the path of the image file is inserted as the value of the
            <codeph>href</codeph> attribute in an <codeph>image</codeph>
            element:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;image href="../images/image_file.png"/></codeblock><note
            type="tip">To replace an image, just drag and drop a new image over the existing one.
              <ph keyref="product"/> will automatically update the reference to the new
            image.</note></li>
        <li>Copy an image file from another document or another application (such as a system file
          browser or web browser) and paste it into your document. <ph keyref="product"/> will
          insert it as a reference to the image file the same as the drag/drop method.</li>
        <li>Select an image (or part of an image) from another application (such as an image
          editor), copy it, and paste it into your document. <ph keyref="product"/> will prompt you
          to save it. After saving the image, a reference to that file path is inserted at the paste
          position.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="image-map-editor.dita#image-map-editor"/><link href="author-image-rendering.dita">
      <linktext>Image Rendering in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> Mode</linktext>
    </link><link href="dita-adding-media.dita#dita-adding-media"/></linklist>
    
    
  </related-links>
</topic>
