<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-navigate-document-content">
  <title>Navigating the Document Content in Author Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Navigation</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode
            editing<indexterm>Navigation</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Navigation in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes some useful features to help you navigate XML documents.</p>
    <section id="using_the_keyboard">
      <title>Using the Keyboard</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to quickly navigate through a document using the
          <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/tab"/> key to move the cursor to the
        next XML node and <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/shift_tab"/> to go to
        the previous one. If you encounter a <xref keyref="glossentry_space-preserved-element"
            ><term>space-preserved element</term></xref> when you navigate through a document and
        you do not press another key, pressing the <uicontrol
          conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/tab"/> key will continue the navigation.
        However, if the cursor is positioned in a <term>space-preserved element</term> and you press
        another key or you position the cursor inside such an element using the mouse, the
          <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/tab"/> key can be used to arrange the
        text.</p>
      <p>To navigate one word forward or backwards, use <uicontrol
          conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_right_arrow"/>, and <uicontrol
          conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_left_arrow"/>, respectively. Entities and
        hidden elements are skipped. To position the cursor at the beginning or at the end of the
        document you can use <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_home"/>, and
          <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_end"/>, respectively.</p>
    </section>
    <section product="author editor" id="navigation_buttons">
      <title>Navigation Buttons</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes some actions that help you to quickly navigate to a
        particular modification. These navigation buttons are available in the main toolbar and the
        actions can also be accessed from the <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol> menu. The three actions
        include:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/GoToLastModification24.png" id="image_hwx_xz2_wr"/>Last
            Modification</uicontrol> - Moves the cursor to the last modification in any opened
          document. </li>
        <li>
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/GoBack24.png" id="image_dmz_wz2_wr"/>Back</uicontrol> -
          Moves the cursor to the previous position. </li>
        <li>
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/GoForward24.png" id="image_krm_xz2_wr"/>Forward</uicontrol>
          - Moves the cursor to the next position after the <uicontrol>Back</uicontrol> button has
          been used at least once. </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section product="authorEclipse editorEclipse" id="navigation_shortcuts">
      <title>Navigation Shortcuts</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes some keyboard shortcuts to help you quickly navigate to a
        particular modification. They are also available as actions in the
          <uicontrol>Navigation</uicontrol> menu.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+Q</shortcut> - Last Edit Location</uicontrol> - Moves the cursor
          to the last modification in any opened document. </li>
        <li>
          <uicontrol><shortcut>Alt+LeftArrow (Command+OpenBracket on OS X)</shortcut> -
            Back</uicontrol> - Moves the cursor to the previous position. </li>
        <li>
          <uicontrol><shortcut>Alt+RightArrow (Command+CloseBracket on OS X)</shortcut> -
            Forward</uicontrol> - Moves the cursor to the next position.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="navigating_with_the_outline_view">
      <title>Navigating with the Outline View</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a very useful <xref
          href="author-outline-view.dita#author-outline-view"><uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol>
          view</xref> that displays a hierarchical tag overview of the currently edited XML
        Document.</p>
      <p>You can use this view to quickly navigate through the current document by selecting nodes
        in the outline tree. It is synchronized with the editor area, so when you make a selection
        in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view, the corresponding nodes are highlighted in the
        editor area.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Outline View Navigation in Author Mode</title>
          <image href="../img/outline-view-navigation.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="using_the_breadcrumb_to_navigate">
      <title>Using the Breadcrumb to Navigate</title>
      <p>A <i>breadcrumb</i> on the top stripe indicates the path from document root to the current
        element. It can also be used as a helpful tool to navigate to specific elements throughout
        the structure of the document. </p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Breadcrumb in Author Mode</title>
          <image href="../img/author_top_stripe.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The last element listed in the <term>breadcrumb</term> is the element at the current cursor
        position. The last element is also highlighted by a thin light blue bar for easier
        identification. Clicking an element from the <term>breadcrumb</term> selects the entire
        element and navigates to it in the editor area. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="using_the_linking_support">
      <title>Using the Linking Support</title>
      <p>When working on multiple documents that reference each other (references, external
        entities, XInclude, DITA conref, etc), the <b>linking support</b> is useful for navigating
        between the documents. In the predefined customizations that are bundled with <ph
          keyref="product"/>, links are marked with an icon representing a chain link (<image
          href="../img/link.png" id="image_x3b_jjf_wr"/>). When hovering over the icon, the mouse
        pointer changes its shape to indicate that the link can be accessed and a tooltip presents
        the destination location. Click the link to open the referenced resource in the editor or
        system browser. <ph product="author editor">The same effect can be obtained by using the <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Open file at cursor (<shortcut
                conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_enter_shortcut"/>)</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> action when the cursor is inside a link element.</ph><ph
          product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">The same effect can be obtained by pressing the
            <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/F3"/> key when the cursor is in a
          link element.</ph><note>Depending on the referenced file type, the target link will either
          be opened in the <ph keyref="product"/> or in the default system application. If the
          target file does not exist, <ph keyref="product"/> prompts you to create it.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section product="author editor" id="navigating_with_bookmarks">
      <title>Navigating with Bookmarks</title>
      <p>A position in a document can be marked with a bookmark. You can then quickly go to the
        marked position with a keyboard shortcut or a menu action. This is useful when navigating
        large documents or working on multiple documents where the cursor needs to move between
        several marked positions. The bookmarks are displayed with a small icon on the vertical
        strip to the left of the editor. You can place up to nine distinct bookmarks in any
        document. Shortcut keys are available to place the bookmarks or to return to any of the
        marked positions. You can configure these shortcut keys in the <xref
          href="preferences-menu-shortcut-keys.dita#preferences-menu-shortcut-keys"><menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Menu Shortcut Keys</uicontrol>
          </menucascade></xref> menu.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_wx1_hz4_2r">
          <title>Editor Bookmarks</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_editor_bookmarks_author.png" id="image_bz1_hz4_2r"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>A bookmark can be inserted in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode by doing one of the
          following:<ul id="ul_u3z_jdk_2r">
          <li>Click in the vertical stripe on the left side of the editor.</li>
          <li>Select the <uicontrol><image href="../img/BookMark16.gif" id="image_bsj_tpz_vr"
              />Create Bookmark <shortcut>(F9)</shortcut></uicontrol> action from the <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Bookmarks</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>A bookmark can be removed by right-clicking its icon on the vertical stripe and select
          <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Remove all (Ctrl+F7 (Command+F7 on OS
          X))</uicontrol>.</p>
      <p>You can navigate the bookmarks by using one of the actions available on the <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Bookmarks</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Go to</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> menu or by using the shortcut keys that are listed in that menu.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
