<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-dita-extensions">
    <title>DITA Author Actions</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>DITA Topics Document Type<indexterm>Author extensions</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>The following default actions are available in the <uicontrol>DITA (Author Custom
        Actions)</uicontrol> toolbar:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry id="bold-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Bold16.gif" id="image_tys_tjx_sr"/>Bold</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Surrounds the selected text with a <codeph>b</codeph> tag. You can use this action on
          multiple non-contiguous selections.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="italic-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Italic16.png" id="image_kbn_3xx_sr"
          />Italic</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Surrounds the selected text with an <codeph>i</codeph> tag. You can use this action on
          multiple non-contiguous selections.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="underline-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Underline16.gif" id="image_hr3_vxx_sr"
            />Underline</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Surrounds the selected text with a <codeph>u</codeph> tag. You can use this action on
          multiple non-contiguous selections.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/LinkDrop.png" id="image_rng_tkx_sr"/>Link</uicontrol>
          Actions Drop-Down List</dt>
        <dd>
          <p>The following link actions are available from this list:<ul id="ul_kqs_bhb_2r">
              <li><uicontrol>Cross Reference</uicontrol> - Depending on the context where it is
                invoked, the action inserts one of the following two elements:<ul id="ul_tx4_ggb_2r">
                  <li><codeph>xref</codeph> element, with the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set
                    to <codeph>dita</codeph></li>
                  <li><codeph>fragref</codeph> element, which is a specialization of the
                      <codeph>xref</codeph> element<note>Both elements point to their target using
                      the <codeph>href</codeph> attribute</note></li>
                </ul>The referenced target is selected in a dialog box that lists all the IDs
                extracted from the selected file. When you select an ID, you can preview the content
                in the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> tab or the XML source in the
                  <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> tab. In case you have a large number of IDs in the
                target document, use the <uicontrol>Filter</uicontrol> field to search through the
                IDs. <fig product="editor author" id="fig_ux4_ggb_2r">
                  <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
                  <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_xref.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_ibp_ggb_2r"/>
                </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_xbp_ggb_2r">
                  <title>Insert a Cross Reference in a DITA Document</title>
                  <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_xref.png" placement="inline"
                    id="image_nfp_ggb_2r"/>
                </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The
                  dialog is closed automatically in case you switch to a different
                editor.</note></li>
              <li><uicontrol>Key Reference</uicontrol> - Inserts a user specified element with the
                value of the <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set to a specific key name. As stated
                in the DITA 1.2 specification, keys are defined at map level and referenced
                afterwards. You are able to select the target of the <codeph>keyref</codeph> element
                in the <uicontrol>Insert Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog box. <note>The
                    <uicontrol>Insert Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog box presents the list of keys
                  available in the current DITA Map. If the DITA Map is not opened in the
                    <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view, the <uicontrol>Insert Key
                    Reference</uicontrol> dialog does not display any keys. </note><p>You can also
                  reference elements at sub-topic level by pressing the
                    <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol> button and choosing the target.</p>All keys
                which are presented in the dialog are gathered from the current opened DITA map.
                Elements which have the <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed as
                links. The current opened DITA map is also used to resolve references when
                navigating <codeph>keyref</codeph> links in the Author mode. Image elements which
                use key references are rendered as images.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>File Reference</uicontrol> - Inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element
                with the value of attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to
                <codeph>xml</codeph>.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Web Link</uicontrol> - Inserts an <codeph>xref</codeph> element with
                the value of attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph>, and
                  <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph>.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Related Link to Topic</uicontrol> - Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
                element inside a <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Related Link to File</uicontrol> - Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
                element with the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set to <codeph>xml</codeph>
                inside a <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Related Link to Web Page</uicontrol> - Inserts a <codeph>link</codeph>
                element with the attribute <codeph>format</codeph> set to <codeph>html</codeph> and
                  <codeph>scope</codeph> set to <codeph>external</codeph> inside a
                  <codeph>related-links</codeph> parent. </li>
            </ul></p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="insert-image-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Image16.gif" id="image_lqj_f1z_tr"/>Insert Image
            Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Insert Image</uicontrol> dialog that allows you to configure the
          properties of an image to be inserted into a DITA document at the caret position.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertSectionDrop.png" id="image_i2d_31z_tr"/>Insert
            Section</uicontrol> Drop-Down List</dt>
        <dd>The following link actions are available from this list:<ul id="ul_a21_13b_2r">
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Section16.gif" id="image_btp_v1z_tr"/>Insert
                Section</uicontrol> - Inserts a new section / step in the document, depending on the
              current context. A new section will be inserted in either one of the following
              contexts: <ul id="ul_ikp_ggb_2r">
                <li>section context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element or one of its ancestors contains <codeph>topic</codeph> or
                    <codeph>section</codeph>.</li>
                <li>topic's body context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element contains <codeph>topic/body</codeph>. </li>
              </ul><p>A new step will be inserted in either one of the following contexts: </p><ul
                id="ul_inp_ggb_2r">
                <li>task step context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element or one of its ancestors contains <codeph>task/step</codeph>.</li>
                <li>task steps context, when the value of <codeph>class</codeph> attribute of the
                  current element contains <codeph>task/steps</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertConcept16.gif" id="image_qxk_qcz_tr"/>Insert
                Concept</uicontrol> - Inserts a new concept. Concepts provide background information
              that users must know before they can successfully work with a product or interface.
              This action is available in one of the following contexts: <ul id="ul_czr_d3b_2r">
                <li>concept context, one of the current element ancestors is a
                    <codeph>concept</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
                  inserted after the current <codeph>concept</codeph>.</li>
                <li>concept or DITA context, current element is a <codeph>concept</codeph> or
                    <codeph>dita</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
                  inserted at current caret position.</li>
                <li>DITA topic context, current element is a <codeph>topic</codeph> child of a
                    <codeph>dita</codeph> element. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph>
                  will be inserted at current caret position.</li>
                <li>DITA topic context, one of the current element ancestors is a DITA
                    <codeph>topic</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>concept</codeph> will be
                  inserted after the first <codeph>topic</codeph> ancestor.</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertTask16.gif" id="image_hg5_qcz_tr"/>Insert
                Task</uicontrol> - Inserts a new task. Tasks are the main building blocks for
              task-oriented user assistance. They generally provide step-by-step instructions that
              will enable a user to perform a task. This action is available in one of the following
              contexts: <ul id="ul_qrp_ggb_2r">
                <li>task context, one of the current element ancestors is a <codeph>task</codeph>.
                  In this case an empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted after the last child
                  of the first <codeph>concept</codeph>'s ancestor.</li>
                <li>task context, the current element is a <codeph>task</codeph>. In this case an
                  empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted at current caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context, the current element is a <codeph>dita</codeph>
                  <codeph>topic</codeph>. An empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted at current
                  caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context, one of the current element ancestors is a <codeph>dita</codeph>
                  <codeph>topic</codeph>. An empty <codeph>task</codeph> will be inserted after the
                  last child of the first ancestor that is a <codeph>topic</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150223T113801+0200" comment="Insert content"?><uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/InsertTopic16.gif" id="image_d1z_fbz_tr"/>Insert Topic</uicontrol> -
              <?oxy_comment_end?></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertRef16.gif" id="image_rhf_rcz_tr"/>Insert
                Reference</uicontrol> - Inserts a new reference in the document. A reference is a
              top-level container for a reference topic. This action is available in one of the
              following contexts: <ul id="ul_esp_ggb_2r">
                <li>reference context - one of the current element ancestors is a
                    <codeph>reference</codeph>. In this case an empty <codeph>reference</codeph>
                  will be inserted after the last child of the first ancestor that is a
                    <codeph>reference</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph>reference</codeph> or <codeph>dita</codeph> context - the current
                  element is either a <codeph>dita</codeph> or a <codeph>reference</codeph>. An
                  empty <codeph>reference</codeph> will be inserted at caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context - the current element is <codeph>topic</codeph> descendant of
                    <codeph>dita</codeph> element. An empty <codeph>reference</codeph> will be
                  inserted at caret position.</li>
                <li>topic context - the current element is descendant of <codeph>dita</codeph>
                  element and descendant of <codeph>topic</codeph> element. An empty
                    <codeph>reference</codeph> will be inserted after the last child of the first
                  ancestor that is a <codeph>topic</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></li>
          </ul></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="insert-para-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Paragraph16.gif" id="image_iv4_bfz_tr"/>Insert a new
            paragraph</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Insert a new paragraph at current cursor position.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="dita-insert-content-reference">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Conref16.png" id="image_h2y_rwx_sr"/>Insert DITA Content
            Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>
          <p>Inserts a content reference at the caret position.</p>
          <p>The DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of content
            fragments. The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute stores a reference to another element
            and is processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The
            element containing the content reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced
            element. The identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable
            in the context of the referencing element. See <xref
              href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.0/archspec/conref.html" scope="external"
              format="html">here</xref> for more details.</p>
          <p><ph keyref="product"/>
            <xref href="author-displaying-referenced-content.dita">displays the referenced
              content</xref> of a DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid
            resource. If you have URI's instead of local paths in the XML documents and your DITA OT
            transformation needs an XML catalog to map the URI's to local paths you have to <xref
              href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita">add the catalog to <ph keyref="product"/></xref>. If
            the URI's can be resolved the referenced content will be displayed in Author mode and in
            the transformation output.</p>
          <p>A content reference is inserted with the action <uicontrol>Insert a DITA Content
              Reference</uicontrol> available on the toolbar <uicontrol>Author custom
              actions</uicontrol> and on the menu <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</p>
          <fig product="editor author" id="fig_usp_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conref.png" placement="inline" id="image_jwp_ggb_2r"
            />
          </fig>
          <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_ywp_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conref.png" placement="inline" id="image_ebq_ggb_2r"
            />
          </fig>
          <note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The dialog
            is closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note>
          <p>In the URL chooser you set the URL of the file from which you want to reuse content.
            Depending on the <uicontrol>Target type</uicontrol> filter you will see a tree of
            elements which can be referenced (which have ID's). For each element the XML content is
            shown in the preview area. The <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> value is computed
            automatically for the selected tree element. After pressing
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>, an element with the same name as the target element and
            having the attribute <codeph>conref</codeph> with the value specified in the
              <uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> value field will be inserted at caret position.</p>
          <p>According to the DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute can be
            used to specify content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature when referencing
            multiple consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple contiguous sibling
            selection the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be set to the value of the last
            selected ID path. <ph keyref="product"/> will present the entire referenced range as
            read-only content.</p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="dita-insert-content-key-reference">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Conkeyref16.png" id="image_cnp_swx_sr"/>Insert Content
            Key Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a content key reference at the caret position. <p>As stated in the DITA 1.2
            specification the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of
            content fragments similar with the <codeph>conref</codeph> mechanism. Keys are defined
            at map level which can be referenced using <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>. The
              <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute contains a key reference to another element and
            is processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The element
            containing the content key reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced element.
            The identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable in the
            context of the referencing element.</p><p><ph keyref="product"/>
            <xref href="author-displaying-referenced-content.dita">displays the key referenced
              content</xref> of a DITA <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid
            resource in the context of the current opened DITA map.</p><p>A content key reference is
            inserted with the action <uicontrol>Insert a DITA Content Key Reference</uicontrol>
            available on the toolbar <uicontrol>Author custom actions</uicontrol> and on the menu <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</p><fig product="editor author" id="fig_ubq_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conkeyref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_jfq_ggb_2r"/>
          </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_zfq_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conkeyref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_ojq_ggb_2r"/>
          </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal.
            The dialog is closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note><p>To
            reference target elements at sub-topic level just press the
              <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol> button and choose the target.</p><p>According to the
            DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute can be used to specify
            content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature when referencing multiple
            consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple contiguous sibling selection for
            IDs at sub-topic level the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be set to the
            value of the last selected ID path. <ph keyref="product"/> will present the entire
            referenced range as read-only content.<note type="important">All keys which are
              presented in the dialog are gathered from the current opened DITA map. Elements which
              have the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed by default with the
              target content expanded. The current opened DITA map is also used to resolve
              references when navigating <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> links in the Author
            mode.</note></p></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="insert-list-item-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_list_item.png" id="image_xlq_qc1_fg"
              placement="inline"/>Insert a step or list item</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a new list or step item in the current list type.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="insert-ul-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_itemized_list.png" id="image_nmq_qc1_fg"
              placement="inline"/>Insert an unordered list at the caret position</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts an itemized list. A child list item is also automatically inserted by
          default.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="insert-ol-dlentry">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_ordered_list.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_f52_3jb_2r"/>Insert an ordered list at the caret position</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts an ordered list. A child list item is also automatically inserted by
          default.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Sort16.png" id="image_msv_5c2_fr"/>Sort</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Sorts a table selection.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="table_editing_actions_insert_table">
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Table16.png" id="image_t3c_chz_tr"/>Insert
            Table</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens a dialog that allows you to configure and insert a table. You can generate a
          header and footer, set the number of rows and columns of the table and decide how the
          table is framed.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableRow16.gif" id="image_w2h_ghz_tr"/>Insert
            Row</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a new table row with empty cells. This action is available when the caret is
          positioned inside a table.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableColumn16.gif" id="image_t5x_jhz_tr"/>Insert
            Column</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a new table column with empty cells after the current column. This action is
          available when the caret is positioned inside a table.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableCell16.gif" id="image_iwd_thz_tr"/>Insert
            Cell</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a new empty cell depending on the current context. If the caret is positioned
          between two cells, <ph keyref="product"/> a new cell at caret position. If the caret is
          inside a cell, the new cell is created after the current cell.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DeleteColumn16.gif" id="image_zbk_1gz_tr"/>Delete
            Column</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Deletes the table column located at caret position.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DeleteRow16.gif" id="image_y3t_1gz_tr"/>Delete
            Row</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Deletes the table row located at caret position.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableProperties16.png" id="image_psn_1jz_tr"/>Edit Table
            Properties</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Table properties</uicontrol> dialog that allows you to configure
          properties of a table (such as frame borders).</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableJoinSplitDrop.png" id="image_p2q_c3z_tr"/>Table
            Join/Split</uicontrol> Drop-Down List</dt>
        <dd>The following link actions are available from this list:<ul id="ul_kyv_1kb_2r">
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableJoinRowCells16.gif" id="image_itz_43z_tr"/>Join
                Row Cells</uicontrol> - Joins the content of the selected cells. The operation is
              available if the selected cells are from the same row and they have the same row span.
              The action is also available when the selection is missing, but the caret is
              positioned between two cells.</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableJoinCellUp16.gif" id="image_lcl_q3z_tr"/>Join
                Cell Above</uicontrol> - Joins the content of the cell from the current caret
              position with the content of the cell above it. This action works only if both cells
              have the same column span.</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableJoinCellDown16.gif" id="image_pk4_r3z_tr"/>Join
                Cell Below</uicontrol> - Joins the content of the cell from the current caret
              position with the content of the cell below it. This action works only if both cells
              have the same column span.<note>When you use <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/TableJoinCellUp16.gif" id="image_dhh_s3z_tr"/>Join Cell
                  Above</uicontrol> and <uicontrol><image href="../img/TableJoinCellDown16.gif"
                    id="image_hlv_r3z_tr"/>Join Cell Below</uicontrol>, <ph keyref="product"/>
                deletes the source row is case it remains empty. The cells that span over multiple
                rows are also updated.</note></li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableSplitCellLeft16.gif" id="image_tfd_53z_tr"
                />Split Cell To The Left</uicontrol> - Splits the cell from the current caret
              position in two cells, inserting a new empty table cell to the left. This action works
              only if the current cell spans over more than one column.<ph keyref="product"/>
              decreases the column span of the source cell with one.</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableSplitCellRight16.gif" id="image_lcm_53z_tr"
                />Split Cell To The Right</uicontrol>- Splits the cell from the current caret
              position in two cells, inserting a new empty table cell to the right. This action
              works only if the current cell spans over more than one column.<ph keyref="product"/>
              decreases the column span of the source cell with one.</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableSplitCellUp16.gif" id="image_j53_v3z_tr"/>Split
                Cell Above</uicontrol> - Splits the cell from current caret position in two cells,
              inserting a new empty table cell above. This action works only if the current cell
              spans over more than one row. <ph keyref="product"/> decreases the column span of the
              source cell with one.</li>
            <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/TableSplitCellDown16.gif" id="image_p1q_v3z_tr"
                />Split Cell Below</uicontrol> - Splits the cell from current caret position in two,
              inserting a new empty table cell below. This action works only if the current cell
              spans over more than one row. <ph keyref="product"/> decreases the column span of the
              source cell with one.</li>
          </ul></dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
    <p><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150223T120309+0200" comment="Continue revising the rest of the topic. Note: Refresh references can be reused in all the doc types."?>In
      addition, the following default actions are available from the DITA menu:<?oxy_comment_end?><dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RefreshReferences16.png" id="image_xnb_4hw_sr"/>Refresh
              references</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>You can use this action to manually trigger a refresh and update of all referenced
            resources.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>In addition, the following default actions are available from the contextual menu:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Style Guide</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens the <b>DITA Style Guide Best Practices for Authors</b> in your browser and
          displays a topic that is relevant to the element at the caret position. When editing DITA
          documents, this action is available in the contextual menu of the editing area (under the
            <uicontrol>About Element</uicontrol> sub-menu), in the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu,
          and in some of the documentation tips that are displayed by the <uicontrol>Content
            Completion Assistant</uicontrol>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="browse_ref_manual">
        <dt><uicontrol>Browse reference manual</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens in your web browser of choice a reference to the documentation of the XML element
          closest to the caret position. When editing DITA documents, this action is available in
          the contextual menu of the editing area (under the <uicontrol>About Element</uicontrol>
          sub-menu) and in the documentation tip displayed by the <uicontrol>Content Completion
            Assistant</uicontrol>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><menucascade>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteSpecialDITA16.png" id="image_j1n_mrt_tr"/>Paste
              special</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Paste as content reference</uicontrol>
          </menucascade></dt>
        <dd>Available on the contextual menu of Author editor for any topic file, this operation
          inserts a content reference (a DITA element with a <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute) to
          the DITA XML element from the clipboard. An entire DITA XML element with an ID attribute
          must be present in the clipboard when the action is invoked. The <codeph>conref</codeph>
          attribute will point to this ID value.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><menucascade>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteSpecialDITA16.png" id="image_m34_prt_tr"/>Paste
              special</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Paste as content key reference</uicontrol>
          </menucascade></dt>
        <dd>Allows you to indirectly reference content using the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>
          attribute. When the DITA content is processed, the key references are resolved using key
          definitions from DITA maps. To use this action, do the following:<ol id="ol_fgp_ggb_2r">
            <li>Set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element holding the content you want to
              reference.</li>
            <li>Open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and make sure
              that the <uicontrol>Root map</uicontrol> combo box points to the correct map that
              stores the keys.</li>
            <li>Right click the topic that holds the content you want to reference, select
                <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the
                <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> field.</li>
          </ol></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><menucascade>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteSpecialDITA16.png" id="image_ty4_srt_tr"/>Paste
              special</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Paste as link</uicontrol>
          </menucascade></dt>
        <dd>Available on the contextual menu of Author editor for any topic file, this action
          inserts a <codeph>link</codeph> element or an <codeph>xref</codeph> one (depending on the
          location of the paste operation) that points to the DITA XML element from the clipboard.
          An entire DITA XML element with an ID attribute must be present in the clipboard when the
          action is invoked. The <codeph>href</codeph> attribute of
            <codeph>link</codeph>/<codeph>href</codeph> will point to this ID value.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><menucascade>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteSpecialDITA16.png" id="image_e3s_srt_tr"/>Paste
              special</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Paste as link (keyref)</uicontrol>
          </menucascade></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a link to the element that you want to reference. To use this action, do the
            following:<ol id="ol_tjp_ggb_2r">
            <li>Set the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute of the element that you want to
              reference.</li>
            <li>Open the DITA Map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and make sure
              that the <uicontrol>Root map</uicontrol> combo box points to the correct map that
              stores the keys.</li>
            <li>Right click the topic that holds the content you want to reference, select
                <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the
                <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> field.</li>
          </ol></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Replace conref / conkeyref reference with content</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Replaces the content reference fragment or the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> at caret
          position with the referenced content. This action is useful when you want to make changes
          to the content but decide to keep the referenced fragment unchanged.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Insert Equation</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Allows you to insert an MathML equation. <ph product="editor author">For more
            information, see section <xref href="author-editing-mathml.dita#author-editing-mathml"
              format="dita">Editing MathML Notations</xref></ph>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Create Reusable Component</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Creates a reusable component from a selected fragment of text. For more information, see
            <xref href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
            Content</xref>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Insert Reusable Component</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a reusable component at cursor location. For more information, see <xref
            href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
            Content</xref>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Remove Content Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Removes the <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute of an element. For more information, see
            <xref href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
            Content</xref>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Add/Edit Content Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Add or edit the <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute of an element. For more information,
          see <xref href="dita-reusing-content.dita#dita-reusing-content" format="dita">Reusing
            Content</xref>.</dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
    <dl>
      <dlentry id="generate-ids">
        <dt><uicontrol>Generate IDs</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>
          <p>This action generates and sets unique IDs for:<ul>
              <li>The element at caret position.</li>
              <li>All top-level elements found in the current selection. Additionally, if the
                selection contains elements from the <menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol>
                </menucascade> list, they will all receive an unique ID</li>
            </ul><note>IDs already set are preserved.</note></p>
          <p>The action is available both in the contextual menu and in the
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> main menu.</p>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Action available in the <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> main menu, allows you to specify the elements for which <ph
            keyref="product"/> generates an unique ID if the <uicontrol>Auto generate IDs for
            elements</uicontrol> option is enabled. The configurable ID value pattern can accept
          most of the application supported <xref href="editor-variables.dita">editor
            variables</xref>. <p>To keep an already set element ID when copying content in the same
            document, make sure the <uicontrol>Remove IDs when copying content in the same
              document</uicontrol> option is not checked.</p></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Search References</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Finds the references to the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute value of the selected element
          in all the topics from the current DITA map (opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
            Manager</uicontrol> view). The default shortcut of the action is <uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_g"/> and can be
          changed in the <uicontrol>DITA Topic</uicontrol> document type.</dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
        <p id="drag-and-drop-from-project-to-author-dita-topic">Dragging a file from <xref
        href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita">the
          <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref> or <xref keyref="dita.edit-maps" format="dita"
          ><uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view</xref> and dropping it into a DITA document
      that is edited in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, creates a link to the dragged file (the
        <codeph>xref</codeph> DITA element with the <codeph>href</codeph> attribute) at the drop
      location. Dragging an image file from the default file system application (Windows Explorer on
      Windows or Finder on Mac OS X, for example) and dropping it into a DITA document inserts an
      image element (the <codeph>image</codeph> DITA element with the <codeph>href</codeph>
      attribute) at the drop location.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
