<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-editing-tables">
  <title>Editing Tables in Author Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Tables<indexterm>Editing
            features</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Tables<indexterm>Editing
                features</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Table editing features in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides support for editing data in a tabular form. A variety of
      features and operations are available for editing tables in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode
      and they include the following:</p>
    <section id="adjusting_column_width">
      <title>Adjusting Column Width</title>
      <p>To adjust the width of a column or table, drag the border of the column or table. The
        changes you make to a table are committed into the source document. You can also manage
        table width and column width specifications from the source document, and some types of
        tables include a <uicontrol>colspecs</uicontrol> section that appears above the table in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode that allows you to easily configure some column
        specifications (such as column width). These column width specifications are supported in
        fixed, dynamic, and proportional dimensions. The predefined DITA, DocBook, and XHTML <xref
          keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>frameworks</term></xref> support this feature. The
        layout of the tables for these document types takes into account the table width and the
        column width specifications particular to them.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Resizing a Table Column in Author Mode</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_author_resize_column.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="selecting_columns_and_rows">
      <title>Selecting Columns and Rows</title>
      <p>To select a row or a column of a table, place the mouse cursor above the column or in front
        of the row you want to select, then click. When hovering the mouse cursor in front of rows
        or above column headers, the cursor changes to <image href="../img/RowSelection.png"/> for
        row selection and to <image href="../img/ColumnSelection.png"/> for column selection and
        that specific row or column is highlighted.</p>
      <p>You can use the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol><shortcut>Shift</shortcut></uicontrol> keys to select multiple rows.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="selecting_cells">
      <title>Selecting Cells</title>
      <p>To select a cell in a table, press and hold the
          <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol> key and click anywhere inside the cell.
        You can also use the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol><shortcut>Shift</shortcut></uicontrol> keys to select multiple cells or to
        deselect cells from a selection. Alternatively, you can click the left corner of a cell
        (right corner if you are editing a <xref
          href="control-text-direction-markup.dita#control-text-direction-markup">RTL
          document</xref>) to select it. The cursor changes to <image
          href="../img/CellLtrUpSelection.png" id="image_yr3_2zr_4n"/> when you hover over the
        corner of the cell.</p>
      <p>You can also select multiple rectangular blocks of cells by using your mouse to select a
        cell and drag it to expand the selection.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="drag_and_drop">
      <title>Drag and Drop</title>
      <p>You can use the drag and drop action to edit the content of a table. You can select a
        column and drag it to another location in the table you are editing. When you drag a column
        and hover the cursor over a valid drop position, <ph keyref="product"/> decorates the target
        location with bold rectangles. The same drag and drop action is also available for entire
        rows or columns by hovering the mouse cursor in front of rows or above column headers, then
        selecting the row or column and dragging them to the desired location.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="copycut_and_paste">
      <title>Copy/Cut and Paste</title>
      <p>In <ph keyref="product"/>, you can copy/cut entire rows or columns of the table you are
        editing and paste the copied columns or rows inside the same table or inside other tables.
        You can also use the copy or cut actions for tables located in other documents. If you paste
        a row or column into non-table content, <ph keyref="product"/> introduces a new table that
        contains the fragments of the copied row or column content.</p>
      <p>For copied columns, the fragments are introduced starting with the header of the column.
        Also, if the copied column is from a <term>CALS</term> table, <ph keyref="product"/>
        preserves column width information. This information is then used when you paste the column
        into another <term>CALS</term> table.</p>
      <p>For copied cells, when pasting them into another cell without a selection (the cursor is
        just placed in the new cell), the copied cells are pasted while preserving their initial
        order and spacing. If pasting them into a selection of cells, first the content of the
        selected cells is deleted, then the copied cells are pasted with their initial order and
        spacing preserved and if there are more cells in the selection than in the copied content,
        the pasting will repeat the copied cells until the end of the selection.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="deleting_content">
      <title>Deleting Content</title>
      <p>To delete the content of a cell, select the cell and press the
            <uicontrol><shortcut>Delete</shortcut></uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol><shortcut>Backspace</shortcut></uicontrol> key on your keyboard. If you press
            <uicontrol><shortcut>Delete</shortcut></uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol><shortcut>Backspace</shortcut></uicontrol> again, the selected table
        structure will also be removed.</p>
      <p>To delete an entire row or column, place the cursor inside the row or column (or select it)
        and use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/DeleteRow16.png"/>Delete Row(s)</uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/DeleteColumn16.gif"/>Delete Column(s)</uicontrol> actions
        from the toolbar or contextual menu. This will delete both the content and the table
        structure for the current row or column.</p>
      <p>To delete a selection of multiple rows or columns, select them and use the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/DeleteRow16.png"/>Delete Row(s)</uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/DeleteColumn16.gif"/>Delete Column(s)</uicontrol> actions
        from the toolbar or contextual menu. This will delete both the content and the table
        structure for all rows or columns that exist in the current selection.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="navigating_cells">
      <title>Navigating Cells</title>
      <p>Along with the normal mouse navigation, you can also navigate between cells by using the
        arrow keys on your keyboard. By default, when using the arrow keys to navigate between table
        cells, the cursor jumps from one cell to another. However, if the <xref
          href="caret-navigation.dita#caret-navigation/enable-navigation-cells"><uicontrol>Quick
            navigation in tables</uicontrol> option</xref> is not selected in the <uicontrol>Cursor
          Navigation</uicontrol> preferences page, using the arrow keys to navigate between table
        cells will cause the cursor to navigate between XML nodes, rather than jumping from cell to
        cell.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="add-docbook-table.dita#add-docbook-table"/>
      <link href="eppo-tables.dita#eppo-tables"/>
      <link href="add-table-xhtml.dita#add-table-xhtml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
