<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-editing-text">
  <title>Editing the XML Content</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>edit
    content</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>By default you can type only in elements which accept text content. So if the element is
      declared as empty or element only in the associated schema you are not allowed to insert text
      in it. This is also available if you try to insert <codeph>CDATA</codeph> inside an element.
      Instead a warning message is shown:</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Editing in empty element warning</title>
      <image href="../img/author_insert_text_warning.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>You can disable this behavior by checking the <uicontrol>Allow Text in empty or element only
        content</uicontrol> check box in the <xref href="preferences-author.dita">Author preferences
        page</xref>.</p>
    <p>Entire sections or chunks of data can be moved or copied by using the drag and drop support.
      The following situations can be encountered:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>when both the drag and drop sources are Author pages, an well-formed XML fragment is
        transferred. The section is balanced before dropping it by adding matching tags when
        needed.</li>
      <li>when the drag source is the Author page but the drop target is a text-based editor only
        the text inside the selection is transferred as it is.</li>
      <li>the text dropped from another text editor or another application into the Author page is
        inserted without changes.</li>
    </ul>
    <p product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">The font size of the current WYSIWYG-like editor can be
      increased and decreased on the fly with the same actions as in the Text editor:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_numpad_plus"/>
          or <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_numpad_minus"
          /> or <uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_scroll_forward"/> -
          Increases font size.</li>
        <li><uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_numpad_minus"/>
          or <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_minus"/> or
            <uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_scroll_backwards"/> -
          Decreases font size.</li>
        <li><uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_numpad_0"/> or
            <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_0"/> - Restores
          font size to <xref href="preferences-fonts.dita">the size specified in
              <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol></xref>.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="author-copy-paste-from-Office.dita#author-copy-paste-from-Office"/>
  </related-links>
  <topic id="remove-text-content">
    <title>Removing the Text Content of the Current Element</title>
    <body>
      <p>You can remove the text content of the current element and keep only the markup with the
        action <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_remove_text.png"/>Remove Text</uicontrol> available
        on the submenu <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> of the contextual menu and on the toolbar
          <uicontrol>XML Refactoring</uicontrol>. This is useful when the markup of an element must
        be preserved, for example a table structure but the text content must be replaced.</p>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="generated-id-uniqueness">
    <title>Duplicating Elements with Existing IDs</title>
    <body>
      <p>If the <uicontrol>Auto generate IDs for elements</uicontrol> option (available in the
          <uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol> dialog from DITA, Docbook and TEI document types) is
        turned off and you duplicate elements with existing IDs, the duplicates lose these IDs. If
        the previously mentioned option is active, when you duplicate content, Oxygen makes sure
        that if there is an ID attribute set in the XML markup, the newly created duplicate has a
        new, unique ID attribute value. The option <uicontrol>Remove ID's when copying content in
          the same document</uicontrol> allows you to control if a pasted element should retain its
        ID. </p>
    </body>
  </topic>
</topic>