<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="autocorrect-preferences-page">
  <title>AutoCorrect Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes an option to automatically correct misspelled words as you
      type in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. To enable and configure this feature, <ph
        conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Edit Modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>AutoCorrect</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available:<ul id="ul_vt3_yfy_qr">
        <li><uicontrol>Enable AutoCorrect</uicontrol> - This option is disabled by default. If
          enabled, while editing in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, if you type anything that is
          listed in the <uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol> column of the Replacements table displayed in
          this preferences page, <ph keyref="product"/> will automatically replace it with the value
          listed in the <uicontrol>With</uicontrol> column.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Use additional suggestions from the spell checker</uicontrol> - If enabled,
          in addition to anything listed in the Replacements table displayed in this preferences
          page, <ph keyref="product"/> will also use suggestions from the Spell Checker to
          automatically correct misspelled words. Suggestions from the Spell Checker will only be
          used if the misspelled word is not found in the Replacements table.</li>
      </ul><note>The <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature shares the same options configured in the
          <xref
          href="preferences-editor-spell-check.dita#preferences-editor-spell-check/lang-options-section"
            ><uicontrol>Language options</uicontrol></xref> and <xref
          href="preferences-editor-spell-check.dita#preferences-editor-spell-check/ignore-elements-section"
            ><uicontrol>Ignore elements</uicontrol></xref> sections in the <uicontrol>Spell
          Check</uicontrol> preferences page. </note></p>
    <section id="replacements-section"><title>Replacements Table Section</title>The
        <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature uses the Replacements table to automatically replace
      anything that is listed in the <uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol> column with the value listed in
      the <uicontrol>With</uicontrol> column for each language. You can specify the language in the
        <uicontrol>Replacements for language</uicontrol> drop-down list, and for each language, you
      can configure the items listed in the table. The language selected in this page is not the
      language that will be used by the <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature. It is simply the language
      for which you are configuring the Replacements table.<note>Any changes, additions, or
        deletions you make to this table are saved to a path that is specified in the <xref
          href="autocorrect-dictionaries-preferences.dita#autocorrect-dictionaries-preferences/user-defined-li"
            ><term>AutoCorrect</term>
          <uicontrol>Dictionaries</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>.</note></section>
    <section>
      <title>Smart Quotes Section</title>
      <p>You can also choose to automatically convert double and single quotes to a quotation
        characters of your choice by using the following options in the <uicontrol>Smart
          quotes</uicontrol> section:<ul id="ul_g41_hpy_qr">
          <li><uicontrol>Replace "Single quotes"</uicontrol> - Replaces single quotes with the
            quotation symbols you select with the <uicontrol>Start quote</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol>End quote</uicontrol> buttons.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Replace "Double quotes"</uicontrol> - Replaces double quotes with the
            quotation symbols you select with the <uicontrol>Start quote</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol>End quote</uicontrol> buttons.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Global and Project Options Section</title>
      <p>Selecting <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol> in this preferences page will only save
        your selections in <uicontrol>Enable AutoCorrect</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Use additional
          suggestions from the spell checker</uicontrol>, and the options in the <uicontrol>Smart
          quotes</uicontrol> section. Changes to the Replacements table are not saved in this page.
        To save changes to the Replacements table at project level you need to specify a custom
        location in <xref
          href="autocorrect-dictionaries-preferences.dita#autocorrect-dictionaries-preferences/user-defined-li"
          >the <uicontrol>User-defined replacements</uicontrol> section of the AutoCorrect
          Dictionaries preferences page</xref> and select <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol>
        from that preferences page instead.</p>
      <p><uicontrol>Restore Defaults</uicontrol> - Restores the options in this preferences page to
        their default values and also <b>deletes any changes you have made to the Replacements
          table</b>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
