<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="autocorrect-dictionaries-preferences">
  <title>AutoCorrect Dictionaries Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>Editor<indexterm>Edit
                    Modes<indexterm>Author<indexterm>AutoCorrect<indexterm>AutoCorrect
                    Dictionaries</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        </indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To set the Dictionaries preferences for the <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Edit Modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>AutoCorrect</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Dictionaries</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. This page allows you to specify the location of the dictionaries that <ph
        keyref="product"/> uses for the <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature and the location for saving
      user-defined replacements.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in this preferences page:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Dictionaries default folder</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays the default location where the dictionaries that <ph keyref="product"/> uses
            for the <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature are stored.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Include dictionaries from</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd> Enable this option if you want to specify an additional location for the dictionaries
            that <ph keyref="product"/> will use for the <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature.<note>The
                <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature takes into account dictionaries collected both from
              the default and custom locations and multiple dictionaries from the same language are
              merged into a generic dictionary (for example, <filepath>en_UK.dat</filepath> from the
              default location is merged with <filepath>en_US.dat</filepath> from a custom location,
              and the result is that a third file is created for a generic dictionary called
                <filepath>en.dat</filepath>). However, if there is already a generic dictionary (for
              example, <filepath>en.dat</filepath>) saved in either the default or custom location,
              the other specific dictionaries (for example, <filepath>en_UK.dat</filepath> and
                <filepath>en_US.dat</filepath>) will not be merged and the existing generic
              dictionary will simply be used. Also, if the additional location contains a file with
              the same name as one from the default location, the file in the additional location
              takes precedence over the file from the default location. The user-defined
              replacements are never merged.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>How to add more dictionaries</uicontrol> link</dt>
          <dd>Use this link to open a topic in the <ph keyref="product"/> User Guide that explains
            how to <xref
              href="../tasks/add-dictionaries-for-autocorrect.dita#add-dictionaries-for-autocorrect"
              >add dictionaries for the AutoCorrect feature</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol id="user-defined">Save user-defined replacements in the following
              location</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Specifies the target where added, edited, or deleted replacements are saved. By
            default, the target is the application preferences folder, but you can also choose a
            custom location.<note type="tip">To save changes to <xref
                href="autocorrect-preferences-page.dita#autocorrect-preferences-page/replacements-section"
                >the Replacement table (in the AutoCorrect preferences page)</xref> at project
              level, select a custom location for the <uicontrol>User-defined
                replacements</uicontrol> and select <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol> at the
              bottom of the page.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
