<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="auto-recover-feature">
  <title>Auto Recover Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Auto recovery</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Backup file</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_uft_bgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> includes an <term>Auto Recover</term> feature to help prevent losing
      unsaved content if you encounter an application or system crash. The feature is enabled by
      default and it automatically saves documents you are working on to a specified auto-recover
      file location. At every specified interval, all documents that have been modified since the
      last auto-save are saved to the specified location.</p>
    <p id="p_vft_bgk_54b">This feature is controlled by two options in the <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> preferences
      page. You can disable it, or configure how often content is saved by selecting the desired
      value in the drop-down list of the <xref
        href="preferences-editor-save.dita#preferences-editor-save/save-auto-recover"
          ><uicontrol>Save auto-recover information every</uicontrol> option</xref>, and you can
      specify the location of the saved documents in the <xref
        href="preferences-editor-save.dita#preferences-editor-save/auto-recover-location"
          ><uicontrol>Auto-recover file location</uicontrol> option</xref>.</p>
    <p id="p_wft_bgk_54b">In the event of an application or system crash, once you restart the application, <ph
        keyref="product"/> looks for an auto-recover file for each document that is either
      automatically or manually reopened. If an auto-recover file is found, a dialog box is
      displayed with options for how to handle the recovered information.</p>
    <p id="p_xft_bgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_yft_bgk_54b">
        <title>Auto Recover Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/auto-recover-dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_zft_bgk_54b">The dialog box offers the following choices:<ul id="ul_agt_bgk_54b">
        <li id="li_bgt_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Open recovered content in a new tab</uicontrol> - Opens the recovered
          document in a new tab.<note type="tip" id="note_cgt_bgk_54b">You can use the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/DiffFiles16.png"/>Compare Files</uicontrol> tool (available in the
              <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu) to compare the recovered content with the last
            saved version of the document.</note></li>
        <li id="li_dgt_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Replace current file content with recovered content</uicontrol> - Replaces
          the content of the last saved version of the document with the content of the recovered
          version of the document and removes the auto-recover file from disk.</li>
        <li id="li_egt_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Use current file content and discard recovered content</uicontrol> - Discards
          the recovered document and retains the last saved version of the document.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note type="other" othertype="Notes About the Auto-Recover Feature" id="note_fgt_bgk_54b">
      <ul id="ul_ggt_bgk_54b">
        <li id="li_hgt_bgk_54b">The <term>Auto Recover</term> feature works for both local and remote files.</li>
        <li id="li_igt_bgk_54b">For DITA projects, the <term>Auto Recover</term> feature also works for DITA maps opened
          in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li id="li_jgt_bgk_54b">The <term>Auto Recover</term> feature does NOT work if there is not enough space
          available on the disk where the <xref
            href="preferences-editor-save.dita#preferences-editor-save/auto-recover-location"
            >auto-recover file location is specified</xref>.</li>
        <li id="li_kgt_bgk_54b">The <term>Auto Recover</term> feature does NOT work on files opened in the <xref
            href="huge-file-editor.dita"><term>huge file editor</term></xref> (if you select the
            <xref href="editing-large-documents.dita"><uicontrol>Optimize loading for huge
              files</uicontrol> option when opening large documents</xref>).</li>
      </ul>
    </note>
  </body>
</topic>
