<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="berkeley-connection-level">
  <title>Actions Available at Connection Level</title>
  <body>
    <p>In a Berkeley DB XML repository the actions available at connection level in the
        <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view are the following:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_refresh.png"/> Refresh</uicontrol> - Performs a refresh
        of the selected node's subtree.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Disconnect</uicontrol> - Closes the current database connection.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_options_shortcut.png"/> Configure Database
          Sources</uicontrol> - Opens <xref href="preferences-database.dita">the <uicontrol>Data
            Sources</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> where you can configure both data sources
        and connections.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Add container</uicontrol> - Adds a new container in the repository with the
        following attributes.<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The name of the new container.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Container type</uicontrol> - At creation time, every container must have a
            type defined for it. This container type identifies how XML documents are stored in the
            container. As such, the container type can only be determined at container creation
            time; you cannot change it on subsequent container opens. Containers can have one of the
            following types specified for them: <ul>
              <li><uicontrol>Node container</uicontrol> - XML documents are stored as individual
                nodes in the container. That is, each record in the underlying database contains a
                single leaf node, its attributes and attribute values if any, and its text nodes, if
                any. Berkeley DB XML also keeps the information it needs to reassemble the document
                from the individual nodes stored in the underlying databases. This is the default,
                and preferred, container type.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Whole document container</uicontrol> - The container contains entire
                documents. The documents are stored without any manipulation of line breaks or
                whitespace.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Allow validation</uicontrol> - If checked it causes documents to be
            validated when they are loaded into the container. The default behavior is to not
            validate documents.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Index nodes</uicontrol> - If checked it causes indices for the container to
            return nodes rather than documents. The default is to index at the document level. This
            property has no meaning if the container type is whole document container.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Properties</uicontrol> - Shows a dialog containing a list of the Berkeley
        connection properties: version, home location, default container type, compression
        algorithm, etc.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
