<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="branch-tag">
  <title>Create a Branch / Tag</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Branches/Tags<indexterm>create a branch/tag</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>In the <xref href="working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref> or
      in the <xref href="repository-view.dita"><uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view</xref>,
      select the resource which you want to copy to a branch or tag, then select the command
        <i>Branch / Tag...</i> from the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Branch / Tag dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_svn_branch_tag_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The default target URL for the new branch / tag will be the repository URL of the selected
      resource from your working copy, divided in two: the URL of the parent and the selected
      resource's name. You may specify other resource name if you want to make a branch / tag using
      a different name than the one of the selected resource, by modifying the field labeled
        <uicontrol>Under the name:</uicontrol>. The new branch / tag will be created as child of the
      specified repository directory URL and having the new provided name. To change the parent
      directory URL to the new path for your branch / tag, click on the
        <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol> button and choose a repository target directory for your
      resource.</p>
    <p>You can also specify the source of the copy. There are three options: <ul>
        <li><uicontrol>HEAD revision in the repository</uicontrol> - The new branch / tag will be
          copied in the repository from the HEAD revision. The branch will be created very quickly
          as the repository will make a cheap copy.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Specific revision in the repository</uicontrol> - The new branch will be
          copied in the repository but you can specify exactly the desired revision. This is useful
          for example if you forgot to make a branch / tag when you released your application. If
          you click on the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> button on the right you can select the
          revision number from <xref href="history-dialog.dita#history-dialog" format="dita">the
              <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> dialog</xref>. This type of branch will also be created
          very quickly.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Working copy</uicontrol> - The new branch will be a copy of your local
          working copy. If you have updated some files to an older revision in your working copy, or
          if you have made local changes, that is exactly what goes into the copy. This involves
          transferring some data from your working copy back to the repository, more exactly the
          locally modified files.</li>
      </ul>When you are ready to create the new branch / tag, write a commit comment in the
      corresponding field and press the <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> button.</p>
  </body>
</topic>