<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="branch-tag">
  <title>Create a Branch / Tag</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Branches/Tags<indexterm>Create
          branch/tag</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To create a branch or tag by copying a directory, use the
        <uicontrol>Branch/Tag</uicontrol> action that is available in the
        <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu when an item is selected in the  <xref
        href="working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref> or <xref
        href="repository-view.dita"><uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view</xref>, or from the
      contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Branch/Tag Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_svn_branch_tag_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>You can configure the following options in this dialog box:</p>
    <p> You can specify the source revision of the copy in the <uicontrol>Copy from</uicontrol>
      section. You can choose between the following options: <ul id="ul_xps_t25_pr">
        <li><uicontrol>HEAD revision in the repository</uicontrol> - The new branch or tag will be
          copied in the repository from the <codeph>HEAD</codeph> revision. The branch will be
          created very quickly, as the repository will make a <i>cheap</i> copy.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Specific revision in the repository</uicontrol> - The new branch will be
          copied into the repository, but you can specify the exact desired revision. For example,
          this is useful if you forgot to make a branch or tag when you released your application.
          If you click the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> button you can select the revision number
          from <xref href="history-dialog.dita#history-dialog" format="dita">the
              <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> dialog box</xref>. This type of branch will also be
          created very quickly.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Working copy</uicontrol> - (Available only if the item is selected from the
            <uicontrol>Working copy</uicontrol> view). The new branch will be a copy of your local
          working copy. If you have updated some files to an older revision in your working copy, or
          if you have made local changes, that is exactly what goes into the copy. This involves
          transferring some data from your working copy back to the repository, or more
          specifically, the locally modified files.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>You can specify the location of the new branch or tag in the
        <uicontrol>Destination</uicontrol> section:<ul id="ul_f2j_sf5_pr">
        <li><uicontrol>Into repository's directory</uicontrol> - <xref
            href="entering-local-paths-urls.dita#entering-local-paths-urls/url-section">The URL of
            the parent directory</xref> of the new branch or tag.<note><i>Peg revisions</i> have no
            effect for this operation since it is used to send information to the repository.
          </note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Under the name</uicontrol> - You can specify another branch or tag name other
          than the name of the resource selected in the <uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol>Working copy</uicontrol> view. </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The new branch or tag will be created as a child of the specified URL of the repository
      directory and will have the new name.</p>
  </body>
</topic>