<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="builtin-transformation-scenarios">
  <title>Built-in Transformation Scenarios</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Transformation Scenario<indexterm>built-in transformation
          scenarios</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> comes with
      preconfigured built-in transformation scenarios used for usual transformations. To obtain the
      output simply one of the built-in scenarios with the currently edited document and click the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_ApplyStyleSheet20.png"/>Apply Transformation
        Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button.</p>
    <p>You can use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_ApplyStyleSheet20.png"/>Apply
        Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button even if the document you are editing is not
      associated with a transformation scenario. </p>
    <p>In case the document contains an <codeph>xml-stylesheet</codeph> processing instruction
      referring to an XSLT stylesheet (commonly used to display the document in web browsers), <ph
        keyref="product"/> prompts you to associate
      the document with a built-in transformation scenario. </p>
    <p>The default transformation scenario is suggested based on the processing instruction from the
      edited document. The <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> field of the default transformation
      scenario contains the URL from the <codeph>href</codeph> attribute of the processing
      instruction. The <uicontrol>Use xml-stylesheet declaration</uicontrol> check-box of the
      scenario is selected by default. Saxon is used as transformation engine and no FO processing
      is performed. The result of the transformation is store in a file with the same URL as the
      edited document, but the extension is changed to <filepath>html</filepath>. The name and path
      are preserved because the output file name is specified with the help of two <xref
        href="editor-variables.dita">editor variables</xref>: ${cfd} and ${cfn}. </p>
  </body>
</topic>