<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="canonicalizing-files">
  <title>Canonicalizing Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Digital Signature<indexterm>Canonicalize files</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Canonicalize files tool</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can select the canonicalization algorithm to be used for a document from the dialog box
      that is displayed by using the <uicontrol>Canonicalize</uicontrol> action that is available
      from the <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> submenu when invoking the contextual menu in
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode<ph product="author developer editor"> or from the
          <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu</ph><ph product="developerEclipse editorEclipse"> or
        from the <uicontrol>XML Tools</uicontrol> menu</ph>.</p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editor author developer">
        <title>Canonicalization Settings Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_canonicalize_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <fig product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">
        <title>Canonicalization Settings Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_canonicalize_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Canonicalize</uicontrol> dialog box allows you to set the following
      options:</p>
    <ul>
      <li product="author developer editor developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Input
          URL</uicontrol> - Available if the <uicontrol>Canonicalize</uicontrol> action was selected
        from the <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol
          product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">XML Tools</uicontrol> menu. It allows you to
        specify the location of the input file.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Exclusive</uicontrol> - If selected, the exclusive (uncommented)
        canonicalization method is used.<note id="exclusive-note">Exclusive Canonicalization just
          copies the namespaces you are actually using (the ones that are a part of the XML syntax).
          It does not look into attribute values or element content, so the namespace declarations
          required to process these are not copied. This is useful if you have a signed XML document
          that you want to insert into other XML documents (or you need self-signed structures that
          support placement within various XML contexts), as it will ensure the signature is
          verified correctly each time.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Exclusive with comments</uicontrol> - If selected, the exclusive with comments
        canonicalization method is used.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Inclusive</uicontrol> - If selected, the inclusive (uncommented)
        canonicalization method is used.<note id="inclusive-note">Inclusive Canonicalization copies
          all the declarations, even if they are defined outside of the scope of the signature, and
          all the declarations you might use will be unambiguously specified. Inclusive
          Canonicalization is useful when it is less likely that the signed data will be inserted in
          other XML document and it is the safer method from the security perspective because it
          requires no knowledge of the data that are to be secured to safely sign them. A problem
          may occur if the signed document is moved into another XML document that has other
          declarations because the Inclusive Canonicalization will copy them and the signature will
          be invalid.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Inclusive with comments</uicontrol> - If selected, the inclusive with comments
        canonicalization method is used.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>XPath</uicontrol> - The XPath expression provides the fragments of the XML
        document to be signed.</li>
      <li product="author developer editor developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          ><uicontrol>Output</uicontrol> - Available if the <uicontrol>Canonicalize</uicontrol>
        action was selected from the <uicontrol product="author developer editor"
          >Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">XML
          Tools</uicontrol> menu. It allows you to specify the output file path where the signed XML
        document will be saved.</li>
      <li product="author developer editor developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Open in
          editor</uicontrol> - If checked, the output file will be opened in the editor.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="digital-signature-overview.dita#digital-signature-overview"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>