<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="caret-navigation">
  <title>Caret Navigation Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to configure the appearance of the <term>caret</term> (text
      cursor) in the <xref keyref="mode_author"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode</xref> editor. To
      set caret navigation preferences, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Caret Navigation</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The following options are available:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Highlight elements near caret</uicontrol> - When this option is selected, the
          element containing the caret is highlighted. You can use the color picker to choose the
          color of the highlight. </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show caret position tooltip</uicontrol> - <ph keyref="product"/> uses <xref
            keyref="author_caret-position-tooltips">tool tips in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode
            to indicate the position of the caret in the element structure</xref> of the underlying
          document. Depending on context, the tool tips may show the current element name or the
          names of the elements before and after the current caret position. </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show location tooltip on mouse move</uicontrol> - When this option is
          selected, <ph keyref="product"/> displays <xref
            href="author-position-information.dita#author-position-information/location_tooltip"
              ><term>Location Tooltips</term></xref> when you are editing the document in certain
          tags display modes (Inline Tags, Partial Tags, No Tags) and the mouse pointer is moved
          between block elements.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Quick up/down navigation</uicontrol> - By default, when you navigate using
          the up and down arrow keys in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the caret is placed
          within each of the underlying XML elements between two blocks of text. (The caret turns
          horizontal when it is between blocks of text.) For instance, between a list item in one
          section and the title in a following sections, the caret might stop several times in the
          underlying structure: the list item, the list, the paragraph, the section, and the root
          element between sections, the new section, and finally in the title. Any one of these
          location is a place you might want to insert new content. When this option is selected,
          however, the caret does not stop at these positions, but jumps from one text line to
          another, similar to how the caret behaves in a word processor.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Arrow keys move the caret in the writing direction</uicontrol> - This setting
          determines how the left and right arrow keys behave in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode
          for bidirectional (BIDI) text. When this option is selected, the right arrow key advances
          the caret in the reading direction. When this option is not selected, pressing the right
          arrow will simply move the caret to the right, regardless of the text direction.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
