<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="certificates">
  <title>Certificates</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Digital Signature<indexterm>certificates</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>A certificate is a digitally signed statement from the issuer (an individual, an
      organization, a website or a firm), saying that the public key (and some other information) of
      some other entity has a particular value. When data is digitally signed, the signature can be
      verified to check the data integrity and authenticity. Integrity means that the data has not
      been modified. Authenticity means the data comes indeed from the entity that claims to have
      created and signed it. Certificates are kept in special repositories called keystores.</p>
    <p>A <i>keystore</i> is an encrypted file that contains private keys and certificates. All
      keystore entries (key and trusted certificate entries) are accessed via unique aliases. An
      alias must be assigned for every new entry of either a key or certificate as a reference for
      that entity. No keystore can store an entity if it's alias already exists in that keystore and
      no keystore can store trusted certificates generated with keys in it's keystore.</p>
    <p>In <ph keyref="product"/> there are provided two
      types of keystores: Java Key Store (JKS) and Public-Key Cryptography Standards version 12
      (PKCS-12). A keystore file is protected by a password. In a PKCS 12 keystore you should not
      store a certificate without alias together with other certificates, with or without alias, as
      in such a case the certificate without alias cannot be extracted from the keystore.</p>
    <p>To set the options for a certificate or to validate it, go to menu <xref
        href="preferences-certificates.dita">
        <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Certificates</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>
      </xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>