<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-configure-task-executor-container">
    <title>Configuring the Task Executor Container</title>
    <body>
        <p>The <i><b>Task Executor Container</b></i> is used for executing various tasks, such as
            building deliverables and validating the publications. You can configure the container
            by setting some properties:</p>
    <p id="p_lsh_ccl_hgc">
      <dl id="dl_msh_ccl_hgc">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_nsh_ccl_hgc">
          <dt>executor.service.ope.max.memory</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the maximum memory allocated for a single publishing build. Default value is
            1024 MB.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_osh_ccl_hgc">
          <dt>executor.service.validation.max.memory</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the maximum memory allocated for a single validation build. Default value is
            200 MB.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_psh_ccl_hgc">
          <dt>executor.service.parallel.publishing.builds</dt>
          <dd>Defines the maximum number of publishing builds that the application can execute
            simultaneously. This limits how many publishing processes can be handled at once,
            helping to manage server load and optimize resource usage. Default value is 2.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_qsh_ccl_hgc">
          <dt>executor.service.parallel.validation.builds</dt>
          <dd>Defines the maximum number of validation builds that the application can execute
            simultaneously. Controls how many validation processes can occur at the same time,
            ensuring efficient validation processing while balancing server performance. Default
            value is 5.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_rsh_ccl_hgc">
          <dt>executor.service.metrics.disk.store.period</dt>
          <dd>Determines how long (in days) the server should retain publishing build metrics on
            disk. This ensures that metrics for builds are stored for a limited time, preventing
            disk space overuse by automatically purging old data after the specified retention
            period. Default value is 30.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
        <p><u>Example</u>:</p>
        <p id="p_kfh_wbl_hgc">Sample configuration (to be added under the environment section of the
            <i>task-executor</i> container in the
          <i>docker-compose.override.yml</i>):<codeblock id="codeblock_cdt_w2j_hgc" outputclass="language-bourne">- JAVA_OPTS=-Dexecutor.service.validation.max.memory=500 -Dexecutor.service.ope.max.memory=800 -Dexecutor.service.parallel.builds.number=3 -Xmx512M</codeblock></p>
    </body>
</topic>