<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-configure-publishing-containers">
    <title>Configure Publishing Containers</title>
    <body>
    <p>The Publishing Containers are separated into two components:<ul id="ul_myl_xkk_wbc">
        <li>Task Executor Container - Executes various tasks such as building deliverables.</li>
        <li>Publishing Main Container -  Manages deliverables, the templates used by deliverables,
          and the builds associated with a deliverable.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="section_jtm_plk_wbc">
      <title>Configuring Task Executor</title>
      <p>For the Task Executor container, you can configure the following properties:</p>
      <p>
        <dl id="dl_ons_vjk_wbc">
          <dlentry>
            <dt>executor.service.ope.max.memory</dt>
            <dd>Specifies the maximum memory allocated for the publishing engine. Default value is
              1024 MB.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>executor.service.parallel.builds.number</dt>
            <dd>Defines the maximum number of parallel builds that the application can execute
              simultaneously. Default value is 3.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_x4t_qlk_wbc">
      <title>Configuring Publishing Main</title>
      <p>For the Publishing Main container, you can configure the following properties:</p>
      <p>
        <dl id="dl_u55_zjk_wbc">
          <dlentry>
            <dt>publishing.service.deliverable.builds.number</dt>
            <dd>Sets the number of builds to retain for each deliverable. This helps manage disk
              space and maintain only the most recent builds. Default value is 3.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>publishing.service.allow.automatic.builds</dt>
            <dd>Controls whether automatic builds, triggered by remote modifications or scheduled
              tasks, are allowed. Default value is true.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>publising.service.check.remote.period</dt>
            <dd>The interval, in seconds, at which the system checks for remote changes. Default
              value is 60 seconds.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>publishing.service.start.build.remote.changes.period</dt>
            <dd>The delay, in minutes, before starting a build when remote changes are detected. If
              additional remote changes are detected during this period, the build is re-triggered.
              Default value is 3 minutes.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>publishing.service.start.build.remote.changes.max.period</dt>
            <dd>The delay, in minutes, before starting a build when remote changes are detected. If
              additional remote changes are detected during this period, the build is not
              re-triggered. Default value is 10 minutes.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>publishing.service.build.console.max.lines.numbe</dt>
            <dd> Specifies the maximum number of lines displayed in the console dialog that shows
              the transformation progress. Default value is 1000 lines.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <p>Each property allows you to customize and optimize the behavior of the publishing and build
      processes according to your specific requirements. Adjust these values as necessary to fit
      your operational needs.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
