<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-customizing-options">
  <title>Customizing Options and Features</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Customizing options</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Customizing the editor</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Customize AutoCorrect term list</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Customize spell checker term list</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Customize learned words</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="cf-configuration-page">It is possible to customize the online editor that is built in to
      the <b>Oxygen Content Fusion</b> interface by <xref href="cf-custom-frameworks.dita">using a
        custom framework</xref>, but it is also possible to customize certain options and features
      by making changes to particular configuration files. For example, you can configure term lists
      used by the spell checker or <i>AutoCorrect</i> feature, and you can configure various options
      to customize the editing experience for all users.</p>
    <section id="author_mode_options">
      <title>Configuring Options for the Users' Editing Experience</title>
      <p>The functionality of the <b>Oxygen Content Fusion</b> built-in visual editor shares many of
        the same options used in <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>. The options are stored in an
          <filepath>options.xml</filepath> file that is located in the
          <filepath>/fusion/data/config/webauthor/options</filepath> folder. You can adjust this
        file to configure the options used for the editing experience of all users.</p>
      <p conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-p1"/>
      <p conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-p2"/>
    </section>
    <section id="create_and_add_personalized_term_lists">
      <title>Adding Custom Term Lists for the Spell Checker</title>
      <p>You can create personalized term lists that are used to store specialized terms (<i>learned
          words</i>) or control forbidden words. They can then be added to one of the directories
        that store the spell check dictionaries and the spell checker will be merge them with all
        the dictionaries and other term lists for a particular language.</p>
      <p>To create and add a personalized terms list, follow these steps:<ol>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-spell-li1"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-spell-li2"/>
          <li>Save the file (<filepath>.tdi</filepath>) in the
              <filepath>/fusion/data/config/webauthor/options/spell</filepath> folder.</li>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-spell-li4"/>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="create_autocorrect_term_lists">
      <title>Customizing the AutoCorrect Terms List</title>
      <p>The <b>Oxygen Content Fusion</b> built-in visual editor includes an AutoCorrect feature to
        automatically correct misspelled words as you type. There is a default list of commonly
        misspelled words and symbols for each supported language, but you can modify the list to
        suit your needs.</p>
      <p>To customize the term list used by the <term>AutoCorrect</term> feature, follow these steps:<ol>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-autocorrect-li1"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-autocorrect-li2"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-autocorrect-li3"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-autocorrect-li4"/>
          <li>Copy or move that patch file to the
              <filepath>/fusion/data/config/webauthor/options/autocorrect</filepath> folder.</li>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-cf-wa-waCustom/options-autocorrect-li6"/>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
