<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-custom-frameworks">
  <title>Using Custom Frameworks with Oxygen Content Fusion</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Using custom frameworks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Document type specializations</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="cf-configuration-page">One of the advantages of using the <ph keyref="cfEnterprise"/>
      solution is that it can be configured to support any DITA specialization or XML language. This
      must be done by someone who has access to customize <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term> (for
      example, a server administrator).</p>
    <p>For information about how to create, configure, reuse, test, and upload custom frameworks,
      see <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-waCustom/topics/customizing_frameworks.html"
        format="html" scope="external">Integrating Web Author with Your Content by Creating Custom
        Frameworks</xref>.</p>
    <p>To upload a custom <term>framework</term> to your <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term>
      deployment, follow this procedure:<ol id="upload-framework-ol">
        <li>Go to your <xref href="cf-enterprise-configuration.dita#cf-enterprise-configuration"
            >Content Fusion Enterprise Administration Page</xref>.</li>
        <li>In the <uicontrol>Web Author</uicontrol> tab, click <uicontrol>Manage Web
            Author</uicontrol>. This will open the <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term>
          <uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol> page.</li>
        <li>Select <uicontrol>Frameworks</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>Upload Framework</uicontrol> and choose a <term>framework</term>
          archive to upload.<note type="important"><term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term> does a
            validation check to make sure the uploaded framework archive contains the proper
            extension descriptor file (<filepath>*.framework</filepath>). The archive should contain
            exactly one folder. Otherwise you will receive an error that the upload was
            rejected.</note></li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to upload the file.<p><b>Result:</b> The
              <term>framework</term> should appear in the list on this
              <uicontrol>Frameworks</uicontrol> page. Uploaded frameworks appear with a light green
            highlight so that you can identify them easily.</p></li>
        <li>Once you are finished with all of your changes click the <uicontrol>Restart
            Server</uicontrol> button at the top of the <uicontrol>Frameworks</uicontrol> page.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <p>Once a custom framework has been uploaded to your <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term>
      deployment, whenever a file from that custom framework is opened in <ph keyref="product"/>,
      the reviewers will have access to the customizations made in that framework.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
