<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-disk-space">
  <title>Disk Space Requirements for Content Fusion</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> stores large amounts of data on the disk of the server. This topic
      provides some guidelines on how to provision the server with storage space.</p>
    <section id="section_vxf_kmj_k1c">
      <title>How <ph keyref="product"/> Uses Disk Space</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> uses disk space for several purposes:</p>
      <ol id="ul_wdm_smj_k1c">
        <li>It stores most of the data generated by users in the <filepath>/fusion/data/</filepath>
            folder.<p id="p_htg_v44_pcc"><b>Review Tasks:</b></p><ul id="ol_ksn_gnj_k1c">
            <li id="li_fz4_w44_pcc">When a user uploads a review task, all the files linked from the
              context DITA map are uploaded, even if only a few files are sent in the task.</li>
            <li id="li_gz4_w44_pcc">To reduce the disk space usage, <ph keyref="product"/> stores
              review tasks in groups of 100 and tries to store just one copy of a file uploaded as
              part of multiple review tasks within the same group. Therefore, you may notice a
              steeper increase in disk space usage after 100 tasks are created.</li>
          </ul><p id="p_pht_x44_pcc"><b>Projects:</b></p><ul id="ul_qkj_x44_pcc">
            <li id="li_rkj_x44_pcc">When users create a new project based on a Git repository, a
              clone of that repository is stored.</li>
            <li id="li_kkz_y44_pcc">Review tasks created within a project stores only files that
              were changed since the review task started.</li>
          </ul><p id="p_agn_z44_pcc"><b>Deliverables:</b></p><p id="p_ac3_bp4_pcc">For projects that
            have deliverables, <ph keyref="product"/> stores an additional clone of the Git
            repository for each deliverable. It also stores an output for each deliverable
            associated with the last successful build.</p><p id="p_rmp_bp4_pcc"><b>Search
            Index:</b></p><p id="p_vqr_cp4_pcc">A search index is created and maintained for each
            personal workspace that the end user has started using the <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol>
            functionality. The total amount of disk space allocated for all search indices is about
            2 gigabytes, after which the oldest unused indices are automatically deleted. The
              <codeph>indexing.max.occupied.disk.space.mb</codeph> property can be set to a value
            higher (or lower than <codeph>2000</codeph>) to increase (or decrease) the maximum
            allowed amount of search index data.</p></li>
        <li>Docker stores server logs outside the <filepath>/fusion/data/</filepath> folder.<note
            id="note_mpr_dp4_pcc" type="remember">Make sure you configure limits on the amount of
            logs that are stored.</note></li>
        <li>When an administrator runs a backup script, it stores the backup archive on the server's
          file system. The size of the backup archive is similar to the size of the
            <filepath>/fusion/data/</filepath> directory.<note id="note_dsp_q4j_k1c">It is important
            to move the backups to a different server, ideally in a different geographic
            region.</note></li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section id="section_cfq_dqj_k1c">
      <title>Disk Space Recommendation</title>
      <p>It is recommended to have at least 100GB disk space on the server where you want to install
        Content Fusion. After that, monitor the available disk space for the
          <codeph>/fusion/data/</codeph> folder and <xref
          href="cf-increasing-available-disk-space.dita">increase it as needed</xref>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
