<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-enterprise-server">
  <title>Server Administrator Guide</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Using your own Content Fusion Enterprise server</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Installing an Enterprise server</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion Enterprise virtual machine</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The information in this topic is meant to help system administrators install and configure
      your own Enterprise server solution.</p>
    <section id="the_two_types_of_server_hosting_solutions">
      <title>Types of Server Connections</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Oxygen Content Fusion Connector</uicontrol> add-on supports two types of
        server connections:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><ph keyref="cfPublic"/> (https://fusion.oxygenxml.com)</dt>
            <dd>This solution is a service where content that is uploaded through the <ph
                keyref="product"/> connector add-on is stored on a public server hosted by
                <term>Oxygen</term>. This solution allows you to try <ph keyref="product"/> for free
              but you cannot control the server configuration and your documents will be uploaded to
              a shared server (it is recommended that you use sample documents that do not contain
              sensitive information or ownership rights).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><ph keyref="cfEnterprise"/></dt>
            <dd>
              <p>It is also possible (and usually preferable) to use your own <ph
                  keyref="cfEnterprise"/> server to store uploaded content. This solution allows you
                to host your own server to store content that is uploaded through the <ph
                  keyref="product"/> connector add-on. With this model, you will be able to set up
                and configure your own server. This solution also allows you to <xref
                  href="cf-custom-frameworks.dita#cf-custom-frameworks">upload custom
                  frameworks</xref> so that all contributors will have access to them when reviewing
                content in <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
    <section id="supported_enterprise_server_solutions">
      <title>Supported Enterprise Server Deployment Solutions</title>
      <p>The <ph keyref="cfEnterprise"/> solution supports the following types of server deployments:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><xref href="cf-vmsphere.dita#cf-vmsphere">Your Own Server using VMware
                vSphere</xref></dt>
            <dd>This type of deployment is preferable for organizations that have their own server
              hardware and server administrators who are familiar with the <xref
                href="https://my.vmware.com/en/web/vmware/info/slug/datacenter_cloud_infrastructure/vmware_vsphere/6_5"
                format="html" scope="external">VMware vSphere</xref> Virtual Manager.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><xref href="cf-aws.dita#cf-aws">A Server Hosted on Amazon Web Services</xref>
            </dt>
            <dd>This is preferable for organizations that prefer a cloud-based setup and already
              have their infrastructure running on Amazon's Web Service. This solution requires an
                <xref href="https://aws.amazon.com/" format="html" scope="external">AWS
                account</xref> and the setup requires resources that are not covered in Amazon's
              free tier.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>
              <xref href="cf-ubuntu.dita#cf-ubuntu">Other Platforms using an Installation
              Kit</xref></dt>
            <dd>This type of deployment is preferable for organizations that are using other
              platforms other than <i>VMware vSphere</i> or another cloud provider other than
              Amazon. The installation kit for this solution has been built to run on Ubuntu
              18.04.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
