<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-enterprise-configuration">
  <title>Content Fusion Enterprise Administration Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion Enterprise - Administration Page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Configuring an Enterprise server</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <ph keyref="cfEnterprise"/> solution includes an <uicontrol>Administration
        Page</uicontrol> where you can configure various options.</p>
    <section id="section_hqq_dwg_t1b">
      <title> Signing in to the Administration Page</title>
      <p>
        <ol id="ol_g5c_dwg_t1b">
          <li>Use the IP address shown in the VM console to access the web interface of <ph
              keyref="product"/>. The address should be
              <codeph>https://&lt;server-address>:9080</codeph>.<note>By default, <ph
                keyref="product"/> uses a self-signed certificate. If you did not change it, the
              browser will display a security warning. Continue (for example, if you are using Edge
              or Internet Explorer, click <b>Details</b> and then <b>Go on to the
              webpage</b>).</note></li>
          <li>Log in with the credentials you <xref
              href="cf-enterprise-server.dita#cf-enterprise-server">configured in the initial
              setup</xref>.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="general_tab">
      <title>General Tab</title>
      <p>This tab contains the following options:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Domain Name</dt>
            <dd>Displays the IP address or DNS name of your server and you can change it.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>HTTPS enabled for Content Fusion</dt>
            <dd>Select this option if you want to enable HTTPS protocol for your users. When you
              select this checkbox, it will expand and provide options to upload your certificate
              and private key. The information in the displayed TLS certificate table will be
              updated according to the uploaded certificate.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to apply your changes and then restart the browser.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="license_tab">
      <title>License Tab</title>
      <p>If a license key has been activated on your server, this tab simply contains a
          <uicontrol>Manage License</uicontrol> button. Clicking this button opens a <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/servlet-report-page.html"
          format="html" scope="external">license management and statistics page</xref>.</p>
      <p>If a license key has not been activated, you have two options:<ul>
          <li>If you have already received a license key, choose the <uicontrol>Already have a
              license key</uicontrol> option, paste your license key in the text field and press
              <uicontrol>Activate</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Otherwise, choose the <uicontrol>Request a trial license key</uicontrol> option and
            complete the request form.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="mail_tab">
      <title>Mail Tab</title>
      <p>This tab contains the following options:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Mail configuration</dt>
            <dd>Enter your email server settings in this section.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Use STARTTLS</dt>
            <dd>Select this option if your email server is configured to use STARTTLS.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>SSL on connection</dt>
            <dd>Select this option if your email server accepts SSL connections and specify the
              port.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to apply your changes.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="authentication_tab">
      <title>Authentication Tab</title>
      <p>This tab contains the following option:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Use LDAP Authentication</dt>
            <dd>Select this option is you want to use your own LDAP configuration instead of the
              built-in authentication. When you select this checkbox, it will expand and provide
              options to configure the details of your LDAP authentication.<note>If your LDAP server
                uses a self-signed SSL certificate, select the <uicontrol>Use SSL</uicontrol> option
                and choose your certificate.</note><note type="tip">It is also possible to configure
                your <ph keyref="cfEnterprise"/> to accept <xref href="cf-google-auth.dita"
                  >Google</xref> or <xref href="cf-github-auth.dita">GitHub
                authentication</xref>.</note></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to apply your changes.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="web_author_tab">
      <title>Web Author Tab</title>
      <p>This tab contains a <uicontrol>Manage Web Author</uicontrol> button. Clicking this button
        opens the <b>Oxygen XML Web Author</b>
        <uicontrol>Administration Page</uicontrol>. This page provides options for configuring the
        visual editor that is used in <ph keyref="product"/>. For example, you can <xref
          href="cf-custom-frameworks.dita#cf-custom-frameworks">upload your own custom
          frameworks</xref> using this page.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="maintenance">
      <title>Maintenance</title>
      <p>This tab contains the following sections and options:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Maintenance Mode</dt>
            <dd>Click the <uicontrol>Enable Maintenance Mode</uicontrol> button to enable a
              maintenance mode that prevents users from accessing the server during this time. This
              allows you to perform maintenance tasks without the risk of corrupting data. Users
              will see a message in the <b>Content Fusion</b> browser interface letting them know
              that the site is temporarily down for maintenance purposes.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Announcement Banner</dt>
            <dd>Click the <uicontrol>Configure Message</uicontrol> if you want to display a message
              at the topic of each <b>Content Fusion</b> page. This is helpful if you need to post
              announcements (such as announcing changes, maintenance schedules, or upgrade
              information).</dd>
            <dd>To disable the message, simply configure the message with empty content.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Database</dt>
            <dd><b>Content Fusion</b> stores user profiles and task metadata in a database that is
              backed up every 60 minutes. In this section, you can see a list of the latest backups
              and you have access to the following options:<ul>
                <li><uicontrol>Create Database Backup</uicontrol> - Click this button to create a
                  new backup of the database. Prior to clicking that button, you can also use the
                    <uicontrol>Custom backup name</uicontrol> text field to specify a particular
                  name, useful for identifying the newly created backup.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Restore Database from Backup</uicontrol> - You can select a
                  particular backup listed in this section and then click the <uicontrol>Restore
                    Database from Backup</uicontrol> button to restore the database to that selected
                  backup.</li>
              </ul><note>To create a full Content Fusion backup that contains tasks metadata, tasks
                files, user profile, and configuration information, see <xref
                  href="cf-enterprise-backups.dita#cf-enterprise-backups"/>.</note></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Logs</dt>
            <dd>Click the <uicontrol>Show Logs</uicontrol> button to open a page where you can view
              or download server logs.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
