<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-enterprise-backups">
  <title>Backing Up Content Fusion Data</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion Enterprise - Backups</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Backing up data</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Backups</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>It is recommended for the server administrator to set up periodic backups for <ph
        keyref="cfEnterprise"/>.</p>
    <section id="section_dy1_p3k_ndb">
      <title>Creating a Backup</title>
      <p>A Content Fusion backup contains a <xref href="https://www.postgresql.org/" format="html"
          scope="external">PostgreSQL</xref> database dump along with configuration and task
        files.</p>
      <note type="important">A review task is divided into two parts (task metadata that is stored
        in a database &amp; task files that are stored on the file-system). Therefore, backups might
        contain tasks with small de-synchronizations. For this reason, the server administrator
        should choose a time with the least amount of usage to create the backup.</note>
      <p>To create a backup, execute the following command on the <b>Content Fusion</b> machine:
        <codeblock outputclass="language-javascript">sudo bash /fusion/admin/create-fusion-backup.sh</codeblock>This
        will create a backup archive (<filepath>fusion-backup.tar.gz</filepath>) in the current
        directory. If the backup file already exists, it will be overwritten.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_im4_p3k_ndb">
      <title>Storing a Backup</title>
      <p>The server administrator should create backups and download them to a safe backup storage
        location periodically. One method of doing this is to create a <cmdname>cron</cmdname> job
        that periodically connects to the <b>Content Fusion</b> machine to create a backup and
        download it using <cmdname>rsync</cmdname>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_dzj_q3k_ndb">
      <title>Restoring a Backup</title>
      <p>Before restoring a backup, <b>Content Fusion</b> needs to be shutdown  by executing the
        following
        command:<codeblock outputclass="language-javascript">sudo bash /fusion/admin/stop-content-fusion.sh</codeblock></p>
      <p>To restore <b>Content Fusion</b> from a backup, execute the following command on the
        Content Fusion
        machine:<codeblock outputclass="language-javascript">sudo bash /fusion/admin/restore-fusion-backup.sh /path/to/fusion-backup.tar.gz</codeblock></p>
      <p>The script takes one argument, the path to the backup file to restore from.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
