<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-new-task-from-interface">
  <title>Creating Tasks and Files from the Browser Interface</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Create new task from the browser</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Create new files from the browser</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_uxt_dgk_54b">It is possible to create a task directly in the <ph keyref="product"/>
      browser interface. This means that the task creation process is available to anyone who has
      access to the <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface, even if they do not have access to
        <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.</p>
    <p id="p_bjj_1wv_21c">You can also create or upload files to a newly created task or an existing
      task.</p>
    <p id="p_vxt_dgk_54b">To create a new task and add files:</p>
    <p id="p_vxt_dgk_54bd">
      <ol id="ol_gzj_4pq_4jb">
        <li id="li_wxt_dgk_54bd">From the <uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> page, click the
            <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> button.</li>
        <li id="li_eyt_dgk_54b">Enter a title for the task in the field at the top of the pane.
          Click the check mark on the right side when you are done.</li>
        <li id="li_fyt_dgk_54b">You can create or upload files to the task. To create a new file,
          click the <uicontrol>New File</uicontrol> button and you will be able to choose a file
          type from a list of templates, then choose a file name in the text field at the bottom,
          and click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. To upload a file, click the <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/cf-upload16.png" id="image_tqd_n1g_wr1"/>Upload</uicontrol> button and
          select the file from your system's file browser.</li>
        <li id="li_gp1_qjl_5xb">Open the new file in the <xref
            href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita">visual editor page</xref> (if not already
          opened) and use the visual editor to make changes to the document.<note type="tip"
            id="note_dzt_dgk_54b">If you are a task owner, you have access to the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/TrackChanges20.png" id="image_tqd_n1g_wr"/>Toggle Change
              Tracking</uicontrol> toolbar button. You may want to toggle this feature off when
            adding content to a new file.</note></li>
        <li id="li_gp1_qjl_5xb2">Optionally, select <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> from the left
          stripe to open the <xref href="cf-task-settings.dita"><uicontrol>Task Settings</uicontrol>
            page</xref> to configure options or delete the task.</li>
        <li id="li_hyt_dgk_54b">The next logical step would most likely be to <xref
            href="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.dita">share the task</xref> with anyone you want to
          review the documents.</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
