<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-organization-members">
    <title>Organization Members Page</title>
    <body>
    <p id="p_kbk_qll_qhc">The <b>Members</b> page in Content Fusion allows organization
      administrators to manage user access, assign roles, and allocate licenses within their
      organization. </p>
    <section id="section_access_authentication">
      <title>Accessing the Members Page</title>
      <p id="p_psp_pll_qhc"> Only users with an <b>Organization Administrator</b> role can access
        the members management page. To access this page: <ol id="ol_qsp_pll_qhc">
          <li id="li_rsp_pll_qhc">Click on your user profile name in the top-right corner of the
            interface.</li>
          <li id="li_ssp_pll_qhc">Select <uicontrol>Manage organization</uicontrol> from the
            drop-down menu.</li>
          <li id="li_tsp_pll_qhc">In the organization management interface, click on
              <uicontrol>Members</uicontrol> in the left navigation panel.</li>
        </ol><note type="note" id="note_usp_pll_qhc">If you do not see the <uicontrol>Manage
            organization</uicontrol> option in your user menu, you do not have administrator
          privileges for your organization.</note></p>
    </section>
        <section id="section_jtz_r2p_xfc">
            <title>Page Layout and Components</title>
      <p id="p_mrm_jml_qhc">The <b>Members</b> page provides a centralized interface for viewing and
        controlling all members, their roles, and license usage.</p>
      <p id="p_ql4_kml_qhc">
        <fig id="fig_h2v_kml_qhc">
          <title>Members Page</title>
          <image href="../img/cf-organization-members.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_i1d_dml_qhc">The members page contains the following sections and components:</p>
      <p id="p_gl2_hml_qhc">
        <dl id="dl_ywm_hml_qhc">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_zwm_hml_qhc">
            <dt>Invite Member Button</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_xmq_1nl_qhc">Click the <uicontrol>Invite member</uicontrol> button in the
                top-right corner to invite new members to your organization. In the resulting form
                control, you will enter the email address of the person you wish to invite and
                choose the user role (e.g. Author or Subject Matter Expert) from a drop-down.<note
                  id="note_a2v_4nl_qhc">A license seat based on the user role you specify is
                  automatically allocated when you invite the user even before they sign up in the
                  organization.</note></p>
              <p id="p_ec1_1nl_qhc"><uicontrol>Pending invitations</uicontrol> are listed in the
                members list. You can click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Close12.png"
                  />Cancel</uicontrol> button to cancel the invitation.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_ic4_rnl_qhc">
            <dt>License Allocation</dt>
            <dd>The top section displays how your license seats are allocated. Two progress bars
              display the current usage of your organization's <b>Author</b> license seats and
                <b>SME</b> (subject matter expert) license seats.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_hmz_m4l_qhc">
            <dt>Members List</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_nwx_fql_qhc">The bottom section displays all current members of the
                organization, including the following columns and actions:</p>
              <p id="p_jbg_gql_qhc">
                <dl id="dl_n34_gql_qhc">
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_o34_gql_qhc">
                    <dt>Name</dt>
                    <dd>The member’s name and email address.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_zsf_hql_qhc">
                    <dt>Org-level role</dt>
                    <dd>The member’s role at the organization level (e.g. Admin, Member). Use this
                      drop-down menu to change a member’s organization-level role.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_t1z_hql_qhc">
                    <dt>User role</dt>
                    <dd>The member’s <xref href="platform-user-roles.dita">user role within the
                        platform</xref> (e.g. Author, Subject-Matter Expert). Use this drop-down
                      menu to change a member’s user role.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_avr_3ql_qhc">
                    <dt>Active</dt>
                    <dd>Indicates if the user is currently active. Use this checkbox to activate or
                      deactivate a member’s account. <p id="p_pvg_1pl_qhc">
                        <note id="note_qvg_1pl_qhc">Inactive users cannot log in, do not count
                          against license seat limits, but their data remains intact. An
                          administrator can reactivate them at any time.</note>
                      </p><p id="p_nsf_2pl_qhc"><b>When a user account is deactivated:</b><ul
                          id="ul_tvg_1pl_qhc">
                          <li id="li_uvg_1pl_qhc">The user is immediately logged out and can no
                            longer access the application, including the web interface, desktop app,
                            or any connected tools.</li>
                          <li id="li_vvg_1pl_qhc">The user will not receive any email notifications,
                            even if there is activity on tasks or projects they previously
                            contributed to.</li>
                          <li id="li_wvg_1pl_qhc">The user cannot be assigned to new projects or
                            tasks while deactivated.</li>
                          <li id="li_xvg_1pl_qhc">Their name will appear in the members list and
                            other relevant areas of the interface with the label <b>(Inactive)</b>
                            to indicate their status.</li>
                          <li id="li_yvg_1pl_qhc">The license seat previously allocated to the user
                            becomes available for reassignment to another member.</li>
                          <li id="li_zvg_1pl_qhc">All user data, contributions, and history remain
                            intact and visible to other members, but the user cannot interact with
                            the system until reactivated.</li>
                          <li id="li_awg_1pl_qhc">Deactivation is a reversible action. It is
                            recommended for temporarily suspending access without deleting user data
                            or history.</li>
                        </ul></p><p id="p_wx2_hpl_qhc"><b>Reactivating a user account:</b><ul
                          id="ul_cwg_1pl_qhc">
                          <li id="li_dwg_1pl_qhc">An administrator can reactivate a deactivated
                            account at any time using the same checkbox.</li>
                          <li id="li_ewg_1pl_qhc">Once reactivated, the user regains access to the
                            application and all previous permissions and assignments are
                            restored.</li>
                          <li id="li_fwg_1pl_qhc">The user will resume receiving notifications and
                            can be assigned to new projects or tasks. </li>
                        </ul></p></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_h1g_kql_qhc">
                    <dt>More Options</dt>
                    <dd>You can click the ellipsis (three-dots) menu in the far-right column to
                      access additional actions:<ul id="ul_msh_zpl_qhc">
                        <li id="li_nsh_zpl_qhc"><uicontrol>Anonymize user</uicontrol> - This action
                          removes user data. It is irreversible and can only be performed on users
                          who are already inactive.<note id="note_bfw_5pl_qhc"><ph keyref="product"
                            /> anonymizes the user data stored in the database, but does not
                            anonymize data stored in Git repositories (both stored internally by
                            Content Fusion and linked repositories).</note></li>
                        <li id="li_nw2_dql_qhc"><uicontrol>Delete user</uicontrol> - This action
                          permanently removes the user from the system.</li>
                      </ul></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>
