<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-organization-settings">
  <title>Organization Settings Page</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <b>Organization Settings</b> page in <ph keyref="product"/> allows organization
      administrators to manage their organization's basic information, display settings, and handle
      organization deletions.</p>
    <section id="section_access_settings">
      <title>Accessing the Organization Settings Page</title>
      <p>Only users with an <b>Organization Administrator</b> role can access the organization
        settings page. To access this page:</p>
      <ol id="ol_access_settings_steps">
        <li>Click on your user profile name in the top-right corner of the interface.</li>
        <li>Select <uicontrol>Manage organization</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu.</li>
        <li>In the organization management interface, click on <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> in
          the left navigation panel.</li>
      </ol>
      <note type="note">If you do not see the <uicontrol>Manage organization</uicontrol> option in
        your user menu, you do not have administrator privileges for your organization.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="section_settings_layout">
      <title>Page Layout and Components</title>
      <p id="p_clr_lm1_rhc">The <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> page provides comprehensive control
        over organization-level settings and includes important warnings about subscription impacts
        when deleting an organization.</p>
      <p id="p_d5b_f11_zgc">
        <fig id="fig_o42_f11_zgc">
          <title>Organization Settings Page</title>
          <image href="../img/cf-organization-settings-page.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_fsw_km1_rhc">The organization settings page is organized into several main
        sections:</p>
      <p>
        <dl id="dl_settings_sections">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_general_info">
            <dt>General Information Section</dt>
            <dd>Displays and allows editing of basic organization details: <ul
                id="ul_general_components">
                <li><b>Organization Avatar</b> - Visual representation of the organization with the
                  option to upload a custom image.</li>
                <li><b>Organization ID</b> - Unique identifier for the organization
                  (read-only).</li>
                <li><b>Organization Display Name</b> - Editable name that appears throughout the
                  interface.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_th1_yvh_phc">
            <dt>Disable AI-powered features</dt>
            <dd>Select this option to disable all AI features. If not selected (default),
              organization members have access to the <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-positron-cf/topics/cf-ai-positron-overview-addon.html"
                format="html" scope="external">AI features contributed by the Oxygen AI
                Positron</xref>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_delete_section">
            <dt>Delete Organization Section</dt>
            <dd>Provides options for organization deletion with important alerts: <ul
                id="ul_delete_components">
                <li><b>Deletion Warning</b> - Orange warning box that explains the consequences of
                  deletion.</li>
                <li><b>Auto-renewal Info</b> - Blue information box (appears when applicable) that
                  explains deletions will disable auto-renewal.</li>
                <li><b>Delete Organization Button</b> - Red button to initiate the deletion
                  process.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_general_settings">
      <title>Managing General Organization Settings</title>
      <p>The General Information section allows you to customize your organization's appearance and
        identification:</p>
      <p id="div_organization_avatar"><u><b>Organization Avatar</b></u></p>
      <p>You can upload a custom image to represent your organization:<ol id="ol_avatar_upload">
          <li>Click on the camera icon in the organization avatar area.</li>
          <li>Select an image file from your computer.</li>
          <li>The image will be automatically resized and applied as your organization's
            avatar.</li>
        </ol><note type="note">The avatar image should be square for best results (128 x 128
          pixels). The system will automatically crop the image to fit the display
          requirements.</note></p>
      <p id="div_organization_display_name"><u><b>Organization Display Name</b></u></p>
      <p>You can change how your organization name appears throughout the interface: <ol
          id="ol_display_name_change">
          <li>Click on the current display name or the edit icon next to it.</li>
          <li>Enter the new display name in the text field.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to apply the changes.</li>
        </ol><note type="note">The organization ID cannot be changed as it is a unique system
          identifier. Only the display name can be modified.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_organization_deletion">
      <title>Organization Deletion</title>
      <p>The organization deletion feature allows administrators to permanently remove their
        organization and all associated data. This process includes important considerations
        regarding subscription management.</p>
      <p id="div_deletion_warnings"><u><b>Deletion Warnings and Information</b></u></p>
        <p>When you attempt to delete an organization, the system displays several important notes:
          <ul id="ul_deletion_warnings">
          <li><b>Primary Deletion Warning</b> - An orange warning box that explains the immediate
            suspension and permanent removal of all organization resources, including projects,
            users, and review tasks after a 14-day grace period.</li>
          <li><b>Auto-renewal Impact Info</b> - A blue information box that appears when your
            organization has an active paid subscription with auto-renewal enabled. This warning
            states: "Deleting this organization will also disable the auto-renewal of your
            subscription."</li>
        </ul><note type="important">The auto-renewal warning only appears for organizations with
          paid subscriptions purchased through the Verifone system where auto-renewal is currently
          enabled. If you do not see this warning, your subscription either does not have
          auto-renewal enabled or was not purchased through the Verifone system.</note></p>
        <p id="div_deletion_process"><u><b>Deleting an Organization</b></u></p>
        <p>To delete your organization: <ol id="ol_deletion_process">
          <li>Review all warning messages carefully, including the auto-renewal impact if
            applicable.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Delete organization</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li>If your organization has auto-renewal enabled, the system will automatically disable
            auto-renewal as part of the deletion process.</li>
          <li>The organization will be immediately suspended and scheduled for permanent deletion
            after 14 days.</li>
          <li>All users will lose access to organization resources immediately.</li>
          <li>You will receive email notifications about the deletion schedule.</li>
        </ol><note type="important">Once the deletion process begins, auto-renewal is permanently
          disabled even if you later cancel the organization deletion. You cannot re-enable
          auto-renewal through the <ph keyref="product"/> interface after it has been disabled
          during the deletion process.</note></p>
      <p id="p_dbc_nc1_zgc"><u><b>Cancelling Organization Deletion</b></u></p>
      <p id="p_asj_lc1_zgc">
        <fig id="fig_jkm_lc1_zgc">
          <title>Cancel Organization Deletion</title>
          <image href="../img/cf-organization-settings-page-cancel-deletion.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_uth_h21_zgc">If you change your mind after scheduling deletion, you can cancel it
        during the 14-day grace period:<ol id="ol_cancellation_process">
          <li id="li_qv5_h21_zgc">Navigate to the Organization Settings page.</li>
          <li id="li_rv5_h21_zgc">You will see a warning section titled "Organization scheduled for
            deletion" with an orange warning box.</li>
          <li id="li_sv5_h21_zgc">Click the <uicontrol>Cancel deletion</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li id="li_tv5_h21_zgc">The organization will be restored to active status.</li>
          <li id="li_uv5_h21_zgc">Users will regain access to organization resources.</li>
        </ol><note type="important" id="note_d3t_321_zgc">Cancelling organization deletion does NOT
          re-enable auto-renewal. If auto-renewal was disabled during the deletion process, it
          remains disabled even after cancellation. You must manually re-enable auto-renewal through
          your Verifone account management interface if you want automatic renewal to
        resume.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_auto_renewal_impact">
      <title>Auto-renewal and Subscription Impact After Organization Deletion</title>
      <p>Organization deletion has specific impacts on subscription management that administrators
        should understand:</p>
        <p id="div_auto_renewal_disable"><u><b>Automatic Auto-renewal Disable</b></u></p>
      <p id="p_icc_t21_zgc">When you delete an organization with auto-renewal enabled:<ul
          id="ul_auto_renewal_disable">
          <li id="li_rnk_t21_zgc">The system automatically disables auto-renewal as part of the
            deletion process.</li>
          <li id="li_snk_t21_zgc">This prevents future automatic charges for a subscription that
            will be deleted.</li>
          <li id="li_tnk_t21_zgc">The auto-renewal disable occurs before the organization is
            suspended.</li>
          <li id="li_unk_t21_zgc">If auto-renewal cannot be disabled, the deletion process will fail
            with an error message.</li>
        </ul></p>
        <p id="div_subscription_continuation"><u><b>Subscription Status After Deletion</b></u></p>
      <p id="p_olg_s21_zgc">After organization deletion:<ul id="ul_subscription_continuation">
          <li id="li_k1p_s21_zgc">Your subscription remains active until its natural expiration
            date.</li>
          <li id="li_l1p_s21_zgc">Auto-renewal is permanently disabled.</li>
          <li id="li_m1p_s21_zgc">If you cancel the deletion, the subscription remains active but
            auto-renewal stays disabled.</li>
          <li id="li_n1p_s21_zgc">You must manually renew before expiration if you want to continue
            using the service.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_troubleshooting_settings">
      <title>Troubleshooting Organization Settings</title>
      <p>If you encounter issues with organization settings management:</p>
      <ul id="ul_settings_troubleshooting">
        <li><b>Access Issues</b> - Ensure you have Organization Administrator privileges to access
          settings management features.</li>
        <li><b>Avatar Upload Problems</b> - Verify that your image file is in a supported format
            (<filepath>JPG</filepath>, <filepath>PNG</filepath>, <filepath>WebP</filepath>) and is
          not too large (recommended maximum 100kB).</li>
        <li><b>Display Name Changes</b> - If display name changes do not appear immediately, refresh
          the page or check that you have the necessary permissions.</li>
        <li><b>Deletion Process Issues</b> - If organization deletion fails, check that auto-renewal
          can be disabled successfully. Contact support if the issue persists.</li>
        <li><b>Auto-renewal Note </b> - If you do not see the auto-renewal warning when expected,
          verify that your subscription is paid and purchased through Verifone with auto-renewal
          enabled.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
