<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace_publications_view">
  <title>Workspace Publications View</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_xkq_hrz_vbc">A Content Fusion <i>publication</i> defines a DITA map that is used to
      resolve keys in topics and optionally, a DITAVAL filter used for flagging or filtering
      profiled content.</p>
    <p id="p_pnt_yd3_cfc">The <uicontrol>Publications</uicontrol> view (found inside the project's
        <xref href="cf-projects-workspace.dita">Personal Workspace</xref>) displays the map of a
      publication in a tree editor to make navigating through the topics easier. For a publication
      to appear, it must first be defined in the <xref
        href="#cf-projects-workspace_publications_view/section_cws_2lh_1fc"><uicontrol>Publications
          Management</uicontrol> dialog box</xref>. <note id="note_zmx_klh_1fc">If you have modified
        the publications using the <xref href="cf-projects-publications.dita">project
            <uicontrol>Publications Management</uicontrol> page</xref>, you also need to pull <xref
          href="cf-projects-workspace_incoming_changes.dita">incoming changes into your
          workspace</xref> to retrieve the latest publications. </note></p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Workspace Publications View</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-workspace-publication.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_x2z_ktz_vbc">To select a defined publication, use the publications drop-down control in
      the side-pane. This publication will be used as the context of the open editors. Changing the
      publication triggers a reload of the currently open editor to match the new context.</p>
    <p id="p_hfm_p21_5fc">To add a new publication, click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/CF-AddPub16.png"/>Add publication</uicontrol> button at the top-right corner
      of the view's header. This button opens a drop-down menu with options for creating a new
        publication:<ul id="ul_ifm_p21_5fc">
        <li id="li_jfm_p21_5fc"><uicontrol>From existing DITA map</uicontrol> - Adds a new
          publication based on an existing DITA map. In the resulting dialog box, you enter a name
          for the publication and specify the context DITA map and optionally, a DITAVAL filter
          file.</li>
        <li id="li_kfm_p21_5fc"><uicontrol>From new map</uicontrol> - Adds a new publication based
          on a new DITA map. In the resulting dialog box, you enter a <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol>
          for the new publication, specify the path of the <uicontrol>Parent folder</uicontrol>, and
          choose the <uicontrol>Map type</uicontrol> (either <i>Map</i> or <i>Bookmap</i>).</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p id="p_vy5_pf1_5fc">When finished configuring the options, click the
        <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol> button at the bottom of the dialog box to add the
      publication.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/Cf-ManagePub16.png"/>Manage Publications</uicontrol>
      button at the top-right corner of the view 's header can be used to open a <xref
        href="#cf-projects-workspace_publications_view/section_cws_2lh_1fc"><uicontrol>Manage
          Publications</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> where you have access to all publication
      management features, including creating, editing, and deleting publications. You can also
      reach this configuration dialog box by selecting <uicontrol>Manage publications</uicontrol>
      from the publications drop-down list.</p>
    <p id="p_vrd_dd5_rcc">You can click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/cfRefresh16.png"
        />Refresh</uicontrol> button at the top-right corner of the view 's header to refresh the
      list of publications.</p>
    <p id="p_p2x_vtn_zbc">You can click on a file displayed in the side-pane to open it in the
      visual editor (or double-click a file when the map is open in the tree editor).</p>
    <p id="p_zcc_mtz_vbc">
      <note type="notice">The <uicontrol>Enable tree editing in the Publications
          side-view</uicontrol> option in the Profile Settings page must be selected (default value)
        for the map to be editable. If that option is deselected, the map is displayed as read
        only.</note>
    </p>
    <p>You can use the <uicontrol>Type to filter</uicontrol> text field to search for a file by
      name.</p>
    <section id="section_cws_2lh_1fc">
      <title>Manage Publications Dialog Box</title>
      <p id="p_qwf_423_cfc">
        <fig id="fig_rwf_423_cfc">
          <title>Manage Publications Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/cf-manage-publications.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Manage Publications</uicontrol> dialog box allows you to create and
        configure publications. These publications can be used as context in new review tasks, in
        deliverables, and in your personal workspace.</p>
      <p>To add a new publication from the management dialog box, click the <uicontrol>New
          Publication</uicontrol> button in the top-right corner. This button opens a drop-down menu
        with options for creating a new publication:<ul id="ul_d4r_qd1_5fc">
          <li id="li_e4r_qd1_5fc"><uicontrol>From existing DITA map</uicontrol> - Adds a new
            publication based on an existing DITA map. In the resulting dialog box, you enter a name
            for the publication and specify the context DITA map and optionally, a DITAVAL filter
            file.</li>
          <li id="li_g3w_b21_5fc"><uicontrol>From new map</uicontrol> - Adds a new publication based
            on a new DITA map. In the resulting dialog box, you enter a <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol>
            for the new publication, specify the path of the <uicontrol>Parent folder</uicontrol>,
            and choose the <uicontrol>Map type</uicontrol> (either <i>Map</i> or
            <i>Bookmap</i>).</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p id="p_l1g_lf1_5fc">When finished configuring the options, click the
          <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol> button at the bottom of the dialog box to add the
        publication.</p>
      <p>To edit an existing publication, click the <uicontrol>Configure</uicontrol> button next to
        the particular publication. To delete an existing publication, click the
          <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button next to the particular publication.</p>
      <p>If you have an existing <xref
          href="https://www.dita-ot.org/dev/topics/using-project-files.html" format="html"
          scope="external">DITA-OT project file</xref>, you can include all the
          <codeph>&lt;context></codeph> elements as Publications in your <ph keyref="product"/>
        project using the <uicontrol>Include Publications</uicontrol> button (available when
        managing publications from the workspace). This action will add an
          <codeph>&lt;include></codeph> element in the <ph keyref="product"/>'s builtin DITA-OT
        project file.<note id="note_wfl_2mh_1fc">There are some limitations in regard to the
          supported DITA-OT project files:<p>
            <ul id="ul_uby_1ph_1fc">
              <li>A <codeph>&lt;context></codeph> element that contains more than one
                  <codeph>&lt;profile></codeph> element is not supported and will be ignored.</li>
              <li>Deliverables are not loaded from your project file, but may be in the future.</li>
            </ul>
          </p></note></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
