<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects">
  <title>Projects and Publishing</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Projects</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_o2t_pl3_vxb"><ph keyref="product"/> offers the ability to connect to an existing Git
      repository that has a DITA project as its source. This is managed within the Content Fusion
      browser interface through a feature known as <term>Projects</term>. Users with a <i>Content
        Fusion Author</i> role can create review tasks inside a project and reviewers' suggestions
      are tracked on a dedicated branch in the Git repository. You can also use the
        <term>Projects</term> feature to build and configure deliverables for creating PDF or <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/xml_webhelp/webhelp_responsive.html" format="html"
        scope="external"><b>Oxygen WebHelp Responsive</b></xref> output. Projects also provide
      access to the <xref href="cf-projects-workspace.dita"><term>personal workspace</term>
        feature</xref> that allows authors to make changes across multiple files within a project
      and then commit them to the project.</p>
    <section id="what_is_a_project_in_content_fusion">
      <title>What is a Project in Content Fusion?</title>
      <p id="p_t3k_nm3_vxb">A Content Fusion <b>Project</b>:<ul id="ul_h2q_s4f_zxb">
          <li id="li_i2q_s4f_zxb">Defines a connection to a Git repository that contains DITA
            content.</li>
          <li id="li_vdg_x4f_zxb">Provides a graphical interface to manage the DITA project and
            review processes within the project.</li>
          <li id="li_yhv_1pf_zxb">Allows Authors to create review tasks inside the project and
            reviewer suggestions are tracked on a dedicated branch that is traced in the Git
            repository.</li>
          <li id="li_jlk_mkt_zxb">Helps Authors with building WebHelp or PDF outputs via
              <i>Publications</i> and <i>Deliverables</i>.</li>
          <li id="li_orr_mkt_zxb">Acts as a read-only clone of the Git repository making it
            compatible with existing workflows and tools.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="user_roles">
      <title>User Roles</title>
      <p>When working with projects, there are two user roles:<ul>
          <li><b>Subject Matter Expert (SME)</b> - By default, Content Fusion users have the Subject
            Matter Expert (SME) role assigned. This role allows the user to access review tasks
            assigned to them and to create review tasks from scratch.</li>
          <li><b>Content Fusion Author</b> - This role must be assigned to a user by an
            administrator. In addition to the features that an SME has access to, Content Fusion
            Authors can access all projects and are able to create review tasks inside projects, as
            well as other functionality that is restricted from an SME. They also have access to the
              <xref href="wa-ai-positron.dita"><uicontrol>AI Positron Assistant</uicontrol></xref>
            that provides various ways to use AI-generated content or suggestions while editing or
            reviewing content.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>The license for Content Fusion covers a number of user-based licenses for authors and a
        number of floating licenses for SMEs. A system administrator can assign roles<ph
          product="fusion"> from the <xref href="cf-enterprise-configuration.dita">Administration
            page</xref></ph>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="projects_main_page">
      <title>Main Projects Page</title>
      <p id="p_ppx_2xm_42c"><uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> is one of the two main components (along
        with <b>Review Tasks</b>) within the Content Fusion browser interface. The main
          <uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> page displays a list of all the current projects that are
        available for your organization and your user role.</p>
      <p id="p_qpx_2xm_42c">
        <fig id="fig_rpx_2xm_42c">
          <title>Main Projects Page</title>
          <image href="../img/cf-projects-page.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_kg2_4yb_tbc">To open an existing project, simply click on it. This opens the <xref
          href="cf-projects-review-tasks.dita">project <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol>
          page</xref> by default.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_spx_2xm_42c">
      <title>Branch Management</title>
      <p id="p_lg2_4yb_tbc453">When a project is open, the second stripe at the top includes a
        branch management drop-down menu. The current branch is displayed inside the box and you can
        click it to select a different branch (all the Git branches from your project are
        available).</p>
      <p id="p_ysm_ytf_zxb">
        <fig id="fig_zsm_ytf_zxb">
          <title>Top Header Stripes Inside a Project</title>
          <image href="../img/CF-top-stripe-actions-project.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_lg2_4yb_tbc45345354">In addition to being able to change the branch, the branch
        management drop-down also contains the following actions:<ul id="ul_tpx_2xm_42c">
          <li id="li_upx_2xm_42c"><uicontrol>Create new branch</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog box
            where you can choose the name for a new branch and an existing branch to base it
            on.</li>
          <li id="li_vpx_2xm_42c"><uicontrol>Delete branch</uicontrol> - Opens a confirmation dialog
            box where you have the option to delete the current branch.</li>
          <li id="li_wpx_2xm_42c"><uicontrol>Merge into current branch</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog
            box where you can select an existing branch to merge into the current branch.<p
              id="p_mvp_vnh_42c">
              <fig id="fig_o3w_vnh_42c">
                <title>Merge Branch Dialog Box</title>
                <image href="../img/cf-merge-branch.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p><p id="p_e24_ynh_42c">In the <uicontrol>Merge Branch</uicontrol> dialog box, you can
              select which branch to merge into the current one. Click <uicontrol>Merge</uicontrol>
              to initiate the process. If the merge succeeds without conflicts, a <uicontrol>Merge
                successful</uicontrol> message is displayed. </p><p id="p_x3q_vvv_p2c">If there are
              files with conflicting changes, a special <xref
                href="cf-projects-workspace-conflict-resolution.dita#cf-projects-workspace-conflict-resolution/section_dzh_kdb_p2c"
                >branch merging conflict resolution dialog box</xref> is initiated where you can
              choose a merge action for each particular conflict and you can view each version of a
              conflicted file in a side-by-side comparison view.</p></li>
        </ul></p>
      <p id="p_lg2_4yb_tbc442">An <uicontrol>Edit in workspace</uicontrol> button is always
        displayed in an additional stripe below the top stripe. You can use this button from
        anywhere within the project to edit the project in a <xref href="cf-projects-workspace.dita"
            ><term>personal workspace</term></xref> that allows you to make changes across multiple
        files within the project and then commit them to the repository.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="create-projects">
      <title>Creating a New Project</title>
      <p>Click the <uicontrol>New project</uicontrol> button to create a new project. This opens a
        dialog box where you can choose between two options for creating a project:</p>
      <ul id="ul_bzx_h2h_1fc">
        <li><b>Import from Git</b> - Configure the connection to your Git repository. It includes
          the following fields: <ul id="ul_czx_h2h_1fc">
            <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The name of the project.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> - The description of the project. It is displayed
              under the project's name in the main <uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> page.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Project URL</uicontrol> - The URL of the Git repository.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Branch</uicontrol> - The default branch of the project.</li>
            <li id="visibility-li"><uicontrol>Visibility</uicontrol> - You can choose between
                <uicontrol>Public</uicontrol> (accessible by all members) or
                <uicontrol>Private</uicontrol> (restricts access to select members).</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Username and Access Token</uicontrol> - You can enter the Git credentials
              (username and access token) using this option. <note id="note_ymy_qh5_cbc">The
                personal access token for GitHub must have the following permissions: <ul
                  id="ul_ej1_135_cbc">
                  <li><menucascade>
                      <uicontrol>Repository permissions</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol>Contents</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol>Read and Write</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade>.</li>
                  <li>You should also specify which repositories it has access to.</li>
                </ul></note></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Git Account</uicontrol> - Use this option to select a preconfigured Git
              account.</li>
            <li>Once you are done configuring the details, click the <uicontrol>Create
                project</uicontrol> button to finish the creation process. </li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b>Create from a template</b> - Choose the following configuration options: <ul
            id="ul_kfp_j2h_1fc">
            <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The name of the project.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> - The description of the project. It is displayed
              under the project's name in the main <uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> page.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Visibility</uicontrol> - You can choose between
                <uicontrol>Public</uicontrol> (accessible by all members) or
                <uicontrol>Private</uicontrol> (restricts access to select members).</li>
            <li><b>Template</b> - You can choose from predefined templates to create a project. The
              available templates include: <ul id="ul_ozx_h2h_1fc">
                <li>An empty project</li>
                <li>A "starter" DITA project</li>
                <li>Two sample DITA projects:  </li>
              </ul><p>
                <note id="note_ohb_x2h_1fc">A project created from a template is stored internally
                  in Content Fusion. Later, you can <xref
                    href="cf-projects-settings.dita#cf-projects-settings/section_m45_yph_1fc">link
                    an external Git repository</xref>, and all the content will be moved to that
                  repository</note>
              </p>
            </li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul>
      <p>The newly created project is automatically opened with the <xref
          href="cf-projects-content.dita">project's <uicontrol>Content</uicontrol> page</xref>
        displayed.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
