<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace">
  <title>Personal Workspace</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Personal Workspace</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_pxg_l3m_fgc">When opening a project, it automatically opens in a <term>Personal
        Workspace</term>, which allows you to make changes across multiple files within a project
      and then commit them to the project. Editing inside a <term>Personal Workspace</term> means
      that your changes are private until you commit them to the project's repository.</p>
    <p id="p_w3v_jzb_tbc">Once inside the project's personal workspace, the left stripe contains
      navigation options to open the various project management pages. On the right side of the
      second top stripe, an <xref href="cf-projects-workspace_incoming_changes.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Incoming commits</uicontrol></xref> widget shows if there are incoming changes
      and you can click the drop-down to display more information and access additional actions.</p>
    <p id="p_ztw_s3m_fgc">When a file (document) is open, it appears in the visual editor (within
      the main pane to the right of the file tree pane). Whenever a change is made to a document in
      the visual editor, a <uicontrol>Commit Changes</uicontrol> button also appears to the right of
      the <uicontrol>Incoming commits</uicontrol> drop-down. Clicking this button opens the <xref
        href="cf-projects-workspace_changes_view.dita"><uicontrol>Changes</uicontrol> view</xref>
      where you can commit the changes to the repository.</p>
    <p id="p_a5w_s3m_fgc">
      <fig id="fig_b5w_s3m_fgc">
        <title>Commit Changes</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-header-commit.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section conkeyref="reusables-cf/section_branch-management" id="section-br-mgmnt"></section>
      <note>When
        trying to merge branches inside the Personal Workspace, the merge cannot be processed if you have any local outgoing changes. In
        this case, a warning dialog box is displayed informing you that the outgoing changes must be
        committed or discarded before attempting the merge.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
