<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-deliverables">
  <title>Project Deliverables Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Project deliverables page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The dedicated <uicontrol>Project Deliverables</uicontrol> page provides tools for building
      and configuring deliverables. A Content Fusion deliverable defines the output of a
      publication. WebHelp and PDF are the supported types of output.</p>
    <p id="p_qqk_ddn_zxb">
      <fig id="fig_fhp_ddn_zxb">
        <title>Project Deliverables Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF-deliverables.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_spr_kcn_zxb">From this page, you can create a new deliverable, build an existing
      deliverable, view logs, or download the deliverable as a ZIP archive. You can even schedule a
      periodic build for a deliverable to automate the process.</p>
    <p id="p_xkm_5xn_32c">The current branch is displayed in the header stripe. However, the
      publishing functionality is limited to using the project's default branch (multiple branches
      will be supported in future versions).</p>
    <p>To start building an existing deliverable, click the <uicontrol>Build</uicontrol> button of
      the right side of the particular deliverable. The progress of the build is displayed while it
      is building. While it is processing (or after), you can click the <uicontrol>Log
        File</uicontrol> button for the particular build to see the details of its progress. After
      it is finished, it shows whether or not the build was successful and information about the
      time.</p>
    <p id="p_ofx_5wx_cgc">You can click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button to further customize
      the particular deliverable (you can also click on the connector name next to the
        <uicontrol>Deploy to</uicontrol> label to edit the deliverable). You can click the
        <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button to delete the deliverable and its associated
      builds.</p>
    <p>If you choose to deploy the output using the <xref href="cf-publishing-connectors.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Content Fusion Docs Web Platform</uicontrol></xref>, you can click
        <uicontrol>View deployments</uicontrol> to the right of the connector name to see a pop-up
      window with the deployment builds for this connector. Each deployment includes a link to open
      the output for the latest successful build. You can share this link with others since the
      output is public.</p>
    <p>You can click the <uicontrol>Download</uicontrol> button next to the particular build to
      download an archive of the build package and then use it to publish the output using whatever
      tool you want.</p>
    <section id="section_tfl_xpp_zxb">
      <title>Creating a New Deliverable and Customizing the Output</title>
      <p>To create a new deliverable, click the <uicontrol>New Deliverable</uicontrol> button at the
        top-right corner of the <uicontrol>Project Deliverables</uicontrol> page. This opens the
          <uicontrol>New Deliverable</uicontrol> page where you can create the output
        configuration.</p>
      <p id="p_swp_krp_zxb">
        <fig id="fig_kpx_krp_zxb">
          <title>New Deliverable Page</title>
          <image href="../img/CF-new-deliverable.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_jqr_2sp_zxb">This page includes the following options:</p>
      <p id="p_b3x_c5p_zxb">
        <dl id="dl_lwz_c5p_zxb">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_mwz_c5p_zxb">
            <dt>Name</dt>
            <dd>The name of the deliverable.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_xjz_d5p_zxb">
            <dt>Description</dt>
            <dd>The description of the deliverable.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_bjz_g5p_zxb">
            <dt>Publication</dt>
            <dd>Use this option to specify an existing <xref href="cf-projects-publications.dita"
                >publication</xref> to use in the build. The publication defines a DITA map and
              DITAVAL filter file pair.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_awl_krn_ybc">
            <dt>Add 'Edit Online' links</dt>
            <dd>If this option is enabled, an "Edit online" link is displayed in the top-right
              corner of each topic within the published output. These links open the source document
              in the <xref href="cf-projects-workspace.dita">Content Fusion personal
                workspace</xref> where the user can make changes and commit directly to the
              project's default branch. When using this in conjunction with automated builds and
              publishing connectors, the changes can be seen live within minutes.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_n3c_v5p_zxb">
            <dt>Automatically trigger build when changes are detected in the source repository</dt>
            <dd>If this option is enabled (default), a build will automatically be triggered if
              there are changes detected in the source repository.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_kys_r5p_zxb">
            <dt>Schedule Build</dt>
            <dd>Use this option to schedule a periodic build so that it processes automatically at
              the specified times.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_ev2_hvp_zxb">
            <dt>Type</dt>
            <dd>The type of output. You can choose between <uicontrol>WebHelp</uicontrol> or
                <uicontrol>PDF</uicontrol>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_okf_jvp_zxb">
            <dt>Select a Template</dt>
            <dd>Choose between:<p id="p_ovc_3wp_zxb">
                <dl id="dl_w1f_3wp_zxb">
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_x1f_3wp_zxb">
                    <dt>Use template from templates gallery</dt>
                    <dd>Select this option to select a template from the built-in gallery. Click on
                      the preview image of the current template to open the gallery. From here,
                      select the template you want to use and click the
                        <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol> button at the bottom.<note
                        id="note_fz3_gxp_zxb" type="tip">You can click the 3 vertical dots at the
                        bottom-right corner of a template to access additional options for the
                        template (e.g. <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>,
                        <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Download</uicontrol>,
                          <uicontrol>See WebHelp</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>See
                        PDF</uicontrol>).</note><p id="p_hfq_mwp_zxb">
                        <dl id="dl_rkg_nwp_zxb">
                          <dlentry id="dlentry_skg_nwp_zxb">
                            <dt>Choose other template</dt>
                            <dd>Click this button if you want to duplicate an existing template to
                              customize fine details in the output. This opens the template gallery.
                              Follow these instructions:<ol id="ol_dd1_byp_zxb">
                                <li id="li_ed1_byp_zxb">Select the template you want to
                                  duplicate.</li>
                                <li id="li_mfm_byp_zxb">Click the 3 vertical dots on that template
                                  and select <uicontrol>Duplicate &amp; Edit</uicontrol>.</li>
                                <li id="li_bfb_cyp_zxb">Choose a name for the new template and click
                                    <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol>. This automatically opens it in
                                  the <b>Oxygen Styles Basket</b>, which is a simple web-based tool
                                  that makes it very easy to customize the look and feel of your PDF
                                  or WebHelp output. For more details, go to <xref
                                    href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/styles_basket.html"
                                    format="html" scope="external"/>.</li>
                                <li id="li_lvm_cyp_zxb">When you are done customizing the styling,
                                  click the <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol> button in the top-right
                                  corner. This automatically re-opens the template gallery page and
                                  your newly customized template is listed in the top section.</li>
                                <li id="li_emr_gyp_zxb">Select new customized template and click the
                                    <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol> button at the bottom.</li>
                                <li id="li_uwg_jyp_zxb">Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to
                                  complete the deliverable.</li>
                              </ol></dd>
                          </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                      </p></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_uxz_kwp_zxb">
                    <dt><uicontrol>Use template from source repository</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Select this option to specify the path to a directory that contains custom
                        templates.<note id="note_nbr_3ql_lzb">There are 2 ways to obtain a custom
                        template to use for transformations:<ul id="ul_prd_mql_lzb">
                          <li><u><b>Oxygen Styles Basket</b></u><p>You can use the <xref
                                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/styles_basket.html" format="html"
                                scope="external"><b>Oxygen Styles Basket</b></xref> to customize a
                              custom template. After finishing with your customization, you can
                              download it by using the <b>Download</b> button on the upper toolbar.
                              You can then add the template folder to your Git repository and use it
                              for the transformation.</p></li>
                          <li><u><b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b></u><p>You can use <b><xref
                                  href="https://oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/cshelp.html?contextId=create-your-own-templates"
                                  format="html" scope="external">Oxygen XML Editor/Author</xref></b>
                              to create your own custom document templates. These templates can then
                              be added to your Git repository and used for transformations.</p></li>
                        </ul></note></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_r3z_vc3_zbc">
            <dt>Deploy output using</dt>
            <dd product="fusion">Select this option to use a publishing connector to build the
              output for deliverables. You also need to select the particular connector from the
              drop-down menu below the option. Note that you must first configure the connector in
              the <xref href="cf-publishing-connectors.dita">publishing
                  <uicontrol>Connectors</uicontrol> page</xref>. The following connector types are
                supported:<ul id="ul_vsh_lxk_3bc">
                <li id="li_ywy_5yv_w2c"><xref
                    href="https://oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-amazon-s3-connector.html"
                    format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Amazon S3</uicontrol></xref></li>
                <li id="li_zwy_5yv_w2c"><xref
                    href="https://oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-netlify-connector.html"
                    format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Netlify</uicontrol></xref></li>
                <li id="li_axy_5yv_w2c"><xref
                    href="https://oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-sftp-connector.html"
                    format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>SFTP Server</uicontrol></xref></li>
                <li id="li_khq_4sx_cgc"><xref href="cf-publishing-connectors.dita"
                      ><uicontrol>Content Fusion Docs Web Platform</uicontrol></xref> - This is a
                  built-in connector that deploys the output to a web platform that is accessible
                  publicly. When you create a new project, Content Fusion automatically generates
                  this connector for that project.</li>
              </ul></dd>
            <dd product="fusion-cloud">Select this option to deploy the output using the built-in
                <xref href="cf-publishing-connectors.dita"><uicontrol>Content Fusion Docs Web
                  Platform</uicontrol></xref>. When you create a project in Content Fusion, this
              connector is automatically generated for that project. This connector enables you to
              publish the output of your deliverables using a built-in publishing connector that
              deploys the output to a web platform that is accessible publicly. This feature
              simplifies the process of publishing and sharing documentation and ensures that all
              projects are immediately ready for web-based collaboration and publishing.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
