<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace">
  <title>Project Workspace</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Project workspace</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Add workspace</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_lg2_4yb_tbc">Once a project is open, an additional stripe is displayed below the top
      stripe with an <uicontrol>Open Workspace</uicontrol> button that creates a workspace branch
      starting from the latest version on the "main" branch. If a workspace is already creating,
      invoking the button opens the already existing workspace.</p>
    <p id="p_w3v_jzb_tbc">When a workspace is open, the left stripe contains the following
      navigation options:<ul id="ul_r1y_nzb_tbc">
        <li id="li_s1y_nzb_tbc"><uicontrol>Files</uicontrol> - Displays the file tree of the
          workspace. You can expand or collapse folders similar to any common file browser. Click on
          a file to open it in the visual editor. To add a folder to the workspace, click the 3
          vertical dots next to the parent folder. To delete a file from the workspace, click the 3
          vertical dots next to the particular file and select <uicontrol>Delete
          file</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li id="li_r1l_4zb_tbc"><uicontrol>Publications</uicontrol> - Displays the map of a
          publication in a tree editor. Use the drop-down control in the side-pane to select a
          defined publication. You can click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CF-OpenEditor16.png"
            />Open in editor</uicontrol> button to open the DITA map defined in the particular
          publication in a tree editor that is displayed in the main visual editing area. You can
          click on a file displayed in the side-pane to open it in the visual editor (or
          double-click a file when the map is open in the tree editor).</li>
        <li id="li_aqx_4zb_tbc"><uicontrol>Changes</uicontrol> - Displays all the files that have
          been changed in the workspace. You can click on a file to see a comparison (diff) of the
          changes. The version on the left shows the current workspace version while the version on
          the right shows the current project version. To open a file in the visual editor, click
          the 3 vertical dots next to the particular file and select <uicontrol>Open
            file</uicontrol>. To discard any changes you have made on a file in the workspace, click
          the 3 vertical dots next to the particular file and select <uicontrol>Discard
            changes</uicontrol>.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
