<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace">
  <title>Personal Workspace</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Workspace</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit in workspace</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <term>personal workspace</term> feature allows you to make changes across multiple files
      within a project and then commit them to the project.</p>
    <p id="p_lg2_4yb_tbc">Once a project is open, an additional stripe is displayed below the top
      stripe with an <uicontrol>Edit in workspace</uicontrol> button that creates a personal
      workspace branch starting from the latest version on the project branch. If a personal
      workspace is already created, invoking the button opens the already existing workspace. You
      can also go straight to the personal workspace from the <xref
        href="cf-projects.dita#cf-projects/projects_main_page">main Projects page</xref>.</p>
    <p id="p_ysm_ytf_zxb">
      <fig id="fig_zsm_ytf_zxb">
        <title>Top Stripe Actions Inside a Project</title>
        <image href="../img/CF-top-stripe-actions-project.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_w3v_jzb_tbc">Once inside a personal workspace, the second top stripe changes to make it
      clear that you are editing inside the <uicontrol>Personal Workspace</uicontrol>. The left
      stripe contains navigation options to open the <xref
        href="cf-projects-workspace_files_view.dita"><uicontrol>Files</uicontrol></xref>, <xref
        href="cf-projects-workspace_publications_view.dita"
        ><uicontrol>Publications</uicontrol></xref>, <xref
        href="cf-projects-workspace_changes_view.dita"><uicontrol>Changes</uicontrol></xref>, <xref
        href="cf-projects-workspace_problems_view.dita"><uicontrol>Problems</uicontrol></xref>, or
        <xref href="cf-projects-workspace_search_view.dita"><uicontrol>Search</uicontrol></xref>
      side-views. On the right side of the second top stripe, an <xref
        href="cf-projects-workspace_incoming_changes.dita"><uicontrol>Incoming
        commits</uicontrol></xref> widget shows if there are incoming changes and you can click the
      drop-down to display more information and access additional actions.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Inside the Personal Workspace</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-workspace1.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>When a file (document) is open, it appears in the visual editor (within the main pane to the
      right of the file tree pane). Whenever a change is made to a document in the visual editor, a
        <uicontrol>Commit Changes</uicontrol> button appears at the far-right side of the header
      stripe. Clicking this button opens the <xref href="cf-projects-workspace_changes_view.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Changes</uicontrol> view</xref> where you can commit the changes to the
      repository.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Commit Changes</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-header-commit.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
