<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-publishing-connectors">
  <title>Publishing Connectors</title>
  <body>
    <p>The publishing <uicontrol>Connectors</uicontrol> page shows the publishing connectors that are defined for a project. To reach the page, go to <uicontrol>Deliverables</uicontrol> (found at the bottom of the left navigation stripe when inside a project), then click <uicontrol>Connectors</uicontrol> from the left stripe.</p>

    <section id="available_connector_types">
      <title>Available Connector Types</title>
      <p>The following connector types are available for Content Fusion:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <xref
            href="https://oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-amazon-s3-connector.html"
            format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Amazon S3</uicontrol></xref>
        </li>
        <li>
          <xref href="https://oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-netlify-connector.html"
            format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Netlify</uicontrol></xref>
        </li>
        <li>
          <xref href="https://oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-sftp-connector.html"
            format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>SFTP Server</uicontrol></xref>
        </li>
        <li product="fusion-cloud">
          <xref href="cfdocs-output-hosting.dita"><uicontrol>Content Fusion Docs Web Platform</uicontrol></xref> - This built-in connector is only available in the Cloud version. It deploys the output to a web platform that is accessible publicly. When you create a new project, Content Fusion automatically generates this connector for that project. You can click the <uicontrol>View deployments</uicontrol> button to see a pop-up window with the deployments for this connector. Each deployment includes a link to open the output for the latest successful build, which you can share with others.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <note id="note_gd2_hjc_dgc" product="fusion-cloud">The Content Fusion Docs Web Platform connector does not need to be configured, it will be created immediately.</note>
      <p>To create a new connector, click the <uicontrol>New Connector</uicontrol> button located in the top-right corner of the page. Then, select the desired connector type and fill in the necessary fields in the resulting dialog box.</p>
      <p product="fusion">You can click the ellipsis (3 vertical dots) to the right of a connector to reveal actions to <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> it.</p>
      <p product="fusion-cloud">You can click the ellipsis (3 vertical dots) to the right of a connector to reveal actions to <xref href="cf-projects-deliverables.dita"><uicontrol>View deliverables</uicontrol> for the connector</xref>, <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> it, or <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> it.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
