<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-repository">
  <title>Project Repository Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Repository page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Repository</uicontrol> page displays all of the submitted/committed content
      for the current project and provides ways to open/edit the files in the visual editor, add
      files to a new review task, and <xref href="#./section-br-mgmnt">branch management
        actions</xref> are available from the branch drop-down menu in the header stripe.</p>
    <p id="p_zj4_5sn_zxb">
      <fig id="fig_ak4_5sn_zxb">
        <title>Project Repository Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF-project-content.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_i4h_3cn_zxb">You can expand or collapse folders similar to any common file browser.
      Double-click on a file to open it (as read-only) in the visual editor. If you hover over a
      folder or file, a 3 vertical dots menu appears. It contains contextual actions for that
      particular folder or file.</p>
    <p>To add a file to a new review task that will be created, click the 3 vertical dots next to
      the file and select <uicontrol>Add to review task</uicontrol>. This initiates a new task
      creation process. You need to specify a <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> and select a
        <uicontrol>Context Publication</uicontrol>, which is the DITA map that will be used to
      resolve keys in the topics that will be sent for review (see <xref
        href="cf-projects-publications.dita">Project Publications</xref> for more details).</p>
    <p id="p_qf4_tdn_zxb">You can use the <image href="../img/CF-synch-project18.png"/> button at
      the top-right of the <uicontrol>Files</uicontrol> pane to synchronize the information in the
      view with the Content Fusion server.</p>
    <p>You can use the <uicontrol>Filter by name</uicontrol> text field to search for a file by
      name.</p>
    <section id="section_vr1_1rm_cfc">
      <title>Proposing Changes to Project Files</title>
      <p>Project files cannot be edited directly. Instead, changes must be proposed through one of
        two dedicated workflows. These workflows ensure that edits are made in a controlled,
        traceable way, supporting collaboration, review, and versioning.</p>
      <p>Whenever you open a file from a project, a message appears at the top of the editor to let
        you know the file is read-only and offers the following options for proposing changes:</p>
      <ul id="ul_wr1_1rm_cfc">
        <li>
          <p><b>Edit in Workspace</b> - This opens the file in your personal workspace (a private
            drafting area where you can make changes freely). Once you are satisfied with your
            updates, you can commit them to the project along with a commit message.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><b>Start Review Task</b> - This starts a review process involving the current file. You
            can suggest changes that can then be discussed and reviewed by collaborators. Once
            approved, the updates can be integrated into the project.</p>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section conkeyref="reusables-cf/section_branch-management" id="section-br-mgmnt"/>
  </body>
</topic>
