<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace_changes_view">
  <title>Project Changes View</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Changes</uicontrol> view displays all the files that have been changed in the workspace. It contains two tabs: <uicontrol>Made by you</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>History</uicontrol>.</p>

    <section id="made_by_you_tab">
      <title>Made by You Tab</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Made by you</uicontrol> tab displays all the changes you have made in your workspace. It provides the following main options:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Commit</b>: Allows you to commit your changes to the project. You can select which
          files to include in the commit using check-boxes next to each file. Files not selected
          will remain in your workspace. <ul>
            <li>When you are ready, click the <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> button, provide a commit
              message, and commit your changes.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b>New Review Task</b>: Allows you to create a review task that contains all your
          current changes so others can review them before integration. <ul>
            <li>To create a review task, click the <uicontrol>New Review Task</uicontrol> button.
              You can set a title, due date, and select a context publication. All changed files are
              included in the review task.<note type="note" id="note_lsg_prf_ggc">If you exclude any
                files from the commit, the <uicontrol>New Review Task</uicontrol> button is
                disabled, as creating a review task from a selection of files is not currently
                supported.</note></li>
            <li>You can then <xref href="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.dita">share the task with
                  <b>Reviewers</b></xref>.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul>
      <p>Other features:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Click on a file to see a comparison (diff) of your workspace version (left) and the repository version (right).</li>
        <li>Use the contextual menu (three vertical dots) next to a file for actions such as: <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Open file</uicontrol>: Opens the latest editable workspace version.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Discard changes</uicontrol>: Discards your changes to the file.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Deselect all files</uicontrol>: Deselects all selected files.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Discard changes from all files</uicontrol>: Discards all your
              changes.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="history_tab">
      <title>History Tab</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> tab shows all repository commits up to the latest one in your workspace. Features include:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Viewing the commit graph, which displays the history of branches and merges.</li>
        <li>Hovering over a commit to see details such as the committer's name, date, and commit message.</li>
        <li>Clicking on a commit to display the files included in that commit at the bottom of the pane.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
