<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace_incoming_changes">
  <title>Incoming Commits</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_kqw_s52_vcc">You can click the <uicontrol>Incoming commits</uicontrol> drop-down on the
      right side of the second top stripe to display more information regarding the status of
      incoming commits and gain access to additional actions.</p>
    <p id="p_lqw_s52_vcc">
      <fig id="fig_mqw_s52_vcc">
        <title>Incoming Commits Drop-down</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-incoming-commits1.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_nqw_s52_vcc">Incoming commits are automatically refreshed periodically, but you can
      click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/cfRefresh16.png"/>Refresh</uicontrol> button to
      refresh manually.</p>
    <p id="p_oqw_s52_vcc">When there are no conflicts, you can click the <uicontrol>Pull</uicontrol>
      button to pull the incoming changes. This can also be done from the
        <uicontrol>Changes</uicontrol> view.</p>
    <p id="p_pqw_s52_vcc">When there are no conflicts, you can also click the <uicontrol>View
        changed files</uicontrol> button to see a comparison of the incoming changes versus the
      current workspace version and a <uicontrol>Pull</uicontrol> action is available in that
      comparison dialog box.</p>
    <p id="p_qqw_s52_vcc">If there are conflicts, the badge with the number of incoming commits is
      highlighted in red. You can click the <uicontrol>Resolve conflicts</uicontrol> button to open
      a dialog box where you can choose actions for <xref href="#./section_s3k_xz2_vcc">resolving
        the conflicts</xref>.</p>
    <p id="p_rqw_s52_vcc">
      <fig id="fig_sqw_s52_vcc">
        <title>Incoming Commits with Conflicts</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-incoming-commits2.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="section_s3k_xz2_vcc">
      <title>Resolving and Merging Conflicts</title>
      <p id="p_srv_jjn_ybc">When conflicts are detected between changes in your workspace and
        incoming changes from the project, click the <uicontrol>Resolve conflicts</uicontrol> button
        either from the <uicontrol>Changes</uicontrol> view or the <uicontrol>Incoming
          commits</uicontrol> drop-down. This opens a conflict resolution dialog box.</p>
      <p id="p_zbh_v52_vcc">
        <fig id="fig_ach_v52_vcc">
          <title>Conflict Resolution Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/cf-conflicts1.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_bch_v52_vcc">The left pane shows the incoming changes. You can toggle the
          <uicontrol>Show only conflicts</uicontrol> button to filter the list to focus on the
        conflicts. There are three types of incoming changes and each have a dedicated icon:<ul
          id="ul_cch_v52_vcc">
          <li id="li_dch_v52_vcc"><image href="../img/cfConflicts18.png"/> - Conflicting changes
            that cannot be automatically merged and require manual intervention.</li>
          <li id="li_ech_v52_vcc"><image href="../img/cfMergeableConflicts18.png"/> - Incoming
            changes can be automatically merged.</li>
          <li id="li_fch_v52_vcc"><image href="../img/cfMergeable18.png"/> - Incoming files from the
            project that are not present in your workspace.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p id="p_gch_v52_vcc">The incoming changes that can be automatically merged (<image
          href="../img/cfMergeableConflicts18.png"/>) and new files coming from the project (<image
          href="../img/cfMergeable18.png"/>) do not require any manual action and will be merged
        when you click the <uicontrol>Pull</uicontrol> button. Conflicting files (<image
          href="../img/cfConflicts18.png"/>) require that you choose an action from the drop-down to
        the right of the file entry. The possible actions are:<ul id="ul_hch_v52_vcc">
          <li id="li_ich_v52_vcc"><uicontrol>Manual merge</uicontrol> - The user must edit the file
            and merge the changes manually.</li>
          <li id="li_jch_v52_vcc"><uicontrol>Keep workspace changes</uicontrol> - Overrides the
            changes coming from the project with your workspace changes.</li>
          <li id="li_kch_v52_vcc"><uicontrol>Keep project changes</uicontrol> - Keeps the changes
            coming from the project and discards your workspace changes.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p id="p_lch_v52_vcc">Click the file entry to display a comparison of the two versions of the
        document. The current workspace version of the document is displayed on the left while the
        version from the project is displayed on the right. You can use the toolbar buttons to
        navigate through the changes or copy changes from the right to left (from the project to the
        workspace).</p>
      <p id="p_mch_v52_vcc">You can also edit your current workspace version in the left side and it
        includes content completion and contextual menu actions. Note that if you change the
          <uicontrol>Manual merge</uicontrol> option to another type of resolution, your changes are
        discarded.</p>
      <p id="p_nch_v52_vcc">Once you are finished, click the <uicontrol>Pull</uicontrol> button in
        the bottom-right corner to finish the conflict resolution and merge the changes. If you
        close the dialog box without using the <uicontrol>Pull</uicontrol> button, your changes are
        discarded.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>