<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects">
  <title>Projects</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Projects</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_o2t_pl3_vxb"><ph keyref="product"/> offers the ability to connect to an existing Git
      repository that has a DITA project as its source. This is managed within the Content Fusion
      browser interface through a feature known as <term>Projects</term>. A <b>Content Author</b>
      can create review tasks inside a project and reviewers' suggestions are tracked on a dedicated
      branch in the Git repository. A <b>Content Author</b> can also use the <term>Projects</term>
      feature to build and configure deliverables for creating PDF or <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/xml_webhelp/webhelp_responsive.html" format="html"
        scope="external"><b>Oxygen WebHelp Responsive</b></xref> output.</p>
    <section id="what_is_a_project_in_content_fusion">
      <title>What is a Project in Content Fusion?</title>
      <p id="p_t3k_nm3_vxb">A Content Fusion <b>Project</b>:<ul id="ul_h2q_s4f_zxb">
          <li id="li_i2q_s4f_zxb">Defines a connection to a Git repository that contains a DITA
            content.</li>
          <li id="li_vdg_x4f_zxb">Provides a graphical interface to manage the DITA project and
            review processes within the project.</li>
          <li id="li_yhv_1pf_zxb">Allows Authors to create review tasks inside the project and
            reviewer suggestions are tracked on a dedicated branch that is traced in the Git
            repository.</li>
          <li id="li_jlk_mkt_zxb">Helps Authors with building WebHelp or PDF outputs via
              <i>Publications</i> and <i>Deliverables</i>.</li>
          <li id="li_orr_mkt_zxb">Acts as a read-only clone of the Git repository making it
            compatible with existing workflows and tools.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="user_roles">
      <title>User Roles</title>
      <p>When working with projects, there are two user roles:<ul>
          <li><b>SME (Subject Matter Expert/Reviewer)</b> - By default, Content Fusion users have
            the SME (Subject Matter Expert) role assigned. This role allows the user to access
            review tasks assigned to them and to create review tasks from scratch.</li>
          <li><b>Author</b> - This role must be assigned to a user by an administrator. In addition
            to the features that an SME has access to, Authors can access all projects and are able
            to create review tasks inside projects, as well as other functionality that is
            restricted from an SME.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>The license for Content Fusion covers a number of user-based licenses for authors and a
        number of floating licenses for SMEs. A system administrator can assign roles from the <xref
          href="cf-enterprise-configuration.dita">Administration page</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="projects_main_page">
      <title>Projects Main Page</title>
      <p><uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> is one of the two main components (along with <b>Review
          Tasks</b>) within the Content Fusion browser interface. The main
          <uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> page displays a list of all the current projects that are
        available for your organization and your user role.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Main Projects Page</title>
          <image href="../img/cf-projects-page.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_kg2_4yb_tbc">To open an existing project, simply click on it. This open the <xref
          href="cf-projects-content.dita">project <uicontrol>Content</uicontrol> page</xref> by
        default.</p>
      <p id="p_lg2_4yb_tbc">Once a project is open, an additional stripe is displayed below the top
        stripe with a drop-down action for choosing the branch and an <xref
          href="cf-projects-workspace.dita"><uicontrol>Open Workspace</uicontrol> button that
          creates a workspace branch</xref> starting from the latest version on the "main" branch or
        opens an already existing workspace.</p>
      <p id="p_ysm_ytf_zxb">
        <fig id="fig_zsm_ytf_zxb">
          <title>Top Stripe Actions Inside a Project</title>
          <image href="../img/CF-top-stripe-actions-project.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="create-projects">
      <title>Creating a New Project</title>
      <p>Click the <uicontrol>New project</uicontrol> button to create a new project. This opens a
        dialog box where you will configure the connection to your Git repository. It includes the
        following fields:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The name of the project.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> - The description of the project. It is displayed
            under the project's name in the main <uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> page.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Project URL</uicontrol> - The URL of the Git repository.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Branch</uicontrol> - The default branch of the project.</li>
          <li id="visibility-li"><uicontrol>Visibility</uicontrol> - You can choose between
              <uicontrol>Public</uicontrol> (accessible by all members) or
              <uicontrol>Private</uicontrol> (restricts access to select members).</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Username and Access Token</uicontrol> - You can enter the Git credentials
            (username and access token) using this option.<note id="note_ymy_qh5_cbc">The personal
              access token for GitHub must have the following permissions:<ul id="ul_ej1_135_cbc">
                <li><menucascade>
                    <uicontrol>Repository permissions</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol>Contents</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol>Read and Write</uicontrol>
                  </menucascade>.</li>
                <li>You should also specify which repositories it has access to.</li>
              </ul></note></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Git Account</uicontrol> - Use this option to select a preconfigured Git
            account.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>Once you are done configuring the details, click the <uicontrol>Create project</uicontrol>
        button to finish the creation process. The newly created project is automatically opened
        with the <xref href="cf-projects-content.dita">project's <uicontrol>Content</uicontrol>
          page</xref> displayed.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
