<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace_publications_view">
  <title>Workspace Publications View</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_xkq_hrz_vbc">The <uicontrol>Publications</uicontrol> view displays the map of a
      publication in a tree editor to make navigating through the topics easier. For a publication
      to appear, it must first be defined in the <xref href="cf-projects-publications.dita">project
          <uicontrol>Publications Management</uicontrol> page</xref>. You also need to pull <xref
        href="cf-projects-workspace_incoming_changes.dita">incoming changes into your
        workspace</xref> to retrieve a newly defined publication from the project. </p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Workspace Publications View</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-workspace-publication.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_x2z_ktz_vbc">To select a defined publication, use the drop-down control in the
      side-pane. This publication will be used as the context of the open editors. Changing the
      publication triggers a reload of the currently open editor to match the new context.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/Cf-ManagePub16.png"/>Manage Publications</uicontrol>
      button at the top-right corner of the view can be used to open a dialog box with the <xref
        href="cf-projects-publications.dita">project <uicontrol>Publications Management</uicontrol>
        page</xref> where you can you can configure the publication (or create a new one).</p>
    <p id="p_vrd_dd5_rcc">You can click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/cfRefresh16.png"
        />Refresh</uicontrol> button at the top-right corner to refresh the list of
      publications.</p>
    <p id="p_zcc_mtz_vbc">To open and edit the DITA map defined in the particular publication in a
        <xref href="CF-dita-map-tree-editor.dita">specialized DITA map tree editor</xref>, click the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/CF-OpenEditor16.png"/>Open in editor</uicontrol> button
      next to the drop-down control.</p>
    <p id="p_p2x_vtn_zbc">You can click on a file displayed in the side-pane to open it in the
      visual editor (or double-click a file when the map is open in the tree editor).</p>
    <p>You can use the <uicontrol>Filter by name</uicontrol> text field to search for a file by
      name.</p>
  </body>
</topic>