<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace_problems_view">
  <title>Project Problems View</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_ulk_5v2_vcc">The <uicontrol>Problems</uicontrol> view can be used to validate a
      publication or all publications defined in your DITA project. This provides a way to ensure
      that your project remains valid when you commit your changes. The validation process includes
      checking compliance with the DITA schema and ensuring that all links and key references are
      correctly resolved in your publications.</p>
    <p id="p_rry_hy2_vcc">
      <fig id="fig_sry_hy2_vcc">
        <title>Workspace Problems View</title>
        <image href="../img/CF-problems-view.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_jy4_2cf_vcc">When you go to this page for the first time, there is a
        <uicontrol>Validate now</uicontrol> button that triggers the project validation. While the
      validation is processing, the progress status is displayed with the message <i>Validation is
        running</i>. If the server is too busy, the validation will be scheduled to be executed
      later, and the status message is changed to <i>Pending - Waiting for execution</i>. If the
      validation process fails, an error message is displayed. If the process takes too long, you
      can click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CF-Stop16.png"/>Stop</uicontrol> button to
      terminate the process early.</p>
    <p id="p_k4q_kdf_vcc">Once the validation has processed, the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/CF-Refresh16.png"/>Refresh</uicontrol> in the top-right corner of the view
      triggers a new validation. The number of issues detected is displayed at the top of the page.
      If no problems are detected, a <uicontrol>Restart validation</uicontrol> button appears that
      also triggers a new validation.</p>
    <p id="p_pcw_m2f_vcc">If problems are detected, they are grouped by publication context and each
      one is listed with the severity of the problem (fatal, error, warning, info) displayed in a
      badge at the top-left corner of the problem, the name of the publication in the top-right
      corner, followed by a description of the problem. The file name is listed at the bottom of
      each problem and clicking on the file name opens it in the editor pane with the cursor placed
      at the location of the problem (if the file is from a different publication other than the
      current publication, a dialog box is displayed asking if you want to switch to the other
      publication).</p>
    <p id="p_nwj_nbg_vcc">If problems are detected, you can use the drop-down at the top of the view
      to filter the list to only show the problems for a particular publication (this also switches
      the current context for the entire project to the chosen publication) or you can select <i>All
        publications</i> to show all of them.</p>
  </body>
</topic>