<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-workspace_problems_view">
  <title>Workspace Problems View</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_ulk_5v2_vcc">The <uicontrol>Problems</uicontrol> view can be used to validate a
      publication or all publications defined in your DITA project. This provides a way to ensure
      that your project remains valid when you commit your changes. The validation process includes
      checking compliance with the DITA schema and ensuring that all links and key references are
      correctly resolved in your publications.</p>
    <p id="p_rry_hy2_vcc">
      <fig id="fig_sry_hy2_vcc">
        <title>Workspace Problems View</title>
        <image href="../img/CF-problems-view.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_jy4_2cf_vcc">When you go to this page for the first time, there is a
        <uicontrol>Validate now</uicontrol> button that triggers the project validation. While the
      validation is processing, a message indicates the status. You can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/CF-Stop16.png"/>Stop</uicontrol> button to terminate the process early.</p>
    <p id="p_k4q_kdf_vcc">Once the validation has processed, the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/CF-Refresh16.png"/>Refresh</uicontrol> in the top-right corner of the view
      triggers a new validation. The number of issues detected is displayed at the top of the page.
      If no problems are detected, a <uicontrol>Restart validation</uicontrol> button appears that
      also triggers a new validation.</p>
    <p id="p_pcw_m2f_vcc">If problems are detected, each one is listed with the type of problem
      displayed in a badge at the top-left corner of the problem, the name of the publication in the
      top-right corner, followed by a description of the problem. The file name is listed at the
      bottom of each problem and clicking on the file name opens it in the editor pane (if the file
      is from a different publication other than the current publication, a dialog box is displayed
      asking if you want to switch to the other publication).</p>
    <p id="p_m4f_dff_vcc">If problems are detected, a drop-down also appears at the top of the view
      where you can select a particular publication defined in the project to validate a particular
      publication or you can select <i>All publications</i> to validate the entire project.</p>
  </body>
</topic>