<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-projects-review-tasks">
  <title>Project Review Tasks Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Project review tasks page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Project Review Tasks</uicontrol> page contains all the current tasks that have
      been created within the current project.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Project Review Tasks Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF_task_details1.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>Tasks created from inside a project are slightly different than regular tasks created outside
      of a project:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>A project-based review task is created from the Content Fusion browser interface inside a
        project, while a regular review task is created either from <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>
        or the browser interface, outside a project.</li>
      <li>The changes made to a project-based review task are stored in the Git repository of the
        project and will be merged in the project default branch and pushed to the upstream remote
        repository when the task is finished.</li>
      <li>All the authors that have access to a project will be able to see all review tasks created
        in that project.</li>
      <li>A project-based review task contains all the files in the project (not just the files
        selected for review).</li>
    </ul>
    <p>To open an existing task, simply click on it. This open the <xref href="cf-task-files.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Task Files</uicontrol> page</xref>.</p>
    <p id="p_csm_wfb_z1c">You can use the <uicontrol>Filter by name</uicontrol> field to filter the
      list of review tasks, making it easier to find specific tasks.</p>
    <p id="p_hlq_fwf_zxb">To see tasks that you created (or are assigned as an owner), click the
        <uicontrol>Owned By Me</uicontrol> tab. To see tasks that have been assigned to you, click
      the <uicontrol>Assigned To Me</uicontrol> tab. The table also has columns that show project
      information (if applicable), the <uicontrol>Owners</uicontrol> of the review task, <xref
        href="CF-task-states-user-roles.dita#CF-task-states-user-roles/section_vkk_v4s_1yb">the
          <uicontrol>Review Status</uicontrol></xref>, and the <uicontrol>Due Date</uicontrol> (if
      specified in the <xref href="cf-task-settings.dita"><uicontrol>Task Settings</uicontrol>
        page</xref>).</p>
    <p id="p_wmn_4rz_y1c">A task is displayed as <uicontrol>In review</uicontrol> unless it is
      closed by a task owner. If a task has been closed, the status is displayed as
        <uicontrol>Review closed</uicontrol>. Other task states that a <uicontrol>Content
        Author</uicontrol> could see is <uicontrol>Integrating</uicontrol> and
        <uicontrol>Integrated</uicontrol> (see the <xref
        href="#cf-projects-review-tasks/closing_a_review_and_integrating_changes"/> section
      below).</p>
    <p id="p_ymn_4rz_y1c"><uicontrol>Integrated</uicontrol> tasks are not displayed by default. To
      view all tasks, click the <uicontrol>Show integrated</uicontrol> button (when inside the
        <uicontrol>Owned By Me</uicontrol> tab). To hide them, click the same button again.</p>
    <p id="p_hlq_fwf_zxb2">Also, if you want to see the tasks that have been finalized (for those
      that are assigned to you), click the <uicontrol>Show finalized</uicontrol> button (when inside
      the <uicontrol>Assigned to Me</uicontrol> tab).</p>
    <section id="section_cn4_k3x_4jb">
      <title>Creating New Tasks and Files Within a Project</title>
      <p id="p_vxt_dgk_54b">To create a new task and add files:<ol id="ol_gzj_4pq_4jb">
          <li id="li_wxt_dgk_54b">From the <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol> page, click the
              <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li id="li_eyt_dgk_54b">Enter a title for the task in the field at the top of the pane.
            Click the check mark on the right side when you are done.</li>
          <li>Optionally, you can specify a <uicontrol>Due Date</uicontrol>. The amount of time left
            before the due date arrives is displayed under the review task's title when you have
            navigated inside the task and also in the table in the <xref
              href="content_fusion_task_details.dita"><uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol>
              page</xref>. Also, any reviewers who have not finalized the task will receive an email
            notification when the due date is within 3 days, 1 day, and 12 hours of its
            expiration.</li>
          <li id="li_c15_1m4_g1c">To add files to the task, select the file from the
              <uicontrol>Files</uicontrol> side-pane.<note id="note_b5n_3m4_g1c" type="tip">If you
              want to create a new file to add to the task (or upload an existing one from your
              computer), you will first need to finish creating the task. After clicking the
                <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol> button, the <uicontrol>Task Files</uicontrol> page for
              the review task should be open. On this page, you can create or upload files to the
              task. To create a new file, click the <uicontrol>New File</uicontrol> button and you
              will be able to choose a file type from a list of templates, then choose a file name
              in the text field at the bottom, and click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. You can then
              open the file in the <xref href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita">visual editor
                page</xref> to make changes to the document. To upload a file, click the
                  <uicontrol><image href="../img/cf-upload16.png"/>Upload</uicontrol> button and
              select the file from your computer.</note></li>
          <li id="li_rp5_qn4_g1c">Optionally, you can select a <uicontrol>Context
              Publication</uicontrol> (the publication must already be defined in the <xref
              href="cf-projects-publications.dita"/>). The benefit of specifying a context
            publication is that the files added to the task will be rendered as a hierarchical tree
            based upon the context DITA map defined in the publication.</li>
          <li id="li_j34_pvv_21c">Optionally, select <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> from the left
            stripe to open the <xref href="cf-task-settings.dita"><uicontrol>Task
                Settings</uicontrol> page</xref> to configure options or delete the task.</li>
          <li id="li_etv_n44_g1c">Click <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol> to finish the task creation
            process.</li>
          <li id="li_qgb_qvv_21c">The next logical step would most likely be to <xref
              href="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.dita">share the task</xref> with anyone you want to
            review the documents.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="closing_a_review_and_integrating_changes">
      <title>Closing a Review Task and Integrating Changes</title>
      <p>A <i>task owner</i> can close the review process to reserve some time to address the
        feedback and integrate the changes. To close a task, click the <uicontrol>Close
          review</uicontrol> button in the top stripe (with a task opened). This locks the task and
        prevents others from making changes to the task. If further review is needed, you can click
        the <uicontrol>Reopen review</uicontrol> button to make the task editable again.</p>
      <p>Once a project-based review task is closed, you then have access to a <uicontrol>Start
          integrating</uicontrol> button in the top stripe. This opens a built-in file comparison
        and merge tool where you can visually see the differences, choose which differences to copy
        to your local version, and merge the differences. The task status is changed to
          <uicontrol>Integrating</uicontrol> during this process. </p>
      <p>Once in the <uicontrol>Integrating</uicontrol> state, only the author who initiated the
        integration can work on integrating the task. They can use the <uicontrol>Cancel
          integration</uicontrol> button to abandon the integration and allow another author to
        start the integration. Once they have finished integrating, they can use the
          <uicontrol>Finish integration</uicontrol> button to finalize the merge. This will change
        the task status to <uicontrol>Integrated</uicontrol>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
