<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-security">
  <title>Security Hardening Notes</title>
  <body>
    <section id="section_hm1_xpp_nrb">
      <title>Password Storage</title>
      <p>Content Fusion stores user passwords in a hashed format to prevent them from being stored
        as plain text. The password hashes are <term>stretched</term> and <term>salted</term> to
        provide more security against brute-force attacks.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_s53_xdh_n2c">
      <title>Domain Name</title>
      <p id="p_t53_xdh_n2c">The application should be configured with a valid domain name.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_wnq_mwp_nrb">
      <title>HTTPS</title>
      <p>Traffic toward/from Content Fusion is encrypted by default with an automatically generated
        certificate. The administrator should upload a valid HTTPS certificate for the Content
        Fusion hostname before exposing the service to users and HTTPS should be enabled for the
        main application.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_ddv_l2h_n2c">
      <title>HSTS</title>
      <p id="p_edv_l2h_n2c">Content Fusion enables <i>Full HSTS</i> to protect from session
        fixation.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_vvl_2zp_nrb">
      <title>Incoming Connections</title>
      <p>Content Fusion accepts connections on ports 80 and 443 for serving the Content Fusion Web
        UI and on port 9080 for serving the Administration Web UI. The machine that hosts Content
        Fusion should allow incoming connections on port 22 for SSH access.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_wyt_dxp_nrb">
      <title>Outgoing Connections</title>
      <p>Content Fusion can connect to external services if it is configured to do so:<ul
          id="ul_opb_fxp_nrb">
          <li>Email server for notifications and password resets (see <xref
              href="cf-admin-page-mail.dita">Content Fusion Enterprise Administration Page - Mail
              Tab</xref> for configuration details).</li>
          <li>LDAP server for LDAP authentication (see <xref
              href="cf-admin-page-authentication.dita">Content Fusion Enterprise Administration Page
              - Authentication Tab</xref> for configuration details).</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_opk_3xp_nrb">
      <title>Size Limits</title>
      <p>Tasks have a configurable size limit (default is 1Gb) and a configurable file limit
        (default is 32767).</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_n2k_l5p_nrb">
      <title>Information Exclusivity</title>
      <p>Task owners can choose who has access to Content Fusion tasks. They can specify a list of
        allowed collaborators on a task or allow anyone with access to the link to collaborate. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_s3g_4yp_nrb">
      <title>OAuth2 Authentication</title>
      <p>Content Fusion can be configured to allow users to authenticate using their Google or
        GitHub accounts. When users choose this authentication method, their accounts will not have
        a password. Authentication is delegated to either Google or GitHub, respectively.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_zrg_5yp_nrb">
      <title>Internal Connections</title>
      <p>Content Fusion is composed of multiple internal services that communicate with each other.
        This communication is authenticated with passwords generated at installation time.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_uxv_xcj_bxb">
      <title>Transport Layer Security</title>
      <p id="p_vxv_xcj_bxb">Content Fusion supports TLS v1.2 and TLS v1.3. Note that support for
        v1.0 and v1.1 was removed.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_hsg_g5p_vfc">
      <title>Hard Disk Encryption</title>
      <p id="p_isg_g5p_vfc">The server's hard disk where Content Fusion is installed must be
        encrypted to ensure that persistent history data is secure.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
