<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-task-activity">
  <title>Task Activity Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Task activity</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Clicking on <uicontrol>Task activity</uicontrol> in the left stripe opens the <uicontrol>Task
        Activity</uicontrol> page that lists the history of the activity that has occurred for the
      task (e.g. changes and comments). If a file is open in the visual editor, clicking on
        <uicontrol>Task activity</uicontrol> opens the page in a side-view to the left of the
      editor.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_ww1_tcp_zxb">
        <title>Task Activity Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF-Task-Activity-Tab.png" id="image_phl_5cp_zxb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>This page displays all messages and file change notifications.</p>
    <p id="p_kxb_wnb_lcc">If an activity describes a file change, you can click the file name from
      the <uicontrol>Task activity</uicontrol> to see a comparison (diff) of the changes made for
      that activity.</p>
    <p id="p_lxb_wnb_lcc">If you hover over a file change, you can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/CF-OpenEditor16Blue.png"/>Open latest version</uicontrol> button to open the
      current version of that particular file in the visual editor or you can click the ellipsis (3
      vertical dots) to the far right and the following actions become available:</p>
    <p id="p_m1w_w4b_lcc">
      <dl id="dl_lx1_x4b_lcc">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_mx1_x4b_lcc">
          <dt>Open latest version</dt>
          <dd>Opens the current version of the selected file in the visual editor.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_osc_1pb_lcc">
          <dt>Compare with latest version</dt>
          <dd>Opens a comparison (diff) between the selected file change and the latest version of
            the file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_prz_2pb_lcc">
          <dt>Open this version</dt>
          <dd>Opens the version of the file when the selected file change was made.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_i31_5pb_lcc">
          <dt>Compare with previous version</dt>
          <dd>Opens a comparison (diff) between the selected file change and its previous version of
            the file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p id="p_cgn_jh4_g1c">To communicate with other collaborators directly in the interface, you can
      use the <uicontrol>Add message</uicontrol> button (if the <uicontrol>Task activity</uicontrol>
      is open in the side-pane, you can access the <uicontrol>Add message</uicontrol> action from
      the 3 vertical dots menu on the right side of the header). Note that all messages in this
      panel are attached to the task and not to individual files (to annotate individual files, use
      the <xref
        href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita#making_changes_to_uploaded_files/add-comment"
          ><uicontrol>Add Comment</uicontrol> button in the editor</xref>).</p>
  </body>
</topic>
