<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf-task-activity">
  <title>Task Activity Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Task activity</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Task Activity Page</uicontrol> lists the history of the activity that has
      occurred for the task (e.g. changes and comments). The activity stream is automatically
      refreshed every minute.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_ww1_tcp_zxb">
        <title>Task Activity Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF-Task-Activity-Tab.png" id="image_phl_5cp_zxb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_t5c_rg4_g1c">This page displays all messages and file change notifications. Each
      activity includes an icon that indicates the type of activity, the name of the user who made a
      change within the task, and when it was processed. For added files (denoted with this icon:
        <image href="../img/CF-AddedFiles16.png"/>), you can click the highlighted file name to open
      the file. For changed files (denoted with this icon: <image
        href="../img/CF-ChangedFiles16.png"/>), you can click the highlighted file name to open the
      two versions of the document in a file comparison view so that you can clearly see the
      differences. You can also hover over the highlighted file name for changed files, click the
      ellipsis (3 vertical dots), and select <uicontrol>Open file</uicontrol> to simply open the
      current version of the file in the visual editor (rather than the file comparison).</p>
    <p id="p_cgn_jh4_g1c">To communicate with other collaborators directly in the interface, you can
      use the <uicontrol>Add message</uicontrol> button. However, note that all messages in this
      panel are attached to the task and not to individual files (to annotate individual files, use
      the <xref
        href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita#making_changes_to_uploaded_files/add-comment"
          ><uicontrol>Add Comment</uicontrol> button in the editor</xref>).</p>
  </body>
</topic>
