<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="CF-task-states-user-roles">
  <title>Review Task States and User Roles</title>
  <body>
    <p>The purpose of this topic is to provide a general overview of the possible states for Content
      Fusion review tasks and details about user roles.</p>
    <section id="section_tm2_mfs_1yb">
      <title>Regular Review Tasks vs Project-based Review Tasks</title>
      <p>Content Fusion includes a <xref href="cf-projects.dita"><i>Projects</i> feature</xref> that
        makes it possible for an organization to integrate a Git repository that contains DITA
        content and changes proposed by reviewers can be integrated back into the DITA project
        directly within Content Fusion.</p>
      <p>Review tasks can be created inside or outside projects in Content Fusion and there are some
        difference between the two:</p>
      <p>
        <dl id="dl_ob1_2js_1yb">
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Regular Review Task (created outside a project)</dt>
            <dd>
              <ul id="ul_dpt_hjs_1yb">
                <li>At the end of the review process, the task owner integrates changes proposed by
                  reviewers into their documentation project using <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>
                  or another tool outside of Content Fusion.</li>
                <li>There is no interaction between Content Fusion and a remote repository.</li>
                <li>Only the task owners and the reviewers that are granted access to the task are
                  able to see and access the particular task. </li>
              </ul>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Project-based Review Task (created inside a project)</dt>
            <dd>
              <ul>
                <li>At the end of the review process, the task owner has the ability to integrate
                  changes proposed by reviewers into their documentation project directly within the
                  Content Fusion browser interface.</li>
                <li>The changes made to a project-based review task are stored in the Git repository
                  and merged into the project's branch and pushed to the upstream remote repository
                  when the task is finished.</li>
                <li>All users with <xref
                    href="CF-task-states-user-roles.dita#CF-task-states-user-roles/section_cjw_fns_1yb"
                    >platform user role of <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol></xref> that have access to
                  a project are able to see all review tasks that were created inside that
                  particular project.</li>
              </ul>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_fsr_mls_1yb">
      <title>Review Task Ownership</title>
      <p>On any given review task, collaborators have one of the following roles in regard to task
          ownership:<ul id="ul_d5w_sls_1yb">
          <li><b>Reviewer</b> - A collaborator who is not the task owner can review and edit
            content, add messages to communicate with the task owner and other collaborators, and
            mark the task as finalized once they consider the review process is finished.</li>
          <li><b>Owner</b> - The task owner (the person who created the task or another person who
            is assigned as a task owner by the task creator) can review and edit content, add
            messages to communicate with other collaborators, change task settings, decide when to
            close the review task. For project-based review tasks, a task owner who has a <xref
              href="CF-task-states-user-roles.dita#CF-task-states-user-roles/section_cjw_fns_1yb"
              >platform user role of <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol></xref> can integrate proposed
            changes and build output deliverables.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_cjw_fns_1yb">
      <title>Platform User Roles for Project-based Review Tasks</title>
      <p>For organizations that take advantage of the Content Fusion <xref href="cf-projects.dita"
            ><i>Projects</i> feature</xref>, there are two platform user roles that can be assigned
        by the administrator<ph product="fusion"> (from the <uicontrol>Users Management</uicontrol>
          tab found in the <xref href="cf-enterprise-configuration.dita">Administration
          Page</xref>)</ph>:<ul id="ul_e3j_yns_1yb">
          <li><b>Subject Matter Expert (SME)</b> - By default, Content Fusion users have the Subject
            Matter Expert (SME) role assigned for the platform. They can access review tasks that
            are assigned to them and create tasks from scratch.</li>
          <li><b>Content Fusion Author</b> - This platform role must be assigned by an
            administrator. In addition to the features that an SME has access to, Authors can access
            all projects created within the organization, create review tasks from inside projects,
            build output deliverables, and other advanced features.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_vkk_v4s_1yb">
      <title>Review Task States</title>
      <p>Content Fusion review tasks can be in one of the following possible states:<ul
          id="ul_dxr_lps_1yb">
          <li>
            <p><uicontrol>In review</uicontrol> - This is the initial status for newly created
              review tasks and they remain in this state until the task has been closed by the task
              owner. Both reviewers and task owners can edit the task files while in this state.</p>
          </li>
          <li><uicontrol>Review closed</uicontrol> - Tasks are changed to this status when a task
            owner uses the <uicontrol>Close Review</uicontrol> button to close the task. Only task
            owners can edit the task files while in this state (they are read-only for reviewers).
            Task owners can reopen the task and its status will return to <uicontrol>In
              review</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Integrating</uicontrol> (for project-based review tasks only) - Tasks are
            changed to this status when a task owner uses the <uicontrol>Start
              Integrating</uicontrol> button to integrate the proposed changes into the project.
            Only the task owner that started the integration can edit the task files while in this
            state (they are read-only for all other collaborators). Note that this task status is
            only viewable by those with a <xref
              href="CF-task-states-user-roles.dita#CF-task-states-user-roles/section_cjw_fns_1yb"
              >platform user role of <uicontrol>Content Fusion Author</uicontrol></xref>.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Integrated</uicontrol> (for project-based review tasks only) - Tasks are
            changed to this status when a task owner uses the <uicontrol>Finish
              Integration</uicontrol> button once the integration is complete. Task files are
            read-only for all participants. An integrated review task can no longer be re-opened.
            Note that this task status is only viewable by those with a <xref
              href="CF-task-states-user-roles.dita#CF-task-states-user-roles/section_cjw_fns_1yb"
              >platform user role of <uicontrol>Content Fusion Author</uicontrol></xref>.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <p id="p_sfm_lcj_hzb">
      <fig id="fig_tpy_m1j_hzb">
        <title>Review Task Workflow from Author Role Perspective</title>
        <image href="../img/cf-author-workflow.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
