<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf_task_manager_view">
  <title>Content Fusion Tasks Manager View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Content Fusion Tasks Manager
          view</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion Tasks Manager view</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>As the <b>Content Author</b>, once you have <xref
        href="installing_the_content_fusion_plugin.dita#installing_the_content_fusion_plugin"
        >installed the <b>Oxygen Content Fusion Connector</b> add-on</xref>, the <uicontrol>Content
        Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view can be accessed. To open the view, click the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"/>Show Content Fusion Tasks
        Manager</uicontrol> toolbar button (or go to <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol> / <uicontrol>Show
        View</uicontrol> / <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol>). By default, it is
      displayed to the right of the main editing panel. This view is where you can create tasks,
      manage them, attach documents, and upload them to the Oxygen Content Fusion server.</p>
    <section id="connecting_to_the_server">
      <title>Connecting to the Server</title>
      <p>If this is your first time using it, click the <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> button to
        open the Oxygen Content Fusion interface in your default browser, then click on <xref
          href="account_management.dita#account_management"><uicontrol>SIGN UP</uicontrol> and
          follow the instructions to create your account</xref>.</p>
      <p>If you already have an account but you are not connected, click the
          <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> button to open the Oxygen Content Fusion interface in your
        default browser and click <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</p>
      <p>For information about configuring a connection to your own on-premise server instead of the
        default cloud-based Oxygen Content Fusion server, see <xref
          href="connect-to-enterprise-server.dita#connect-to-enterprise-server"/>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="content_fusion_tasks_manager_view">
      <title>Tasks Manager View</title>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Content Fusion Tasks Manager View</title>
          <image href="../img/CF_task_manager1.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view contains the following actions
        and components:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>User Name drop-down menu</dt>
            <dd>Once connected and authorized, your user name will appear in the upper right corner
              of the view. The drop-down menu offers the following actions:<p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Refresh Tasks</dt>
                    <dd>Forces a refresh to synchronize the information in the view with the Oxygen
                      Content Fusion server.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Go to my Account</dt>
                    <dd>Opens your profile information in your default browser.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Help</dt>
                    <dd>Opens the Oxygen Content Fusion user guide in your default browser.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Disconnect</dt>
                    <dd>Signs you out of Oxygen Content Fusion. To re-establish connection, you need
                      to click <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> and then
                        <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>New Task box</dt>
            <dd>Use this box to create new tasks. Drag files from the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol>
              view, <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, or your system file explorer and drop
              them in this box (or click the <uicontrol>choose</uicontrol> link to select files) to
                <xref href="creating_and_uploading_tasks.dita#creating_and_uploading_tasks">add the
                files to a new task</xref>.<p>
                <fig>
                  <title>New Task Box</title>
                  <image href="../img/CF_task_manager2.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p><p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Files to Review</dt>
                    <dd>You will see all of the attached files in this section.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Context DITA Map</dt>
                    <dd>If you are working with a DITA project, you should attach the context
                        <term>root</term> map so that all references and defined keys can be
                      resolved and displayed properly for the <b>Reviewers</b>. You can drag the
                      DITA map file and drop it in this box or click to the <uicontrol><image
                          href="../img/Open16.png"/>Choose Context Map</uicontrol> button to select
                      the map.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Task Details / Summary</dt>
                    <dd>You must enter a description or title for the task in the
                        <uicontrol>Summary</uicontrol> field. This task summary will help you
                      differentiate between multiple tasks so each description should be
                      unique.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Upload/Cancel buttons</dt>
                    <dd>Once you are finished adding files and entering a task summary, use the
                        <uicontrol>Upload</uicontrol> button to finalize the task and upload it to
                      the Oxygen Content Fusion server. Use the <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> button
                      to cancel the task creation process.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Tasks</dt>
            <dd>Each created task is listed with its own box in the view. In this box, you will see
              the task name, the time it was created, and notifications when messages are added in
              the Oxygen Content Fusion interface or when a file is changed (the background color of
              the task box also changes when a new message or file change is detected). Click on the
              name of a task to <xref
                href="content_fusion_user_interface_author.dita#content_fusion_user_interface_author"
                >open the Oxygen Content Fusion interface</xref> in your default browser where you
              can view the details of the task, share a link to it with <b>Reviewers</b>, view and
              add messages, and monitor the task progress. When viewing new messages, once you have
              stayed on the task details page for at least 3 seconds, the new message notification
              in the task box will disappear.<p>
                <fig>
                  <title>Task Display Box</title>
                  <image href="../img/CF_task_box.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p></dd>
            <dd>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Get Changes</dt>
                    <dd>Once the <b>Reviewers</b> are done with their process, you will have access
                      to a <uicontrol>Get Changes</uicontrol> link. Clicking this link opens the
                        <xref href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes"><b>Get Changes</b> merge
                        tool</xref> that allows you to automatically merge all the changes back into
                      Oxygen XML Editor or Oxygen XML Author. </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Delete Task</dt>
                    <dd>Once you are finished merging the changes, you can click the
                        <uicontrol>Delete Task</uicontrol> link to remove it from the view and the
                      Oxygen Content Fusion server. It is recommended that you always delete tasks
                      that have been merged so that you do not accidentally merge them again since
                      that could create some complicated conflicts.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="connect-to-enterprise-server.dita#connect-to-enterprise-server"/>
      <link href="creating_and_uploading_tasks.dita#creating_and_uploading_tasks"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
