<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf_task_manager_view">
  <title>Content Fusion Task Manager View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Content Fusion Task Manager
          view</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion Task Manager view</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>As the <b>Content Author</b>, once you have <xref
        href="installing_the_content_fusion_plugin.dita#installing_the_content_fusion_plugin"
        >installed the <b>Content Fusion Connector</b> plugin</xref>, the <uicontrol>Content Fusion
        Task Manager</uicontrol> view can be accessed. To open the view, click the <uicontrol>Show
        Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> toolbar button (or go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>). This view is where you can create tasks, manage them, attach documents, and
      upload them to the <ph keyref="product"/> server.</p>
    <p>If this is your first time using it, click the <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> button to open
      the <ph keyref="product"/> interface in your most recently used browser, then click on <xref
        href="account_management.dita#account_management"><uicontrol>SIGN UP</uicontrol> and follow
        the instructions to create your account.</xref></p>
    <p>If you already have an account but you are not connected, click the
        <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> button to open the <ph keyref="product"/> interface in your
      most recently used browser and click <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> view contains the following actions
      and components:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>User Name drop-down menu</dt>
          <dd>Once connected and authorized, your user name will appear in the upper right corner of
            the view. The drop-down menu offers the following actions:<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Refresh Tasks</dt>
                  <dd>Forces a refresh to synchronize the information in the view with the <ph
                      keyref="product"/> server.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Go to my Account</dt>
                  <dd>Opens your profile information in your most recently used browser.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Help</dt>
                  <dd>Opens the <ph keyref="product"/> user guide in your most recently used
                    browser.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Disconnect</dt>
                  <dd>Signs you out of <ph keyref="product"/>. To re-establish connection, you need
                    to click <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> and then
                      <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>New Task box</dt>
          <dd>Use this box to create new tasks. Drag files from the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol>
            view, <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, or your system file explorer and drop
            them in this box (or click the <uicontrol>choose</uicontrol> link to select files) to
            add the files to a new task.<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Files to Review</dt>
                  <dd>You will see all of the attached files in this section.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Context DITA Map</dt>
                  <dd>If you are working with a DITA project, you should attach the context
                      <term>root</term> map so that all references and defined keys can be resolved
                    and displayed properly for the <b>Reviewers</b>. You can drag the DITA map file
                    and drop it in this box or click to the <uicontrol><image
                        href="../img/Open16.png"/> Choose Context Map</uicontrol> button to select
                    the map.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Task Details</dt>
                  <dd>You must enter a description or title for the task in the
                      <uicontrol>Summary</uicontrol> field. This task summary will help you
                    differentiate between multiple tasks so each description should be unique.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Upload/Cancel buttons</dt>
                  <dd>Once you are finished adding files and entering a task summary, use the
                      <uicontrol>Upload</uicontrol> button to finalize the task and upload it to the
                      <ph keyref="product"/> server. Use the <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> button to
                    cancel the task creation process.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Tasks</dt>
          <dd>Each created task is listed with its own box in the view. Click on the name of a task
            to open the <ph keyref="product"/> interface in your most recently used browser where
            you can view the details of the task and share a link to it with <b>Reviewers</b>.</dd>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Get Changes</dt>
                  <dd>Once the <b>Reviewers</b> are done with their process, you will have access to
                    a <uicontrol>Get Changes</uicontrol> link. Clicking this link opens the
                      <b>Merge</b> tool that allows you to automatically merge all the changes back
                    into Oxygen XML Editor or Oxygen XML Author. </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Delete Task</dt>
                  <dd>Once you are finished merging the changes, you can click the <uicontrol>Delete
                      Task</uicontrol> link to remove it from the view and <ph keyref="product"/>.
                    It is recommended that you always delete tasks that have been merged so that you
                    do not accidentally merge them again since that could create some complicated
                    conflicts.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
