<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="cf_task_manager_view">
  <title>Content Fusion Tasks Manager View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion Tasks Manager view</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_lkt_dgk_54b">To open the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> view, click the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"/>Show Content Fusion Tasks
        Manager</uicontrol> toolbar button (or go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>). If neither of them is there, see <xref
        href="installing_the_content_fusion_plugin.dita"/>.</p>
    <p id="p_mkt_dgk_54b">By default, the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> view is displayed to the
      right of the main editing panel. This view is where you can create tasks, manage them, attach
      documents, and upload them to the <ph keyref="product"/> server.</p>
    <section id="connecting_to_the_server">
      <title>Connecting to the Server</title>
      <p id="p_nkt_dgk_54b"><ph product="fusion">If this is your first time using it, you first need
          to <xref href="connect-to-enterprise-server.dita">configure your Enterprise server
            address</xref>. </ph>Click the <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> button to open the <ph
          keyref="product"/> interface in your default browser, click <xref
          href="account_management.dita#account_management"><uicontrol>SIGN UP</uicontrol>, and
          follow the instructions to create your account</xref>. When finished, click
          <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</p>
      <p id="p_okt_dgk_54b">If you already have an account but you are not connected, click the
          <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> button to open the <ph keyref="product"/> interface in your
        default browser, enter your credentials, and click <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="content_fusion_tasks_manager_view">
      <title>Tasks Manager View</title>
      <p id="p_pkt_dgk_54b">
        <fig id="fig_qkt_dgk_54b">
          <title>Content Fusion Tasks Manager View</title>
          <image href="../img/CF_task_manager1.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_rkt_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view contains the following actions
        and components:</p>
      <p id="p_skt_dgk_54b">
        <dl id="dl_tkt_dgk_54b">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_ukt_dgk_54b">
            <dt>User Name drop-down menu</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_vkt_dgk_54b">Once connected and authorized, your user name will appear in the upper right corner
                of the view. If you hover over your name, you can see what email address is
                associated with the account. The drop-down menu offers the following actions:</p>
              <p id="p_wkt_dgk_54b">
                <dl id="dl_xkt_dgk_54b">
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_ykt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Refresh Tasks</dt>
                    <dd>Forces a refresh to synchronize the information in the view with the <ph
                        keyref="product"/> server.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_zkt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Go to my Account</dt>
                    <dd>Opens your profile information in your default browser.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_alt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Connection Status</dt>
                    <dd>Provides information such as the server address, plugin version, and
                      connection status. This option can be used for troubleshooting purposes. For
                      more information, see <xref
                        href="known_issues.dita#known_issues/content_fusion_connector_addon_doesnt_recognize_c"
                      />.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_blt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Help</dt>
                    <dd>Opens the <ph keyref="product"/> user guide in your default browser.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_clt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Preferences</dt>
                    <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Oxygen Content Fusion Connector</uicontrol> preferences
                        page<ph product="fusion"> where you can <xref
                          href="connect-to-enterprise-server.dita#connect-to-enterprise-server/changing_the_url_of_the_content_fusion_server"
                          >change the server address</xref></ph>.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_dlt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Disconnect</dt>
                    <dd>Signs you out of <ph keyref="product"/>. To re-establish the connection, you
                      need to click <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> and then
                        <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_elt_dgk_54b">
            <dt>New Task box</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_flt_dgk_54b">Use this box to create new tasks. Drag files from the
                  <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view, <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, or
                your system file explorer and drop them in this box (or click the
                  <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol> link to select files) to <xref
                  href="creating_and_uploading_tasks.dita#creating_and_uploading_tasks">add the
                  files to a new task</xref>.</p>
              <p id="p_glt_dgk_54b">
                <fig id="fig_hlt_dgk_54b">
                  <title>New Task Box (for DITA Projects)</title>
                  <image href="../img/CF_task_manager2.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
              <p id="p_ilt_dgk_54b">
                <dl id="dl_jlt_dgk_54b">
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_klt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Title</dt>
                    <dd>The task title will help you differentiate between multiple tasks so each
                      one should be unique.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_llt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Files to Review</dt>
                    <dd>You will see all of the attached files in this section. There are several
                      ways to add files to the task. For more details, see <xref
                        href="creating_and_uploading_tasks.dita"/>.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_mlt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>DITA Context (for DITA projects only)</dt>
                    <dd>
                      <p id="p_nlt_dgk_54b">
                        <dl id="dl_olt_dgk_54b">
                          <dlentry id="dlentry_plt_dgk_54b">
                            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ChooseDitaRootMap16.png"
                                  id="image_epg_zhh_sjb"/>Root Map</uicontrol></dt>
                            <dd>If you are working with a DITA project, context <term>root</term>
                              map is used to resolve the references and defined keys so that they
                              are displayed properly for the reviewers and they can see the
                              hierarchy of all the attached files in the <ph keyref="product"/>
                              interface. When you add DITA files to the task, the <term>root</term>
                              map that is specified in the toolbar of the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                                Manager</uicontrol> is automatically detected but you can also drag
                              a DITA map file and drop it in this section or click to the
                                  <uicontrol><image href="../img/Open16.png" id="image_nvx_cl4_f1b"
                                />Choose context root map</uicontrol> button to select a map.</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                          <dlentry id="dlentry_qlt_dgk_54b">
                            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar16.png"
                                  id="image_dd2_s3h_sjb"/>DITAVAL File</uicontrol></dt>
                            <dd>If you are working with a DITA project, you can specify a DITAVAL
                              file so that the content in the uploaded DITA topics is filtered based
                              upon the conditional profiling attribute values defined in the DITAVAL
                              file. You can drag a DITAVAL file and drop it in this section or click
                              to the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Open16.png"
                                  id="image_klf_y3h_sjb"/>Choose DITAVAL</uicontrol> button to
                              select a file. If a condition set is selected in the DITA Maps
                              Manager, the corresponding DITAVAL file will automatically be selected
                              in the task.</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                      </p>
                    </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_rlt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Also include all files that are referenced within the attached files
                      (non-DITA files only)</dt>
                    <dd>If you have only attached non-DITA XML files (and a DITA map is not selected
                      as the context root map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>), this
                      option becomes available. If selected, snapshots of any files that are
                      referenced within any of the attached <uicontrol>Files to Review</uicontrol>
                      will also be attached so that reviewers will have access to the referenced
                      content. Also, when this option is selected, you can click the
                        <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button to preview the referenced files and you
                      can choose to remove any that you do not want uploaded.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_lyw_53p_21c">
                    <dt>Due Date</dt>
                    <dd>Optionally, you can specify a <uicontrol>Due Date</uicontrol>. Within the
                      browser interface, the amount of time left before the due date arrives is
                      displayed under the review task's title when you have navigated inside the
                      task and also in the table in the <xref
                        href="content_fusion_task_details.dita"><uicontrol>My Review
                          Tasks</uicontrol> page</xref>. Also, any reviewers who have not finalized
                      the task will receive an email notification when the due date is within 3
                      days, 1 day, and 12 hours of its expiration.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_slt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Upload/Cancel buttons</dt>
                    <dd>Once you are finished adding files and entering a task summary, use the
                        <uicontrol>Upload</uicontrol> button to finalize the task and upload it to
                      the <ph keyref="product"/> server. Use the <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol>
                      button to cancel the task creation process.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_tlt_dgk_54b">
            <dt>Tasks</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_ult_dgk_54b">Each created task is listed with its own box in the view. In
                this box, you will see the task name, the date/time it was created, that task status
                (if it is in the state of either <uicontrol>Integrating</uicontrol> or
                  <uicontrol>Review closed</uicontrol>), and notifications when messages are added
                in the <ph keyref="product"/> interface or when a file is changed (the background
                color of the task box also changes when a new message or file change is detected).
                Click on the name of a task to open it in your default browser where you can view
                and manage the task, share a link to it with reviewers, view and add messages, and
                monitor the task progress.</p>
              <p id="p_vlt_dgk_54b">
                <fig id="fig_wlt_dgk_54b">
                  <title>Task Display Box</title>
                  <image href="../img/CF_task_box.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_xlt_dgk_54b">
                <dl id="dl_ylt_dgk_54b">
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_zlt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Get Changes</dt>
                    <dd>Once the reviewers are done with their process, you will have access to a
                        <uicontrol>Get Changes</uicontrol> link. Clicking this link opens the <xref
                        href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes"><b>Get Changes</b> merge
                        tool</xref> that is used to automatically merge all the changes back into
                      the original documents. </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_amt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Delete Task</dt>
                    <dd>Once you are finished merging the changes, you can click the
                        <uicontrol>Delete Task</uicontrol> link to remove it from the view and the
                        <ph keyref="product"/> server. It is recommended that you always delete
                      tasks that have been merged so that you do not accidentally merge them again
                      since that could create some complicated conflicts.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_bmt_dgk_54b">
            <dt>Contextual Menu</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_cmt_dgk_54b">If you right-click a task box, the contextual menu offers the following
                actions:</p>
              <p id="p_dmt_dgk_54b">
                <dl id="dl_emt_dgk_54b">
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_fmt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Open task in browser</dt>
                    <dd>Opens the task in your default browser.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_gmt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Copy task link</dt>
                    <dd>Copies the task link to the system clipboard. You can then use any common
                      messaging application to send this copied link to reviewers. You can also
                      paste the copied link in any browser to open it in the Content Fusion browser
                      interface.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_xyp_33f_qtb">
                    <dt>Edit context DITA map</dt>
                    <dd>Opens the DITA map that is specified as the context map for the task in the
                      editor. It allows you to open and edit a file from the Content Fusion server
                      directly in <uicontrol>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</uicontrol>.<note
                        id="note_irn_4wx_qtb" type="other" othertype="Notes">
                        <ul id="ul_cyx_2td_rtb">
                          <li id="li_dyx_2td_rtb">This action is only available for tasks with a
                            context map specified.</li>
                          <li id="li_qyg_gtd_rtb">The editing works only for servers with a version
                            5.0 or higher. For versions prior to 5.0, you can open files but they
                            are read-only.</li>
                        </ul>
                      </note></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_bsm_wzl_k1c">
                    <dt>Close/Reopen Review</dt>
                    <dd>Closes or reopens the review for the task. Closing the review locks the task
                      and prevents others from making changes to it, giving you some time to address
                      the feedback before integrating the changes. Reopening the review makes the
                      task editable again in case further review is needed.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_hmt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Get changes</dt>
                    <dd>Opens the <xref href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes"><b>Get
                          Changes</b> merge tool</xref> that is used to automatically merge all the
                      changes back into the original documents.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_y3k_p1m_k1c">
                    <dt>Mark as integrated</dt>
                    <dd>Marks the task as integrated to archive the task, remove it from visibility
                      for all users, and make it uneditable.<note id="note_z4g_v1m_k1c">A <i>task
                          owner</i> can view integrated (archived) tasks in the browser interface by
                        clicking the <uicontrol>Show integrated review tasks</uicontrol> button at
                        the bottom of the <uicontrol>Owned By Me</uicontrol> tab in the
                          <uicontrol>My Review Task</uicontrol> page.</note></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_imt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Delete task</dt>
                    <dd>Removes the task from the view and the <ph keyref="product"/> server.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_jmt_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Refresh tasks</dt>
                    <dd>Refreshes the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
      <link href="connect-to-enterprise-server.dita#connect-to-enterprise-server" product="fusion"/>
      <link href="creating_and_uploading_tasks.dita#creating_and_uploading_tasks"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
