<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ch_fallback_fonts">
  <title>Fallback Fonts</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_d4v_dgk_54b">Whenever a character is not covered by the font specified in the CSS, it
      can still be rendered by <ph keyref="product"/>
      <term>fallback</term> fonts. In order to use these fallback fonts, you just need to add one of
      the three generic font families indicated below in your CSS.</p>
    <p id="p_e4v_dgk_54b">Here is the list of fallback fonts that are automatically added for these
      generic font families:</p>
    <ul id="ul_cpd_thr_ylb">
      <li id="li_f4v_dgk_54b"><b>Sans-Serif</b> - <codeph>Segoe UI, Symbol, Segoe UI Symbol,
          Microsoft YaHei, Yu Gothic, Malgun Gothic, Latha, Arial Unicode MS</codeph></li>
      <li id="li_g4v_dgk_54b"><b>Serif</b> - <codeph>Times, Times New Roman, Symbol, Segoe UI
          Symbol, SimSun, MingLiU, MS Mincho, Batang, Vijaya, Arial Unicode MS</codeph></li>
      <li id="li_h4v_dgk_54b"><b>Monospace</b> - <codeph>Segoe UI, Symbol, Segoe UI Symbol,
          Microsoft YaHei, Yu Gothic, Malgun Gothic, Latha, Arial Unicode MS</codeph></li>
    </ul>
    <p>If you are using a Linux machine, the list of fallback fonts is the following:</p>
    <ul id="ul_jnv_zp2_yrb">
      <li><b>Sans-Serif</b> - <codeph>DejaVu Sans, FreeSans, Noto Sans CJK SC, Noto Sans CJK JP,
          Noto Sans CJK KR</codeph></li>
      <li><b>Serif</b> - <codeph>Times, DejaVu Serif, FreeSerif, Noto Serif CJK SC, Noto Serif CJK
          JP, Noto Serif CJK KR</codeph></li>
      <li><b>Monospace</b> - <codeph>DejaVu Sans Mono, FreeMono, Noto Sans CJK SC, Noto Sans CJK JP,
          Noto Sans CJK KR</codeph></li>
    </ul>
    <p id="p_i4v_dgk_54b">If you use the processor on multiple operating systems/machines, make sure
      you have a consistent list of fonts installed on each of them. For instance, if you are using
      a Linux and a Windows machine to run transformations in parallel and the PDF produced on Linux
      has some missing characters (they are replaced with the # symbol), then you can fix this by
      inspecting the fonts listed in the <uicontrol>Document Properties</uicontrol> dialog box in
      the PDF reader and install them on the Linux machine (make sure you respect the licensing
      terms for the font).</p>
    <note id="note_ng5_5p2_yrb">It is not necessary to have all the fallback fonts installed on the
      system.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
