<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ch_page_boundaries">
    <title>Page Boundaries</title>
    <body>
    <p>The PDF specification defines two printing medium: the finished medium, like a sheet of
      paper, or the intermediate medium used in prepress process, like a film or a reproduction
      plate. The intermediate medium may contains additional content such as bleeds or printer marks
      that are presented outside the finished page boundaries. To handle these cases, a PDF page may
      define different boundaries to control each aspect:<ul id="ul_pgw_f1p_k1c">
        <li>The <i>media box</i> defines the boundaries of the physical medium on which the page is
          to be printed. It may include any extended area surrounding the finished page for bleed,
          printing marks, etc.</li>
        <li>The <i>bleed box</i> defines the boundaries in which the content of the page shall be
          cropped in a production environment. It may include any extra bleed area needed to
          accommodate the physical limitations of cutting, folding, and trimming equipment.</li>
        <li>The <i>trim box</i> defines the boundaries of the finished page after trimming.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The boundary can be set directly from the CSS by using the <xref
        href="ch_css_extensions.dita#ch_css_extensions/oxy-crop-box"
        ><codeph>-oxy-crop-box</codeph></xref>
      property:<codeblock id="codeblock_pps_h2p_k1c" outputclass="language-css">@page {
  -oxy-crop-box: trim-box;
}</codeblock></p>
    <image href="../img/ch_page_boundaries.png" id="image_gxx_ypx_k1c"/>
    <section id="section_d3k_kgp_k1c">
      <title>Page Bleeding</title>
      <p>The page bleeding can be controlled by using either one, or both of the
          <codeph>bleed</codeph> and <xref
          href="ch_css_extensions.dita#ch_css_extensions/oxy-crop-offset"
            ><codeph>-oxy-crop-offset</codeph></xref>
          properties:<codeblock id="codeblock_zd4_dfp_k1c" outputclass="language-css">@page {
  -oxy-crop-offset: 1cm;
}</codeblock><note id="note_vns_gfp_k1c">If only one of the properties is present, its
          value will be used, if both are set:<ul id="ul_wds_jfp_k1c">
            <li>If the crop box is set to media-box (default), the bigger value will be used.</li>
            <li>If the crop box is set to bleed-box, only the bleed value will be used.</li>
            <li>If the crop box is set to trim-box (finished page), no value will be used.</li>
          </ul></note></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
