<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="setting_image_width_and_height">
    <title>Setting Image Width and Height</title>
    <body>
        <p>The image size can be determined from the number of pixels of the image, taking into account the <xref href="ch_image_resolution.dita">image resolution</xref>, if available. There are cases in which this computed size is not what you need, and you want to specify the size explicitly. </p>
        <p>For HTML is enough to use the image attributes directly in your document.</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;img src="my_image.png" <b>width="300"</b> <b>height="250"</b> /></codeblock>
        <p>For an arbitrary XML, you can indicate the image width and height through a rule that matches the element (or its pseudo elements :before or :after) and sets the <codeph>width</codeph> and <codeph>height</codeph> CSS properties.</p>
        <codeblock>imagedata {
    display: inline;
    content: attr(src, url);
    <b>width: attr(width, length);
    height: attr(height, length);</b>
}</codeblock>
        <p>Or, if you use an image as a decorator, you can specify fixed dimensions in the CSS:</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-css">chapter title:before {
    content: url("my_artwork.png");
    width: 300px;
}</codeblock>
        <p>
            <note>For static content as in the example above, <ph keyref="product"/> tries to use the width and height set on the pseudo element, then the ones that are set on the parent element, but only if the static content is composed of a single image. Mixing text and images in the <codeph>content</codeph> property disables the width and height specification.</note>
        </p>
        <p>If you want to limit the width of the images to a maximum size, you can use the <codeph>max-width</codeph> property. The image will be scaled down to fit the maximum size, if it is larger.</p>
        <codeblock>imagedata {
    ...
    content: attr(src, url);
    <b>max-width: attr(width, length);</b> 
    ...
}</codeblock>
    </body>
</topic>
