<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_l1z_ydb_by">
  <title>The Page Rule</title>
  <body>
    <section id="section_ut5_vs3_5z">
      <title>Setting the Page Size</title>
      <p>If you do not set the size, <ph keyref="product"/> uses portrait <keyword>US-LETTER</keyword> with margins of 1in. </p>
      <p>This is the basic choice you will have to make for your output. You can use the <codeph>@page</codeph> rule like this: <codeblock outputclass="language-css">@page { 
  size: us-letter;
}</codeblock>The page sizes can be selected by name, like: <keyword>A4</keyword>, <keyword>A3</keyword>, <keyword>US-LEGAL</keyword> (these are case insensitive), or, if you are planning to print on a non-standard sheet, you can specify the width and height: <codeblock outputclass="language-css">@page { 
  size: 5in 7in;
}</codeblock></p>
      <p>You can also specify the page orientation, using the <codeph>portrait</codeph> or <codeph>landscape</codeph> keywords.</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-css">@page { 
  size: A3 landscape;
}</codeblock>
      <p>You can use multiple times the <codeph>@page</codeph> rule, the properties will merge as in ordinary CSS element styling rules. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_wms_rq3_5z">
      <title>Using Page Selectors to Style the Blank, Left, Right, First and Last Pages</title>
      <p>There are cases in which you need to have different page settings depending on the position of the page in the printed material. </p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-css">@page :left {
  border-right: 0.5in solid yellow;
}

@page :right {
  border-left: 0.5in solid yellow;
}</codeblock>
      <p>The <codeph>:first</codeph> selector is used to style the the first page from a sequence of pages.</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-css">@page :first {
  border-top: 5pt solid yellow;
}</codeblock>
      <p>The <codeph>:blank</codeph> selector is used to sytle the blank pages that appear as a result of <?oxy_comment_start author="dan" timestamp="20170505T102207+0300" comment="link

"?>forced page breaks<?oxy_comment_end?>. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_w32_l43_5z">
      <title>Using Named Pages</title>
      <p>In the examples above, we changed the default page settings. </p>
      <p>Let's consider that  we need to put one of our document <codeph>table</codeph> elements on a landscape page. We define a named page: <codeph>table-landscape-page</codeph>, that switches the orientation to landscape. To maximize the space available to the table, this page has a smaller margin. The A4 size defined by the default <codeph>@page</codeph> rule is inherited by the named page.</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-css">@page {
  size: A4;
  margin: 1in;
}

@page <b>table-landscape-page</b> {
  size: landscape;
  margin: 0.5in;
}

table {
  page: <b>table-landscape-page</b>;
}</codeblock>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
