<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="checking-xml-well-formedness">
  <title>Checking XML Well-Formedness</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing XML Documents<indexterm>checking XML
          well-formedness</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>A <i>Well-Formed XML</i> document is a document that conforms to the XML syntax rules. A
        <i>Namespace Well-Formed XML</i> document is a document that is XML Well-Formed and is also
      namespace-wellformed and namespace-valid.</p>
    <p>The XML Syntax rules for Well-Formed XML are:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>All XML elements must have a closing tag.</li>
      <li>XML tags are case-sensitive.</li>
      <li>All XML elements must be properly nested.</li>
      <li>All XML documents must have a root element.</li>
      <li>Attribute values must always be quoted.</li>
      <li>With XML, white space is preserved.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The namespace-wellformed rules are:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>All element and attribute names contain either zero or one colon.</li>
      <li>No entity names, processing instruction targets, or notation names contain any
        colons.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The namespace-valid rules are:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>The prefix <i>xml</i> is by definition bound to the namespace name
          <i>http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace</i>. It MAY, but need not, be declared, and MUST
        NOT be undeclared or bound to any other namespace name. Other prefixes MUST NOT be bound to
        this namespace name.</li>
      <li>The prefix <i>xmlns</i> is used only to declare namespace bindings and is by definition
        bound to the namespace name <i>http://www.w3.org/2000/xmlns/</i>. It MUST NOT be declared or
        undeclared. Other prefixes MUST NOT be bound to this namespace name.</li>
      <li>All other prefixes beginning with the three-letter sequence <i>x</i>, <i>m</i>, <i>l</i>,
        in any case combination, are reserved. This means that users SHOULD NOT use them except as
        defined by later specifications and processors MUST NOT treat them as fatal errors.</li>
      <li>The namespace prefix, unless it is <i>xml</i> or <i>xmlns</i>, MUST have been declared in
        a namespace declaration attribute in either the start-tag of the element where the prefix is
        used or in an ancestor element (i.e. an element in whose content the prefixed markup
        occurs). Furthermore, the attribute value in the innermost such declaration MUST NOT be an
        empty string.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>To check if a document is <i>Namespace Well-Formed XML</i>, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Check Well-Formedness<shortcut product="editor author developer">(Ctrl (Meta on
            Mac OS)+Shift+W)</shortcut>
          <shortcut product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">(Alt+Shift+V W (Cmd+Alt+V
            W on Mac))</shortcut></uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. You can also open the drop-down menu of the <image
        href="../img/Validate20.png" id="image_k4z_p4t_2g"/> validate button on the toolbar and
      select <uicontrol>
        <image href="../img/WellFormed20.png" id="image_c4t_44t_2g"/> Check
        Well-Formedness</uicontrol>. If any error is found the result is returned to the message
      panel. Each error is one record in the result list and is accompanied by an error message.
      Clicking the record will open the document containing the error and highlight its approximate
      location.</p>
    <example><title>A not Well-Formed XML
      Document</title><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;root&gt;&lt;tag&gt;&lt;/root&gt;</codeblock>When
        <uicontrol>Check Well-Formedness</uicontrol> is performed the following error is
        raised:<codeblock>The element type "tag" must be terminated by the matching end-tag "&lt;/tag&gt;"</codeblock><p>To
        resolve the error, click in the result list record which will locate and highlight the
        errors approximate position. Identify which start tag is missing an end tag and insert
        &lt;/tag&gt;.</p></example>
    <example>
      <title>A not namespace-wellformed document</title>
      <p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;x::y&gt;&lt;/x::y&gt;</codeblock>When <uicontrol>Check document
          form</uicontrol> is performed the following error is raised:
        <screen xml:space="preserve">Element or attribute do not match QName production: QName::=(NCName':')?NCName.</screen></p>
    </example>
    <example>
      <title> A not namespace-valid document</title>
      <p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;x:y&gt;&lt;/x:y&gt;</codeblock> When <uicontrol>Check document
          form</uicontrol> is performed the following error is raised:
        <screen xml:space="preserve">The prefix "x" for element "x:y" is not bound.</screen></p>
    </example>
    <p>Also the files contained in the current project and selected with the mouse in <xref
        href="using-the-project-view.dita">the Project view</xref> can be checked for
      well-formedness with one action available on the popup menu of the Project view <ph
        product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">in the <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol>
      submenu</ph>: <uicontrol><image href="../img/WellFormed20.png"/>Check
        Well-Formedness</uicontrol>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
