<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="check-out-working-copy">
  <title>Check Out a Working Copy</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Checking out a working copy</indexterm>
        </indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><i>Check out</i> means to make a copy of a project from a repository to your local file
      system. This copy is called a <i>working copy</i>. An <ph keyref="apacheSubversion"/> working
      copy is a specially formatted directory structure that contains additional
        <filepath>.svn</filepath> directories that store Subversion information, as well as a
      pristine copy of each item that is checked out.</p>
    <p>To check out a working copy, locate and select the desired directory in the
        <uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view and select the <uicontrol>Check out</uicontrol>
      action from the contextual menu, the toolbar, or the <uicontrol>Repository</uicontrol>
      menu.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_bhn_tyk_4r">
        <title>Check Out Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_svn_check_out_dialog.png" id="image_lhn_tyk_4r"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The following options can be configured in the <uicontrol>Check out</uicontrol> dialog
      box:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>URL</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><xref href="entering-local-paths-urls.dita#entering-local-paths-urls/url-section">The
              location of the repository directory</xref> to be <i>checked out</i>.<note type="note"
              >To check out an item that was deleted, moved, or replaced, you need to specify the
              original URL (before the item was removed) and use a <xref
                href="../topics/using-peg-revisions.dita#using-peg-revisions"><i>peg</i>
                revision</xref> at the end (for example, <codeph>URL@rev1234</codeph>).</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Revision</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>You can choose between the <uicontrol>HEAD</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Other</uicontrol>
            revision. If you need to <i>check out</i> a specific revision, specify it in the
              <uicontrol>Other</uicontrol> text box or use the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> button
            and choose a revision from <xref href="../topics/history-dialog.dita#history-dialog"
              format="dita">the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> dialog box</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Check out to</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Specify<xref
              href="entering-local-paths-urls.dita#entering-local-paths-urls/local-path-section">
              the location where you want to <i>check out</i></xref> the new working copy by typing
            the local path in the text box or by using the <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol> button. If
            the specified local path does not point to an existing directory, it will automatically
            be created.<p>
              <note type="important">By default, the SVN system only checks out the content of the
                directory specified by the URL, and not the directory itself. Therefore, it is
                recommended to use the <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol> button to select the <i>check
                  out</i> location so that the client will automatically append the name of the
                remote directory to the path of the selected directory.</note>
              <note type="warning">The destination directory should be empty. If files exist, they
                are skipped (left unchanged) by the <i>check out</i> operation and <xref
                  href="working-copy-view.dita#working-copy-view/wc_local_file_status">displayed as
                    <i>modified</i></xref> after the operation has finished. Also, the destination
                directory must not already be under version control.</note>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The SVN format of the working copy. You can choose between <uicontrol>SVN
              1.8</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>SVN 1.7</uicontrol>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Depth</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The depth is useful if you want to <i>check out</i> only a part of the selected
            repository directory and bring the rest of the files and subdirectories in a future
            update. You can find out more about the checkout depth in the <xref
              href="../topics/sparse-checkouts.dita">sparse checkouts</xref> section. You can choose
            between the following depths:<ul id="ul_zp2_jzk_4r">
              <li><uicontrol>Recursive (infinity)</uicontrol> - Checks out all the files and folders
                contained in the selected folder.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Immediate children (immediates)</uicontrol> - Checks out only the child
                files and folders without recursing subfolders.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>File children only (files)</uicontrol> - Checks out only the child
                files.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>This folder only (empty)</uicontrol> - Checks out only the selected
                folder (no child file or folder is included).</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Ignore "svn:externals" definitions</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When selected, external items are ignored in the <i>check out</i> operation. This
            option is only available if you choose the <uicontrol>Recursive (infinity)</uicontrol>
            depth.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p>After a check out, the new working copy is added to the list in the <xref
        href="../topics/working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref> and
      loaded automatically.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
