<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="checking-for-errors">
  <title>Validating XML Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Validation side panel</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Validating documents</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Quick Fixes</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> automatically checks the document for errors. The errors and
      warnings reported by the validation engine include problems found in the following:<ul>
        <li>The structural integrity and well-formedness of the document.</li>
        <li>A set of best practice rules (such as a maximum number of words in a paragraph).</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="presenting_validation_problems_in_the_editing_pan">
      <title>Presenting Validation Problems in the Editing Panel</title>
      <p>In the editing panel, the validation errors appear underlined in red, while warnings are
        underlined in yellow. On a desktop device, if you hover the mouse over the errors or
        warnings, a tooltip is displayed that provides more information about the problem.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="validation_side_panel">
      <title>Validation Side Panel</title>
      <p>Details about the validation problems are also presented in the
          <uicontrol>Validation</uicontrol> side panel.<ph
          conkeyref="reusables-webapp/side-panel-ph"/></p>
      <p>A red marker shows the number of errors found in the document. Each detected problem is
        listed in its own box in this side panel and each box has a colored left border that
        indicates the type of problem.<ul>
          <li><b>Red</b> – Indicates a validation error.</li>
          <li><b>Yellow</b> - Indicates a validation warning.</li>
          <li><b>Blue</b> - Indicates an informational message.</li>
        </ul>If you click (or tap) a validation item in this side panel, that particular problem is
        highlighted in the editor. Similarly, if the cursor is located at a location in the document
        where there is a problem, that particular validation item is highlighted in the
          <uicontrol>Validation</uicontrol> side panel. The editor and the side panel are
        automatically synced in real time.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Validation Side Panel</title>
          <image href="../img/WA_validation_tab.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="quick_fixes_to_solve_validation_problems">
      <title>Quick Fixes to Solve Validation Problems</title>
      <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> also includes support for <term>Quick Fixes</term> that help
        you resolve validation issues that appear in XML documents by offering you proposals for
        automatically solving the issues with one click.</p>
      <p>For any validation item that has a detected <term>Quick Fix</term>, the proposals are
        listed in the <uicontrol>Validation</uicontrol> side panel as links. On a desktop device,
        these links also appear in the tooltip that is displayed when hover over a problem in the
        editor.</p>
      <p>For information about common errors that appear in XML documents that are validated against
        DTD, XSD, or Relax NG schemas, see <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/xsd-rng-quick-fixes.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Quick Fixes for DTD, XSD, and Relax NG Errors</xref>.</p>
      <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> also supports Schematron Quick Fixes. A developer can create
        custom Schematron Quick Fixes to help impose Authoring rules and provide quick solutions to
        fix errors. For more information, see the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/schematron-quick-fixes.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Schematron Quick Fixes (SQF) section in the Oxygen XML
          Editor User Manual</xref>. There is also an interesting Blogpost written on this subject
        available at: <xref
          href="http://blog.oxygenxml.com/2015/05/schematron-checks-to-help-technical.html"
          format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
      <note><term>Quick Fixes</term> cannot be applied to read-only documents.</note>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
