<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="colors-and-styles-preferences">
  <title>Colors and Styles Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p>To open the Author <uicontrol>Colors and Styles</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Edit modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Colors and Styles</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The central area of the page contains a table that lists both styles associated with the
      profiling attributes values defined in the <xref
        href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#profiling.conditions" format="dita">profiling
        options page</xref> and custom styles.</p>
    <p>To add profiling styles use one of the following actions:<ul id="ul_vjj_x33_sn">
        <li><uicontrol>Import from DITAVAL...</uicontrol> - Allows you to import profiling styles
          from <filepath>.ditaval</filepath> files. You can merge these new profiling styles with
          the existing ones, or replace them completely. If the imported styles conflict with the
          existing ones, <ph keyref="product"/> displays a dialog box containing two tables: the
          first one previews the imported styles and the second one previews the already defined
          styles. You can choose either to keep the existing styles or replace them with the
          imported ones.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Automatic styling</uicontrol> - For every profiling attribute value that has
          no style defined, applies one of the following color or style: background, foreground,
          text decoration (underline, overline, double-underline) or text style (bold, italic).</li>
        <li><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> - Opens the <uicontrol>Add Profiling Style</uicontrol> dialog
          that allows you to associate a set of coloring and styling properties to a profiling
            value.<note>You can define a default style for a specific attribute by setting the
              <uicontrol>Attribute value</uicontrol> field to <codeph>&lt;ANY></codeph>. This style
            is applied for attribute values that do not have a specific style associated with
            it.</note></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To modify an already defined style use one of the following actions:<ul id="ul_gcd_hg3_sn">
        <li>double click the style in the styles table to open the <uicontrol>Edit Profiling
            Style</uicontrol> dialog;</li>
        <li>select the style in the styles table and press <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> to open the
            <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Style</uicontrol> dialog.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To delete the styles, select one or more styles and click the <uicontrol>Clear
        Style</uicontrol> button or press the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> key on your
      keyboard.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
