<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="colors-and-styles-preferences">
  <title>Colors and Styles Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> lets you set the colors and styles used to display <xref
        keyref="options_editor_profiling">profiling / conditional text</xref> in the <xref
        href="author-editor.dita#author-editor"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode editor</xref>. To
      set Colors and Styles preferences, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Edit modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Colors and Styles</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The preference page includes the following options and sections:<dl>
        <dlentry id="show-profiling-colors-styles">
          <dt><uicontrol>Show profiling colors and styles</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Toggles whether or not the <xref
              href="profiling-conditional-text-menu.dita#profiling-conditional-text-menu/show-profiling-colors"
                ><uicontrol>Show Profiling Colors and Styles</uicontrol> option</xref> in the
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingDrop.png"/> Profiling / Conditional
              Text</uicontrol> drop-down menu is enabled by default.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Import from DITAVAL</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to import profiling styles from <filepath>.ditaval</filepath> files. You
            can merge these new profiling styles with the existing ones, or replace them completely.
            If the imported styles conflict with the existing ones, <ph keyref="product"/> displays
            a dialog box containing two tables: the first one previews the imported styles and the
            second one previews the already defined styles. You can choose to either keep the
            existing styles or replace them with the imported ones.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Profiling Colors and Styles Table</dt>
          <dd>You can use buttons below this table to set specific colors and styles for the listed
            profiling attribute values. The table includes two categories:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>Defined attributes values</uicontrol> - Contains the styles for
                profiling attribute values defined in the <xref
                  href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                  format="dita"><uicontrol>Profiling / Conditional Text</uicontrol></xref>
                preferences page. Each profiling attribute value has an associated style. To ease
                the process of customizing styles, the <uicontrol>Defined attributes
                  values</uicontrol> category contains by default the list of empty styles. All you
                have to do is to adjust the colors and decorations, thus skipping the process of
                manually defining the association rules (document type, attribute name and value).
                This is the reason why a style from this category can only be <xref
                  href="#colors-and-styles-preferences/reset_style" format="dita">reset</xref>, not
                deleted.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Other</uicontrol> - This category contains styles for attribute values
                that are not marked as profiling values, in the <xref
                  href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                  format="dita"><uicontrol>Profiling / Conditional Text</uicontrol></xref>
                preferences page. In this category are listed:<ul>
                  <li>All the styles that were defined in other projects (with other profiling
                    attribute value sets).</li>
                  <li>All the styles set for the profiling attributes defined in a <xref
                      href="subject-scheme-map.dita#subject-scheme-map"><term>subject scheme
                        map</term></xref>.</li>
                </ul></li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Automatic styling</uicontrol> button</dt>
          <dd>If you click this button, <ph keyref="product"/> will apply automatic styling to the
            profiling attribute values that do not have a style defined.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> button</dt>
          <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Add Profiling Style</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you to
            associate a set of coloring and styling properties to a profiling value. <note>You can
              define a default style for a specific attribute by setting the <uicontrol>Attribute
                value</uicontrol> field to <codeph>&lt;ANY&gt;</codeph>. This style is applied for
              attribute values that do not have a specific style associated with it.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button</dt>
          <dd>Open the <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Style</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you to
            edit the colors or style for an existing profiling value. You can also double-click the
            value to open this dialog box.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="reset_style">
          <dt><uicontrol>Clear style</uicontrol> button</dt>
          <dd>Resets the style for the selected value to its default setting (no color or
            decoration).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button</dt>
          <dd>Delete the selected style from the <uicontrol>Other</uicontrol> category.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="dita-ditaval-file.dita#dita-ditaval-file"/><link href="dita-flag-content-ditaval.dita#dita-flag-content-ditaval"/></linklist>
    
  </related-links>
</topic>
