<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="compare-merge-docs-with-change-tracking-highlights">
  <title>How to Compare and Merge Documents with Change Tracking Highlights</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Compare documents with change tracking highlights</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_zkz_rr2_pzb"><ph keyref="product"/> includes two actions (<b>Merge Documents with
        Change Tracking Highlights</b> and a <b>Merge Directories with Change Tracking
        Highlights</b>) within the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Comparison Tools</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu that can be used to compare and merge content and the comparison results
      are saved as documents with highlighted tracked changes that can be later reviewed and
      accepted or rejected.</p>
    <p>This topic provides instructions and several different use cases for how to get the most out
      of comparing and merging documents with change tracking highlights present.</p>
    <section id="section_vg4_hnf_pzb">
      <title>Use Case 1: Review Changes Made to an XML Document</title>
      <p id="p_w3v_bgk_54b">The <xref href="merge-docs-with-change-tracking-highlights.dita"
            ><uicontrol>Merge Documents with Change Tracking Highlights</uicontrol> tool</xref> can
        be used to merge two XML documents, based on a 2-way mode comparison. The files involved in
        the process are merged by saving the comparison results as documents with highlighted
        tracked changes.</p>
      <p>Here is the basic procedure:<ol>
          <li>Select the <uicontrol>Merge Documents with Change Tracking Highlights</uicontrol>
            action that is found in the <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Comparison Tools</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu to invoke the tool. It opens a dialog box where you can specify the
            documents to merge.</li>
          <li>In the resulting dialog box, you need to provide the URLs of the base version of the
            document (<uicontrol>Base document</uicontrol>) and the modified version
              (<uicontrol>Document to merge with</uicontrol>), and then click the
              <uicontrol>Merge</uicontrol> button.<p><b>Step Result:</b> The resulting document is
              automatically loaded into a new editor tab. It incorporates special markings for the
              tracked changes/differences between the 2 compared and analyzed XML files.</p></li>
          <li>Switch to the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and then open the
              <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view (click the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/ManageReviews20.png"/>Manage reviews</uicontrol> button on the toolbar
            or select it from the <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu).<p><b>Step Result:</b> All detected changes are listed in the
                <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view and they are marked accordingly in the resulting
              document as well.</p></li>
          <li>You can analyze each detected change one by one and accept or reject them individually
            or in bulk.</li>
          <li>Save the changes you made during the reviewing process.</li>
        </ol></p>
      <p id="p_ylj_f1h_nyb2">
        <fig>
          <title>Revised Merged Document</title>
          <image href="../img/merged-doc.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_fnt_lnf_pzb">
      <title>Use Case 2: Compare Differences Between Two Versions</title>
      <p id="p_z53_fs2_pzb">Another interesting way of using the resulting merged document that
        incorporates the change tracking marks between 2 versions is to apply a transformation of
        the resulting document into a PDF file that highlights the changes between the compared
        versions.</p>
      <p id="p_clb_lmf_pzb">Here is the basic procedure (for this particular example, suppose the
        resulting merged document is a DITA file):<ol>
          <li>Select the <uicontrol>Merge Documents with Change Tracking Highlights</uicontrol>
            action that is found in the <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Comparison Tools</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu to invoke the tool. It opens a dialog box where you can specify the
            documents to merge.</li>
          <li>In the resulting dialog box, you need to provide the URLs of the base version of the
            document (<uicontrol>Base document</uicontrol>) and the modified version
              (<uicontrol>Document to merge with</uicontrol>), and then click the
              <uicontrol>Merge</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li>With the resulting merged document open in the editor, click the <uicontrol>Configure
              Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button from the toolbar.</li>
          <li>Select the default read-only scenario <uicontrol>DITA PDF - based on HTML5 &amp;
              CSS</uicontrol> and click the <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> button to create a copy
            so that you can make a few changes to the default settings.</li>
          <li>In the resulting <uicontrol>Edit DITA Scenario</uicontrol> dialog box, go to the
              <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab and type "changes" in text filter field above
            the table of parameters. This will display the three parameters that are responsible for
            displaying the tracked changes in the resulting PDF and they must all be set to the
            value of <i>yes</i>:<ul>
              <li><codeph>show.changes.and.comments</codeph></li>
              <li><codeph>show.changes.and.comments.as.changebars</codeph></li>
              <li><codeph>show.changes.and.comments.as.pdf.sticky.notes</codeph></li>
            </ul><p id="p_s3v_hs2_pzb"><image href="../img/param-edit-01.png"/></p></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>, and with the newly created copy of the scenario
            selected, click the <uicontrol>Apply associated</uicontrol> button to run the
                transformation.<p><b>Result:</b> Once the transformation is finished, the resulting
              PDF is automatically opened in the system's default PDF reader (e.g. Adobe). If you
              hover the mouse over the presented colored markers, you will notice that the tooltip
              shows that some are of the type "inserted", while others are of the type "deleted".
              Text areas and fragments with changes are also marked with gray "change" bars on the
              left. The changed content is placed between curly brackets and is colored blue or red
              depending on the type of change (insertion or deletion).</p><p id="p_a2x_ht2_pzb"
                ><image href="../img/adobe-01.png"/></p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_lw3_rnf_pzb">
      <title>Use Case 3: Compare and Merge Entire Directories</title>
      <p id="p_mw3_rnf_pzb">Another use case is to use the <b>Merge Directories with Change Tracking
          Highlights</b> action to merge entire directories instead of specified pairs of XML
        files.</p>
      <p>Here is the basic procedure (for this particular example, suppose you want to review the
        changes between two versions of an entire DITA project):<ol>
          <li>Select the <uicontrol>Merge Directories with Change Tracking Highlights</uicontrol>
            action that is found in the <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Comparison Tools</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu to invoke the tool. It opens a dialog box where you can specify the
            documents to merge.</li>
          <li>In the resulting dialog box, you need to provide the URLs of the <uicontrol>Base
              directory</uicontrol>, the <uicontrol>Directory to merge with</uicontrol>, and the
              <uicontrol>Output directory</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>You can optionally select the <uicontrol>Backup the base directory</uicontrol> option.
            Not that this option is automatically activated and selected in the following cases:<ul>
              <li>The output directory is not specified (the field is left blank).</li>
              <li id="li_rhl_4t2_pzb">The specified output directory is the base directory
                itself.</li>
            </ul><p id="p_shl_4t2_pzb">In these situations, a backup of the base directory will be
              performed automatically and the backup operation must succeed to proceed with the
              merge. Otherwise, the merge process is aborted.</p></li>
          <li>You can adjust the settings in the <uicontrol>Merge options</uicontrol> section. You
            can find details for each option in <xref
              href="merge-dirs-with-change-tracking-highlights.dita#merge-dirs-with-change-tracking-highlights/dlentry_esx_djc_kqb"
              >Merge Directories with Change Tracking Highlights: Merge Options</xref>. Note that
            all of these options are enabled by default except for <uicontrol>Create change tracking
              markers for the XML files to be added</uicontrol>.<p id="p_uhl_4t2_pzb">To better
              understand the merge options presented in this section, note that the merge process
              has a preliminary phase where the entire structure and the content of the base
              directory is copied to the output directory.</p><p>Since this example is for reviewing
              the changes between two versions of an entire DITA project, you would select all
              options in the <uicontrol>Merge options</uicontrol> section, including the
                <uicontrol>Create change tracking markers for XML files to be added</uicontrol>
              option.</p></li>
          <li>Click the he <uicontrol>Merge</uicontrol> button to start the process of generating
            the results of the merge operation. Depending on the number of files in the compared
            directories and the total number of changes detected, the process may take some
                time.<p><b>Step Result:</b> The operation report should automatically open in
                <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. The listed URLs are actually links that will
              open the corresponding merged DITA file in the editor. You can inspect the changes and
              accept or reject them, individually or in bulk.</p><p id="p_slr_tt2_pzb"><image
                href="../img/merge-report.png"/></p><p id="p_l5z_wt2_pzb">The first group of URLs
              listed represents the group of XML files detected as modified and merged with change
              tracking highlights.</p><p id="p_p5z_wt2_pzb">The modified non-XML file group follows.
              Since the <uicontrol>Update the modified non-XML files</uicontrol> option was
              selected, these type of non-XML files from the <uicontrol>Base directory</uicontrol>
              were replaced by their corresponding files in the <uicontrol>Directory to merge
                with</uicontrol>.</p><p id="p_q5z_wt2_pzb">Next are the XML files that were
              initially present only in the <uicontrol>Directory to merge with</uicontrol>. They
              were also added to the <uicontrol>Output directory</uicontrol>, since the
                <uicontrol>Add the files found only in the directory to merge with</uicontrol>
              option was selected.</p><p id="p_t5z_wt2_pzb">Since the <uicontrol>Create change
                tracking markers for the XML files to be added</uicontrol> was also selected, change
              tracking markers of type "entire content added/inserted" were created. Note that it
              does not make sense to reject that type of change. The <uicontrol>Create change
                tracking markers for the XML files to be added</uicontrol> option is not intended
              for the merge process itself, but it is useful if you want to apply various
                <i>Oxygen</i> transformation scenarios to the resulting output directory, as
              explained later.</p><p id="p_w5z_wt2_pzb">Next comes the group of non-XML files
              initially present only in the <uicontrol>Directory to merge with</uicontrol> and they
              were also copied to the output directory. Basically, these are resources (usually
              image or video files) used by the file group listed above. Clicking these types of
              file links results in opening them in the appropriate application installed on your
              computer.</p><p id="p_z5z_wt2_pzb">The last group listed in the report represents the
              group of files from the "base directory" that have no longer counterparts in the
              "directory to merge with". Since the <uicontrol>Delete the files found only in the
                base directory</uicontrol> option was selected, these files are eventually deleted,
              even if they were initially copied to the output directory. The links also work for
              them, opening the associated files from the <uicontrol>Base
            directory</uicontrol>.</p></li>
          <li>Now that you have the directory resulting from the merge operation at your disposal,
            you can apply a transformation scenario to obtain a PDF document that highlights the
            changes between the 2 versions. Open the DITA map that resulted from the merge operation
            in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, click the <uicontrol>Configure
              Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button in the toolbar of the view, and apply
            the <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS - Copy</uicontrol> transformation
            scenario using the same configuration as explained in <xref
              href="#compare-merge-docs-with-change-tracking-highlights/section_fnt_lnf_pzb"
                />.<p><b>Step Result:</b> Once the transformation is finished, the resulting PDF is
              automatically opened in the system's default PDF reader (e.g. Adobe).</p></li>
          <li>In Adobe, there is a side view identified as <uicontrol>Bookmarks</uicontrol> (on the
            right or left side, depending of the Adobe version). By selecting
              <uicontrol>Contents</uicontrol> in this view and then scrolling down, you can hover
            the mouse over the presented colored markers for the new topics and you will notice that
            tooltip shows that they are "inserted". You can click on any of these new topics to
            scroll to the respective topic and you will notice that it is marked with blue in the
            document (the color used for newly added content). If you continue to scroll down the
            PDF, you will notice various "insert" and "delete" changes.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Review comments</uicontrol> button on the side stripe of the
              <uicontrol>Bookmarks</uicontrol> view:<p id="p_o3s_xt2_pzb"><image
                href="../img/adobe-02.png"/></p><p><b>Step Result:</b> A list appears that contains
              all highlighted changes in the PDF.</p></li>
          <li>You can scroll through the list and click on the changes listed to conveniently
            analyze and review all tracked and highlighted changes between the 2 versions of the
            DITA project.</li>
        </ol></p>
      <p><u><b>WebHelp Responsive Alternative</b></u></p>
      <p id="p_lzv_j52_pzb">As an alternative to the <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp;
          CSS</uicontrol> transformation, there are other types of transformations that can be
        applied to the resulting DITA map, leading to a different kind of output. For example, you
        can use the <uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp Responsive</uicontrol> transformation scenario:<ol>
          <li>Select the default read-only scenario <uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp
              Responsive</uicontrol> and click the <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> button to create
            a copy so that you can make a few changes to the default settings.</li>
          <li>In the resulting <uicontrol>Edit DITA Scenario</uicontrol> dialog box, go to the
              <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab and type "changes" in text filter field above
            the table of parameters. Make sure the
              <codeph>webhelp.show.changes.and.comments</codeph> parameter is set to <i>yes</i>.<p
              id="p_xtm_k52_pzb"><image href="../img/param-edit-02.png"/></p></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>, and with the newly created copy of the scenario
            selected, click the <uicontrol>Apply associated</uicontrol> button to run the
                transformation.<p><b>Step Result:</b> Once the transformation finishes, the
              resulting WebHelp output is opened in your default Internet browser. By clicking on
              any of the chapters listed, you can browse the respective content and observe how the
              changes are rendered. The color code is the same (blue for the changes of the type
              "added" or "inserted", and red for those of the type "deleted"). The yellow markings
              on the right side also help to navigate through and analyze/review the highlighted
              changes.</p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <?oxy_comment_start author="Steven" timestamp="20231226T170542-0700" comment="Add link to video once it&apos;s complete (EXM-53867)"?>
    <section id="resources">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p>For more information about how to merge documents/directories with change tracking
        highlights, watch our video demonstration:</p>
    </section><?oxy_comment_end?>
  </body>
</topic>
