<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="comparing-and-merging-documents">
    <title>Compare Files or Directories </title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Comparing files and directories</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a simple means of performing file and folder comparisons.
      You can see the differences in your files and folders and merge the changes. You can also use
      the file comparison to compare fragments or files inside zip-based archives.</p>
        <p>There are two types of comparison tools: <uicontrol>Compare Directories</uicontrol> or
        <uicontrol>Compare Files</uicontrol>. These utilities<ph> are available from the
          <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu or</ph> can be opened as stand-alone applications from
      the <ph keyref="product"/> installation folder (<filepath>diffDirs.exe</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffFiles.exe</filepath>).</p>
    <section id="starting_the_tools_from_a_command_line">
      <title>Starting the Tools from a Command Line</title>
      <p>The comparison tools can also be started by using command-line arguments. In the
        installation folder there are two executable shells (<filepath>diffFiles.bat</filepath> and
          <filepath>diffDirs.bat</filepath> on Windows, <filepath>diffFiles.sh</filepath> and
          <filepath>diffDirs.sh</filepath> on Unix/Linux, <filepath>diffFilesMac.sh</filepath> and
          <filepath>diffDirsMac.sh</filepath> on OS X). To specify files or directories to compare,
        you can pass command-line arguments to each of these shells. The arguments can point to file
        or folder paths in directories or archives (supported formats: <term>zip</term>,
          <term>docx</term>, and <term>xlsx</term>).</p>
      <p>For example, to start the comparison between the two Windows directories
          <filepath>c:\Program Files</filepath> and <filepath>c:\ant</filepath>, use the following
        command:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">diffDirs.bat "c:\Program Files" "c:\ant"</codeblock>If
        there are spaces in the path names, surround the paths with quotes. If you pass only one
        argument, you are prompted to manually choose the second directory or archive. This is also
        true for the files comparison utility.</p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
