<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="comparing-and-merging-documents">
    <title>Comparing and Merging Documents</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Comparing and Merging Documents</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>In large teams composed either of developers or technical writers, the usage of a shared
      repository for the source or document files is a must. Often many authors are editing the same
      file at the same time.</p>
        <p>Finding what has been modified in your files and folders can be hard. If your data is
      changing, you can benefit from accurate identification and processing of changes in your files
      and folders with <ph keyref="product"/>'s
      features for comparing files and directories. These are powerful and easy to use tools that
      will do the job fast and thoroughly. With the new possibilities of differencing and merging,
      it is now easy to manage multiple changes.</p>
        <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a simple
      means of performing file and folder comparisons. You can see the differences in your files and
      folders and merge the changes.</p>
        <p>There are two levels on which the comparison can be done, namely comparing directories or
      comparing individual files. <ph product="editor author diff developer">These two operations
        are available from the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu.</ph></p>
    <note><ph keyref="product"/> uses diff directories
      to compare archive files. </note>
        <p>The comparison tool can also be started using command line arguments. In the installation
      folder there are two executable shells (<filepath>diffFiles.bat</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffDirs.bat</filepath> on Windows, <filepath>diffFiles.sh</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffDirs.sh</filepath> on Unix/Linux, <filepath>diffFilesMac.sh</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffDirsMac.sh</filepath> on Mac OS X). You can pass one or two command-line
      arguments to each of these shells. Both arguments can point to directories or archives
      (supported formats: <term>zip</term>, <term>docx</term>, and <term>xlsx</term>).</p>
        <p>For example, to start the comparison between two Windows directories, use the following
      command:<screen xml:space="preserve">diffDirs.bat "c:\Program Files" "c:\ant"</screen>If there
      are spaces in the path names, surround the paths with quotes. If you pass only one argument,
      you are prompted to manually choose the second directory or archive. This is valid for the
      files diff utility as well.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
