<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="comparing-and-merging-documents">
    <title>Compare and Merge Files or Directories </title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Comparing and Merging Documents</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>In large teams composed of developers or content authors, the use of a shared repository
      for the source or document files is a must. Often times multiple authors may be editing the
      same file at the same time. It is easy to manage multiple changes by using the <ph
        keyref="product"/> comparison and merging tools.</p>
        <p>It can be difficult to recognize which files and folders have been modified. If your data
      has changed, you can use the helpful <ph keyref="product"/> features for comparing files and
      directories to accurately identify and process changes in your files and folders. These tools
      are powerful, easy-to-use, and produce fast, thorough results. </p>
        <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a simple
      means of performing file and folder comparisons. You can see the differences in your files and
      folders and merge the changes.</p>
        <p>There are two types of comparison tools: <uicontrol>Compare Directories</uicontrol> or
        <uicontrol>Compare Files</uicontrol>. These utilities are available from the
        <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu or can be opened as stand-alone applications from the <ph
        keyref="product"/> installation folder (<filepath>diffDirs.exe</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffFiles.exe</filepath>).</p>
    <note>File comparison and merging actions can also be performed on files inside ZIP-based
      archives. </note>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Compare Files</uicontrol> tool can also be used to compare XML fragments. They
      can be compared and merged by copying and pasting the fragments into both sides of the
      comparison window, without selecting files.</p>
        <p>The comparison tools can also be started by using command-line arguments. In the
      installation folder there are two executable shells (<filepath>diffFiles.bat</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffDirs.bat</filepath> on Windows, <filepath>diffFiles.sh</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffDirs.sh</filepath> on Unix/Linux, <filepath>diffFilesMac.sh</filepath> and
        <filepath>diffDirsMac.sh</filepath> on OS X). To specify files or directories to compare,
      you can pass command-line arguments to each of these shells. The arguments can point to file
      or folder paths in directories or archives (supported formats: <term>zip</term>,
        <term>docx</term>, and <term>xlsx</term>).</p>
        <p>For example, to start the comparison between the two Windows directories
        <filepath>c:\Program Files</filepath> and <filepath>c:\ant</filepath>, use the following
      command:<screen xml:space="preserve">diffDirs.bat "c:\Program Files" "c:\ant"</screen>If there
      are spaces in the path names, surround the paths with quotes. If you pass only one argument,
      you are prompted to manually choose the second directory or archive. This is also true for the
      files comparison utility.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
