<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="configure-toolbars">
  <title>Configuring Toolbars</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configuring Toolbars</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Toolbar configuration</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_ubs_bgk_54b">You can configure the toolbars in <ph keyref="product"/> to personalize
      the interface for your specific needs. You can choose which toolbars to show or hide in the
      current editor mode (<uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>, <ph product="author editor json"
          ><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>,</ph><ph product="developer editor json"
          ><uicontrol>Design</uicontrol>,</ph> or <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol>)<ph
        product="author developer editor"> and in the current <xref keyref="glossentry_perspective"
            ><term>perspective</term></xref> (<uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol><ph
          product="developer editor">, <uicontrol>XSLT Debugger</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>XQuery
            Debugger</uicontrol>,</ph> or <uicontrol>Databse</uicontrol>)</ph>. You can also choose
      which actions to display in each toolbar, add actions to toolbars, and customize the layout of
      the toolbars.</p>
    <p id="p_vbs_bgk_54b">To configure the toolbars, open the <uicontrol>Configure Toolbars</uicontrol> dialog box by
      doing one of the following:<ul id="ul_zfv_y1z_cr">
        <li id="li_wbs_bgk_54b">Right-click any toolbar and select <uicontrol>Configure Toolbars</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li id="li_xbs_bgk_54b">Select <uicontrol>Configure Toolbars</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
          menu.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p id="p_ybs_bgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_zbs_bgk_54b">
        <title>Configure Toolbars Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_configure_toolbars.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_acs_bgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Configure Toolbars</uicontrol> dialog box provides the following features:<dl id="dl_bcs_bgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ccs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Filter Text Box</dt>
          <dd>You can use the filter text box at the top of the dialog box to search for a specific
            toolbar or action.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_dcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Show or Hide Toolbars</dt>
          <dd>You can choose whether to show or hide a toolbar by using the checkbox next to the
            toolbar name. This checkbox is only available for toolbars that are available for the
            current <ph
              product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"><xref
                keyref="glossentry_perspective"><term>perspective</term></xref> and </ph>editing
            mode.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ecs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Show or Hide Actions in a Toolbar</dt>
          <dd>To show or hide actions in a toolbar, expand it by clicking the arrow next to the
            toolbar name, then use the checkbox to select or deselect the appropriate actions. The
            toolbar configuration changes in the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> column according to
            your changes.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_fcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Add Actions to a Toolbar</dt>
          <dd>Use the <uicontrol>Add Actions</uicontrol> button to open the <uicontrol>Add
              Actions</uicontrol> dialog box that displays all the actions that can be added to any
            of the toolbars, with the exception of those that are contributed from <xref
              keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>frameworks</term></xref> or 3rd party <xref
              keyref="glossentry_plugin"><term>plugins</term></xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_gcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Remove Actions from a Toolbar</dt>
          <dd>You can remove actions that you have previously added to toolbars by using the
              <uicontrol>Remove Action</uicontrol> button.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_hcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Move Actions in a Toolbar</dt>
          <dd>Use the <uicontrol>Move Up</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Move Down</uicontrol> actions to
            change the order of the actions in a toolbar.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p id="p_ics_bgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Configure Toolbars</uicontrol> dialog box also provides a variety of other
      ways to customize the layout in <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
    <p id="p_jcs_bgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_kcs_bgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_lcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Customize My Toolbar</dt>
          <dd>You can customize the <uicontrol>My Toolbar</uicontrol> to include your most commonly
            used actions. By default, this toolbar is listed first. Also, it is hidden until you add
            actions to it and you can easily hide it with the <uicontrol>Hide "My Toolbar"
              Toolbar</uicontrol> action that is available when you right-click anywhere in the
            toolbar area. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_mcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Drop-down Menu Actions</dt>
          <dd>Composite actions that are usually displayed as a drop-down menu can only be selected
            in one toolbar at a time. These actions are displayed in the <uicontrol>Configure
              Toolbars</uicontrol> dialog box with the name in brackets. <image
              href="../img/composite_action.png" id="image_z4s_hng_dr" placement="break"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ncs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Configure External Tools Action</dt>
          <dd>There is a <uicontrol><image href="../img/ExternalTools20.png" id="image_ukz_fpz_vr"
              />Configure external tools</uicontrol> composite action that appears in the toolbar
            called <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>. It is a drop-down menu that contains any external
            tools that are configured in the <uicontrol>External Tools</uicontrol> preferences
              page.<note id="note_ocs_bgk_54b">If no external tools are configured, this drop-down menu is not shown in
              the toolbar.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p id="p_pcs_bgk_54b">Additional actions are available from the <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol> menu or contextual
      menu when invoked from a toolbar that allows you to further customize your layout. These
      actions include:</p>
    <p id="p_qcs_bgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_rcs_bgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_scs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Reset Toolbars</dt>
          <dd>To reset the layout of toolbars to the default setting, select the <uicontrol>Reset
              Toolbars</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu or <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
            menu.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_tcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Reset Layout</dt>
          <dd>To reset the entire layout (including toolbars, editing modes, views, etc.) to the
            default setting, select <uicontrol>Reset Layout</uicontrol> from the contextual menu or
              <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol> menu.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ucs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Export Layout</dt>
          <dd>You can use the <uicontrol>Export Layout</uicontrol> action that is available in the
              <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol> menu to export the entire layout of the application to
            share it with other users.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_vcs_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Hide Toolbars</dt>
          <dd>You can use the <uicontrol>Hide Toolbar</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu to
            easily hide a displayed toolbar. When you right-click a toolbar it will be highlighted
            to show you which actions are included in that toolbar.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
      <link href="dockable-views-and-editors.dita#dockable-views-and-editors"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
