<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="configure-transformation-dialog">
  <title>The Configure Transformation Scenario(s) Dialog</title>
  <body>
    <p>You can use this dialog to manage both the <xref
        href="builtin-transformation-scenarios.dita#builtin-transformation-scenarios">built-in
        transformation scenarios</xref> and the ones you create. </p>
    <p>To open it, either click the <uicontrol>
        <image href="../img/bt_transform_config.png"/>Configure Transformation
        Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button on the application toolbar, or go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author developer">Document</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editor author developer"> Transformation</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse"> XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Configure transformation scenario. <shortcut product="editor author developer"
            >(Ctrl (Meta on Mac OS)+Shift+C)</shortcut>
          <shortcut product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">(Alt+Shift+T
            C)</shortcut>
          <shortcut product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">( (Cmd+Alt+T C on Mac
            OS))</shortcut></uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <fig id="figure-configure-transformation-scenario-oxygen" product="editor author developer">
      <title>Configure Transformation Scenario(s) Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_scenario_list_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="figure-configure-transformation-scenario-oxygenEclipse"
      product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>Configure Transformation Scenario(s) Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_scenario_list_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The top section of the dialog contains a filter that allows you to search through the
      scenarios list. Using the <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> button you can configure the
      following options:<ul>
        <li><ph conref="scenarios-view.dita#scenarios-view/show-all-scenarios"/>;</li>
        <li><ph conref="scenarios-view.dita#scenarios-view/scenarios-available-for-editor"/>;</li>
        <li><ph conref="scenarios-view.dita#scenarios-view/show-associated-scenarios"/>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ImportScenario16.png"/>Import scenarios</uicontrol> - use
          this option to open the <uicontrol>Import scenarios</uicontrol> dialog. The
            <uicontrol>Import scenarios</uicontrol> dialog allows you to select which scenario of
          the <filepath>scenarios</filepath> files you want to import. In case one of the scenarios
          you import is identical with an existing scenario, <ph
            keyref="product"/> ignores the scenario
          you are importing. In case a conflict appears (an imported scenario has the same name with
          an existing one), you can choose between two options:<ul>
            <li>keep or replace the existing scenario;</li>
            <li>keep both scenarios.<note>When you keep both scenarios, <ph
                  keyref="product"/> adds
                  <filepath>imported</filepath> to the name of the imported scenario.</note></li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><ph conref="scenarios-view.dita#scenarios-view/export-selected-scenarios"/>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The middle section of the dialog presents the scenarios that you can apply to the document
      you are editing. You can view both the scenarios associated with the current document type and
      the scenarios defined at project level. The following columns are used to display the
      transformation scenarios:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Association</uicontrol> - the check-boxes in this column mark whether a
          transformation scenario is associated with the document you are editing;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Scenario</uicontrol> - this column presents the names of the transformation
          scenarios;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - specifies the type of the transformation scenario. For
          further details about the different types of transformation scenarios available in <ph
            keyref="product"/> go to <xref
            href="defining-new-transformation-scenario.dita#defining-new-transformation-scenario"
            >Defining a New Transformation Scenario</xref>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> - specifies whether a transformation scenario is defined
          at project level.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>Left click the header of each column to sort its items. The contextual menu of each header
      allows you to show or hide the <uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol>
      columns, group the columns by <uicontrol>Association</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Type</uicontrol>,
      and <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol>, ungroup all of them, or reset the layout.</p>
    <p>The bottom section of the dialog contains the following actions:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Association follows selection</uicontrol> - enable this check-box to
          associate selected transformation scenarios automatically with the document you are
          editing. This option also works for multiple selection;<note>When this option is enabled,
            the <uicontrol>Association</uicontrol> column is no longer presented.</note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> - this button allows you to create a new transformation
          scenario <xref
            href="defining-new-transformation-scenario.dita#defining-new-transformation-scenario"
            >depending on its type</xref>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> - this button opens the <uicontrol>Edit scenario</uicontrol>
          dialog which allows you to configure the options of the transformations scenario you are
            editing;<note>In case you try to edit a transformation scenario associated with a
            document type, <ph keyref="product"/>
            displays a warning message to inform you that this is not possible. You have the option
            to create a <xref
              href="../tasks/create-transformation-scenario.dita#create-transformation-scenario"
              >duplicated transformation scenario</xref> and edit this one instead. </note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> - use this button to create a <xref
            href="../tasks/create-transformation-scenario.dita#create-transformation-scenario"
            >duplicated transformation scenario</xref>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> - use this button to remove transformation
            scenarios.<note>Removing scenarios associated with a document type is not permitted.
          </note></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol>, and
        <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> actions are also available in the contextual menu of the
      transformation scenarios listed in the middle section of the <uicontrol>Configure
        Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol>. This contextual menu also contains the <xref
        href="scenarios-view.dita#scenarios-view/import-scenarios"><uicontrol><image
            href="../img/ImportScenario16.png"/>Import scenarios</uicontrol></xref> and <xref
        href="scenarios-view.dita#scenarios-view/export-selected-scenarios"><uicontrol><image
            href="../img/ImportScenario16.png"/>Export selected scenarios</uicontrol></xref> actions
      and allows you to change the storage of a transformation scenario.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
