<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="connect-to-enterprise-server">
  <title>Configuring Your Enterprise Server Address</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Connecting to your Enterprise server</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_wjt_dgk_54b">If your organization is connecting to Content Fusion using your own hosted
      server, your system administrator first needs to <xref
        href="cf-enterprise-server.dita#cf-enterprise-server">set up and configure your Enterprise
        server</xref> and they can either use a <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-configure-server-address-property-file.html"
        format="html" scope="external">properties file to impose the Enterprise server
        address</xref> or they can send you the server address and you can manually configure
        <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term> to connect to the server.</p>
    <section id="configuring_the_onpremise_server_in_oxygen">
      <title>Manually Configuring Oxygen XML Editor/Author to Connect to Your Enterprise
        Server</title>
      <p id="p_xjt_dgk_54b">
        <ol id="ol_yjt_dgk_54b">
          <li id="step6">Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"/>Show Content
              Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> toolbar button to display <xref
              href="cf_task_manager_view.dita#cf_task_manager_view">the task management
            view</xref>.</li>
          <li id="li_zjt_dgk_54b">You are asked to <uicontrol>Choose the Oxygen Content Fusion
              server</uicontrol>. Select <uicontrol>Enterprise</uicontrol> and enter the address of
            your Enterprise server (for example,<filepath>http://fusion.example.com</filepath>). Ask
            your system administrator for the server address if you do not know it. If your
            organization uses the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-configure-server-address-property-file.html"
              format="html" scope="external">properties file to impose the Enterprise server
              address</xref>, you will not need to enter it manually.<note type="important"
              id="note_akt_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Evaluation</uicontrol> option is a service where
              the content is stored on an Evaluation server hosted by <term>Oxygen</term> and with a
              default configuration. It is meant for trial purposes only. When using this option,
              you should only use sample documents that do not contain sensitive information or
              ownership rights.</note></li>
          <li id="li_bkt_dgk_54b">Click <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> to open the Content Fusion
            interface in your default browser.<note id="note_ckt_dgk_54b">If a connection to the
              server could not be established, a <uicontrol>Choose the Oxygen Content Fusion
                server</uicontrol> box is displayed . You can enter the address of your server (it
              must be a valid URL), click <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol>, and this also
              automatically sets the address of your server in the preference page described in
              steps 3 and 4.</note></li>
          <li id="li_dkt_dgk_54b">If this is your first time using Content Fusion, click on
              <uicontrol>SIGN UP</uicontrol> and follow the instructions to create your account. If
            you already have an account, log in and click <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol>.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p id="p_ekt_dgk_54b"><b>Result:</b> You are now ready to start using the <uicontrol>Content
          Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> and when you upload tasks, the documents are stored on
        your Enterprise server.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="changing_the_url_of_the_content_fusion_server">
      <title>Manually Changing the Enterprise Server Address in Oxygen XML Editor/Author</title>
      <p id="p_fkt_dgk_54b">To change the server address of your Enterprise server, use the following procedure:<ol id="ol_gkt_dgk_54b">
          <li id="li_hkt_dgk_54b">In <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>, go to <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Oxygen Content Fusion Connector</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</li>
          <li id="li_ikt_dgk_54b">Enter the new address in the <uicontrol>Server URL</uicontrol> field.<note type="tip" id="note_jkt_dgk_54b"
              >You can click the <uicontrol>Test Connection</uicontrol> button to test the URL. If
                <b>Content Fusion</b> cannot find a connection, it attempts to find an alternative
              (for example, the same URL without a port number). If the attempt at connecting to the
              alternative URL is successful, you are given the choice to connect to that server
              address instead.</note></li>
          <li id="li_kkt_dgk_54b">Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
      <link href="cf_task_manager_view.dita#cf_task_manager_view"/>
    <link href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/cf-enterprise-server.html"
      format="html" scope="external">
      <linktext>Server Administrator Guide</linktext>
    </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>
