<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="conref-push-mechanism">
  <title>Working with the Conref Push Mechanism</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Reusing content<indexterm>Content Reference Push
              mechanism</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Conref Push</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section id="content_reference_push_mechanism">
      <title>Content Reference Push Mechanism</title>
      <p>The usual method of using content references pulls element content from a source element
        and inserts it in the current topic. DITA 1.2 introduced an alternative method of content
        referencing, allowing element content to be pushed, or injected, from a source topic to
        another topic without any special coding in the topic where the content will be re-used.
        This technique is known as a content reference <term>push</term> mechanism (<term>conref
          push</term>).</p>
      <p>The <term>conref push</term> mechanism requires elements in the target topic (the topic
        where the content is to be pushed) to have id elements, as the push mechanism inserts
        elements <term>before</term> or <term>after</term> a named element, or <term>replaces</term>
        the named element. Assuming the source topic is included in the <xref
          keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref>, the <term>conref push</term>
        will be processed during publishing stage for the <term>DITA map</term>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="example_of_a_conref_push_scenario">
      <title>Example of a Conref Push Scenario</title>
      <p>An example of a scenario in which a <term>conref push</term> would be useful is where a car
        manufacturer produces driver manuals that are distributed to various regions with their own
        specific regulations and certain sections need to be customized by the local car dealers
        before publishing. The local dealer could use a <term>conref push</term> technique to insert
        specific content without modifying the manufacturer-supplied content.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="push_current_element_action">
      <title>Push Current Element Action</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes an action that allows you to easily reference content with
        a <term>conref push</term> mechanism. The <uicontrol>Push Current Element</uicontrol> action
        is available in the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu and in the <uicontrol>Reuse</uicontrol>
        subfolder of the contextual menu when editing in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.
        Selecting this action opens the <uicontrol>Push current element</uicontrol> dialog box that
        allows you to select a target resource and element, and where to insert the current element
        content.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_j2g_vxg_5s">
          <title>Push Current Element Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_push_element.png" id="image_yst_4zg_5s" placement="inline"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>This dialog box allows you to configure the following options for the <term>conref
          push</term> action:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Choose the target resource</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Allows you to select a <uicontrol>Location</uicontrol> URL or a
                <uicontrol>Key</uicontrol> for the target resource and the table in the next section
              of the dialog box will be populated using the information from the specified
              resource.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Select the target element</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>The table in this section contains the available elements (identified by their ID)
              that belong to the same class as the current element on which the action was
              invoked.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Push action</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Allows you to choose one of the following options for where you want to insert the
              current element content:<p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol>replace the target element</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>The target element will be replaced with the current element content. <p>On
                        the technical side, the value of the <codeph>conaction</codeph> attribute in
                        the current element will be set to <codeph>pushreplace</codeph> and the
                          <codeph>conref</codeph> or <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute will be
                        set to the specified reference.</p></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol>push before</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>The current element content will be inserted before the specified target
                      element in the target resource. <p>On the technical side, the value of the
                          <codeph>conaction</codeph> attribute in the current element will be set to
                          <codeph>pushbefore</codeph>. Another element with the same name and class
                        as the target element will be inserted in the document after the current
                        element. The new element will have the <codeph>conaction</codeph> attribute
                        set to <codeph>mark</codeph> and the <codeph>conref</codeph> or
                          <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute will be set to the specified
                        reference.</p></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol>push after</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>The current element content will be inserted after the specified target
                      element in the target resource. <p>On the technical side, the value of the
                          <codeph>conaction</codeph> attribute in the current element will be set to
                          <codeph>pushafter</codeph>. Another element with the same name and class
                        as the target element will be inserted in the document before the current
                        element. The new element will have the <codeph>conaction</codeph> attribute
                        set to <codeph>mark</codeph> and the <codeph>conref</codeph> or
                          <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute will be set to the specified
                        reference.</p></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
      <p>You can also use the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> panel to view the content that will be
        pushed and the <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> panel to see the XML code for the content to be
        pushed. After you click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>, the <term>conref push</term> mechanism is
        inserted in the current document. The changes in the target resource will be processed when
        you transform the <term>DITA map</term>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link format="html" href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/dita/styleguide/webhelp-feedback/#Artefact/Content_Reuse/c_Conref_Push.html" scope="external">
      <linktext>For more technical details about the conref push mechanism, refer to "The Conref
        Push Technique" section of The DITA Style Guide Best Practices for Authors.</linktext>
    </link></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
