<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="control-text-direction-markup">
  <title>Controlling the Text Direction Using XML Markup</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> Supports the following CSS properties:</p>
    <table frame="all">
      <title>CSS Properties Controlling Text Direction</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
        <colspec colname="newCol2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><codeph>direction</codeph></entry>
            <entry>Specifies the writing direction of the text. The possible values are
                <codeph>ltr</codeph> (the text direction is left to right), <codeph>rtl</codeph>
              (the text direction is right to left, and <codeph>inherit</codeph> (specifies whether
              the value of the direction property is inherited from the parent element). </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><codeph>unicodeBidi</codeph></entry>
            <entry>Used with the <codeph>direction</codeph> property, sets or returns whether the
              text is overridden to support multiple languages in the same document. The possible
              values of this property are <codeph>bidi-override</codeph> (creates an additional
              level of embedding and forces all strong characters to the direction specified in the
                <codeph>direction</codeph>), <codeph>embed</codeph> (creates an additional level of
              embedding), <codeph>normal</codeph> (does not use an additional level of embedding),
              and <codeph>inherit</codeph> ( the value of the <codeph>unicodeBidi</codeph> property
              is inherited from parent element).</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <p>For instance, to declare an element as being Right to Left, you could use a stylesheet like
      the one below:</p>
    <example>
      <p>XML File:</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;article>
  &lt;myRTLpara>RIGHT TO LEFT TEXT&lt;/myRTLPara>
&lt;/article></codeblock>
      <p>Associated CSS File:</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-css">myRTLpara{
    direction:rtl;
    unicode-bidi:embed;
}</codeblock>
    </example>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> recognizes the <codeph>dir</codeph> attribute on any XML document. The
      supported values are:</p>
    <table>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><codeph>ltr</codeph></entry>
            <entry>The text from the current element is Left to Right, embedded.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><codeph>rtl</codeph></entry>
            <entry>The text from the current element is Right to Left, embedded.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><codeph>lro</codeph></entry>
            <entry>The text from the current element is Left to Right, embedded.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><codeph>rlo</codeph></entry>
            <entry>The text from the current element is Right to Left, embedded.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <p>The following XML document types make use of the <codeph>dir</codeph> attribute with the
      above values:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>DITA;</li>
      <li>Docbook;</li>
      <li>TEI;</li>
      <li>XHTML.</li>
    </ul>
    <note>When the inline element tags are visible, the text in the line is arranged according to
      the BIDI algorithm after replacing the tags symbols with Object Replacement Characters. This
      makes it possible to get a different text arrangement when viewing a document in the
        <uicontrol>No Tags</uicontrol> mode versus viewing it in the <uicontrol>Full
        Tags</uicontrol> mode. </note>
  </body>
</topic>
