<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="content_fusion_task_details">
  <title>Managing Review Tasks in the Browser Interface</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>My Review Tasks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Creating new tasks</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_yq2_hmz_txb">When you navigate to <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol>, the
        <uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> page is opened in the main area. It displays a list
      of all the current tasks that are owned by you and those that are assigned to you.<note
        id="note_j3d_zfg_zxb" type="tip">There are several ways to reach the <uicontrol>My Review
          Task</uicontrol> page. You click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"
            id="image_q2d_1h3_4jb"/>Oxygen Content Fusion</uicontrol> logo on the left side of the
        top ribbon, click the <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol> button in the left stripe (if you
        are in the main <uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> page), click on <uicontrol>My Review
          Tasks</uicontrol> in the top stripe, or you can click the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/CF-Home16.png"/>Home</uicontrol> button in the top stripe or you can use
        the breadcrumb (if a page within a review task is open).</note></p>
    <p id="p_bpt_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_fn2_44w_4jb">
        <title>My Review Tasks Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF_task_details0.png" id="image_gn2_44w_4jb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_hlq_fwf_zxb">To see tasks that you created (or are assigned as an owner), click the
        <uicontrol>Owned By Me</uicontrol> tab. To see tasks that have been assigned to you, click
      the <uicontrol>Assigned To Me</uicontrol> tab. The table also has columns that show
        <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> information (if applicable), the
        <uicontrol>Owners</uicontrol> of the review task, the task's <xref
        href="CF-task-states-user-roles.dita#CF-task-states-user-roles/section_vkk_v4s_1yb"
          ><uicontrol>Status</uicontrol></xref>, the <uicontrol>Due Date</uicontrol> (if specified
      in the <xref href="cf-task-settings.dita"><uicontrol>Task Settings</uicontrol> page</xref>),
      and the <uicontrol>Last Access</uicontrol> column shows the last time you accessed the
      task.</p>
    <p id="p_hlq_fwf_zxb2">Also, if you want to see the tasks that have been finalized (for those
      that are assigned to you), click the <uicontrol>Show finalized</uicontrol> button (when inside
      the <uicontrol>Assigned to Me</uicontrol> tab).</p>
    <p id="p_csm_wfb_z1c">You can use the <uicontrol>Filter by name</uicontrol> field to filter the
      list of review tasks, making it easier to find specific tasks.</p>
    <p>To open an existing task, simply click on it. This open the <xref href="cf-task-files.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Task Files</uicontrol> page</xref>.</p>
    <p>The status of the task is displayed to the right of each task. A task is displayed as
        <uicontrol>In review</uicontrol> unless it is closed by a task owner. If a task has been
      closed, the status is displayed as <uicontrol>Review closed</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p id="p_xhd_sn2_z1c">For tasks in the <uicontrol>Owned By Me</uicontrol> tab, if you hover over
      the task, an ellipsis (3 vertical dots) becomes available on the far right side. This opens an
      actions menu that includes:<ul id="ul_bqs_b42_z1c">
        <li id="li_cqs_b42_z1c"><uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> - Deletes the review task.</li>
        <li id="li_olh_d42_z1c"><uicontrol>Mark as integrated</uicontrol> (Available if the task is
          in the <uicontrol>Review closed</uicontrol> state) - Archives the task and removes it from
          visibility for all users.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="section_cmw_vby_lcc">
      <title>Review Tasks Header</title>
      <p id="p_bgw_42y_lcc">Whenever a review task is open, the upper part of the header stripe
        remains the same no matter what page you navigate to within the review task, which makes
        certain navigation options and the breadcrumb available at all times.</p>
      <p id="p_uqx_wby_lcc">
        <fig id="fig_ppl_cbp_zxb">
          <title>Review Tasks Header Stripe (Non-Project Task)</title>
          <image href="../img/CF-Header.png" id="image_m1v_dbp_zxb"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_t1j_nfl_b1c">The bottom part of the header stripe changes depending on the context
        and user role. It contains a variety of helpful information and some useful actions. You can
        see the title of the task, the <xref
          href="CF-task-states-user-roles.dita#CF-task-states-user-roles/section_vkk_v4s_1yb">status
          of the task</xref>, information about the task owners, details about the number of
        reviewers who have <xref href="finishing_tasks.dita">finalized the task</xref>, and
        information about when its due (if a due date is specified in the <xref
          href="cf-task-settings.dita"><uicontrol>Task Settings</uicontrol> page</xref>). You can
        click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/MoreDetails16.png"/>More Details</uicontrol> button
        to see information such as the creation time and current branch (if inside a project).</p>
      <p id="p_t1j_nfl_b1c1213">If you are the owner of the task, the <uicontrol>Share</uicontrol>
        button is available to open a dialog box where you can configure share settings.</p>
      <p id="p_t1j_nfl_b1c121">You can click on the <uicontrol>Owners</uicontrol> area to see
        information about the task owners.</p>
      <p id="p_t1j_nfl_b1c12313">You can click on the <uicontrol>Finalized</uicontrol> widget
        (drop-down) to see the status for each assigned reviewer:</p>
      <p id="p_bnz_n2y_lcc"><image href="../img/cf-finalized-widget.png"/></p>
      <p id="p_yfw_x22_h1c">If a task <i>owner</i> clicks on the <uicontrol>Finalized</uicontrol>
        widget (drop-down) for a task that has reviewers who have finalized their review, the task
        owner has access to a <uicontrol>Request re-review</uicontrol> button. Clicking this button
        resets the finalized status for all reviewers and their status is changed to <i>In
          progress</i>. Also, if the task owner re-opens a <xref href="cf-closing-tasks.dita">closed
          task</xref>, the finalized status is reset for all reviewers.</p>
      <p id="p_p2b_1lb_z1c">Any users who have been assigned to the task but have not yet accessed
        it are labeled as <i>Pending</i> in the <uicontrol>Review Status Summary</uicontrol> pop-up
        window so that task owners can identify users who have ignored the review request.</p>
      <p id="p_yrn_zk2_h1c">When a reviewer opens a task that the owner requested that they do
        another review, the <uicontrol>Task Files</uicontrol> page includes a <uicontrol>Changed
          files only</uicontrol> filter option to make it easy to identify which files have changes
        that need to be reviewed again.</p>
      <p id="p_vrr_jl2_h1c"><image href="../img/cf-changed-files-only.png"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_cn4_k3x_4jb">
      <title>Creating New Tasks and Files in the Browser Interface</title>
      <p id="p_uxt_dgk_54b">It is possible to create a task directly in the <ph keyref="product"/>
        browser interface. This means that the task creation process is available to anyone who has
        access to the <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface, even if they do not have access to
          <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.</p>
      <p>You can also create or upload files to a newly created task or an existing task.</p>
      <p id="p_vxt_dgk_54b">To create a new task and add files:<ol id="ol_gzj_4pq_4jb">
          <li id="li_wxt_dgk_54b">From the <uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> page, click the
              <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li id="li_eyt_dgk_54b">Enter a title for the task in the field at the top of the pane.
            Click the check mark on the right side when you are done.</li>
          <li id="li_fyt_dgk_54b">You can create or upload files to the task. To create a new file,
            click the <uicontrol>New File</uicontrol> button and you will be able to choose a file
            type from a list of templates, then choose a file name in the text field at the bottom,
            and click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>. To upload a file, click the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/cf-upload16.png" id="image_tqd_n1g_wr1"/>Upload</uicontrol> button and
            select the file from your system's file browser.</li>
          <li id="li_gp1_qjl_5xb">Open the new file in the <xref
              href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita">visual editor page</xref> (if not already
            opened) and use the visual editor to make changes to the document.<note type="tip"
              id="note_dzt_dgk_54b">If you are a task owner, you have access to the
                  <uicontrol><image href="../img/TrackChanges20.png" id="image_tqd_n1g_wr"/>Toggle
                Change Tracking</uicontrol> toolbar button. You may want to toggle this feature off
              when adding content to a new file.</note></li>
          <li id="li_gp1_qjl_5xb2">Optionally, select <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> from the left
            stripe to open the <xref href="cf-task-settings.dita"><uicontrol>Task
                Settings</uicontrol> page</xref> to configure options or delete the task.</li>
          <li id="li_hyt_dgk_54b">The next logical step would most likely be to <xref
              href="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.dita">share the task</xref> with anyone you want to
            review the documents.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
