<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="content_fusion_task_details">
  <title>Review Tasks</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>My Review Tasks</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Reviewer Guide<indexterm>My Review Tasks</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>My Review Tasks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Creating new tasks</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_yq2_hmz_txb"><uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol> is one of the two main components
      (along with <b>Projects</b>) within the Content Fusion browser interface. When you navigate to
        <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol>, the <uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> page is
      opened in the main area. It displays a list of all the current tasks that are owned by you and
      those that are assigned to you.<note id="note_j3d_zfg_zxb" type="tip">There are several ways
        to reach the <uicontrol>My Review Task</uicontrol> page. You click the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_q2d_1h3_4jb"/>Oxygen Content Fusion</uicontrol>
        logo on the left side of the top ribbon, select <uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> from
        the user drop-down menu in the top stripe, click the <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol>
        button in the left stripe (if you are in the main <uicontrol>Projects</uicontrol> page),
        click on <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol> in the top stripe (if a page within a review
        task or project is open), or you can use the breadcrumb (if a page within a review task is
        open).</note></p>
    <p id="p_hlq_fwf_zxb">To see tasks that you created (or are assigned as an owner), click the
        <uicontrol>Owned By Me</uicontrol> tab. To see tasks that have been assigned to you, click
      the <uicontrol>Assigned To Me</uicontrol> tab. Also, for those assigned to you, if you want to
      see the tasks that have been finalized, click the <uicontrol>Show finalized review
        tasks</uicontrol> link at the bottom of the list.</p>
    <p id="p_bpt_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_fn2_44w_4jb">
        <title>My Review Tasks Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF_task_details1.png" id="image_gn2_44w_4jb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>To open an existing task, simply click on it. This open the <xref href="cf-task-files.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Task Files</uicontrol> page</xref>.</p>
    <p>The status of the task is displayed to the right of each task. A task is displayed as
        <uicontrol>In review</uicontrol> unless it is closed by a task owner. If a task has been
      closed, the status is displayed as <uicontrol>Review closed</uicontrol>.</p>
    <section id="section_cn4_k3x_4jb">
      <title>Creating New Tasks and Files in the Browser Interface</title>
      <p id="p_uxt_dgk_54b">It is possible to create a task directly in the <ph keyref="product"/>
        browser interface. This means that the task creation process is available to anyone who has
        access to the <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface, even if they do not have access to
          <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.</p>
      <p id="p_vxt_dgk_54b">To create a new task:<ol id="ol_gzj_4pq_4jb">
          <li id="li_wxt_dgk_54b">From the <uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> page, click the
              <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li id="li_eyt_dgk_54b">Enter a title for the task in the field at the top of the pane.
            Click the check mark on the right side when you are done.</li>
          <li id="li_fyt_dgk_54b">Click the <uicontrol>New File</uicontrol> button to create a new
            file from a list of templates. Select an appropriate template, choose a file name in the
            text field at the bottom, and click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>.<p id="p_bzt_dgk_54b"
                ><b>Step Result:</b> The new file is opened in the <xref
                href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita">visual editor page</xref> with some of
              the XML structure already added for you.</p></li>
          <li id="li_gp1_qjl_5xb">Use the visual editor to make changes to the document.<note
              type="tip" id="note_dzt_dgk_54b">Since you are the task owner, you have access to the
                  <uicontrol><image href="../img/TrackChanges20.png" id="image_tqd_n1g_wr"/>Toggle
                Change Tracking</uicontrol> toolbar button. You may want to toggle this feature off
              when adding content to a new file.</note></li>
          <li id="li_gp1_qjl_5xb2">Optionally, select <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> from the left
            stripe to open the <xref href="cf-task-settings.dita"><uicontrol>Task
                Settings</uicontrol> page</xref> to configure options or delete the task.</li>
          <li id="li_hyt_dgk_54b">The next logical step would most likely be to <xref
              href="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.dita">share the task</xref> with anyone you want to
            review the documents.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
