<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="content_fusion_task_details">
  <title>Task Details Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Task Details</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Reviewer Guide<indexterm>Task Details</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Task Details</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Whenever a task is opened, the main area displays a <i>Task Details</i> page. There are
      multiple ways to access the <i>Task Details</i> page:<ul id="ul_zg1_2ww_4jb">
        <li>You can click a task in the list of tasks that is displayed when selecting <uicontrol>My
            Tasks</uicontrol> from the user name drop-down menu in the top ribbon (if you click a
          task that is listed in the <uicontrol>Review tasks assigned to me</uicontrol> section, the
            <xref href="#content_fusion_task_details/section-task-details-page-reviewers"
            format="dita"><b>Reviewer</b> version of the <i>Task Details</i> page</xref> will be
          displayed, while clicking a task listed in the <uicontrol>Review tasks owned by
            me</uicontrol> section will display the <xref
            href="#content_fusion_task_details/section-task-details-page-owner" format="dita"
              ><b>Task Owner</b> version of the page</xref>).</li>
        <li>You can paste the task link in your browser address bar.</li>
        <li>A <b>Content Author</b> who has access to <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i> can click on
          the name of a task in the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="section-task-details-page-owner">
      <title>Task Details Page for the Task Owner</title>
      <p>The task owner (the person who created the task) has access to more options in this page
        than <b>Reviewers</b> (people who receive a link to the task). For example, the task owner
        has access to a <uicontrol>SETTINGS</uicontrol> tab where you can select whether or not
          <i>Change Tracking</i> is always on.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_fn2_44w_4jb">
          <title>Task Details Page (Task Owner)</title>
          <image href="../img/CF_task_details1.png" id="image_gn2_44w_4jb"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>When logged in as the task owner, the <i>Task Details</i> page includes the following
        options and features:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry id="share">
            <dt>SHARE</dt>
            <dd>Click the <uicontrol>Share</uicontrol> button to open the <uicontrol>Sharing
                settings</uicontrol> page.<p>
                <fig id="fig_pyf_rd1_hmb">
                  <title>Sharing Settings Dialog Box</title>
                  <image href="../img/cf_assign_owner.png" id="image_qyf_rd1_hmb"/>
                </fig>
              </p><p>This dialog box includes the following options:</p></dd>
            <dd>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Shareable link</dt>
                    <dd>Displays the link to the task and you can click on the <uicontrol><image
                          href="../img/CF_Copy18.png" id="image_vnw_z4w_4jb"/>Copy</uicontrol>
                      button to copy the link to the clipboard so that you can send it to
                        <b>Reviewers</b>.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Who has access</dt>
                    <dd>This section displays the task owner along with anyone who has been assigned
                      to the task. The task owner can remove collaborators by clicking the <image
                        href="../img/Remove16Gray.png" id="image_sx4_qm1_fmb"/> button to the right
                      of their information.<note type="notice">If the <xref
                          href="#content_fusion_task_details/reviewer-access" format="dita"
                            ><uicontrol>Anyone who opens the link is automatically granted access as
                            a Reviewer</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected, if a removed
                        collaborator re-opens the task via its link, they will automatically be
                        re-added as a <b>Reviewer</b>. To prevent this, you can simply deselect this
                        option.</note></dd>
                    <dd>
                      <p>
                        <dl>
                          <dlentry id="reviewer-access">
                            <dt>Anyone who opens the link is automatically granted access as a
                              Reviewer</dt>
                            <dd>This option is available only if the <xref
                                href="cf-enterprise-configuration.dita#cf-enterprise-configuration/task-sharing-behavior"
                                  ><uicontrol>Tasks can be shared publicly</uicontrol> toggle
                                option</xref> is selected in the Administration page. If this option
                              is selected, then anyone who accesses the link to the task is
                              automatically granted access to the task as a <b>Reviewer</b>.<note>If
                                this option is not selected and the <xref
                                  href="cf-enterprise-configuration.dita#cf-enterprise-configuration/specified-collaborators"
                                    ><uicontrol>Tasks can only be accessed by specified
                                    collaborators</uicontrol> toggle option</xref> is selected in
                                the Administration page, when a non-registered user tries to access
                                the task via its link, they will receive a warning message that
                                indicates that they do not have permission to access the task. They
                                can request access by clicking the <uicontrol>Request
                                  access</uicontrol> button that is displayed in that warning
                                message. This sends an email to the owner of the task and they have
                                the ability to accept the request for access and a link or button in
                                the email will direct the task owner to the <uicontrol>Sharing
                                  settings</uicontrol> page with the requesting user's information
                                already populated in the <uicontrol>Add collaborator</uicontrol>
                                field.</note></dd>
                          </dlentry>
                          <dlentry>
                            <dt id="add-collaborator">Add collaborator</dt>
                            <dd>You can assign a collaborator to a task by adding their email
                              address in this section. You can also add them by name if they are a
                              registered user. For non-registered users, they are listed as a
                                <i>Pending Collaborator</i> until they sign up for an account and
                              they access the task via its link. Once a collaborator is no longer
                              pending, the task owner can change the role for any of the assigned
                              collaborators from <uicontrol>Reviewer</uicontrol> to
                                <uicontrol>Owner</uicontrol>, and vice versa.</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                      </p>
                    </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><menucascade>
                <uicontrol>MORE</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol>Download</uicontrol>
              </menucascade></dt>
            <dd>Selecting this action will download a zip archive that contains all task files,
              along with change history downloaded as a Git working directory (making changes
              traceable). To inspect the history, extract the archive and open the root directory in
              your Git client. Information about the email and author name of the person who made
              the change in <b>Content Fusion</b> is included.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><menucascade>
                <uicontrol>MORE</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>
              </menucascade></dt>
            <dd>Selecting this action will delete the task from the <ph keyref="product"/>
              server.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Files</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>You can click on any of the files attached to the task to open it in a version of
                  <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term>. This is the editor that the <b>Reviewers</b>
                will use to make changes and add comments to the files.</p>
              <p>If other people have the file open, you will see their avatars on the right side
                of the <uicontrol>Files</uicontrol> box. You can hover over an avatar to see the
                name of the person.</p>
              <p>Only one person can edit a particular file at once. If someone else is currently
                editing the particular file, you will see a <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/CF_Lock20.png" id="image_wnw_z4w_4jb"/>Lock</uicontrol> icon on the
                left side of the <uicontrol>Files</uicontrol> box and that person's avatar on the
                right side of the <uicontrol>Files</uicontrol> box will have a red border. When a
                file is locked, no one else can edit the file until that person navigates back to
                the <i>Task Details</i> page, closes the browser, or uses the <uicontrol>Finalize
                  Review</uicontrol> button. If you hover over the lock icon, it will show you who
                has the file locked.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>ADD MESSAGE</dt>
            <dd>You can use this button to add messages to communicate with the
              <b>Reviewers</b>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Messages and File Changes</dt>
            <dd>All messages and file change notifications are displayed underneath the
                <uicontrol>Add Message</uicontrol> button. You can see the name of the user who
              added the message or changed the file and when it was processed. You can compare
              changes made by the <b>Reviewer</b> by using a <i>diff</i> link that is available for
              every file change. The <i>diff</i> link can be shared between the <b>Content
                Author</b> and <b>Reviewer</b>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>SETTINGS Tab</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>This tab offers the following option:</p>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry id="force-change-tracking">
                    <dt>Force Change Tracking On</dt>
                    <dd>This option is selected by default, which means that <i>Change Tracking</i>
                      is always on when the <b>Reviewers</b> make changes or add comments in the
                      files attached to the task. This allows you and other <b>Reviewers</b> to see
                      exactly what has been changed and you will have the ability to accept or
                      reject the changes after you have integrated them back into <term>Oxygen XML
                        Editor/Author</term>. If you deselect this option, the <i>Change
                        Tracking</i> mechanism is turned off for this particular task, but other
                      tasks are not affected.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section-task-details-page-reviewers">
      <title>Task Details Page for Reviewers</title>
      <p>As a <b>Reviewer</b> (someone who receives a link to a task), when you access the <ph
          keyref="product"/> browser interface using the link that was sent, the <i>Task Details</i>
        page is displayed in the main area of the interface.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_tv5_xqw_4jb">
          <title>Task Details Page (Reviewer)</title>
          <image href="../img/CF_task_details2.png" id="image_uv5_xqw_4jb"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>When logged in as a <b>Reviewer</b>, the <i>Task Details</i> page includes the following
        options and components:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Files to review</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>You can click on any of the files attached to the task to open it in a visual
                editor. This is where you will proofread, make changes, and add comments in the
                files. If someone else is currently reviewing the particular file, you will see a
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/CF_Lock20.png" id="image_br2_slk_y3b"
                  />Lock</uicontrol> icon and it cannot be edited until that person navigates back
                to the <i>Task Details</i> page, closes the browser, or uses the <uicontrol>Finalize
                  Review</uicontrol> button. If you hover over the lock icon, it will show you who
                has the file locked.</p>
              <p>For DITA projects, if the <b>Content Author</b> specifies a context DITA map, you
                can see the hierarchy of all the attached files as they appear in the specified DITA
                map. The topic title hierarchy from the DITA map is also displayed underneath each
                topic.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>FINALIZE REVIEW</dt>
            <dd>You can click this button to let the <b>Content Author</b> know that the review
              process is finished. For more information, see <xref
                href="finishing_tasks.dita#finishing_tasks"/>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>ADD MESSAGE</dt>
            <dd>You can use this button to add messages to communicate with the <b>Content
                Author</b> or other <b>Reviewers</b>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Messages and File Changes</dt>
            <dd>All messages and file change notifications are displayed underneath the
                <uicontrol>Add Message</uicontrol> button. You can see the name of the user who
              added the message or changed the file and when it was processed. The activity stream
              is automatically refreshed every minute.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
