<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="content-fusion-addon">
  <title>Content Fusion Connector Add-on</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Add-ons<indexterm>Content Fusion Connector</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion Connector add-on</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes an <b>Oxygen Content Fusion Connector</b> add-on that comes
      bundled and pre-installed. <b>Oxygen Content Fusion</b> is a flexible, intuitive collaboration
      platform designed to adapt to virtually any type of workflow that a collaborative team may use
      for their documentation review process. The add-on provides access to the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"/>Show Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> toolbar
      button. Clicking this button will open the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol>
      view where you can create tasks, manage them, attach documents, and upload them to the
        <b>Content Fusion</b> server. You can also go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> to open the view. If the button is not displayed on the toolbar or the view is
      not listed in the <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol> menu, see <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/installing_the_content_fusion_plugin.html"
        format="html" scope="external">Re-installing the Content Fusion Connector Add-on</xref>. </p>
    <p>To fully take advantage of all of the benefits and features, your organization will need an
        <b>Oxygen Content Fusion Enterprise Server</b>. This solution allows you to host, setup, and
      configure your own server and control your data. With this model, you are also able to upload
      custom frameworks and plugins, and to configure various settings. It is possible to evaluate
        <b>Content Fusion</b> free of charge, for a limited time. For more information, see the
        <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/content_fusion/get_started.html" format="html"
        scope="external"><b>Oxygen Content Fusion</b> website</xref>.</p>
    <p>For more information about using <b>Content Fusion</b> in <ph keyref="product"/>, see the
        <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/" format="html" scope="external"
          ><b>Oxygen Content Fusion User Guide</b></xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
