<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="content_fusion_user_interface">
    <title>Browser Interface Overview</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion interface</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p id="p_h4t_dgk_54b">The <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface can be accessed by using a
      task link and then logging in. Reviewers usually receive the link via some sort of messaging
      app, while task creators can access the interface by clicking on the task name in the
        <uicontrol>Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view (within <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>) or from
      your organization's Content Fusion browser login page.</p>
    <p id="p_zch_gqf_zxb">The <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface includes a top stripe that is
      always visible and it contains a user drop-down menu and other actions depending on the page
      that is opened within the interface. A left navigation stripe is also always visible and it
      contains buttons for navigating to various pages within the interface. The main area (below
      the top stripe and to the right of the left navigation stripe) displays the current page
      within the interface and is where most activities occur.</p>
    <section id="section_cpp_m5w_4jb">
      <title>Top Stripe</title>
      <p id="p_mvx_gtq_txb">
        <fig id="fig_nvx_gtq_txb">
          <title>Content Fusion Interface - Top Header Stripe</title>
          <image href="../img/CF-ribbon.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="p_i4t_dgk_54b">The stripe at the top of the interface includes the following options
        and components:</p>
      <p id="p_j4t_dgk_54b">
        <dl id="dl_k4t_dgk_54b">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_l4t_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_yvc_4f3_4jb"/>Oxygen
                Content Fusion</uicontrol> Logo</dt>
            <dd>Clicking on the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"
                  id="image_jxn_1g3_4jb"/>Oxygen Content Fusion</uicontrol> logo on the left side of
              the top stripe opens the <xref href="content_fusion_task_details.dita"><uicontrol>My
                  Review Tasks</uicontrol> page</xref> that lists all the tasks that are assigned to
              you and tasks that you created (or own).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Projects</dt>
            <dd>Opens the <xref href="cf-projects.dita">Projects page</xref> that displays a list of
              all the projects.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="my-tasks">
            <dt>My Review Tasks</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_q4t_dgk_54b">Opens the <xref href="content_fusion_task_details.dita"
                    ><uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> page</xref> that displays a list of all
                the current tasks that you own or that were assigned to you.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_m4t_dgk_54b">
            <dt>User Name Menu</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_n4t_dgk_54b">Your user name is displayed at the right side of the top stripe.
                If you click on your name, you have access to the following options:</p>
              <p id="p_o4t_dgk_54b">
                <dl id="dl_p4t_dgk_54b">
                  <dlentry id="profile-information-page">
                    <dt>Profile</dt>
                    <dd>Opens a <xref href="cf-profile-settings.dita">profile settings page</xref>
                      that displays your name, email, avatar, and allows you to delete your account
                      or specify which types of notifications will be sent to you via email.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_u4t_dgk_54b">
                    <dt>Log Out</dt>
                    <dd>Logs out of the <ph keyref="product"/> interface.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_k3w_21b_jfc">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/CF-Help16.png"/>Help Menu</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>This menu contains the following actions:<ul id="ul_lbn_s1b_jfc">
                <li id="li_mbn_s1b_jfc"><uicontrol>User Guide</uicontrol> - Opens the online version
                  of the user guide.</li>
                <li id="li_twg_x1b_jfc"><uicontrol>Video Demonstrations</uicontrol> - Opens a
                  webpage with a variety of video demonstrations, webinars, and other presentations
                  for <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
                <li id="li_ktg_fbb_jfc">
                  <uicontrol>What's New</uicontrol> - Opens the <i>What's New in Oxygen Content
                    Fusion</i> webpage, presenting the features and updates that were added in the
                  latest version.</li>
                <li id="li_um3_nbb_jfc"><uicontrol>About</uicontrol> - Opens a popup window that
                  displays information about the current version of <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p id="p_oxy_1tf_zxb">When a page within a review task or project is open, a breadcrumb is
        displayed at the top of the main area that can be used to navigate to previous pages and
        additional actions become available below the top stripe, depending on the page and the user
        role.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_lyh_rm1_n2c">
      <title>Review Tasks vs Projects</title>
      <p id="p_fvr_c32_z1c">The main differences between working with non-project based review tasks
        and projects are:<ul id="ul_wcv_lxf_zxb">
          <li id="li_vc1_qxf_zxb"><b>Non-Project Review Tasks</b> - Provides tools for technical
            writers and reviewers to create and use review tasks for efficient collaboration during
            their documentation review process.</li>
          <li id="li_xcv_lxf_zxb"><b>Project Review Tasks</b> - Provides additional tools for
            technical writers to help manage a DITA project hosted in a Git repository while
            maintaining full compatibility with existing tools and workflows. Review tasks created
            within a Content Fusion project offer additional functionality, such as the ability to
            merge changes using a built-in file comparison/merge tool and to build WebHelp or PDF
            output deliverables.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_y13_vsq_txb">
      <title>Left Stripe</title>
      <p id="p_z13_vsq_txb">When a page within a review task or project is open, a navigation stripe
        on the left side of the interface appears and provides buttons for opening various Content
        Fusion pages.</p>
      <p id="p_zkf_vzf_zxb">After you navigate to a page within a review task or an existing
        project, the buttons on the left stripe may change to reveal more navigation buttons,
        depending on the page and the user role. For example, the following image shows the buttons
        that are available when a page is open within a review task that you are assigned as an
        owner.</p>
      <p id="p_xz5_31g_zxb">
        <fig id="fig_yz5_31g_zxb">
          <title>Left Vertical Stripe - Inside a Review Task</title>
          <image href="../img/CF-left-stripe2.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_yws_24w_4jb">
      <title>Main Area</title>
      <p id="p_v4t_dgk_54b">The main area (below the top horizontal stripe and to the right of the
        left stripe) displays the current page and is where most of your activity takes place.
        Various actions and possibilities become available depending on the page and user role.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
