<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="content_fusion_user_interface">
    <title>Content Fusion Interface for Reviewers</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Reviewer Guide<indexterm>Content Fusion interface</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion interface for Reviewers</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p>As the <b>Reviewer</b>, when you use a task link that is sent to you by the <b>Content
        Author</b>, the <ph keyref="product"/> interface is opened in your most recently used
      browser and the task details are displayed.</p>
    <p>When logged in as a <b>Reviewer</b>, the <ph keyref="product"/> interface includes the
      following options and components:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="task-details">
          <dt>Task Details</dt>
          <dd>The main interface presents the task with all the attached files listed and a few
            options for communicating with the <b>Content Author</b> or other <b>Reviewers.</b><p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Files to review</dt>
                  <dd>You can click on any of the files attached to the task to open it in a version
                    of Oxygen XML Web Author. This is the editor that you will use to proofread,
                    make changes, and add comments in the files.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>FINALIZE REVIEW</dt>
                  <dd>You can click this button to let the <b>Content Author</b> know that the
                    review process is finished. For more information, see <xref
                      href="finishing_tasks.dita#finishing_tasks"/>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>ADD MESSAGE</dt>
                  <dd>You can use this button to add messages to communicate with the <b>Content
                      Author</b> or other <b>Reviewers</b>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>User Name Menu</dt>
          <dd>Your user name is displayed in the top-right corner of the page. If you click on your
            name, you have access to the following options:<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Profile</dt>
                  <dd>Opens your profile information page that displays your name, email, avatar,
                    and allows you to delete your profile.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>My Tasks</dt>
                  <dd>Displays a list of all the current tasks that you are assigned to. Clicking on
                    a task name will open it in the <ph keyref="product"/> interface.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Sign Out</dt>
                  <dd>Signs you out of the <ph keyref="product"/> interface.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
