<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="content_fusion_user_interface_author">
  <title>Content Fusion Interface for the Content Author</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Content Fusion interface</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Fusion interface for Content Author</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>As the <b>Content Author</b>, when you click on the name of a task in the <uicontrol>Content
        Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> view, the <ph keyref="product"/> interface is opened in your
      default browser. You can also quickly open your profile by selecting <uicontrol>Go to my
        Account</uicontrol> from the user drop-down menu. The <b>Content Author</b> has access to
      more options in the interface than the <b>Reviewers</b>. For example, the <b>Content
        Author</b> has access to a <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> tab where you can select whether
      or not <i>Change Tracking</i> is always on.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Content Fusion Interface (Content Author)</title>
        <image href="../img/CF_task_details1.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>When logged in as the <b>Content Author</b>, the <ph keyref="product"/> interface includes
      the following options and components:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="details-tab">
          <dt>DETAILS Tab</dt>
          <dd>This tab includes the <i>task details</i>, and allows you to share the task, download
            it, delete it, open files in Oxygen XML Web Author, view messages or file change
            notifications, and add messages for <b>Reviewers.</b><p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>SHARE</dt>
                  <dd>Click the <uicontrol>Share</uicontrol> button to display a link to the task
                    and you can click on the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CF_Copy18.png"
                      />Copy</uicontrol> button to copy the link to the clipboard so that you can
                    send it to <b>Reviewers</b>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><menucascade>
                      <uicontrol>MORE</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol>Download</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade></dt>
                  <dd>Selecting this action will zip all the files attached to the task into an
                    archive and download it according to your browser settings. </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><menucascade>
                      <uicontrol>MORE</uicontrol>
                      <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade></dt>
                  <dd>Selecting this action will delete the task from the <ph keyref="product"/>
                    server and the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> view.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Files</dt>
                  <dd>You can click on any of the files attached to the task to open it in a version
                    of Oxygen XML Web Author. This is the editor that the <b>Reviewers</b> will use
                    to make changes and add comments to the files.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>ADD MESSAGE</dt>
                  <dd>You can use this button to add messages to communicate with the
                      <b>Reviewers</b>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Messages and File Changes</dt>
                  <dd>All messages and file change notifications are displayed underneath the
                      <uicontrol>Add Message</uicontrol> button. You can see the name of the user
                    who added the message or changed the file and when it was processed.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>SETTINGS Tab</dt>
          <dd>This tab offers the following option:<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry id="force-change-tracking">
                  <dt>Force Change Tracking On</dt>
                  <dd>This option is selected by default, which means that <i>Change Tracking</i> is
                    always on when the <b>Reviewers</b> make changes or add comments in the files
                    attached to the task. This allows you and other <b>Reviewers</b> to see exactly
                    what has been changed and you will have the ability to accept or reject the
                    changes after you have integrated them back into Oxygen XML Editor/Author. If
                    you deselect this option, the <i>Change Tracking</i> mechanism is turned off for
                    this particular task, but other tasks are not affected.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>User Name Menu</dt>
          <dd>Your user name is displayed in the top-right corner of the page. If you click on your
            name, you have access to the following options:<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Profile</dt>
                  <dd>Opens your profile information page that displays your name, email, avatar,
                    and allows you to delete your profile.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>My Tasks</dt>
                  <dd>Displays a list of all the current tasks that are either assigned to you or
                    created by you. Clicking on a task name will open it in the <xref
                      href="#content_fusion_user_interface_author/details-tab" format="dita"
                        ><uicontrol>Details Tab</uicontrol></xref>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Sign Out</dt>
                  <dd>Signs you out of the <ph keyref="product"/> interface.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
