<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="context-sensitive-help-system">
  <title>Context-Sensitive WebHelp System</title>
 <!--Proofed-->
  <body>
    <p>Context-sensitive help systems assist users by providing specific informational topics for
      certain components of a user interface, such as a button or window. This mechanism works based
      on mappings between a unique ID defined in the topic and a corresponding HTML page.</p>
    <p>When WebHelp (with or without Feedback) output is generated by <ph keyref="product"/>, the
      transformation process produces an XML mapping file called
        <filepath>context-help-map.xml</filepath> and copies it in the output folder. This XML file
      maps an ID to a corresponding HTML page
      like:<codeblock>&lt;map productID="oxy-webhelp" productVersion="1.1"&gt;
  &lt;appContext helpID="annotations-view" path="topics/annotations-view.html"/&gt;
  &lt;appContext helpID="button-editor" path="concepts/button-editor.html"/&gt;
    .  .  .
&lt;/map&gt;</codeblock></p>
    <p>where:<ul id="ul_ct2_qrn_kq">
        <li><codeph>helpID</codeph> - unique ID provided by a topic from two possible sources:<ul
            id="ul_hrr_1pn_kq">
            <li>the <codeph>resourceid</codeph> element set to it in the <codeph>prolog</codeph>
              section:<codeblock>&lt;prolog>
    &lt;resourceid id="context-sensitive-help-system"/>
&lt;/prolog></codeblock></li>
            <li>the <codeph>id</codeph> attribute set on the topic root element</li>
          </ul><note type="important">You must ensure that these defined IDs are unique in the
            context of the entire DITA project. If the IDs are not unique, the transformation
            scenario will display warning messages in the transformation console output.</note></li>
        <li><codeph>path</codeph> - path to a corresponding topic. This path is relative to the
          location of the <filepath>context-help-map.xml</filepath> mapping file.</li>
        <li><codeph>productID</codeph> - ID of the product for which you are writing documentation.
          Applicable only if you are using WebHelp with Feedback transformations.</li>
        <li><codeph>productVersion</codeph> - version of the product for which you are writing
          documentation. Applicable only if you are using WebHelp with Feedback
          transformations.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The XML mapping file can be used in the following ways:<ul id="ul_wlj_tpn_kq">
        <li>invoke the WebHelp system and pass it the <codeph>contextID</codeph> parameter with a
          specific value. The WebHelp JavaScript engine will look up the ID in the mapping file and
          load the corresponding HTML help page.</li>
        <li>implement a PHP script on the server side that reads the mapping file. Invoke the PHP
          script and pass the ID of the appropriate HTML help page as a GET parameter.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
