<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="converting-between-schema-languages">
  <title>Converting Schema to Another Schema Language</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>XML Schemas<indexterm>Generate/Convert Schema tool</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Convert schema to another schema language</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/ConvertTo16.png"/>Generate/Convert Schema</uicontrol> tool
      allows you to convert a DTD or Relax NG (full or compact syntax) schema or a set of XML files
      to an equivalent XML Schema, DTD or Relax NG (full or compact syntax) schema. Where perfect
      equivalence is not possible due to limitations of the target language, <ph keyref="product"/>
      generates an approximation of the source schema. <ph keyref="product"/> uses <xref
        href="http://www.thaiopensource.com/relaxng/trang.html" format="html" scope="external"
          ><term>Trang multiple format converter</term></xref> to perform the actual schema
      conversions. </p>
    <p>To use this tool, select the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ConvertTo16.png"
          id="image_kyg_2wm_wr"/>Generate/Convert Schema</uicontrol>
      <uicontrol>(<shortcut conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_shift_c_shortcut"
          product="developer editor"/><shortcut
          conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl-shift-shortcut"
          product="developerEclipse editorEclipse"/>)</uicontrol> action from the <uicontrol
        product="developer editor">Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol
        product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">XML Tools</uicontrol> menu<ph
        product="developer editor"> or from the <uicontrol>Open with</uicontrol> submenu when
        invoking the contextual menu in the <xref
          href="../topics/using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view"
            ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref></ph>. This action opens the
        <uicontrol>Generate/Convert Schema</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you to configure
      various options for conversion.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="figure-trang-converter-dialog-oxygen" product="editor developer">
        <title>Generate/Convert Schema Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_convert_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <fig id="figure-trang-converter-dialog-oxygenEclipse" product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <title>Generate/Convert Schema Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_convert_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Generate/Convert Schema</uicontrol> dialog box includes the following options:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Input</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>Allows you to select the language of the source schema. If the conversion is based on
            a set of XML files, rather than just a single XML file, select the <uicontrol>XML
              Documents</uicontrol> option and use the file selector to add the XML files involved
            in the conversion.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Output</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>Allows you to select the language of the target schema.<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Options</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>You can choose the <uicontrol>Encoding</uicontrol>, the maximum
                      <uicontrol>Line width</uicontrol>, and the <uicontrol>Indent size</uicontrol>
                    (in number of spaces) for one level of indentation.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Output file</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Specifies the path for the output file that will be generated.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Close dialog when finished</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If you deselect this option, the dialog box will remain opened after the conversion so
            that you can easily continue to convert more files.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Advanced options</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If you select <uicontrol>XML 1.0 DTD</uicontrol> for the input, you can click this
            button to access more advance options to further fine-tune the conversion. The following
            advanced options are available:<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>XML 1.0 DTD Input</uicontrol> section</dt>
                  <dd>These options apply to the source DTD: <ul>
                      <li><uicontrol>xmlns</uicontrol> - Specifies the default namespace, that is
                        the namespace used for unqualified element names.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>attlist-define</uicontrol> - Specifies how to construct the
                        name of the definition representing an attribute list declaration from the
                        name of the element. The specified value must contain exactly one percent
                        character. This percent character is replaced by the name of element (after
                        colon replacement) and the result is used as the name of the
                        definition.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>colon-replacement</uicontrol> - Replaces colons in element
                        names with the specified chars when constructing the names of definitions
                        used to represent the element declarations and attribute list declarations
                        in the DTD.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>any-name</uicontrol> - Specifies the name of the definition
                        generated for the content of elements declared in the DTD as having a
                        content model of ANY.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>element-define</uicontrol> - Specifies how to construct the
                        name of the definition representing an element declaration from the name of
                        the element. The specified value must contain exactly one percent character.
                        This percent character is replaced by the name of element (after colon
                        replacement) and the result is used as the name of the definition.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>annotation-prefix</uicontrol> - Default values are represented
                        using an annotation attribute <codeph>prefix:defaultValue</codeph> where
                        prefix is the specified value and is bound to
                          <codeph>http://relaxng.org/ns/compatibility/annotations/1.0</codeph> as
                        defined by the RELAX NG DTD Compatibility Committee Specification. By
                        default, the conversion engine will use a for prefix unless that conflicts
                        with a prefix used in the DTD.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>inline-attlist</uicontrol> - Instructs the application not to
                        generate definitions for attribute list declarations, but instead move
                        attributes declared in attribute list declarations into the definitions
                        generated for element declarations. This is the default behavior when the
                        output language is XSD.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>strict-any</uicontrol> - Preserves the exact semantics of
                          <i>ANY</i> content models by using an explicit choice of references to all
                        declared elements. By default, the conversion engine uses a wildcard that
                        allows any element</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>generate-start</uicontrol> - Specifies whether or not the
                        conversion engine should generate a start element. DTD's do not indicate
                        what elements are allowed as document elements. The conversion engine
                        assumes that all elements that are defined but never referenced are allowed
                        as document elements.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>xmlns mappings</uicontrol> table - Each row specifies the
                        prefix used for a namespace in the input schema.</li>
                    </ul></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>W3C XML Schema Output</uicontrol> section</dt>
                  <dd>This section is available if you select <uicontrol>W3C XML Schema</uicontrol>
                    for the output.<ul>
                      <li><uicontrol>disable-abstract-elements</uicontrol> - Disables the use of
                        abstract elements and substitution groups in the generated XML Schema. This
                        can also be controlled using an annotation attribute.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>any-process-contents</uicontrol> - One of the values: strict,
                        lax, skip. Specifies the value for the <codeph>processContents</codeph>
                        attribute of any elements. The default is skip (corresponding to RELAX NG
                        semantics) unless the input format is DTD, in which case the default is
                        strict (corresponding to DTD semantics).</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>any-attribute-process-contents</uicontrol> - Specifies the
                        value for the <codeph>processContents</codeph> attribute of
                          <codeph>anyAttribute</codeph> elements. The default is skip (corresponding
                        to RELAX NG semantics).</li>
                    </ul></dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
