<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="creating_and_uploading_tasks">
    <title>Creating and Uploading Tasks</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Creating new tasks</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Uploading tasks</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Creating new tasks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Uploading tasks</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p>As the <b>Content Author</b>, to create a new task, add files to it, and then upload the task
      to the <ph keyref="product"/> server, follow these steps:<ol>
        <li>If the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view is not already opened,
          click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"/> Show Content Fusion Task
            Manager</uicontrol> toolbar button (or go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>).</li>
        <li>Drag files that you want to be reviewed from the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view,
            <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, or your system file explorer and drop them in
          the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box (or click the <uicontrol>choose</uicontrol> link
          to select the files) to add the files to a new task. If you drag and drop a folder from
          the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view or system file explorer, all files in that
          directory will be added to the task.<note type="tip">You can also add the currently opened
            document to a task by selecting <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"/> Add
              File to Review Task</uicontrol> from the contextual menu in
              <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode or <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode. Also, for DITA
            documents, you can select <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"/> Add to
              Review Task</uicontrol> from the contextual menu in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
              Manager</uicontrol> and if the topic reference has unselected child nodes, a dialog
            box will be displayed that asks you whether or not you want to include the child
            nodes.</note><p>
            <fig>
              <title>Adding Files to the New Task Box</title>
              <image href="../img/CF_new_task1.png"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
        <li>If you are working with a DITA project, you should attach the context <term>root</term>
          map so that all references and defined keys can be resolved and displayed properly for the
            <b>Reviewers</b>. If you added files to the task by dragging them from the
            <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, the <term>root</term> map that is specified in
          the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> is automatically added as the
            <uicontrol>Context DITA Map</uicontrol>, but you can also drag a DITA map file and drop
          it in the <uicontrol>Context DITA Map</uicontrol> section or click to the
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/Open16.png"/>Choose Context Map</uicontrol> button to
          select a map.<p>
            <fig>
              <title>Creating a New Task</title>
              <image href="../img/CF_task_manager2.png"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
        <li>Enter a description or title for the task in the <uicontrol>Summary</uicontrol> field.
          This task summary will help you differentiate between multiple tasks so each description
          should be unique.</li>
        <li>Click the <uicontrol>Upload</uicontrol> button to finish the task creation process and
          upload the information to the <ph keyref="product"/> server.</li>
      </ol></p>
  </body>
</topic>
