<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="create-patch-two-revisions">
  <title>Create Patch Between Two Revisions of an Item</title>
  <shortdesc>This type of patch contains historical changes between two revisions of a selected
    item.</shortdesc>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>This option is useful if you want to share changes between two revisions with other team
        members.</p>
      <p><note type="tip">If you need to generate a patch between two revisions of a previously
            <i>deleted</i>, <i>moved</i>, or <i>replaced</i> item, you should use <xref
            href="create-patch-repository.dita#create-patch-repository">the <uicontrol>Create patch
              between two repository items</uicontrol> option</xref> instead. </note>The steps are
        as follows:</p>
    </context>
    <steps id="steps_cym_5px_lr">
      <step id="patch-wizard-open">
        <cmd>Go to menu <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Create patch</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</cmd>
        <stepresult>This opens the <uicontrol>Create patch</uicontrol> wizard.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Create patch between two revisions of an item</uicontrol> option
          in the dialog box.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Press the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <stepresult>The second step of the wizard is opened:<p>
            <fig id="fig_n1n_5px_lr">
              <title>Create Patch Wizard - Step 2</title>
              <image href="../img/sa_svn_create_patch_two_revisions.png" id="image_cbn_5px_lr"/>
            </fig>
          </p></stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the starting and ending revisions in the <uicontrol>From</uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol>To</uicontrol> sections. </cmd>
        <info>You can select between the <uicontrol>HEAD revision</uicontrol> and a specific
          revision number. For the <uicontrol>other revision</uicontrol> option, you can press <xref
            href="history-dialog.dita#history-dialog" format="dita">the
              <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> button</xref> to display a list of the item revisions.
            <note>The patch will only include changes between the two specified revisions, starting
            with the changes that were made <b>after</b> the older revision.</note><note type="tip"
            >If you want to reverse changes done between two revisions by using a patch file, you
            can specify the newer revision in the <uicontrol>From</uicontrol> section and the older
            version in the <uicontrol>To</uicontrol> section.</note></info>
      </step>
      <step id="create-patch-options">
        <cmd>Optionally, if you want <xref href="create-patch-options.dita">to configure
            the options</xref> for your patch, press the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <info>This options page does not remember your selections when creating future patches. It
          will revert to the default values.</info>
        <stepresult>The <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> wizard page is displayed.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Press the <uicontrol>Create patch</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <stepresult>The patch is created and stored in the path specified in <xref
            href="create-patch-options.dita">the <b>Output</b> section of the
              <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> page</xref> or in the default location.</stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
