<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="creating_and_uploading_tasks">
  <title>Creating Tasks and Uploading Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Creating new tasks</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Uploading tasks</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Creating new tasks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Create task</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Uploading tasks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Upload task</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Upload files</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>There are two ways for a <b>Content Author</b> to create a new task. You can create the task
      in <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term> or in the <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface
      (the less common approach).</p>
    <section id="section_qbh_xmq_4jb">
      <title>Creating a Task in Oxygen XML Editor/Author</title>
      <p>Creating a task using the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view in
          <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term> provides the benefits of being able to add existing
        files, you can select a context root map to resolve keys and references or a DITAVAL file
        for filtering purposes (for DITA content), you do not need to leave the application (other
        than to send the task link to <b>Reviewers</b>), and you will be able to merge proposed
        changes back in your project.</p>
      <p>To create a new task, add files to it, and then upload the task to the <ph keyref="product"
        /> server, follow these steps:<ol id="ol_hvx_cl4_f1b">
          <li>If the <xref href="cf_task_manager_view.dita"><uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks
                Manager</uicontrol> view</xref> is not already opened, click the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_ivx_cl4_f1b"/>Show Content Fusion Task
              Manager</uicontrol> toolbar button (or go to <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol> /
              <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol> / <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks
            Manager</uicontrol>).</li>
          <li>
            <p>Add files to the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box:</p>
            <p>
              <fig id="fig_lvx_cl4_f1b">
                <title>Adding Files to the New Task Box</title>
                <image href="../img/CF_new_task1.png" id="image_mvx_cl4_f1b"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
            <p>You can use any of the following methods:<ul id="ul_m5v_ynq_4jb">
                <li>Drag files that you want to be reviewed from the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol>
                  view or your system file explorer and drop them in the <uicontrol>New
                    Task</uicontrol> box (or click the <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol> link to select
                  the files) to add the files to a new task. If you drag and drop a folder from the
                    <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view or system file explorer, all files in that
                  directory will be added to the task.</li>
                <li>You can add the currently open document to a task by selecting <uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_jvx_cl4_f1b"/>Add File to Review
                    Task</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> submenu in the
                  contextual menu in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode (or in
                    <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode for Markdown documents).</li>
                <li>You can also add external resources (for example, WebDAV resources or DITA
                  references to external resources). For example, you can drag resources from the
                    <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view and drop them in the
                    <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box. However, only modifications to external
                  resources can be applied when you <xref
                    href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes">merge the changes</xref> (you cannot
                  add or delete external resources).</li>
                <li>For DITA projects, drag files from the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>
                  and drop them in the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box (or select
                      <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_n5v_ynq_4jb"/>Add
                    to Review Task</uicontrol> from the contextual menu in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                    Manager</uicontrol>). If the topic reference has unselected child nodes, a
                  dialog box will be displayed that asks you whether or not you want to include the
                  child nodes.<note>By default, DITA resources that either have a
                      <xmlatt>processing-role</xmlatt> attribute set to <b>resource-only</b> or a
                      <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> attribute set to something other than <b>dita</b> or
                      <b>ditamap</b> are not automatically added to a new task. If either one of
                    these scenarios is detected, a message will be displayed indicating that
                      <uicontrol>some files were not added</uicontrol> and you can click a link to
                    open a <uicontrol>Manage Files</uicontrol> dialog box where you can see the
                    reason for each file and you can choose to manually add them to the new task, if desired.<p>
                      <fig id="fig_o5v_ynq_4jb">
                        <title>Manage Files Dialog Box</title>
                        <image href="../img/CF_Manage_Files.png" id="image_p5v_ynq_4jb"/>
                      </fig>
                    </p></note></li>
              </ul></p>
          </li>
          <li>Enter a <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> for the task. This task title will help you
            differentiate between multiple tasks so each one should be unique.</li>
          <li id="context-dita-map">
            <p><b>[DITA Projects Only]</b> If you are working with a DITA project, you should attach
              the context <term>root</term> map (<image href="../img/ChooseDitaRootMap16.png"
                id="image_epg_zhh_sjb"/>) so that all references and defined keys can be resolved
              and displayed properly for the <b>Reviewers</b>. When you add files to the task, if a
              context root map is specified in the toolbar of the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                Manager</uicontrol>, it is automatically added in the <uicontrol>DITA
                Context</uicontrol> section, but you can also drag a DITA map file and drop it in
              that section or click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Open16.png"
                  id="image_nvx_cl4_f1b"/>Choose context root map</uicontrol> button to select a
              map. Specifying the root map also allows <b>Reviewers</b> to edit content referenced
              through a <xmlatt>conref</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt> attribute.</p>
            <p>
              <fig id="fig_ovx_cl4_f1b">
                <title>Creating a New Task</title>
                <image href="../img/CF_task_manager2.png" id="image_pvx_cl4_f1b"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
          </li>
          <li><b>[DITA Projects Only]</b> If you are working with a DITA project, you can specify a
            DITAVAL file (<image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar16.png" id="image_dd2_s3h_sjb"/>) so
            that the content in the uploaded DITA topics is filtered based upon the conditional
            profiling attribute values defined in the DITAVAL file. You can drag a DITAVAL file and
            drop it in the <uicontrol>DITA Context</uicontrol> section or click the
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/Open16.png" id="image_klf_y3h_sjb"/>Choose
              DITAVAL</uicontrol> button to select a file. If a condition set is selected in the
            DITA Maps Manager, the corresponding DITAVAL file will automatically be selected in the
            task.</li>
          <li><b>[Non-DITA Projects]</b> If the attached files are detected as any file type other
            than DITA (and a DITA map is not selected as the context root map in the <uicontrol>DITA
              Maps Manager</uicontrol>), an option (<uicontrol>Also include all files that are
              referenced within the attached files</uicontrol>) will be available. If you select
            this option, all files that are referenced within the attached documents will
            automatically be attached to the task so that <term>Reviewers</term> will have access to
            the referenced content. Also, when this option is selected, you can click the
              <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button to preview the referenced files and you can choose
            to remove any that you do not want uploaded.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Upload</uicontrol> button to finish the task creation process and
            upload the information to the <ph keyref="product"/> server.</li>
        </ol></p>
      <p><b>Result:</b> The task information is now available in the <ph keyref="product"/> browser
        interface. The next logical step would most likely be to <xref
          href="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.dita">share the task link</xref> with anyone you want
        to review the documents.<note>No actual files are uploaded, rather snapshots of the files
          are uploaded with the task information. Therefore, when you eventually <xref
            href="merging_changes.dita">merge the proposed changes</xref> back into the original
          files in <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>, you will use your normal process to save
          the actual files in your project and eventually commit the changes to your
          repository.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_nhd_dpq_4jb">
      <title>Creating a Task in the Content Fusion Browser Interface</title>
      <p>This method of creating a task is intended for <b>Reviewers</b> or those who want to use
          <ph keyref="product"/> solely from a browser without using <term>Oxygen XML
          Editor/Author</term>, so it is less common for a <b>Content Author</b>, but it is
        available to anyone who has access to the <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface.</p>
      <p>To create a new task from the Content Fusion browser interface, follow these steps:<ol
          id="ol_gzj_4pq_4jb">
          <li>Go to the <ph keyref="product"/> browser interface. If you do not know your base URL
            (for example, <i>https://fusion.oxygenxml.com</i>), there are several ways to reach the
            browser interface from the <xref href="cf_task_manager_view.dita"><uicontrol>Content
                Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view</xref>. For example, you can click the link in
            any existing task, or right-click a task and select <uicontrol>Open task in
              browser</uicontrol>, or select <uicontrol>Go to my account</uicontrol> from the
              <i>User Name</i> drop-down menu at the top-right corner of the view.</li>
          <li>
            <p>Log in, if necessary. Then click your user name at the right side of the top ribbon
              and select <uicontrol>My Tasks</uicontrol>.</p>
            <p><b>Step Result:</b> This opens a page that displays a list of all the current tasks
              that are either assigned to you or were created (owned) by you.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>Click the <uicontrol>NEW TASK</uicontrol> button.</p>
            <p><b>Step Result:</b> This opens a new <i>Task Details</i> page where you can add a
              title, add new files from templates, retrieve the task link to share with others, and
              more.</p>
          </li>
          <li>Click the text field where it shows <uicontrol>Add a title</uicontrol> to enter a
            description or title for the task.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>NEW FILE</uicontrol> button to create a new file from a list of
            templates. The newly created file will automatically be attached to this new task.</li>
          <li>Click on the file name to open it in the <xref
              href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita#making_changes_to_uploaded_files">visual
              editor where you can proofread, add comments, and make changes</xref> to the
            document.</li>
          <li>The next logical step would most likely be to <xref
              href="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.dita">share the task link</xref> either with anyone
            you want to review the documents or with a <uicontrol>Content Author</uicontrol> who can
            integrate the new content into their project in <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.
            To retrieve the link, you can click the <uicontrol>SHARE</uicontrol> button, then use
            the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CF_Copy18.png" id="image_vnw_z4w_4jb"
              />Copy</uicontrol> button to copy the link to the clipboard. You could also copy the
            link from the browser address bar.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
