<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="creating_and_uploading_tasks">
  <title>Creating Tasks and Uploading Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Creating new tasks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Create task</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Uploading tasks</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Upload task</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Upload files</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_lmt_dgk_54b">Creating a task using the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks
        Manager</uicontrol> view in <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term> offers several advantages.
      You can add existing files, select a context root map to resolve keys and references, or
      specify a DITAVAL file for filtering purposes (for DITA content), you do not need to leave the
      application (other than to send the task link to reviewers), and you will be able to merge
      proposed changes back into your documentation.</p>
    <p id="p_mmt_dgk_54b">To create a new task, add files to it, and then upload the task to the
      Content Fusion server, follow these steps:<ol id="ol_hvx_cl4_f1b">
        <li id="li_nmt_dgk_54b">If the <xref href="cf_task_manager_view.dita"><uicontrol>Content
              Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view</xref> is not already opened, click the
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_ivx_cl4_f1b"/>Show Content
            Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> toolbar button (or go to <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol> /
            <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol> / <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks
          Manager</uicontrol>).</li>
        <li id="li_omt_dgk_54b">
          <p id="p_pmt_dgk_54b">Add files to the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box:</p>
          <p id="p_qmt_dgk_54b">
            <fig id="fig_lvx_cl4_f1b">
              <title>Adding Files to the New Task Box</title>
              <image href="../img/CF_new_task1.png" id="image_mvx_cl4_f1b"/>
            </fig>
          </p>
          <p id="p_rmt_dgk_54b">You can use any of the following methods:<ul id="ul_m5v_ynq_4jb">
              <li id="li_smt_dgk_54b">Drag files that you want to be reviewed from the
                  <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view or your system file explorer and drop them in
                the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box (or click the <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol>
                link to select the files) to add the files to a new task. If you drag and drop a
                folder from the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view or system file explorer, all
                files in that directory will be added to the task.</li>
              <li id="li_tmt_dgk_54b">You can add the currently open document to a task by selecting
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_jvx_cl4_f1b"/>Add
                  File to Review Task</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> submenu in
                the contextual menu in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</li>
              <li id="li_umt_dgk_54b">You can also add external resources (for example, WebDAV
                resources or DITA references to external resources). For example, you can drag
                resources from the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view and drop them in
                the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box. However, only modifications to external
                resources can be applied when you <xref href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes"
                  >merge the changes</xref> (you cannot add or delete external resources).</li>
              <li id="li_vmt_dgk_54b">For DITA files, drag the files from the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                  Manager</uicontrol> and drop them into the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box (or
                select <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_n5v_ynq_4jb"/>Add
                  to Review Task</uicontrol> from the contextual menu in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                  Manager</uicontrol>). If the topic reference has unselected child nodes, a dialog
                box will be displayed that asks you whether or not you want to include the child
                  nodes.<note id="note_wmt_dgk_54b">By default, DITA resources that either have a
                    <xmlatt>processing-role</xmlatt> attribute set to <b>resource-only</b> or a
                    <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> attribute set to something other than <b>dita</b> or
                    <b>ditamap</b> are not automatically added to a new task. If either one of these
                  scenarios is detected, a message will be displayed indicating that <uicontrol>some
                    files were not added</uicontrol> and you can click a link to open a
                    <uicontrol>Manage Files</uicontrol> dialog box where you can see the reason for
                  each file and you can choose to manually add them to the new task, if desired.<p
                    id="p_xmt_dgk_54b">
                    <fig id="fig_o5v_ynq_4jb">
                      <title>Manage Files Dialog Box</title>
                      <image href="../img/CF_Manage_Files.png" id="image_p5v_ynq_4jb"/>
                    </fig>
                  </p></note></li>
            </ul></p>
        </li>
        <li id="li_ymt_dgk_54b">Enter a <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> for the task. This task title
          will help you differentiate between multiple tasks so each one should be unique.</li>
        <li id="context-dita-map">
          <p id="p_zmt_dgk_54b"><b>[DITA Only]</b> If you are working with DITA, you should attach
            the context <term>root</term> map (<image href="../img/ChooseDitaRootMap16.png"
              id="image_epg_zhh_sjb"/>) so that all references and defined keys can be resolved and
            displayed properly for the reviewers. When you add files to the task, if a context root
            map is specified in the toolbar of the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, it is
            automatically added in the <uicontrol>DITA Context</uicontrol> section, but you can also
            drag a DITA map file and drop it in that section or click the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/Open16.png" id="image_nvx_cl4_f1b"/>Choose context root map</uicontrol>
            button to select a map. Specifying the root map also allows reviewers to edit content
            referenced through a <xmlatt>conref</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt>
            attribute.</p>
          <p id="p_ant_dgk_54b">
            <fig id="fig_ovx_cl4_f1b">
              <title>Creating a New Task</title>
              <image href="../img/CF_task_manager2.png" id="image_pvx_cl4_f1b"/>
            </fig>
          </p>
        </li>
        <li id="li_bnt_dgk_54b"><b>[DITA Only]</b> If you are working with DITA, you can specify a
          DITAVAL file (<image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar16.png" id="image_dd2_s3h_sjb"/>) so
          that the content in the uploaded DITA topics is filtered based upon the conditional
          profiling attribute values defined in the DITAVAL file. You can drag a DITAVAL file and
          drop it in the <uicontrol>DITA Context</uicontrol> section or click the <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/Open16.png" id="image_klf_y3h_sjb"/>Choose DITAVAL</uicontrol> button to
          select a file. If a condition set is selected in the DITA Maps Manager, the corresponding
          DITAVAL file will automatically be selected in the task.</li>
        <li id="li_cnt_dgk_54b"><b>[Non-DITA]</b> If the attached files are detected as any file
          type other than DITA (and a DITA map is not selected as the context root map in the
            <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>), an option (<uicontrol>Also include all files
            that are referenced within the attached files</uicontrol>) will be available. If you
          select this option, all files that are referenced within the attached documents will
          automatically be attached to the task so that reviewers will have access to the referenced
          content. Also, when this option is selected, you can click the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>
          button to preview the referenced files and you can choose to remove any that you do not
          want uploaded.</li>
        <li id="li_j14_fxp_21c">Optionally, you can specify a <uicontrol>Due Date</uicontrol>.
          Within the browser interface, the amount of time left before the due date arrives is
          displayed under the review task's title when you have navigated inside the task and also
          in the table in the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/content_fusion_task_details-x2.html"
            format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> page</xref>. Also,
          any reviewers who have not finalized the task will receive an email notification when the
          due date is within 3 days, 1 day, and 12 hours of its expiration.</li>
        <li id="li_dnt_dgk_54b">Click the <uicontrol>Upload</uicontrol> button to finish the task
          creation process and upload the information to the Content Fusion server.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <p id="p_ent_dgk_54b"><b>Result:</b> The task information is now available in the Content Fusion
      browser interface. The next logical step would most likely be to <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-content-fusion/topics/sharing_tasks_with_reviewers.html"
        format="html" scope="external">share the task</xref> link with anyone you want to review the
        documents.<note id="note_fnt_dgk_54b">No actual files are uploaded, rather snapshots of the
        files are uploaded with the task information. Therefore, when you eventually <xref
          href="merging_changes.dita">merge the proposed changes</xref> back into the original files
        in <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>, you will use your normal process to save the
        actual files and eventually commit the changes to your repository.</note></p>
    <section id="uploading_a_review_task_takes_too_long">
      <title>Uploading a Review Task Takes Too Long</title>
      <p id="p_mpm_r35_13c">When uploading a review task that contains DITA files, along with the
        files explicitly selected for review, the task also contains the DITA map and all the files
        referenced from it (directly or indirectly). For large projects, this set of files is also
        large and can take a long time to upload.</p>
      <p id="p_npm_r35_13c">To improve the loading time, go to <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Oxygen Content Fusion Connector</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and enable the <uicontrol>Upload only resources that are directly referenced
          in the files to be reviewed.</uicontrol> option.</p>
      <p id="p_opm_r35_13c">When this option is enabled, only resources such as other topics and
        images that are directly referenced from the files to review are uploaded, including all the
        submaps that are referenced in the context DITA map. This may lead to a smaller set of
        files, but there are some limitations:</p>
      <p id="p_ppm_r35_13c">
        <ul id="ul_uln_gvd_crb">
          <li id="li_qpm_r35_13c">References that use the <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt> attribute are
            not uploaded.</li>
          <li id="li_rpm_r35_13c">References that use the <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> element will
            be uploaded and reviewers can open them. However, images and other references in these
            files will not be uploaded.</li>
          <li id="li_spm_r35_13c">If the set of files to be reviewed is large, the upload will still
            take a long time.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="cf_task_manager_view.dita"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
