<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="create-topic-in-map">
  <title>Creating a New DITA Topic</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Topics<indexterm>Create new
          topic</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The basic building block for DITA information is the DITA topic. DITA provides a variety of
      specialized topic types, the most common of which are:<ul id="ul_omg_4rd_ts">
        <li><i>Topic</i> - The base topic type from which all other topic types are specialized.
          Typically, it is used when a more specialized topic type is inappropriate.</li>
        <li><i>Task</i> - For procedural information such as how to use a dialog box.</li>
        <li><i>Concept</i> - For general, conceptual information such as a description of a product
          or feature.</li>
        <li><i>Reference</i> - For reference information.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> also supports numerous other specialized topic types that you will
      find templates for in the various folder in the <xref
        href="#create-topic-in-map/new_dita_file_dialog_box" format="dita"
          ><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> DITA file dialog box</xref>. They include DITA 1.3
      specializations, Lightweight DITA templates, MathML composites, Markdown documents, and other
      DITA specialized topic and <xref keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref>
      types such as <i>Glossentry</i>, <i>Troubleshooting</i>, <xref keyref="glossentry_bookmap"
          ><term>Bookmap</term></xref>, and <xref keyref="glossentry_subject-scheme-map"
          ><term>Subject Scheme Map</term></xref>. </p>
    <p>To create a new DITA topic and add a reference to it in your <xref
        keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref>, follow these steps:<ol
        conkeyref="reusables-author-for-dita/new-dita-topic-ol">
        <li/>
      </ol></p>
    <section id="new_dita_file_dialog_box">
      <title><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> DITA File Dialog Box</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> DITA file dialog box allows you to create a new DITA topic
        using various types of DITA file templates and provides some options that help you to
        configure the new topic.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_x5w_wzd_ts" product="author editor">
          <title>New DITA File Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_new_file_dialog.png" id="image_jvb_112_ts"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_hdb_yzd_ts" product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">
          <title>New DITA File Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/ec_new_file_dialog.png" id="image_rqk_b12_ts"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <note>The templates that appear in this dialog box include all templates that have an
        associated <codeph>.properties</codeph> file and the <codeph>type</codeph> property is set
        to <userinput>dita</userinput>, as well as templates that do not have an associated
        properties file or the <codeph>type</codeph> property is not defined. It will also include
        custom templates that you create using the procedures presented in <xref
          href="create-your-own-templates.dita#create-your-own-templates"/>.</note>
      <p>The <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> DITA file dialog box includes the following features and
        options:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Choose a file template</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use the template preview pane to select the appropriate type of DITA file you want
              to create. You can use the filter text box to search for a template.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Title</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Depending on the selected file template, the value of the
                <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> field is set in:<ul>
                <li>the <codeph>title</codeph> element of a DITA topic file. The
                    <codeph>title</codeph> element needs to be the first child of the root
                  element.</li>
                <li>the <codeph>glossterm</codeph> element of a <i>Glossentry</i> file.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Use the title to generate the file name</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Select this option to use the text entered in the <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> field
              to automatically generate a file name. By default, the generated name will transform
              spaces into underscores (<codeph>_</codeph>), all illegal characters will be removed,
              and all upper case characters changed to lower case (the generated name can be seen in
              the <uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> field). You can configure these rules by clicking
              the <xref href="preferences-dita.dita#preferences-dita/file-name-rules"
                  ><uicontrol>File name generation rules</uicontrol> link</xref>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use this option to specify a file name and path for the new file. <ph
                conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path"/></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Use the file name as the value of the root ID attribute</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Select this option to use the file name in the <uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> field
              (without the file extension) as the value of the root <codeph>id</codeph> attribute
              for the new topic.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Create</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>When you click this button, a reference (<codeph>topicref</codeph>) to the new topic
              is added to the current <term>DITA map</term> and the new topic is opened in the
              editor.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="eppo-first-dita-topic.dita#eppo-first-dita-topic"/>
    <link href="eppo-add-topic-to-map.dita#eppo-add-topic-to-map"/>
    <link href="markdown-dita.dita#markdown-dita"/>
      <link href="fast-create-topics.dita#fast-create-topics"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
