<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="customizing_frameworks">
  <title>Integrating Web Author with Your Content by Creating Custom Frameworks</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Customizing your content for Web Author</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Customizing frameworks for Web Author</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Customizing document types for Web Author</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can customize <term>Web Author</term> to make it simple for everyone to write structured
      content and still adhere to your project conventions. This topic provides details about
      reusing frameworks between the standalone versions of <term>Oxygen</term> and <term>Web
        Author</term>, how to create customized frameworks, how to test and upload your
      customization, and other framework customization tips.</p>
    <section id="section_jqs_3sf_11b">
      <title>Examples of Framework Customization Use-Cases</title>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Document Schema</dt>
            <dd>Web Author supports any XML schema in any schema language. It also offers <xref
                href="webauthor-predefined-frameworks.dita#webauthor-predefined-frameworks">built-in
                support for DITA, DocBook, TEI and XHTML</xref>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Add Support for a New XML Vocabulary</dt>
            <dd>You can customize <term>Web Author</term> to work with any XML-based document type.
              For example, you can customize <term>Web Author</term> to work with a <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/dita-specialization-support.html"
                format="html" scope="external">DITA specialization</xref>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Authoring Experience</dt>
            <dd>You can configure how documents are rendered in <term>Web Author</term> or display
                <xref
                href="dg-form-controls-properties-matrix.dita#dg-form-controls-properties-matrix"
                >inline form-controls</xref> to allow users to edit attribute values.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Business Rules</dt>
            <dd>You can configure the automatic validation to use Schematron to enforce various
              business rules and propose solutions for them. For more information, see the <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/schematron-quick-fixes.html"
                format="html" scope="external">Schematron Quick Fixes (SQF) section in the Oxygen
                XML Editor User Manual</xref>. There is also an interesting Blogpost written on this
              subject available at: <xref
                href="http://blog.oxygenxml.com/2015/05/schematron-checks-to-help-technical.html"
                format="html" scope="external"/>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Document Templates</dt>
            <dd>You can <xref href="#customizing_frameworks/new-templates-li" format="dita">specify
                document templates</xref> that users can choose from when creating a new
              document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Embedded Formats</dt>
            <dd>Web Author supports embedded formats such as MathML, SVG, videos, and others using
                <xref href="customizing_plugins.dita#customizing_plugins">plugins</xref> or <xref
                href="dg-form-controls-properties-matrix.dita#dg-form-controls-properties-matrix"
                >flexible form-controls</xref>. Also, support for embedded formats can be
              implemented by third parties. For example, <xref
                href="http://www.wiris.com/en/plugins/docs/oxygen" format="html" scope="external"
                >WIRIS provides a plugin</xref> that can be used to edit MathML equations in a
              visual way.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="reusing_frameworks_between_and_web_author">
      <title>Reusing Frameworks Between Oxygen XML Editor/Author and Web Author</title>
      <p>Custom <xref keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>frameworks</term></xref> that are designed
        for documentation purposes can be reused interchangeably between <term>Oxygen</term>
        standalone distributions and the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>. However, some fine-tuning
        might be necessary to maximize the editing experience for your content authors. The
        advantages of using a common <term>framework</term> include:<ul id="ul_rlf_yvy_1r">
          <li>Uniform experience across multiple <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>
            distributions.</li>
          <li>Ability to reuse previously developed <term>frameworks</term>.</li>
          <li>Many of the customized items that are added to your <term>framework</term> in the
              <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term> standalone distribution also carry over to <ph
              keyref="webappProduct"/>. For example, items that are added to the list of proposals
            for the <xref keyref="glossentry_content-completion-assistant"><term>Content Completion
                Assistant</term></xref> will appear in both distributions.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_zzf_pns_vz">
      <title>How to Create a Custom Framework (Document Type)</title>
      <p>You can create a custom <term>framework</term> by extending an existing one: <ol>
          <li>In a location where you have full write access, create a folder structure similar to
            this: <filepath>custom_frameworks/dita-extension</filepath>. </li>
          <li>Open a standalone version of <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.</li>
          <li>Open the <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol> dialog box <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>(Options</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Preferences)</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> and go to <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Locations</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>. In this preferences page, add the path to your
              <filepath>custom_frameworks</filepath> folder in the <uicontrol>Additional frameworks
              directories</uicontrol> list.</li>
          <li>Go to the <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol> preferences page and select
            an existing <term>framework</term> configuration and use the
              <uicontrol>Extend</uicontrol> button to create an extension for it.</li>
          <li>Give the extension an appropriate name (for example, <b><i>DITA - Custom</i></b>),
            select <uicontrol>External</uicontrol> for the <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option,
            and specify an appropriate path (for example,
              <filepath>path/to/.../custom_frameworks/dita-extension/dita-extension.framework</filepath>).</li>
          <li id="make-changes-li">Make your changes to the extension. There is a large variety of
            ways to customize your extended <term>framework</term>. These are just some of the ways:<ul>
              <li>The <xref
                  href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
                  format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Document Type</uicontrol> configuration
                  dialog box</xref> contains various tabs and subtabs that allow you to configure
                the extended <term>framework</term>.</li>
              <li id="new-templates-li">You can <xref href="wa-file-templates.dita">create your own
                  custom document templates</xref> and once the framework is uploaded to <term>Web
                  Author</term>, users will have access to the templates when creating a new
                document.</li>
              <li>See the <xref
                  href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/dg-complex-customization-tutorial.html"
                  format="html" scope="external">Oxygen Advanced Framework Customization
                  section</xref> for numerous procedures and examples of how to configure various
                aspects of the extended <term>framework</term>.</li>
              <li>For information about using CSS files to configure the extended
                  <term>framework</term>, see <xref
                  href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/dg-customize-default-CSS.html"
                  format="html" scope="external">Customizing the Main CSS of a
                Framework</xref>.</li>
              <li>For information about configuring the Content Completion proposals for the
                extended <term>framework</term>, see <xref
                  href="wa-cc-configuration.dita#wa-cc-configuration"/>.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to close the dialog box and then
              <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol> to save the changes.</li>
          <li>Create an archive that only contains your custom framework folder that you created in
            the first step of this procedure. The archive should contain exactly one folder (for
            example, <codeph>dita-extension</codeph>). You will need this archive structure to <xref
              href="#customizing_frameworks/deploying_a_framework" format="dita">upload the
                <term>framework</term> to Web Author</xref>.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="developing_and_testing_a_framework_using_the_weba">
      <title>Testing a Custom Framework Using the Oxygen XML Web Author Test Server Add-on</title>
      <p>The following procedures assumes that you have access to an <term>Oxygen XML
          Editor/Author</term> standalone installation. This is not a mandatory requirement, but
        rather a way to speed up the development process.</p>
      <p>
        <ol id="ol_g2c_pnz_1r">
          <li>Use the standalone installation of <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term> to <xref
              href="#customizing_frameworks/section_zzf_pns_vz" format="dita">customize a specific
                <term>framework</term></xref>.</li>
          <li>Install the <uicontrol>Oxygen Web Author Test Server</uicontrol> add-on.<ol>
              <li>Go to <menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Install new add-ons</uicontrol>
                </menucascade> to open an add-on selection dialog box.</li>
              <li>In the <uicontrol>Show add-ons from</uicontrol> text box, enter the following url:
                  <b>http://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Addons/optional/updateSite.xml</b>.</li>
              <li>Select the <b>Oxygen Web Author Test Server</b> add-on and click
                  <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</li>
              <li>Select the <b>I accept all terms of the end user license agreement</b> option and
                click <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>.</li>
              <li>Restart the application.<p><b>Result:</b> You should now have a <uicontrol>Start
                    Web Author Server</uicontrol> button on the toolbar.</p></li>
            </ol></li>
          <li>Open an XML file in <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.<note type="note">The <b>Web
                Author Test Server</b> does not load <term>frameworks</term> that have the
                <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option set to <uicontrol>Internal</uicontrol> in the
                <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
                format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Document Type</uicontrol> configuration
                dialog box</xref>. Therefore, the XML file needs to be from a <term>framework</term>
              that has that option set to <uicontrol>External</uicontrol>.</note></li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Start Web Author Server</uicontrol> button found on the toolbar.
            This starts a Tomcat server and opens a file chooser dialog box:<p>
              <fig>
                <title>Web Author Test Server File Chooser Dialog Box</title>
                <image href="../img/wa_test_server_dialog1.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p>The dialog box shows a URL entry for up to two network interfaces that are available
            on your desktop PC. The Tomcat server accesses the <term>frameworks</term> and options
            currently in use by <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.</li>
          <li>Open the XML document with one of the following methods:<ul>
              <li><b>Mobile Device</b> - To open the current document in your mobile device, click
                the <uicontrol>QR Code</uicontrol> button next to one of the network interface
                listings and use a QR code reader on your mobile device.</li>
              <li><b>Desktop Browser</b> - To open the current document in your desktop browser,
                click the <uicontrol>Open in Browser</uicontrol> button next to one of the network
                interface listings.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><xref href="#customizing_frameworks/make-changes-li" format="dita">Make whatever
              changes you want to your <term>framework</term></xref>. Note that these changes will
            not automatically be reflected in the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> if it was already
            running. To see the results of changes, close the server using the <b>Close and stop
              server</b> button in the file chooser dialog box and start it again.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p>
        <note type="attention">When using this test server add-on, editing sessions have a limited
          duration. If the session stops working, click the <b>Close and stop server</b> button in
          the file chooser dialog box and start it again.</note>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="deploying_a_framework">
      <title>Uploading a Custom Framework to Web Author</title>
      <p>To upload a custom <term>framework</term> to your <term>Web Author</term> deployment,
        follow this procedure:<ol conkeyref="reusables-sdk-webauthor/upload-framework-ol">
          <li/>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="adding_javascript_code_to_a_framework">
      <title>Adding JavaScript Code to a Framework</title>
      <p>To load JavaScript code, you can add JavaScript files (<filepath>.js</filepath> extension)
        directly inside the <filepath>[Framework_Directory]/web</filepath> folder. All the files
        will be loaded in the browser in lexicographical order. JavaScript files located in
        subfolders of the <filepath>web</filepath> folder will not be loaded. If you have a
        framework extension and it contains a JavaScript file with the same name as a similar file
        in the base framework, the one in the extension takes precedence.</p>
      <p>These files can contain code that calls the <xref keyref="jscript_api">Web Author
          JavaScript API</xref> to implement custom editing actions. The possible use cases include
        the following:<ul>
          <li>Create custom actions and add them to the toolbar or contextual menu. For more
            details, see the <xref keyref="jscript_api_customaction">JS custom action
              tutorial</xref>.</li>
          <li>Create custom form controls. For more details, see the <xref
              keyref="jscript_api_formcontrol">JS form control tutorial</xref>.</li>
          <li>Add more views. For more details, see the <xref keyref="jscript_api_customview">JS
              custom view tutorial</xref>.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="customization_tips">
      <title>Other Customization Tips</title>
      <p>
        <ul id="ol_css_3h1_br">
          <li>If you want to use CSS rules that only apply when the <term>framework</term> is used
            in the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>, use the following <codeph>media</codeph>
            query:<codeblock outputclass="language-css">@media oxygen AND (platform:webapp) {
 ... 
}</codeblock></li>
          <li>If the <term>framework</term> contains custom <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode
            operations (Java implementations of the
              <codeph>ro.sync.ecss.extensions.api.AuthorOperation</codeph> interface), they can be
            enabled to be used by the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> using the
              <codeph>ro.sync.ecss.extensions.api.WebappCompatible</codeph> annotation.<p>If you
              plan to invoke a custom <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode operation from the
              JavaScript code (as in <xref keyref="jscript_api_customaction">this tutorial</xref>),
              the operation has to be annotated with
                <codeph>ro.sync.ecss.extensions.api.webapp.WebappRestSafe</codeph>. <note
                type="warning">Operations annotated with
                  <codeph>ro.sync.ecss.extensions.api.webapp.WebappRestSafe</codeph> can be invoked
                with user supplied parameters. Use this annotation only for operations that are safe
                to execute with any parameter combination. For example, an action that would execute
                a process on the server based on a command-line script specified by the user is
                  <b>not</b> safe.</note></p><note><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode operations
              that use <term>Java Swing</term> components to display a graphical interface are not
              compatible with the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> and they should not be
              annotated.</note></li>
          <li>The <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> continuously validates the XML documents using the
            default validation scenarios defined at <term>framework</term> level. Only the
            validation units that have the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/edit-validation-scenario.html#edit-validation-scenario__validation-config-dialog"
              format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Automatic Validation</uicontrol> option
              selected in the <uicontrol>Edit Scenario</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> that is
            accessed by editing a scenario in the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/document-type-validation-tab.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Validation</uicontrol> subtab when editing a
              document type</xref>.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
