<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="customization_overview">
  <title>Customization Overview</title>
  <body>
    <p>The core of <ph keyref="product"/> can be deployed on a server, allowing a variety of
      HTML5-enabled client devices to edit and review XML content. <note>Despite the efforts spent
        to ensure that the frameworks, options, and plugins behave similarly in both the <ph
          keyref="webappComponent"/> and the standalone version of <ph keyref="product"/>, there might be
        some differences imposed by specific platform limitations.</note></p>
    <section><title>A Graphical Description of the <ph keyref="webappComponent"/> System</title><image
        id="image_dbg_qcs_1r" href="../img/diag_webapp.png"/></section>
    <p>The <ph keyref="webappComponent"/> was designed to accommodate a large degree of
      customization.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Options</title>
      <p>Functionality is common with the standalone distribution of <ph keyref="product"/>, as they
        share the same options. This allows you to configure a consistent editing experience for all
        users.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Documentation Frameworks</title>
      <p>Custom documentation frameworks can be re-used between the <ph keyref="product"/>
        standalone distribution and the <ph keyref="webappComponent"/>.<note>The <ph
            keyref="webappComponent"/> comes bundled with specially tuned frameworks for <ph
            conref="editingActions.dita#editingActions/webapp_supported_frameworks"/>. Any other
          framework from the standalone distribution can also be customized and used in the <ph
            keyref="webappComponent"/>.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Server Side</title>
      <p>The <ph keyref="webappComponent"/> server side can be customized by using the following plugin
          types:<ul id="ul_esk_jhs_1r">
          <li>The <b>URLStreamHandler plugins</b> can be used to integrate the <ph keyref="webappComponent"/>
            with CMS or XML databases.</li>
          <li>The <b>WorkspaceAccess plugins</b> that provides access to the <ph keyref="product"/>
            plugin-level Java API.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Client Side</title>
      <p>Client side customization is available through a JavaScript API. Unlike the server side
        customization, it can be used to modify the application's GUI.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
