<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="custom-refactoring-operations">
  <title>Custom Refactoring Operations</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Refactoring<indexterm>Custom
            operations</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Refactoring tool<indexterm>Custom operations</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Custom XML refactoring operations</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>While <ph keyref="product"/> includes a variety of built-in XML refactoring operations to
      help you accomplish particular tasks, you can also create custom operations according to your
      specific needs. For example, you could create a custom refactoring operation to convert an
      attribute to an element and insert the element as the first child of the parent element.</p>
    <p>An XML Refactoring operation is defined as a pair of resources:<ul id="ul_gwv_s4c_jr">
        <li>An <i>XQuery Update script</i> or <i>XSLT stylesheet</i> that <ph keyref="product"/>
          will run to refactor the XML files.</li>
        <li>An <i>XML Operation Descriptor</i> file that contains information about the operation
          (such as the name, description, and parameters).</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_dgt_f4c_jr">
        <title>Diagram of an XML Refactoring Operation</title>
        <image href="../img/xml_refactoring_diagram.png" id="image_ktw_k4c_jr" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>All the defined custom operations are loaded by the <b>XML Refactoring Tool</b> and presented
      in <xref
        href="refactoring-xml-documents.dita#refactoring-xml-documents/refactoring_operations_dlentry"
        >the <uicontrol>Refactoring Operations</uicontrol> wizard page</xref>, along with the
      built-in operations. </p>
    <p>After the user chooses an operation and specifies its parameters, <ph keyref="product"/>
      processes an XQuery Update or XSLT transformation over the input file. This transformation is
      executed in a <b>safe mode</b>, which implies the following:<ul id="ul_psd_jpm_kr">
        <li>When loading the document:<ul id="ul_jgd_kpm_kr">
            <li>The <b>XInclude</b> mechanism is disabled. This means that the resources included by
              using XInclude will not be visible in the transformation.</li>
            <li>The DTD entities will be processed without being expanded.</li>
            <li>The associated DTD will be not loaded, so the default attributes declared in the DTD
              will not be visible in the transformation.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li>When saving the updated XML document:<ul id="ul_bcl_ppm_kr">
            <li>The <codeph>DOCTYPE</codeph> will be preserved.<note>This can be changed using <xref
                  href="custom_operation_sample.dita#custom_operation_sample/using_saxon_extension_functions_to_allow_custom_r"
                  >Saxon extension functions in XSLT</xref>.</note></li>
            <li>The DTD entities will be preserved as they are in the original document when the
              document is saved.</li>
            <li>The attribute values will be kept in their original form without being
              normalized.</li>
            <li>The spaces between attributes are preserved. Basically, the spaces are lost by a
              regular XML serialization since they are not considered important.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The result of this transformation overrides the initial input file.<note>To achieve some of
        the previous goals, the XML Refactoring mechanism adds several attributes that are
        interpreted internally. The attributes belong to the
          <filepath>http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/xmlRefactoring/additional_attributes</filepath>
        namespace. These attributes should not be taken into account when processing the input XML
        document since they are discarded when the transformed document is serialized.</note><note
        type="restriction"><i>Comments</i> or <i>processing instructions</i> that are in any node
        before or after the root element cannot be modified by an XML Refactoring operation. In
        other words, XML Refactoring operations can only be applied on the root element and the
        nodes inside it. However, as a work around to this limitation, you can use <xref
          href="custom_operation_sample.dita#custom_operation_sample/using_saxon_extension_functions_to_allow_custom_r"
          >Saxon extension functions and the XSLT stylesheet method</xref> to implement the new
        custom XML refactoring operation.</note></p>
    <section id="creating_a_custom_refactoring_operation">
      <title>Creating a Custom Refactoring Operation</title>
      <p>To create a custom refactoring operation, follow these steps:<ol id="ol_swm_crc_jr">
          <li>Create an <xref
              href="custom_operation_sample_xquery.dita#custom_operation_sample_xquery">XQuery
              Update script</xref> or <xref
              href="custom_operation_sample.dita#custom_operation_sample">XSLT stylesheet
              file</xref>.</li>
          <li>Create an <b>XML Refactoring Operation Descriptor</b> file contains the path to the
              <xref
              href="custom_operation_sample_xquery.dita#custom_operation_sample_xquery/descriptor-example-section"
              >XQuery Update script</xref> or <xref
              href="custom_operation_sample.dita#custom_operation_sample/descriptor-example-section"
              >XSLT stylesheet</xref>.</li>
          <li>Store both files in <xref
              href="sharing-custom-refactoring-operations.dita#sharing-custom-refactoring-operations"
              >one of the locations that <ph keyref="product"/></xref> scans when loading the custom
                operations.<p><b>Result:</b> Once you run the <uicontrol>XML Refactoring</uicontrol>
              tool again, the custom operation appears in <xref
                href="refactoring-xml-documents.dita#refactoring-xml-documents/refactoring_operations_dlentry"
                >the <uicontrol>Refactoring Operations</uicontrol> wizard page</xref>.</p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="sharing-custom-refactoring-operations.dita#sharing-custom-refactoring-operations"
      />
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
