<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="customization_overview">
  <title>Customization Overview</title>
  <body>
    <p>The core of <ph keyref="product"/> can be deployed on a server, allowing a variety of
      HTML5-enabled client devices to edit and review XML content. </p>
    <p>WebApp Component is a highly versatile application which can be customized to work with any
      XML vocabulary and any file repository system. It uses the same extension points as the
      standalone version of oXygen XML Author: frameworks, options, and plugins. <note>The
        frameworks, options and plugins used by the WebApp Component are very similar with those
        used in the oXygen XML product suite. This means that you can use them with a high degree of
        compatibility across oXygen products.</note></p>
    <section><title>A Graphical Description of the <ph keyref="webappComponent"/> System</title><image
        id="image_dbg_qcs_1r" href="../img/diag_webapp.png"/></section>
    <p>The <ph keyref="webappComponent"/> was designed to accommodate a large degree of
      customization.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Options</title>
      <p>Functionality is common with the standalone distribution of <ph keyref="product"/>, as they
        share the same options. This allows you to configure a consistent editing experience for all
        users.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Documentation Frameworks</title>
      <p>Custom documentation frameworks can be re-used between the <ph keyref="product"/>
        standalone distribution and the <ph keyref="webappComponent"/>.<note>The <ph
            keyref="webappComponent"/> comes bundled with specially tuned frameworks for <ph
            conref="editingActions.dita#editingActions/webapp_supported_frameworks"/>. Any other
          framework from the standalone distribution can also be customized and used in the <ph
            keyref="webappComponent"/>.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Server Side</title>
      <p>The <ph keyref="webappComponent"/> server side can be customized by using a <xref
          href="customizing_plugins.dita#customizing_plugins">series of plugins</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Client Side</title>
      <p>Client side customization is available through a JavaScript API. Unlike the server side
        customization, it can be used to modify the application's GUI.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
