<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="customization_overview">
  <title>Customization Overview</title>
  <body>
    <p>The core of oXygen XML Author can be deployed on a server, allowing a variety of HTML5
      enabled client devices to edit and review XML content. <note>Despite the efforts spent to
        ensure that the frameworks, options and plugins behave similarly in both WebApp and
        standalone version of oXygen XML, there might be some differences imposed by specific
        platform limitations.</note></p>
    <p>A graphical description of the system would look like this:</p>
    <image id="image_dbg_qcs_1r" href="../img/diag_webapp.png"/>
    <p><ph keyref="webapp"/> was designed to accommodate a large degree of customization on several
      layers:</p>
    <section>
      <title>Options</title>
      <p>Functionality common with the standalone distribution of oXygen XML share the same options.
        This allows you to configure a consistent editing experience for all users.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Documentation frameworks</title>
      <p>Custom documentation frameworks can be re-used between the oXygen standalone distribution
        and <ph keyref="webapp"/>.<note><ph keyref="webapp"/> comes bundled with especially tuned
          frameworks for DITA, DocBook, TEI and XHTML. Any other framework from the standalone
          distribution can also be customized and used in <ph keyref="webapp"/>.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Server side</title>
      <p><ph keyref="webapp"/>'s server side can be customized by using the following plugin
          types:<ul id="ul_esk_jhs_1r">
          <li>The <b>URLStreamHandler plugins</b> can be used to integrate the WebApp with CMS-es or
            XML databases.</li>
          <li>The <b>WorkspaceAccess plugins</b> which provides access to the oXygen plugin-level
            Java API.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Client side</title>
      <p>Client side customization is available through a JavaScript API. Unlike the server side
        customization, it can be used to modify the application's GUI.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
