<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dcpp_the_customization_css">
    <title>Customization CSS</title>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <keywords>
        <indexterm product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          >DITA Map to PDF WYSIWYG Transformation <indexterm>Customization
          CSS</indexterm></indexterm>
                <indexterm product="pdf-css">Customization CSS</indexterm>
            </keywords>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>The publishing process of the <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - WYSIWYG</uicontrol>
      transformation scenario is driven by a customization CSS. </p>
        <p>To change the styling of the output:</p>
        <ol>
            <li>Create a custom CSS file that will contain all your customizations. It is
        recommended to create this file in your project directory. <note type="important">Always use
          CSS rules that match the DITA class attribute values. Avoid using CSS selectors containing
          element names, because they have a weaker specificity and will not override the styles
          defined in the built-in CSS files. For instance, to match the <codeph>p</codeph> element,
          use its class
          attribute:<codeblock outputclass="language-css">*[class ~= "topic/p"] {
  color: gray;
}</codeblock>Instead
          of:<codeblock outputclass="language-css">p {
  color: gray;
}</codeblock></note><note
          type="tip">You can organize the CSS rules in separate files, but they all need to be
          imported from a single master CSS file. For simplicity, this manual provides instructions
          based upon a single CSS file.</note><note><xref
            href="https://scotch.io/tutorials/getting-started-with-less" format="html"
            scope="external">LESS</xref> files are supported (LESS is a CSS pre-processor with a
          CSS-like syntax, but has a lot of features designed to speed up development).</note></li>
            <li>Add the custom CSS rules. See the topics in this section for assistance with
        specific types of customizations.</li>
            <li>In the <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - WYSIWYG</uicontrol> transformation scenario, set
        the full path to the custom CSS file as the value of the <codeph>args.css</codeph>
        parameter.</li>
        </ol>
    </body>
</topic>
