<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dcpp_parameters">
  <title>Transformation Parameters</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Transformation parameters</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>This list includes the most common customization parameters that are available in the <b>DITA
        Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS</b> or <b>DITA Map PDF -based on DITA &amp; CSS
        (WYSIWYG)</b> transformation scenarios. Other standard DITA-OT parameters were omitted for
      clarity, but they are still supported.</p>
    <table id="table_mns_3zw_rcb" frame="all" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="c1" colwidth="1*" rowsep="1"/>
        <colspec colnum="2" colname="c2" colwidth="2.11*" rowsep="1"/>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><b>args.css</b></entry>
            <entry>You can use this to specify a list of CSS URLs to be used in addition to those
              specified in the <b>dita.css.list</b> parameter or publishing template (for the
                <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS</uicontrol> transformation). The
              files must have URL syntax and be separated using semicolons.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>args.input</b></entry>
            <entry>Specifies the master DITA map file for your documentation project.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>clean.temp</b></entry>
            <entry>Specifies whether the DITA-OT deletes the files in the temporary directory after
              it finishes a build. Allowed values: <b>yes</b> (default) / <b>no</b>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>css.processor.type</b></entry>
            <entry>Specifies the processor to use for the transformation. Allowed values:
                <b>chemistry</b> (default) / <b>antenna-house</b> / <b>prince</b>. </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>css.processor.path.chemistry</b></entry>
            <entry>Path to the <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b> executable file that needs to be run to
              generate the PDF (for example, <filepath>C:\path\to\chemistry.bat</filepath> on
              Windows). If this parameter is not set, the plugin will use the system's PATH
              environment variable to locate and start <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b>.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>css.processor.path.antenna-house</b></entry>
            <entry>Path to the Antenna House executable file that needs to be run to generate the
              PDF (for example, <filepath>C:\path\to\AHFCmd.exe</filepath> on Windows).</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>css.processor.path.prince</b></entry>
            <entry>Path to the Prince executable file that needs to be run to generate the PDF (for
              example, <filepath>C:\path\to\prince.exe</filepath> on Windows).</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>editlink.remote.ditamap.url</b></entry>
            <entry>Use this parameter in conjunction with <codeph>editlink.web.author.url</codeph>
              to add an <i>Edit</i> link next to the topic title in the PDF output. When a user
              clicks the link, the topic is opened in <b>Oxygen XML Web Author</b> where they can
              make changes that can be saved to a file server. The value should be set as the custom
              URL of the <term>main DITA map</term>. For example, a GitHub custom URL might look
              like this:
                <filepath>https://getFileContent/oxyengxml/userguide/master/UserGuide.ditamap</filepath>.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>editlink.web.author.url</b></entry>
            <entry>This parameter needs to be used in conjunction with
                <codeph>editlink.remote.ditamap.url</codeph> to add an <i>Edit</i> link next to the
              topic title in the PDF output. When a user clicks the link, the topic is opened in
                <b>Oxygen XML Web Author</b> where they can make changes that can be saved to a file
              server. The value should be set as the URL of the Web Author installation. For
              example:
              <filepath>https://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen-xml-web-author/</filepath>.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>show.changes.and.comments</b></entry>
            <entry>
              <p>When set on <b>yes</b>, the user comments, colored highlights and track-changes are
                shown in the output.</p>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><b>figure.title.placement</b></entry>
            <entry>Controls the title placement of the figures, relative to the image. Possible
              values include <b>top</b> (default) and <b>bottom</b>. </entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <div>For the <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS</uicontrol> transformation type,
      the following parameters can be used to specify a publishing template: <table frame="all"
        rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_fc2_qbd_b2b">
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
          <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="2.13*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry><b>pdf.publishing.template</b></entry>
              <entry>Specifies the path to the folder containing the custom PDF template.</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry><b>pdf.publishing.template.descriptor</b></entry>
              <entry>Specifies the name of the descriptor to be loaded from the PDF template folder
                or package. If it is not specified, the first encountered descriptor will be
                loaded.</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table></div>
  </body>
</topic>
