<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="debug-stack-view">
  <title>Stack View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>XSLT/XQuery Debugger<indexterm>viewing processing information<indexterm>stack
              view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>This view shows the current execution stack of both source and XSLT/XQuery nodes. During
      transformation two stacks are managed: one of source nodes being processed and the other for
      XSLT/XQuery nodes being processed. <ph
        keyref="product"/> shows both node types into one
      common stack. The source (XML) nodes are preceded by a red color icon while XSLT/XQuery nodes
      are preceded by a green color icon. The advantage of this approach is that you can always see
      the source scope on which a XSLT/XQuery instruction is executed (the last red color node on
      the stack). The stack is oriented upside down.</p>
    <fig id="the-stack-view-oxygen" product="editor developer">
      <title>The Stack View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_stack_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="the-stack-view-oxygenEclipse" product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Stack View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_stack_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The contextual menu contains one action: <uicontrol>Go to</uicontrol>, which moves the
      selection in the editor panel to the line containing the XSLT element that is displayed on the
      selected line from the view.</p>
    <table id="table-debug-stack-details">
      <title>Stack columns</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry>Column</entry>
            <entry>Description</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>#</entry>
            <entry>Order number, represents the depth of the node (0 is the stack base).</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>XML/XSLT/XQuery Node</entry>
            <entry>Node from source or stylesheet document currently being processed. One particular
              stack node is the document root, noted as <uicontrol>#document</uicontrol>.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Attributes</entry>
            <entry>Attributes of the node (a list of <codeph>id="value"</codeph> pairs).</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Resource</entry>
            <entry>Resource file where the node is located. <ph product="editor developer">The entire path is
                available as tooltip.</ph></entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <note type="important">Remarks:<ul>
        <li>Clicking a record from the stack highlights that node's location inside resource.</li>
        <li>Using Saxon, the stylesheet elements are qualified with XSL proxy, while using Xalan you
          only see their names. (example: <codeph>xsl:template</codeph> using Saxon and
            <codeph>template</codeph> using Xalan).</li>
        <li>Only the Saxon processor shows element attributes.</li>
        <li>The Xalan processor shows also the built-in rules.</li>
      </ul></note>
  </body>
</topic>