<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="delete-resources-working-copy">
  <title>Delete Resources</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Working copy resource management<indexterm>Delete
              resources</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNDelete16.gif" id="image_uvd_tbp_5r"/> Delete</uicontrol>
      action is available in the contextual menu of the <xref href="working-copy-view.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref>. When you delete an item from the working
      copy, it is marked as <i>deleted</i> (scheduled for deletion from repository upon the
      next commit) and removed from the file system. Depending on the state of each item, you are
      prompted to confirm the operation.</p>
    <p>If a resource is deleted from the file system without Subversion's knowledge, the resource is
      marked as <i>missing</i> ( <image href="../img/SVNWCMissing10.png"/> ) in your working
      copy. You can decide what you want to do with a <i>missing</i> item:<ul>
        <li>In the case of a commit, any <i>missing</i> item is first automatically deleted
          and then committed.<note>Not any <i>missing</i> item can be committed as
              <i>deleted</i>, and removed from the repository. For example, you cannot commit
            an item that no longer exists on the disk and that was scheduled for addition ( <image
              href="../img/SVNWCAdded10.png" id="image_nfh_4jp_5r"/> ) previously, since this item
            does not exist in the repository, but you can use the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>
            action instead.</note></li>
        <li>If you want to recover <i>missing</i> items, either <xref
            href="update-working-copy.dita">update</xref> the items themselves or one of their
          parent directories. This fetches their latest version from the repository.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>You can also delete conflicting items (file content conflicts, property conflicts,
      tree-conflicts) and Syncro SVN Client automatically marks them as resolved.<note>It is
        recommended that you resolve conflicts manually to avoid loosing any important remote
        modifications.</note></p>
    <p>Finally, you can change your mind and <xref href="revert-changes.dita">revert</xref> the
      deleted items to their initial, pristine, state.</p>
  </body>
</topic>