<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="detecting-master-files">
  <title>Detecting Master Files</title>
  <body>
    <p>
      <ph keyref="product"/> allows you to detect the master files using the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/DetectMasterFiles16.png"/>Detect Master Files...</uicontrol> option available
      in the contextual menu of the project. This action applies to the folders you select in the
      project. To detect master files over the entire project do one of the following:<ul>
        <li>right click the root of the project and select <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/DetectMasterFiles16.png"/>Detect Master Files...</uicontrol>;</li>
        <li>use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/DetectMasterFiles16.png"/>Detect Master Files
            from Project...</uicontrol> option available in the contextual menu of the
            <uicontrol>Master Files</uicontrol> folder.</li>
      </ul>Both these options display the <uicontrol>Detect Master Files</uicontrol> wizard dialog.
        <ph product="developer developerEclipse editor editorEclipse">In the first panel you can
        select what type of master files you want <ph keyref="product"/> to detect. In the following
        panel the detected master files are presented in a tree like fashion.</ph><ph
        product="author authorEclipse"> The detected master files are presented in a tree like
        fashion. </ph>The resources are grouped in three categories: <ul>
        <li>Possible master files - the files presented on the first level in this category are not
          imported/included from other files. These files are most likely to be set as master
          files.</li>
        <li>Cycles - the files that are presented on the first level have circular dependencies
          between them. Any of the files presented on the first level of a cycle is a possible
          master file. </li>
        <li>Standalone - files that do not include/import other files and are also not
          included/imported themselves. No need to be set as master files.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To set the master files you can enable their check-boxes. <ph
        keyref="product"/> marks all the children of
      a master file as modules. Modules are renderer in gray and their tool-tip presents a list with
      their master files. A module can be accessed from more than one master file.</p>
    <p>The master files already defined in the project are marked automatically in the tree and
      cannot be removed. The only way to disable a master file is to delete it from the
        <uicontrol>Master Files</uicontrol> folder.</p>
    <p>The third panel displays a list with the selected master files. Click the
        <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol> button to add the master files in the <uicontrol>Master
        Files</uicontrol> folder.</p>
    <p>You can use the <uicontrol>Select Master Files</uicontrol> option to mark automatically all
      master files. This action sets as master files all the resources from the <uicontrol>Possible
        Master Files</uicontrol> category and the first resource of each
        <uicontrol>Cycle</uicontrol>.<note type="tip">We recommend you to add only top-level files
        (files that are the root of the include/import graph) in the <uicontrol>Master
          Files</uicontrol> directory. Keep the file set to a minimum and only add files that import
        or include other files. </note><note type="attention" product="author developer editor">In
        case the <uicontrol>Master Files</uicontrol> support is disabled, the <uicontrol>Master
          Files</uicontrol> directory is rendered only if it contains master files.</note></p>
  </body>
</topic>
