<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="dg-configure-toolbar">
  <title>Configure the Toolbars for a Framework</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>The procedure below describes how to add defined actions to a toolbar for a custom <xref
          keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>framework</term></xref>. These steps use examples from
        the two previous help topics that described how to define the <b><xref
            href="dg-insert-section-action.dita#dg-insert-section-action" format="dita"
            >Insert Section</xref></b> and <b><xref
            href="dg-insert-table-action.dita#dg-insert-table-action" format="dita">Insert
            Table</xref></b> actions. You can also configure additional toolbars to add other custom
        actions.</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Open the <xref href="the-document-type-dialog.dita#the-document-type-dialog"
              ><uicontrol>Document Type</uicontrol> configuration dialog box</xref> for your custom
            <term>framework</term> and select the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab. Next, go to the
            <uicontrol>Toolbar</uicontrol> subtab.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            <fig product="editor author ">
              <title>Configuring the Toolbar</title>
              <image href="../img/sa_dg_configuring_toolbar.png"/>
            </fig>
          </p>
          <p>
            <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
              <title>Configuring the Toolbar</title>
              <image href="../img/ec_dg_configuring_toolbar.png"/>
            </fig>
          </p>
          <p>The panel is divided in two sections: the left side contains a list of actions, while
            the right one contains an action tree, displaying the list of actions added in the
            toolbar. The special entry called <i>Separator</i> allows you to visually separate the
            actions in the toolbar.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Insert section</uicontrol> action in the left panel section and
          the <uicontrol>Toolbar</uicontrol> label in the right panel section, then press the
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/AddAsChild16.png"/>Add as child</uicontrol>
          button.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Insert table</uicontrol> action in the left panel section and the
            <uicontrol>Insert section</uicontrol> in the right panel section. Press the
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/AddAsSibling16.png"/>Add as sibling</uicontrol>
          button.</cmd>
        <stepresult>When opening a document of the particular <term>framework</term> in
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the toolbar with the new buttons will be displayed
          in the toolbar area.<note type="tip">If you have many custom toolbar actions, or want to
            group actions according to their category, add more toolbars with custom names and split
            the actions to better suit your purpose. If your toolbar is not displayed when switching
            to the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, right-click the main toolbar, select
              <uicontrol>Configure Toolbars</uicontrol>, and make sure the appropriate toolbar (such
            as the <uicontrol>Author Custom Actions</uicontrol> toolbar) is
          selected.</note></stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
