<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dg-default-author-operations">
  <title>Author Mode Default Operations</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author mode default operations</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>This topic lists the default operations for the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</p>
    <section id="changeattributeoperation">
      <title>ChangeAttributeOperation</title>
      <p>This operation allows you to add/modify/remove an attribute. You can use this operation in
        your own custom <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode action to modify the value for a certain
        attribute on a specific XML element. The arguments of the operation are:<ul
          id="ul_kwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>name</b> - The attribute local name.</li>
          <li><b>namespace</b> - The attribute namespace.</li>
          <li><b>elementLocation</b> - The XPath location that identifies the element.</li>
          <li><b>value</b> - The new value for the attribute. If empty or null the attribute will be
            removed.</li>
          <li><b>editAttribute</b> - If an in-place editor exists for this attribute, it will
            automatically activate the in-place editor and start editing.</li>
          <li><b>removeIfEmpty</b> - The possible values are <codeph>true</codeph> and
              <codeph>false</codeph>. True means that the attribute should be removed if an empty
            value is provided. The default behavior is to remove it.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="changepseudoclassesoperation">
      <title>ChangePseudoClassesOperation</title>
      <p>Operation that sets a list of pseudo-class values to nodes identified by an XPath
        expression. It can also remove a list of values from nodes identified by an XPath
        expression. The operation accepts the following parameters:<ul id="ul_rwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>setLocations</b> - An XPath expression indicating a list of nodes for which the
            specified list of pseudo-classes will be set. If it is not defined, then the element at
            the cursor position will be used.</li>
          <li><b>setPseudoClassNames</b> - A space-separated list of pseudo-class names that will be
            set on the matched nodes.</li>
          <li><b>removeLocations</b> - An XPath expression indicating a list of nodes from which the
            specified list of pseudo-classes will be removed. If it is not defined, then the element
            at the cursor position will be used.</li>
          <li><b>removePseudoClassNames</b> - A space-separated list of pseudo-class names that will
            be removed from the matched nodes.</li>
          <li><b>includeAllNodes</b> - The possible values are <codeph>yes</codeph> and
              <codeph>no</codeph>. If set to <codeph>yes</codeph>, comments, CDATA, and text nodes
            are included when evaluating XPath expressions. If set to <codeph>no</codeph>, they are
            ignored.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="deleteelementoperation">
      <title>DeleteElementOperation</title>
      <p>Deletes the node indicated by the <codeph>elementLocation</codeph> parameter XPath
        expression. If missing, the operation will delete the node at the cursor location.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="deleteelementsoperation">
      <title>DeleteElementsOperation</title>
      <p>Deletes the nodes indicated by the <codeph>elementLocations</codeph> parameter XPath
        expression. If missing, the operation will delete the node at the cursor location.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="executecommandlineoperation">
      <title>ExecuteCommandLineOperation</title>
      <p>This operation allows you to start a process executing a given command line. It has the
        following arguments:<ul>
          <li><b>name</b> - The name of the operation (or name of the console panel that corresponds
            to the process run by an action built over this operation).</li>
          <li><b>workingDirectory</b> - The path to the directory where the command line is
            executed. The default value is <codeph>"."</codeph> (current directory).</li>
          <li><b>cmdLine</b> - The command line to be executed (accepts <xref
              href="#dg-default-author-operations/editor_variables_in_author_mode_operations"
              format="dita">editor variables</xref>).</li>
          <li><b>showConsole</b> - If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, the console panel will be
            displayed in <ph keyref="product"/>. The default value is <codeph>false</codeph>.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="executemultipleactionsoperation">
      <title>ExecuteMultipleActionsOperation</title>
      <p>This operation allows the execution of a sequence of actions, defined as a list of action
        IDs. The actions must be defined by the corresponding <term>framework</term>, or one of the
        common actions for all <term>frameworks</term> supplied by <ph keyref="product"/>.<ul
          id="ul_hvc_pdd_vm">
          <li><b>actionIDs</b> - The action IDs list that will be executed in sequence, the list
            must be a string sequence containing the IDs separated by commas or new lines.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="executemultiplewebappcompatibleactionsoperation">
      <title>ExecuteMultipleWebappCompatibleActionsOperation</title>
      <p>An implementation of an operation that runs a sequence of <ph keyref="webappProduct"
        />-compatible actions, defined as a list of IDs.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="executetransformationscenariosoperation">
      <title>ExecuteTransformationScenariosOperation</title>
      <p>This operation allows running one or more transformation scenarios defined in the current
          <xref keyref="glossentry_document_type_association"><term>document type
          association</term></xref>. It is useful to add to the toolbar buttons that trigger
        publishing to various output formats. The argument of the operation is:<ul
          id="ul_owk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>scenarioNames</b> - The list of scenario names that will be executed, separated by
            new lines.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="insertequationoperation">
      <title>InsertEquationOperation</title>
      <p>Inserts a fragment containing a MathML equation at the cursor offset. The argument of this
        operation is:<ul id="ul_jwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>fragment</b> - The XML fragment containing the MathML content that should be
            inserted.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="insertfragmentoperation">
      <title>InsertFragmentOperation</title>
      <p>Inserts an XML fragment at the current cursor position. The selection, if there is one,
        remains unchanged. The fragment will be inserted in the current context of the cursor
        position meaning that if the current XML document uses some namespace declarations then the
        inserted fragment must use the same declarations. The namespace declarations of the inserted
        fragment will be adapted to the existing namespace declarations of the XML document. For
        more details about its list of parameters, see <xref
          href="dg-author-op-InsertFragmentOperation-arguments.dita"/>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="insertorreplacefragmentoperation">
      <title>InsertOrReplaceFragmentOperation</title>
      <p>Similar to <xref href="#dg-default-author-operations/insertfragmentoperation" format="dita"
            ><b>InsertFragmentOperation</b></xref>, except it removes the selected content before
        inserting the fragment. Also, the <b>insertPosition</b> parameter has another possible
        value: <b>Replace</b>. If this value is used, the operation deletes the node selected by the
        XPath expression denoted by the <b>insertLocation</b> parameter. For more details about its
        list of parameters, see <xref href="dg-author-op-InsertFragmentOperation-arguments.dita"
        />.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="insertorreplacetextoperation">
      <title>InsertOrReplaceTextOperation</title>
      <p>Inserts a text at current position removing the selected content, if any. The argument of
        this operation is:<ul id="ul_hwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>text</b> - The text section to insert.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="insertxincludeoperation">
      <title>InsertXIncludeOperation</title>
      <p>Insert an <codeph>XInclude</codeph> element at the cursor offset. Opens a dialog box that
        allows you to browse and select content to be included in your document and automatically
        generates the corresponding XInclude instruction.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="jsoperation">
      <title>JSOperation</title>
      <p>Allows you to call the Java API from custom JavaScript content. For some sample
          <b>JSOperation</b> implementations, see <xref
          href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/javascript-sample-operations" format="html"
          scope="external"/>.<note type="notice">For the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>, this
          operation cannot be invoked using the JavaScript API.</note></p>
      <p>This operation accepts the following parameter:<ul id="ul_af1_4dr_qr">
          <li><b>script</b><p>The JavaScript content to execute. It must have a function called
                <codeph>doOperation()</codeph>, which can use the predefined
                <codeph>authorAccess</codeph> variable. The <codeph>authorAccess</codeph> variable
              has access to the entire <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Editor/SDK/javadoc/ro/sync/ecss/extensions/api/AuthorAccess.html"
                format="html" scope="external"
                ><i>ro.sync.ecss.extensions.api.AuthorAccess</i></xref> Java API. </p><p>The
              following example is a script that retrieves the current value of the <b>type</b>
              attribute on the current element, allows the end user to edit its new value and sets
              the new value in the
              document:<codeblock outputclass="language-javascript">function doOperation(){ 
 //The current node is either entirely selected...
 currentNode = authorAccess.getEditorAccess().getFullySelectedNode();
 if(currentNode == null){
 //or the cursor is placed in it
 caretOffset = authorAccess.getEditorAccess().getCaretOffset(); 
 currentNode = authorAccess.getDocumentController().getNodeAtOffset
                          (caretOffset);
 }
 //Get current value of the @type attribute
  currentTypeValue = "";
  currentTypeValueAttr = currentNode.getAttribute("type");
  if(currentTypeValueAttr != null){
    currentTypeValue = currentTypeValueAttr.getValue();
  }
 //Ask user for new value for attribute.
 newTypeValue = javax.swing.JOptionPane.showInputDialog
                         ("Input @type value", currentTypeValue);
 if(newTypeValue != null){
   //Create and set the new attribute value for the @type attribute.
   attrValue = new Packages.ro.sync.ecss.extensions.api.node.AttrValue
                         (newTypeValue);
   authorAccess.getDocumentController().setAttribute
                         ("type", attrValue, currentNode);
 }
} </codeblock></p></li>
        </ul><note type="tip">You can call functions defined inside a script called
            <filepath>commons.js</filepath> from your custom script content so that you can use that
          external script file as a library of functions. Note that this
            <filepath>commons.js</filepath> file must be placed in the root of the
            <term>framework</term> directory (for example, <filepath><term
              conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"
            />/frameworks/dita/commons.js</filepath>) because that is the only location where <ph
            keyref="product"/> will look for it.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="movecaretoperation">
      <title>MoveCaretOperation</title>
      <p>Flexible operation for moving the cursor within a document and it is also capable of
        performing a selection. The operation accepts the following arguments:<ul>
          <li><b>xpathLocation</b> - An XPath expression that identifies the node relative to where
            the cursor will be moved. If the expression identifies more than one node, only the
            first one will be taken into account.</li>
          <li><b>position</b> - The position relative to the node obtained from the XPath expression
            where the cursor will be moved. When also choosing to perform a selection, you can use
            the following possible values:<ul>
              <li><codeph>Before</codeph> - Places the cursor at the beginning of the
                selection.</li>
              <li><codeph>Inside, at the beginning</codeph> - Places the cursor at the beginning of
                the selection.</li>
              <li><codeph>After</codeph> - Places the cursor at the end of the selection.</li>
              <li><codeph>Inside, at the end</codeph> - Places the cursor at the end of the
                selection.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><b>selection</b> - Specifies if the operation should select the element obtained from
            the XPath expression, its content, or nothing at all. The possible values of the
            argument are: <codeph>None</codeph>, <codeph>Element</codeph>, and
              <codeph>Content</codeph>.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="moveelementoperation">
      <title>MoveElementOperation</title>
      <p>Flexible operation for moving an XML element to another location from the same document.
        XPath expressions are used to identify the source element and the target location. The
        operation takes the following parameters:<ul id="ul_qwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>sourceLocation</b> - XPath expression that identifies the content to be moved.</li>
          <li><b>deleteLocation</b> - XPath expression that identifies the node to be removed. This
            parameter is optional. If missing, the <b>sourceLocation</b> parameter will also
            identify the node to be deleted.</li>
          <li><b>surroundFragment</b> - A string representation of an XML fragment. The moved node
            will be wrapped in this string before moving it in the destination.</li>
          <li><b>targetLocation</b> - XPath expression that identifies the location where the node
            must be moved to.</li>
          <li><b>insertPosition</b> - Argument that indicates the insert position.</li>
          <li><b>moveOnlySourceContentNodes</b> - When <codeph>true</codeph>, only the content of
            the source element is moved.</li>
          <li><b>processTrackedChangesForXpathLocations</b> - When nodes are located via an XPath
            expression and the nodes are deleted with <xref keyref="glossentry_track-changes"
                ><term>Change Tracking</term></xref> enabled, they are considered as being present
            by default (thus, the <term>change tracking</term> is ignored). If you set this argument
            to <codeph>true</codeph> and <term>change tracking</term> is enabled, deleted nodes will
            be ignored when the XPath locations are computed (thus, the <term>change tracking</term>
            is NOT ignored).</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="openinsystemappoperation">
      <title>OpenInSystemAppOperation</title>
      <p>Opens a resource in the system application that is associated with the resource in the
        operating system. The arguments of this operation is:<ul id="ul_nd3_btn_5r">
          <li><b>resourcePath</b> - An XPath expression that, when executed, returns the path of the
            resource to be opened. <xref href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables">Editor
              variables</xref> are expanded in the value of this parameter, before the expression is
            executed.</li>
          <li><b>isUnparsedEntity</b> - Possible values are <codeph>true</codeph> or
              <codeph>false</codeph>. If the value is <codeph>true</codeph>, the value of the
              <b>resourcePath</b> argument is treated as the name of an unparsed entity.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="reloadcontentoperation">
      <title>ReloadContentOperation</title>
      <p>Reloads the content of the editor by re-reading the information from the URL used to open
        it. It accepts the following argument:<ul>
          <li><b>markAsNotModified</b> - The possible values are <codeph>true</codeph> and
              <codeph>false</codeph>. After reloading the editor, the content may appear as modified
            and in some cases where the content is already present on the file server, you would not
            want the user to save it again. You can set this flag to <codeph>true</codeph> to
            prevent the editor from showing the content as modified.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="removepseudoclassoperation">
      <title>RemovePseudoClassOperation</title>
      <p>An operation that removes a pseudo-class from an element. Accepts the following
          parameters:<ul id="ul_lvb_n3h_ps">
          <li><b>name</b> - Name of the pseudo-class to be removed.</li>
          <li><b>includeAllNodes</b> - The possible values are <codeph>yes</codeph> and
              <codeph>no</codeph>. If set to <codeph>yes</codeph>, comments, CDATA, and text nodes
            are included when evaluating XPath expressions. If set to <codeph>no</codeph>, they are
            ignored.</li>
          <li><b>elementLocation</b> - The XPath location that identifies the element. Leave it
            empty for the current element. It can also identify multiple elements, in which case the
            pseudo class will be removed from all of them.<p><b>Example:</b></p><p>Suppose that
              there is a pseudo-class called <codeph>myClass</codeph> on the element
                <codeph>paragraph</codeph> and there are CSS styles matching the pseudo-class. </p><p>
              <codeblock outputclass="language-css">paragraph:myClass{
  font-size:2em;
  color:red;
}
paragraph{
  color:blue;
}</codeblock>
            </p><p>In the previous example, by removing the pseudo-class, the layout of the
                <codeph>paragraph</codeph> is rebuilt by matching the other rules (in this case, the
              foreground color of the <codeph>paragraph</codeph> element will become blue.</p></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="renameelementoperation">
      <title>RenameElementOperation</title>
      <p>This operation allows you to rename all occurrences of the elements identified by an XPath
        expression. The operation requires two parameters:<ul id="ul_nwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>elementName</b> - The new element name</li>
          <li><b>elementLocation</b> - The XPath expression that identifies the element occurrences
            to be renamed. If this parameter is missing, the operation renames the element at
            current cursor position.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="setpseudoclassoperation">
      <title>SetPseudoClassOperation</title>
      <p>An operation that sets a pseudo-class to an element. The operation accepts the following
          parameters:<ul id="ul_swk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>elementLocation</b> - An XPath expression indicating the element for which the
            pseudo-class will be set. If it is not defined, then the element at cursor position will
            be used.</li>
          <li><b>name</b> - The pseudo-class local name.</li>
          <li><b>includeAllNodes</b> - The possible values are <codeph>yes</codeph> and
              <codeph>no</codeph>. If set to <codeph>yes</codeph>, comments, CDATA, and text nodes
            are included when evaluating XPath expressions. If set to <codeph>no</codeph>, they are
            ignored.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="showelementdocumentationoperation">
      <title>ShowElementDocumentationOperation</title>
      <p>Opens the associated specification HTML page for the current element. The operation accepts
        as parameter a URL pattern that points to the HTML page containing the documentation.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="surroundwithfragmentoperation">
      <title>SurroundWithFragmentOperation</title>
      <p>Surrounds the selected content with a text fragment. Since the fragment can have multiple
        nodes, the surrounded content will be always placed in the first leaf element. If there is
        no selection, the operation will simply insert the fragment at the cursor position. For more
        details about the list of parameters go to <xref
          href="dg-author-op-SurroundWithFragmentOperation-arguments.dita"/>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="surroundwithtextoperation">
      <title>SurroundWithTextOperation</title>
      <p>This operation has two arguments (two text values) that will be inserted before and after
        the selected content. If there is no selected content, the two sections will be inserted at
        the cursor position. The arguments of the operation are:<ul id="ul_iwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>header</b> - The text that is placed before the selection.</li>
          <li><b>footer</b> - The text that is placed after the selection.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="togglepseudoclassoperation">
      <title>TogglePseudoClassOperation</title>
      <p>An implementation of an operation to toggle on/off the pseudo-class of an element. Accepts
        the following parameters:<ul>
          <li><b>name</b> - Name of the pseudo-class to be toggled on/off.</li>
          <li><b>includeAllNodes</b> - The possible values are <codeph>yes</codeph> and
              <codeph>no</codeph>. If set to <codeph>yes</codeph>, comments, CDATA, and text nodes
            are included when evaluating XPath expressions. If set to <codeph>no</codeph>, they are
            ignored.</li>
          <li><b>elementLocation</b> - The XPath location that identifies one or more elements for
            which the pseudo class will be toggled. Leave it empty for the current
                element.<p><b>Example:</b></p><codeblock outputclass="language-css">paragraph:myClass{
  color:red;
}
paragraph{
  color:blue;
}</codeblock><p>By
              default, the paragraph content is rendered in blue. Suppose that we have a
                <codeph>TogglePseudoClassOperation</codeph> configured for the
                <codeph>myClass</codeph> pseudo-class. Invoking it the first time will set the
                <codeph>myClass</codeph> pseudo-class and the paragraph will be rendered in red.
              Invoking the operation again, will remove the pseudo-class and the visible result will
              be a blue rendered <codeph>paragraph</codeph> element.</p></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="togglesurroundwithelementoperation">
      <title>ToggleSurroundWithElementOperation</title>
      <p>This operation allows wrapping and unwrapping content in a specific wrapper element that
        can have certain attributes specified on it. It is useful to implement toggle actions such
        as highlighting text as bold, italic, or underline. The operation supports processing
        multiple selection intervals, such as multiple cells within a table column selection. The
        arguments of the operation are:<ul id="ul_mwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>element</b> - The element to wrap or unwrap content.</li>
          <li><b>schemaAware</b> - <ph
              conkeyref="reusables-author-mode-customization/schema_aware_argument"/></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="unwraptagsoperation">
      <title>UnwrapTagsOperation</title>
      <p>This operation allows removing the element tags either from the current element or for an
        element identified with an XPath location. The argument of the operation is<ul
          id="ul_lwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>unwrapElementLocation</b> - An XPath expression indicating the element to unwrap.
            If it is not defined, the element at the cursor position is unwrapped.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="xqueryupdateoperation">
      <title>XQueryUpdateOperation</title>
      <p>Allows you to execute an XQuery Update script directly over content in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.<note type="notice">This operation is not applicable to
          the <ph keyref="authorComponent"/> or the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>.</note></p>
      <p>It supports the following arguments:<ul>
          <li><b>script</b> - The XQuery Update script to be executed. The value can either be an
            XQuery script or a URL that points to the XQuery Update script. You can use the <xref
              href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables/edvar-framework"
              ><i>${framework}</i></xref> or <xref
              href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables/edVar-frameworkDir"
                ><i>${frameworkDir}</i></xref> editor variables to refer the scripts from the
              <term>framework</term> directory.<p>The script will be executed in the context of the
              node at the cursor position. If the script declares the following variable, it will
              also receive the selected nodes (assuming that entire nodes are
              selected):</p><codeblock outputclass="language-ini">declare variable $oxyxq:selection external;</codeblock><p>In
              the <xref href="#dg-default-author-operations/example1" format="dita">example
                below</xref>, you can see how this argument is used.</p></li>
          <li><b>externalParams</b> - A string that can assign multiple key-value pairs separated by
            a comma or a new line character.<p>For example, if an XQuery script declares two
              external parameters like this:
            </p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">declare variable $param1 external;
declare variable $param2 external;</codeblock>You
            can pass custom values for each parameter by setting the <b>externalParams</b> to
              <codeph>param1=value1,param2=value2</codeph>.</li>
          <li><b>expandXincludeReferences</b> - Makes all <i>Xinclude</i> elements transparent to
            the XQuery transformer. When the <i>Xinclude</i> references are transparent, the
              <b>XQueryUpdateOperation</b> can use the referenced elements for further processing in
            the current document, but it cannot change their values in the original document. The
            default value is <codeph>false</codeph>, which means the <i>Xinclude</i> elements are
            not transparent.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p id="example1">An example of an XQuery Update Script that converts paragraphs to list
        items:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">declare namespace oxyxq = "http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/xqu";
(: This variable will be linked to the selected nodes assuming that there are 
actually fully selected nodes. For example this selection will return null: 
&lt;p>{SEL_START}text{SEL_END} in para&lt;/p>
but this will give two "p" elements:
{SEL_END}&lt;p>text&lt;/p>&lt;p>text2&lt;/p>{SEL_END}

If a multiple selection exists it will also be processed and forwarded.
 Again, only fully selected nodes will be passed.
:)
declare variable $oxyxq:selection external;

(: We will process either the selection or the context node :)
let $toProcess := if (empty($oxyxq:selection)) then
    (.)
else
    ($oxyxq:selection)

returnif (not(empty($toProcess))) then
        (
        (: Create the list :)
        let $ul :=
        &lt;ul>
            {
                for $sel in $toProcess
                return
                    &lt;li>{$sel}&lt;/li>
            }
        &lt;/ul>
        
        return
            (
            (: Delete the processed nodes :)
            for $sel in $toProcess
            return
                delete node $sel,
            (: Inserts the constructed list :)
            insert node $ul
                before $toProcess[1]
            )
        )
    else
        ()</codeblock></p>
    </section>
    <section id="xsltoperation_and_xqueryoperation">
      <title>XSLTOperation and XQueryOperation</title>
      <p>Applies an XSLT or XQuery script on a source element and then replaces or inserts the
        result in a specified target element.<note type="notice">For the <ph keyref="webappProduct"
          />, these operations cannot be invoked using the <xref keyref="jscript_api">JavaScript
            API</xref>.</note></p>
      <p>These operations accept the following parameters:<ul id="ul_pwk_qjh_ps">
          <li><b>sourceLocation</b><p>An XPath expression indicating the element that the script
              will be applied on. If it is not defined, then the element at the cursor position will
              be used. </p><p>There may be situations in which you want to look at an ancestor of
              the current element and take decisions in the script based on this. To do this, you
              can set the <b>sourceLocation</b> to point to an ancestor node then declare a
              parameter called <b>currentElementLocation</b> in your script and use it to
              re-position in the current element, as in the following
              example:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;xsl:stylesheet xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" version="2.0" 
  xpath-default-namespace="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
  xmlns:saxon="http://saxon.sf.net/" exclude-result-prefixes="saxon">     
    &lt;!-- This is an XPath location to be sent by the operation to the script -->
    &lt;xsl:param name="currentElementLocation"/>
    
    &lt;xsl:template match="/">
        &lt;!-- Evaluate the XPath of the current element location -->
        &lt;xsl:apply-templates 
        select="saxon:eval(saxon:expression($currentElementLocation))"/>
    &lt;/xsl:template>
    
    &lt;xsl:template match="para">
        &lt;!-- And the context is again inside the current element, 
        but we can use information from the entire XML -->
        &lt;xsl:variable 
            name="keyImage" select="//imagedata[@fileref='images/lake.jpeg']
              /ancestor::inlinemediaobject/@xml:id/string()"/>
                &lt;xref linkend="{$keyImage}" role="key_include" 
                  xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
                    &lt;xsl:value-of 
                          select="$currentElementLocation">&lt;/xsl:value-of>
        &lt;/xref>
    &lt;/xsl:template>    
&lt;/xsl:stylesheet></codeblock></p></li>
          <li><b>targetLocation</b><p>An XPath expression indicating the insert location for the
              result of the transformation. If it is not defined then the insert location will be at
              the cursor location.</p></li>
          <li><b>script</b><p>The script content (XSLT or XQuery). The base system ID for this will
              be the <term>framework</term> file, so any include/import reference will be resolved
              relative to the <filepath>.framework</filepath> file that contains this action
              definition.</p><p>For example, for the following script, the imported
                <filepath>xslt_operation.xsl</filepath> needs to be located in the current
                <term>framework</term>
              directory.</p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;xsl:stylesheet xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" 
             version="1.0">
    &lt;xsl:import href="xslt_operation.xsl"/>
&lt;/xsl:stylesheet></codeblock><p>You
              can also use a path for an included or imported reference. When using a path, the
              following apply:<ul>
                <li>A relative path is resolved to the <term>framework</term> directory.</li>
                <li>The <xref href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables/edvar-framework"
                      ><i>${framework}</i> editor variable</xref> can also be used to reference
                  resources from the <term>framework</term> directory.</li>
                <li>The path is passed through the catalog mappings. It helps to use an absolute URL
                  (for instance, <filepath>http://www.oxygenxml.com/fr/testy.xsl</filepath>) and map
                  it in the <filepath>catalog.xml</filepath> file from the <term>framework</term>
                  directory to a resource from the <term>framework</term>.</li>
              </ul></p></li>
          <li><b>action</b><p>The insert action relative to the node determined by the target XPath
              expression. It can be: Replace, At cursor position, Before, After, Inside as first
              child or Inside as last child.</p></li>
          <li><b>caretPosition</b><p>The position of the cursor after the action is executed. It can
              be: <codeph>Preserve</codeph>, <codeph>Before</codeph>, <codeph>Start</codeph>,
                <codeph>First editable position</codeph>, <codeph>End</codeph>, or
                <codeph>After</codeph>. If this parameter is not set, you can still indicate the
              position of the cursor by using the <xref
                href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables/edvar-caret"><i>${caret}</i> editor
                variable</xref> in the inserted content.</p></li>
          <li><b>expandEditorVariables</b><p>Parameter controlling the expansion of <xref
                href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables">editor variables</xref> returned by
              the script processing. Expansion is enabled by default.</p></li>
          <li><b>suspendTrackChanges</b><p>It has 2 possible values (<codeph>true</codeph> and
                <codeph>false</codeph>). The default value is <codeph>false</codeph>. When set to
                <codeph>true</codeph>, the <xref keyref="glossentry_track-changes"><i>Track
                  Changes</i></xref> feature is deactivated. When using this argument, after the
              action is finished, the state of the <term>Track Changes</term> feature is restored to
              its initial value.</p></li>
          <li><b>externalParams</b> - A string that can assign multiple key-value pairs separated by
            a comma or a new line character.<p>For example, if an XQuery script declares two
              external parameters like this:
            </p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">declare variable $param1 external;
declare variable $param2 external;</codeblock>You
            can pass custom values for each parameter by setting the <b>externalParams</b> to
              <codeph>param1=value1,param2=value2</codeph>.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p><b>XSLTOperation Example: Sort a list with respect to the language declared on the root
          element-</b></p>
      <p>Suppose we want an action that will sort a list with respect to the language declared on
        the root element and we have an XML file like
        this:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;article xml:lang="en">
  &lt;ul>
     &lt;li>B&lt;/li>
     &lt;li>C&lt;/li>
     &lt;li>A&lt;/li>
  &lt;/ul>
&lt;/article></codeblock></p>
      <p>The <b>XSLTOperation</b> needs to be configured as follows:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>sourceLocation</b> is set to /* so that the script has access to the root element and
          its children.</li>
        <li><b>targetLocation</b> is left untouched (assuming that the action is active only when
          the cursor is inside the list).</li>
      </ul>
      <p>The XSLT script would look like
        this:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;xsl:stylesheet xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" 
  xmlns:saxon="http://saxon.sf.net/"
  xmlns:lds="http://www.lds.org/schema/lds-meta/v1" 
  xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
  exclude-result-prefixes="xs saxon" version="2.0">

  &lt;xsl:param name="currentElementLocation"/>

  &lt;xsl:template match="/">
      &lt;!-- 
          sourceLocation parameter was set to /* to have a larger context.
          We can pinpoint the element that contained the caret 
          using $currentElementLocation
      -->
     &lt;xsl:apply-templates select="saxon:eval(saxon:expression($currentElementLocation))"/>
  &lt;/xsl:template>

  &lt;xsl:template match="ul">
        
    &lt;!-- Because the sourceLocation parameter was set to /* we now have access to 
         the root element and its attributes. -->
    &lt;xsl:variable name="lang" select="/*/@xml:lang"/>
    &lt;xsl:variable name="collationURI">
      &lt;xsl:value-of select="concat('http://www.w3.org/2013/collation/UCA?lang=', $lang)"/>
    &lt;/xsl:variable>
        
      &lt;xsl:copy>
          &lt;xsl:copy-of select="@*"/>
            
          &lt;!-- Copy the list items, but sorted. -->
          &lt;xsl:apply-templates select="li">
              &lt;xsl:sort collation="{$collationURI}" select="text()"/>
          &lt;/xsl:apply-templates>
      &lt;/xsl:copy>
  &lt;/xsl:template>
    
  &lt;!-- This copy template will handle the contents of the list items. -->
  &lt;xsl:template match="@* | node()">
      &lt;xsl:copy>
          &lt;xsl:apply-templates select="@* | node()"/>
      &lt;/xsl:copy>
  &lt;/xsl:template>
&lt;/xsl:stylesheet></codeblock></p>
      <sectiondiv><b>Using Entities and Xincludes with an XSLTOperation</b></sectiondiv>
      <p>
        <ul>
          <li><b>Entities</b> will be resolved in the result.</li>
          <li><b>Xincludes</b> are also resolved in the result, and you can alter the XML obtained
            after the resolving using the XSLT/XQuery script of the operation, but you cannot alter
            the included document itself.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="editor_variables_in_author_mode_operations">
      <title>Editor Variables in Author Mode Operations</title>
      <p id="editor-variables"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode operations can include parameters
        that contain the following <xref href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables">editor
          variables</xref>:<ul>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-caret"/>
        </ul><note>The <b>${caret}</b> editor variable is available only for parameters that take
          XML content as values. It is replaced with the <b>${UNIQUE_CARET_MARKER_FOR_AUTHOR}</b>
          macro. The default Author operations process this macro and position the cursor at the
          designated offset. </note><ul>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edvar-selection"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-ask"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edvar-timestamp"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edvar-uuid"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-id"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-cfn"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-cfne"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edvar-cf"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-cfd"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-frameworksDir"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-pd"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-oxygenInstallDir"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-homeDir"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-pn"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edvar-env"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-system"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editor-variables/edVar-date"/>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <topic id="info-arguments">
    <title>How to Find More Information About the Arguments of an Operation</title>
    <body>
      <p>If you need to find more information about the arguments of an operation, there are several
        places where this information is available:<ul>
          <li>In the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Editor/SDK/javadoc/ro/sync/ecss/extensions/api/AuthorOperation.html"
              format="html" scope="external">API documentation</xref> for the particular
            operation.</li>
          <li>By invoking the <codeph>getArguments()</codeph> method on the operation.</li>
          <li>In the source code of the operation.</li>
          <li>In <ph keyref="product"/>:<ol>
              <li>Go to <menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol>
                </menucascade>, select a document type and click the <xref
                  href="preferences-document-type-association.dita#preferences-document-type-association"
                    ><uicontrol>New</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>,
                    <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Extend</uicontrol>
                button</xref>.</li>
              <li>Go to the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab and then the
                  <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> subtab. At the bottom of this subtab, click
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/Add16.png"/>New</uicontrol> to open the <xref
                  href="the-action-dialog.dita"><uicontrol>Action</uicontrol> dialog
                box</xref>.</li>
              <li>Locate the <uicontrol>Operation</uicontrol> field and click the
                  <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol> button on the right side. This will open a dialog
                box that displays the default operations.</li>
              <li>Double-click the operation (or select it and click
                  <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>).<p>The arguments for the operation will now be
                  displayed in the <xref href="the-action-dialog.dita"><uicontrol>Action</uicontrol>
                    dialog box</xref>.</p></li>
            </ol></li>
        </ul></p>
    </body>
  </topic>
</topic>
