<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dg-folding-elements">
  <title>Folding Elements: <codeph>-oxy-foldable</codeph>, <codeph>-oxy-not-foldable-child</codeph>
    and <codeph>-oxy-folded</codeph> properties</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Oxygen CSS Extensions<indexterm>additional properties<indexterm>folding
              elements</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> Author allows you to
      declare some elements to be <i>foldable</i> (collapsible). This is especially useful when
      working with large documents organized in logical blocks, editing a large DocBook article or
      book for instance. <ph keyref="product"
      /> marks the foldable content with a small blue triangle. When you hover with your mouse
      pointer over this marker, a dotted line borders the collapsible content. The following
      contextual actions are available:</p>
    <ul
      conref="folding-of-the-xml-elements.dita#folding-of-the-xml-elements/folding-elements-actions">
      <li/>
    </ul>
    <p>To define the element whose content can be folded by the user, you must use the property:
        <codeph>-oxy-foldable:true;</codeph>. To define the elements that are folded by default, use
      the <codeph>-oxy-folded:true</codeph> property.<note>The <codeph>-oxy-folded</codeph> property
        works in conjunction with the <codeph>-oxy-foldable</codeph> property. Thus, the
          <codeph>folded</codeph> property is ignored if the <codeph>-oxy-foldable</codeph> property
        is not set on the same element.</note></p>
    <p>When collapsing an element, it is useful to keep some of its content visible, like a short
      description of the collapsed region. The property <codeph>-oxy-not-foldable-child</codeph> is
      used to identify the child elements that are kept visible. It accepts as value an element name
      or a list of comma separated element names. If the element is marked as <i>foldable</i>
        (<codeph>-oxy-foldable:true;</codeph>) but it doesn't have the property
        <codeph>-oxy-not-foldable-child</codeph> or none of the specified non-foldable children
      exists, then the element is still foldable. In this case the element kept visible when folded
      will be the <codeph>before</codeph> pseudo-element.<note>Deprecated properties
          <codeph>foldable</codeph>, <codeph>not-foldable-child</codeph>, and
          <codeph>folded</codeph> are also supported.</note></p>
    <example>
      <title>Folding DocBook Elements</title>
      <p>All the elements below can have a <codeph>title</codeph> child element and are considered
        to be logical sections. You mark them as being <term>foldable</term> leaving the
          <codeph>title</codeph> element visible.</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-css">set,
book,
part,
reference,
chapter,
preface,
article,
sect1,
sect2,
sect3,
sect4,
section,
appendix,
figure,
example,
table {
    -oxy-foldable:true;
    -oxy-not-foldable-child: title;
}</codeblock>
    </example>
  </body>
</topic>
