<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dg-style-images">
    <title>Styling Images</title>
    <body>
        <p>The CSS 2.1 does not specify how an element can be rendered as an image. To overpass this
            limitation, <ph keyref="product"/> Author
            supports a CSS Level 3 extension allowing to load image data from an URL. The URL of the
            image must be specified by one of the element attributes and it is resolved through the
            catalogs specified in <ph
                keyref="product"/>.</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-css">
image{
    display:block;
    content: attr(href, url);
    margin-left:2em;
}</codeblock>
        <p>Our <codeph>image</codeph> element has the required attribute <codeph>href</codeph> of
      type <codeph>xs:anyURI</codeph>. The <codeph>href</codeph> attribute contains an image
      location so the rendered content is obtained by using the
      function:<codeblock>attr(href, url)</codeblock> The first argument is the name of the
      attribute pointing to the image file. The second argument of the <codeph>attr</codeph>
      function specifies the type of the content. If the type has the <codeph>url</codeph> value,
      then <ph keyref="product"/> identifies the content as being an image. If the type is missing,
      then the content will be the text representing the attribute value.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> Author handles both absolute and relative specified URLs. If the image
      has an <i>absolute</i> URL location (e.g:
      "http://www.oasis-open.org/images/standards/oasis_standard.jpg") then it is loaded directly
      from this location. If the image URL is <i>relative</i> specified to the XML document (e.g:
      "images/my_screenshot.jpg") then the location is obtained by adding this value to the location
      of the edited XML document.</p>
        <p>An image can also be referenced by the name of a DTD entity which specifies the location
            of the image file. For example if the document declares an entity <b>graphic</b> which
            points to a JPEG image file:</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;!ENTITY graphic SYSTEM "depo/keyboard_shortcut.jpg" NDATA JPEG&gt;</codeblock>
        <p>and the image is referenced in the XML document by specifying the name of the entity as
            the value of an attribute:</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;mediaobject&gt;
    &lt;imageobject&gt;
        &lt;imagedata entityref="graphic" scale="50"/&gt;
    &lt;/imageobject&gt;
&lt;/mediaobject&gt;</codeblock>
        <p>The CSS should use the functions <codeph>url</codeph>, <codeph>attr</codeph> and
                <codeph>unparsed-entity-uri</codeph> for displaying the image in the Author
            mode:</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-css">imagedata[entityref]{
    content: url(unparsed-entity-uri(attr(entityref))); 
}
</codeblock>
        <p>To take into account the value of the <codeph>width</codeph> attribute of the
                <codeph>imagedata</codeph> and use it for resizing the image, the CSS can define the
            following rule:</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-css">imagedata[width]{
  width:attr(width, length);
}</codeblock>
        <fig>
            <title>Samples of images in Author</title>
            <image href="../img/bt_dg_images_in_author.png"/>
        </fig>
    </body>
</topic>
