<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dg-style-section-element">
    <title>Styling the <codeph>section</codeph> Element</title>
    <body>
        <p>The title of any section must be bold and smaller than the title of the parent section.
            To create this effect a sequence of CSS rules must be created. The <codeph>*</codeph>
            operator matches any element, it can be used to match titles having progressive depths
            in the document.</p>
        <p>
            <codeblock outputclass="language-css">title{
    font-size: 2.4em;
    font-weight:bold;    
}
* * title{
    font-size: 2.0em;
}
* * * title{
    font-size: 1.6em;
}
* * * * title{
    font-size: 1.2em;
}</codeblock>
        </p>
        <p>It's useful to have before the title a constant text, indicating that it refers to a
            section. This text can include also the current section number. The
                <codeph>:before</codeph> and <codeph>:after</codeph> pseudo elements will be used,
            plus the CSS counters.</p>
        <p>First declare a counter named <codeph>sect</codeph> for each <codeph>book</codeph> or
                <codeph>article</codeph>. The counter is set to zero at the beginning of each such
            element:</p>
        <p>
            <codeblock outputclass="language-css">book, 
article{
    counter-reset:sect;
}
                        </codeblock>
        </p>
        <p>The <codeph>sect</codeph> counter is incremented with each <codeph>section</codeph>, that
      is a direct child of a <codeph>book</codeph> or an <codeph>article</codeph> element.</p>
        <p>
            <codeblock outputclass="language-css">book &gt; section,
article &gt; section{
    counter-increment:sect;
}   </codeblock>
        </p>
        <p>The "static" text that will prefix the section title is composed of the constant "Section
            ", followed by the decimal value of the <codeph>sect</codeph> counter and a dot.</p>
        <p>
            <codeblock outputclass="language-css">book &gt; section &gt; title:before,
article &gt; section &gt; title:before{
    content: "Section " counter(sect) ". ";
}</codeblock>
        </p>
        <p>To make the documents easy to read, you add a margin to the sections. In this way the
            higher nesting level, the larger the left side indent. The margin is expressed
            relatively to the parent bounds:</p>
        <p>
            <codeblock outputclass="language-css">section{
    margin-left:1em;
    margin-top:1em;
}</codeblock>
        </p>
        <fig>
            <title>A sample of nested sections and their titles.</title>
            <image href="../img/bt_dg_sections.png"/>
        </fig>
        <p>In the above screenshot you can see a sample XML document rendered by the CSS stylesheet.
            The selection "avoids" the text that is generated by the CSS "content" property. This
            happens because the CSS generated text is not present in the XML document and is just a
            visual aid.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
