<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dictionaries-preferences-page">
  <title>Dictionaries Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Dictionaries</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Spell Check</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Dictionaries</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. This page allows you to configure the dictionaries and term lists that <ph
        keyref="product"/> uses and to choose where to save new learned words.<note>A term list must
        have the <filepath>.tdi</filepath> extension.</note></p>
    <p>The following options are available:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Dictionaries and term lists default folder</uicontrol> - specifies the
          default location where the dictionaries and term lists that <ph
            keyref="product"/> uses are stored;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Include dictionaries and term list from</uicontrol> - specifies a location
          where you can store dictionaries and term lists, different from the default one;</li>
      </ul><note>In case the additional location contains a file with the same name as one from the
        default location, the additional file is proffered.</note><note>The spell checker takes into
        account term lists, collected both from the default and additional locations. </note><ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Save learned words in the following location</uicontrol> - specifies the
          target in which new learned words are saved;<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Default</uicontrol> - the default location where the dictionaries and
              term lists are stored;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Custom</uicontrol> - a custom location where you can store dictionaries
              and term lists;</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li id="delete-learned-words"><uicontrol>Delete learned words</uicontrol> - opens the list
          of learned words, allowing you to select the items you want to remove, without deleting
          the dictionaries and term lists.</li>
      </ul><note>These options are valid when <ph
          keyref="product"/> uses the Hunspell spell
        checking engine.</note></p>
  </body>
</topic>
