<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dictionaries-preferences-page">
  <title>Dictionaries Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p>To set the Dictionaries preferences, <ph conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"
      /> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Spell Check</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Dictionaries</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. This page allows you to configure the dictionaries and term lists
        (<filepath>.tdi</filepath> files) that <ph keyref="product"/> uses and to choose where to
      save new learned words.</p>
    <p>The following options are valid when <ph keyref="product"/> uses the Hunspell spell checking engine:<ul>
        <li>
          <uicontrol>Dictionaries and term lists default folder</uicontrol> - Specifies the default
          location where the dictionaries and term lists that <ph keyref="product"/> uses are
          stored. </li>
        <li>
          <uicontrol>Include dictionaries and term list from</uicontrol> - Specifies a location
          where you can store dictionaries and term lists that are different from the default one.
        </li>
      </ul><note>If the additional location contains a file with the same name as one from the
        default location, the additional file takes precedence. The spell checker takes into account
        term lists collected both from the default and custom locations and the dictionaries from
        both are merged.</note><ul>
        <li>
          <uicontrol>Save learned words in the following location</uicontrol> - Specifies the target
          where the newly learned words are saved. By default, the target is the application
          preferences folder, but you can also choose a custom location.</li>
        <li id="delete-learned-words">
          <uicontrol>Delete learned words</uicontrol> - Opens the list of learned words, allowing
          you to select the items you want to remove, without deleting the dictionaries and term
          lists. </li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
