<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="diff-view">
    <title>Compare View</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Compare
        view</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
      <p>In the <ph keyref="product"/> there are three types of files that can be checked for
      differences: text files, image files and binary files. For the text files and image files you
      can use the built-in <uicontrol>Compare view</uicontrol>. <fig>
        <title>Compare View</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_svn_compare_view.png"/>
      </fig></p>
        <p>At the top of each of the two editors, there are presented the name of the opened file,
            the corresponding SVN revision number (for remote resources) and the author who
            committed the associated revision.</p>
        <p>When comparing text, the differences are computed using a <i>line differencing
                algorithm</i>. The view can be used to show the differences between two files in the
            following cases: <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>after obtaining the outgoing status of a file with a
                            <uicontrol>Refresh</uicontrol> operation, the view can be used to show
                        the differences between your working file and the pristine copy. In this way
                        you can find out what changes you will be committing;</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>after obtaining the incoming and outgoing status of the file with the
                            <uicontrol>Synchronize</uicontrol> operation, you can examine the exact
                        differences between your local file and the <i>HEAD</i> revision file;</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>you can use the <uicontrol>Compare view</uicontrol> from the
                            <uicontrol>History view</uicontrol> to compare the local file and a
                        selected revision or compare two revisions of the same file.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>The Compare view contains two editors. Edits are allowed only in the left editor
            and only when it contains the working copy file. To learn more about how the view can be
            used in the day by day work see <xref href="view-diffs.dita">View
            differences</xref>.</p>
    </body>
</topic>