<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="overview">
  <title>Overview</title>
  <body>
    <p>Digital signatures are widely used as security tokens, not just in XML. A digital signature
      provides a mechanism for assuring integrity of data, the authentication of its signer, and the
      non-repudiation of the entire signature to an external party:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>A digital signature must provide a way to verify that the data has not been modified or
        replaced to ensure integrity.</li>
      <li>The signature must provide a way to establish the identity of the data's signer for
        authentication.</li>
      <li>The signature must provide the ability for the data's integrity and authentication to be
        provable to a third party for non-repudiation.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>A public key system is used to create the digital signature and it's also used for
      verification. The signature binds the signer to the document because digitally signing a
      document requires the originator to create a hash of the message and then encrypt that hash
      value with his own private key. Only the originator has that private key and he is the only
      one that can encrypt the hash so that it can be unencrypted using his public key. The
      recipient, upon receiving both the message and the encrypted hash value, can decrypt the hash
      value, knowing the originator's public key. The recipient must also try to generate the hash
      value of the message and compare the newly generated hash value with the unencrypted hash
      value received from the originator. If the hash values are identical, it proves that the
      originator created the message, because only the actual originator could encrypt the hash
      value correctly.</p>
    <p>XML Signatures can be applied to any digital content (data object), including XML (see W3C
      Recommendation, <xref href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmldsig-core/" scope="external" format="html"
        >XML-Signature Syntax and Processing</xref> ). An XML Signature may be applied to the
      content of one or more resources:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>enveloped or enveloping signatures are applied over data within the same XML document as
        the signature</li>
      <li>detached signatures are applied over data external to the signature element; the signature
        is "detached" from the content it signs. This definition typically applies to separate data
        objects, but it also includes the instance where the signature and data object reside within
        the same XML document but are sibling elements.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The XML Signature is a method of associating a key with referenced data. It does not
      normatively specify how keys are associated with persons or institutions, nor the meaning of
      the data being referenced and signed.</p>
    <p>The original data is not actually signed. Instead, the signature is applied to the output of
      a chain of canonicalization and transformation algorithms, which are applied to the data in a
      designated sequence. This system provides the flexibility to accommodate whatever
      "normalization" or desired preprocessing of the data that might be required or desired before
      subjecting it to being signed.</p>
    <p>To canonicalize something means to put it in a standard format that everyone generally uses.
      Because the signature is dependent on the content it is signing, a signature produced from a
      not canonicalized document could possibly be different from one produced from a canonicalized
      document. The canonical form of an XML document is physical representation of the document
      produced by the method described in this specification. The term canonical XML refers to XML
      that is in canonical form. The XML canonicalization method is the algorithm defined by this
      specification that generates the canonical form of a given XML document or document subset.
      The term XML canonicalization refers to the process of applying the XML canonicalization
      method to an XML document or document subset. XML canonicalization is designed to be useful to
      applications that require the ability to test whether the information content of a document or
      document subset has been changed. This is done by comparing the canonical form of the original
      document before application processing with the canonical form of the document result of the
      application processing.</p>
    <p>A digital signature over the canonical form of an XML document or document subset would
      allows the signature digest calculations to be oblivious to changes in the original document's
      physical representation. During signature generation, the digest is computed over the
      canonical form of the document. The document is then transferred to the relying party, which
      validates the signature by reading the document and computing a digest of the canonical form
      of the received document. The equivalence of the digests computed by the signing and relying
      parties (and hence the equivalence of the canonical forms over which they were computed)
      ensures that the information content of the document has not been altered since it was
      signed.</p>
    <p>The following canonicalization algorithms are used in <ph
        keyref="product"/>: Canonical XML (or Inclusive XML
        Canonicalization)(<xref href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2001/REC-xml-c14n-20010315"
        scope="external" format="html">XMLC14N</xref>) and Exclusive XML Canonicalization(<xref
        href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2002/REC-xml-exc-c14n-20020718/" scope="external" format="html"
        >EXCC14N</xref>). The first is used for XML where the context doesn't change while the
      second was designed for canonicalization where the context might change.</p>
    <p>Inclusive Canonicalization copies all the declarations, even if they are defined outside of
      the scope of the signature. In this way all the declarations you might use will be
      unambiguously specified. A problem appears when the signed XML is moved into another XML
      document which has other declarations because the Inclusive Canonicalization will copy then
      and the signature will be invalid.</p>
    <p>Exclusive Canonicalization finds out what namespaces you are actually using (the ones that
      are a part of the XML syntax) and just copies those. It does not look into attribute values or
      element content, so the namespace declarations required to process these are not copied.</p>
    <p>This type of canonicalization is useful when you have a signed XML document that you wish to
      insert into other XML documents and it will insure the signature verifies correctly every
      time, so it is required when you need self-signed structures that support placement within
      different XML contexts.</p>
    <p>Inclusive Canonicalization is useful when it is less likely that the signed data will be
      inserted in other XML document and it's the safer method from the security perspective because
      it requires no knowledge of the data that are to be secured in order to safely sign them.</p>
    <p>The canonicalization method can specify whether or not comments should be included in the
      canonical form output by the XML canonicalization method. If a canonical form contains
      comments corresponding to the comment nodes in the input node-set, the result is called
      canonical XML with comments. In an uncommented canonical form comments are removed, including
      delimiter for comments outside document element.</p>
    <p>These three operations: Digital Signing, Canonicalization and Verification of the signature
      are available from the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu or from the Editor's <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>contextual menu</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
