<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-search-rename-ids">
  <title>Search and Rename Actions for IDs in DITA</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to search references to ID attributes (either direct
      references using the <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> and <xmlatt>conref</xmlatt> attributes or indirect
      references using <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt> attributes) or to
      rename the id attribute in all the declared and referenced locations. The main benefit of this
      feature is the fact that it allows you to rename <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attributes (or search for
      their references) in the scope of the entire project. It also works for IDs defined inside
      DITA maps and then referenced in maps and topics.</p>
    <p>In <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, these operations are available for DITA documents in
      the contextual menu (grouped in the <uicontrol>Manage IDs</uicontrol> submenu). In
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, these actions are also available in the <uicontrol>Quick
        Assist</uicontrol> menu. To access it, place the cursor inside the value of an
        <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute and click the yellow light bulb icon.</p>
    <p>The possible actions include:<dl>
        <dlentry id="rename-in">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RenameXSLResource16.png" id="image_frs_xck_cs"/>Rename
              in</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Renames the ID and all of its occurrences. Selecting this action opens a dialog box
            where you insert the new ID value and choose the scope of the rename operation. For a
            preview of the changes you are about to make, click <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol>. This
            opens the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> dialog box, which presents a list with the
            files that contain changes and a preview zone of these changes.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="rename-in-file">
          <dt><uicontrol>Rename in File</uicontrol> (Available in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
            mode only)</dt>
          <dd>Renames the ID you are editing and all its occurrences in the current file. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="search-references">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SearchReferences16.png" id="image_ikc_wck_cs"/>Search
              References</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches for the references of the ID. By default, the scope of this action is the
            current project.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Search References in</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches for the references of the ID and you can choose the scope of the operation or
            configure working sets to use for the scope.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="search-declaration">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SearchDeclarations16.png" id="image_pwt_vck_cs"/>Search
              Declarations</uicontrol> (Available in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode only)</dt>
          <dd>Searches for the declaration of the ID reference. By default, the scope of this action
            is the current project.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Search Declarations in</uicontrol> (Available in the
              <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode only)</dt>
          <dd>Searches for the declaration of the ID reference and you can choose the scope of the
            operation or configure working sets to use for the scope.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="search-occurrences">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/OccurrencesInFile16.png" id="image_qtm_5ck_cs"/>Search
              Occurrences in file</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches for the declaration and references of the ID in the current document and
            presents the results in the message panel at the bottom of the application.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ConfigureSearchScope16.png" id="image_cd4_pck_cs"
              />Change scope</uicontrol> (Available in the <uicontrol>Quick Assist</uicontrol> menu
            in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode only)</dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box where you can choose the scope of the operation or configure
            working sets to use for the scope.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <note type="tip">A quick way to go to the declaration of an ID in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
      mode is to move the cursor over an ID reference and use the <uicontrol
        conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_click"/> navigation.</note>
    <p>Selecting an ID that you use for search or refactor operations differs between the
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> modes. In the
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, you position the cursor inside the declaration or
      reference of an ID. In the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, <ph keyref="product"/> collects
      all the IDs by analyzing each element from the path to the root. If more IDs are available,
      you are prompted to choose one of them.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="dita-master-files.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
