<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-ot-customization">
  <title>Customizing DITA Transformations</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Output<indexterm>Customizing
          Transformations</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Customizing DITA transformations</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can customize the appearance of any of the output types by customizing the output
      transformations. There are several ways to do this:<ul id="ul_ftq_nmt_vp">
        <li>Most transformations are configurable by passing parameters to the transformation
          script. <ph keyref="product"/> allows you to <xref
            href="dita-map-edit-parameters.dita#dita-map-edit-parameters">set parameters</xref> on a
          transformation scenario and you can <xref
            href="transformation-scenarios-sharing.dita#transformation-scenarios-sharing">save and
            share them with others</xref>. You can also use the <xref
            href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables/edVar-ask"><b>${ask}</b> editor
            variable</xref> in the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab to instruct <ph
            keyref="product"/> to prompt you for a particular parameter whenever a transformation
          scenario is run. You can set up multiple transformation scenarios for a given output type,
          allowing you to maintain several customized transformation scenarios for multiple types of
          output configurations.</li>
        <li>If you want to customize an output in a way not supported by the built-in customization
          options, you can create a modified version of the transformation code and execute it <xref
            href="dita-map-use-your-own-build-file.dita#dita-map-use-your-own-build-file">using a
            custom build file</xref>. Sometimes the transformation code exports specific forms of
          extensions or customizations. You should consult the DITA Open Toolkit for the
          transformation type that you are interested in to see what customization options are
          supported. <ph product="editor editorEclipse"><ph keyref="product"/> provides full editing
            and <xref href="debugging.dita#debugging">debugging support from XSLT and CSS
              stylesheets</xref>, which you can use to modify transformation code.</ph></li>
        <li>You can also write your own transformation code (and execute it <xref
            href="dita-map-use-your-own-build-file.dita#dita-map-use-your-own-build-file">using a
            custom build file</xref>) to produce a type of output not supported by the DITA Open
          Toolkit. <ph product="editor editorEclipse"><ph keyref="product"/> provides a full source
            editing environment for developing such transformations. </ph>You can create <ph
            keyref="product"/> transformation scenarios to run these scripts once they are
          complete.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>There are also many other ways to customize specific types of output generated from DITA transformations:<ul>
        <li><b>WebHelp</b> - For information about customizing WebHelp output, see the <xref
            href="wh_webhelp_output.dita#wh_webhelp_output">WebHelp Output section</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>PDF</b> - For information about customizing PDF output generated from DITA content,
          see <xref href="dita-pdf-output.dita#dita-pdf-output"/>.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="dita-map-transform.dita"/><link format="html" href="http://www.dita-ot.org/" scope="external">
      <linktext>DITA Open Toolkit Documentation</linktext>
    </link></linklist>
    
  </related-links>
</topic>