<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-ot-external-refs">
  <title>Topic References Outside the Main DITA Map Folder</title>
  <body>
    <section id="problem">
      <title>Problem</title>
      <p>Referencing a DITA topic, <term>map</term>, or binary resource (for example, image) that is
        located outside of the folder where the main <xref keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA
            map</term></xref> is located leads to problems when publishing the content using the
        DITA Open Toolkit.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="solution">
      <title>Solution</title>
      <p>The DITA-OT does not handle it well when references are outside the directory where the
        published <term>DITA map</term> is found. By default, it does not even copy the referenced
        topics to the output directory. </p>
      <p>To solve this, choose one of the following options:<ul id="ol_mkn_r34_l3">
          <li>Create another <term>DITA map</term> that is located in a folder path above all
            referenced folders and reference from it the original <term>DITA map</term>. Then
            transform this <term>DITA map</term> instead.</li>
          <li>Edit the transformation scenario and in the <b>Parameters</b> tab edit the
              <uicontrol>fix.external.refs.com.oxygenxml</uicontrol> parameter. This parameter is
            used to specify whether or not the application tries to fix such references in a
            temporary files folder before the DITA Open Toolkit is invoked on the fixed references.
            The fix has no impact on your edited DITA content. The allowed values are
              <codeph>false</codeph> and <codeph>true</codeph>. The default value is
              <codeph>false</codeph>.<note type="important">The
                <uicontrol>fix.external.refs.com.oxygenxml</uicontrol> parameter is only supported
              when the DITA OT transformation process is started from <ph keyref="product"
            />.</note></li>
          <li>For PDF output, you can edit the transformation scenario and in the <b>Parameters</b>
            tab set the value of the <uicontrol>generate.copy.outer</uicontrol> parameter to
              <codeph>3</codeph>. This parameter specifies whether to generate output files for
            content that is not located in or beneath the directory containing the DITA map file. By
            setting the value of this parameter to <codeph>3</codeph>, the transformation scenario
            shifts the output directory so that it contains all output for the publication.<note
              type="important">This method is recommended for transformation scenarios that use an
              external DITA-OT.</note></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
