<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ditamap-pdf-css-html5">
  <title>DITA Map to PDF - based on HTML5 and CSS Transformation</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Transformation Scenarios<indexterm>DITA Map to PDF CSS
          HTML5</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA Map to PDF CSS HTML5 transformation</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>
      <ph keyref="product"/> includes a built-in <b>DITA Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS </b>
      transformation scenario based on a <i>DITA-OT CSS-based PDF Publishing plugin</i> that convert
      DITA maps to PDF using a CSS-based processing engine and a HTML5 intermediate format. <ph
        keyref="product"/> comes bundled with a built-in CSS-based PDF processing engine called
        <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b>. <ph keyref="product"/> also supports a few third-party
      processors. </p>
    <p>For those who are familiar with CSS, this makes it very easy to style and customize the PDF
      output of your DITA projects without having to work with <i>xsl:fo</i> customizations. This
      transformation also includes some built-in publishing templates that you can use for the
      layout of your PDF output and you can create your own templates or edit existing ones.</p>
    <p>The following CSS-based PDF processors can be used:<ul id="ul_rhb_myq_vs">
        <li><b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b> - A built-in processor that is bundled with <ph
            keyref="product"/>. For more information, see the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-chemistry/" format="html" scope="external">Oxygen
            PDF Chemistry User Guide</xref>. This is the supported processor. </li>
        <li><b>Prince Print with CSS</b> (not included in the <ph keyref="product"/> installation
          kit) - A third-party component that needs to be purchased from <xref
            href="http://www.princexml.com/" format="html" scope="external"
            >http://www.princexml.com</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>Antenna House Formatter</b> (not included in the <ph keyref="product"/> installation
          kit) - A third-party component that needs to be purchased from <xref
            href="http://www.antennahouse.com/antenna1/formatter/" format="html" scope="external"
          />.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="creating_the_transformation_scenario">
      <title>How to Create the Transformation Scenario</title>
      <p>To create an <b>DITA Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS </b> transformation scenario,
        follow these steps:<ol id="ol_z3j_gxq_vr">
          <li>Click the <uicontrol><image id="image_d3c_lxq_vr" href="../img/TransformConfig16.png"
              />Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button<ph
              product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> from the <xref
                href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
                  Manager</uicontrol></xref> toolbar</ph>.</li>
          <li>Select <b>DITA Map PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS </b>.</li>
          <li>If you want to configure the transformation, click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
                button.<p><b>Step Result:</b> This opens an <uicontrol>Edit scenario</uicontrol>
              configuration dialog box that allows you to configure various options in the following tabs:<ul>
                <li><xref href="templates-tab-whr.dita#templates-tab-whr"
                      ><uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> Tab</xref> - This tab contains a set of
                  built-in publishing templates that you can use for the layout of your WebHelp
                  system output. You can also create your own publishing templates by saving one
                  from the gallery and changing it.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>CSS Processor</uicontrol> Tab - This is where you choose the
                  processor type. You can select between <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b>, <b>Prince
                    XML</b>, or <b>Antenna House</b>.</li>
                <li><xref href="dita-map-edit-parameters.dita#dita-map-edit-parameters"
                      ><uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> Tab</xref> - This tab includes numerous
                  parameters that can be set to customize your WebHelp system output.</li>
                <li><xref href="dita-map-edit-filters.dita#dita-map-edit-filters"
                      ><uicontrol>Filters</uicontrol> Tab</xref> - This tab allows you to filter
                  certain content elements from the generated output.</li>
                <li><xref href="dita-map-edit-advanced.dita#dita-map-edit-advanced"
                      ><uicontrol>Advanced</uicontrol> Tab</xref> - This tab allows you to specify
                  some advanced options for the transformation scenario.</li>
                <li><xref href="dita-map-edit-output.dita#dita-map-edit-output"
                      ><uicontrol>Output</uicontrol> Tab</xref> - This tab allows you to configure
                  options that are related to the location where the output is generated.</li>
              </ul></p></li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab, configure any of the following
            parameters (if applicable):<ul id="ul_uqz_txq_vr">
              <li><b>args.css</b> - Specifies a path to a custom CSS to be used in addition to those
                specified in the publishing template<ph
                  product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">. The files must have URL
                  syntax and be separated using semicolons. Also, the <codeph>dita.css.list</codeph>
                  parameter must be left empty to use these files in addition to the selection in
                  the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down menu</ph>.</li>
              <li><b>css.processor.path.chemistry</b> (if you are using the <b>Oxygen PDF
                  Chemistry</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b>
                executable file that will be run to generate the PDF. If this parameter is not set,
                your system's PATH environment variable will be used to find and start the <b>Oxygen
                  PDF Chemistry</b> processor.</li>
              <li><b>css.processor.path.prince</b> (if you are using the <b>Prince Print with
                  CSS</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the Prince executable file that will be
                run to produce the PDF. If you installed Prince using its default settings, you can
                leave this blank.</li>
              <li><b>css.processor.path.antenna-house</b> (if you are using the <b>Antenna House
                  Formatter</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the Antenna House executable file
                that will be run to produce the PDF. If you installed Antenna House using its
                default settings, you can leave this blank.</li>
              <li><b>show.changes.and.comments</b> - When set to <codeph>yes</codeph>, user
                comments, replies to comments, and <term>tracked changes</term> are published in the
                PDF output. The default value is <codeph>no</codeph>.</li>
              <li><b>figure.title.placement</b> - Controls the position of the figure title relative
                to the image. Allowed values are "top" and "bottom", "top" is the default</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> and run the transformation scenario.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="customizing_css_styles_using_oxygen_pdf_chemistry">
      <title>Customizing the Output</title>
      <p>For more information, see the <xref href="pdf-css-html5-output.dita"/>. </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="edit-scenario-dialog.dita#edit-scenario-dialog"/>
      <link href="configure-transformation-dialog.dita#configure-transformation-dialog"/>
      <link format="html" href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-chemistry/" scope="external">
        <linktext>Oxygen PDF Chemistry User Guide</linktext>
      </link>
      <link href="pdf-css-html5-output.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
