<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-map-transform">
  <title>Publishing DITA Output</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Output</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Publishing</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>As a structured writing format, DITA produces structured content (content that is annotated
      with specific structural and semantic information rather than with formatting information). To
      create a publication, your <xref keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref> and
      its associated topics must be processed by a transformation script. That script is responsible
      for how the structural and semantic information in the DITA files is converted into formatting
      information for display.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> publishes DITA content to various output sources using a bundled
      version of the <xref href="https://www.dita-ot.org/" format="html" scope="external">DITA Open
        Toolkit</xref>. The DITA OT is an open-source publishing engine that can publish DITA
      content to various output sources such as <b>XHTML</b>, <b>PDF</b>, or <b>Windows Help
        (CHM)</b>. Since it has a plugin-based architecture, it can be extended with extra plugins
      that either define new formats for conversion or customize an existing conversion format. You
      can run the DITA-OT from <ph keyref="product"/> using a transformation scenario or you can run
      it directly from a command line: <xref
        href="http://www.dita-ot.org/dev/topics/building-output.html" format="html" scope="external"
      />.</p>
    <p>The DITA-OT that comes bundled with <ph keyref="product"/> contains more plugins than the
      standard DITA-OT that can be downloaded from their official web site. For example, it contains
      pre-installed plugins for converting DITA content to Word, EPUB, WebHelp, or to publish to PDF
      using CSS to customize the output: <xref
        href="http://blog.oxygenxml.com/2017/03/useful-dita-ot-plugins.html" format="html"
        scope="external"/>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
