<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ditamap-pdf-css">
  <title>DITA Map to PDF WYSIWYG Transformation</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Transformation Scenarios<indexterm>DITA Map to PDF
          WYSIWYG</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA Map to PDF WYSIWYG transformation</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Chemistry processor</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Prince Print with CSS processor</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Antenna House Formatter processor</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> comes bundled with a DITA OT plugin that allows you to convert <xref
        keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA maps</term></xref> to PDF using a CSS layout
      processor. <ph keyref="product"/> also comes bundled with a built-in CSS-based PDF processing
      engine called <b>Chemistry</b>. For those who are familiar with CSS, this makes it very easy
      to style and customize the PDF output of your DITA projects without having to work with
        <i>xsl:fo</i> customizations.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> supports the following processors (not included in the <ph
        keyref="product"/> installation kit):<ul id="ul_rhb_myq_vs">
        <li><b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b> - A built-in processor that is bundled with <ph
            keyref="product"/>. For more information, see the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-chemistry/" format="html" scope="external">Oxygen
            PDF Chemistry User Guide</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>Prince Print with CSS</b> - A third-party component that needs to be purchased from
            <xref href="http://www.princexml.com/" format="html" scope="external"
            >http://www.princexml.com</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>Antenna House Formatter</b> - A third-party component that needs to be purchased from
            <xref href="http://www.antennahouse.com/antenna1/formatter/" format="html"
            scope="external"/>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The DITA-OT plugin is located in the following directory: <filepath><term
          keyref="glossentry_dita_ot_dir"/>/plugins/com.oxygenxml.pdf.css</filepath>. </p>
    <p>Although it includes a set of CSS files in its <filepath>css</filepath> subfolder, when this
      plugin is used in <ph keyref="product"/>, the CSS files located in the
        <filepath>${frameworks}</filepath> directory take precedence.</p>
    <section id="creating_the_transformation_scenario">
      <title>Creating the Transformation Scenario</title>
      <p>To create an <b>DITA Map to PDF WYSIWYG</b> transformation scenario, follow these steps:<ol
          id="ol_z3j_gxq_vr">
          <li>Click the <uicontrol><image id="image_d3c_lxq_vr" href="../img/TransformConfig16.png"
              />Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button<ph
              product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> from the <xref
                href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
                  Manager</uicontrol></xref> toolbar</ph>.</li>
          <li>Select <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - WYSIWYG</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>CSS Processor</uicontrol> tab, choose the processor type. You can
            select between <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b>, <b>Prince XML</b>, or <b>Antenna
            House</b>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab, configure any of the following
            parameters (if applicable):<ul id="ul_uqz_txq_vr">
              <li><b>css.processor.path.chemistry</b> (if you are using the <b>Oxygen PDF
                  Chemistry</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b>
                executable file that will be run to generate the PDF. If this parameter is not set,
                your system's PATH environment variable will be used to find and start the <b>Oxygen
                  PDF Chemistry</b> processor.</li>
              <li><b>css.processor.path.prince</b> (if you are using the <b>Prince Print with
                  CSS</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the Prince executable file that will be
                run to produce the PDF. If you installed Prince using its default settings, you can
                leave this blank.</li>
              <li><b>css.processor.path.antenna-house</b> (if you are using the <b>Antenna House
                  Formatter</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the Antenna House executable file
                that will be run to produce the PDF. If you installed Antenna House using its
                default settings, you can leave this blank.</li>
              <li><b>show.changes.and.comments</b> - When set to <codeph>yes</codeph>, user
                comments, replies to comments, and <term>tracked changes</term> are published in the
                PDF output. The default value is <codeph>no</codeph>.</li>
              <li><b>dita.css.list</b> - Allows you to specify a list of CSS URLs to be used by the
                PDF processor (instead of the default CSS files). The files must have URL syntax and
                be separated using semicolons.<ph
                  product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> If the value is empty, the
                  CSS associated with the current selection from the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol>
                  drop-down menu is used.</ph></li>
              <li><b>args.css</b> - Allows you to specify a list of CSS URLs to be used in addition
                to those specified in the <codeph>dita.css.list</codeph> parameter<ph
                  product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> OR in addition to the CSS
                  that is currently selected in the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down menu.
                  The files must have URL syntax and be separated using semicolons. Also, the
                    <codeph>dita.css.list</codeph> parameter must be left empty to use these files
                  in addition to the selection in the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down
                  menu</ph>.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> and run the transformation scenario.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="customizing_the_styles_for_output_and_editing">
      <title>Customizing the Styles (for Output and Editing)</title>
      <p>If you need to change the styles in the associated CSS, make sure you install <ph
          keyref="product"/> in a folder where you have full read and write privileges (for
        instance, your user home directory). This is due to the fact that the installed files are
        usually placed in a read-only folder (for instance, in Windows, <ph keyref="product"/> is
        installed in the <filepath>Program Files</filepath> folder where the users do not have
        change rights).</p>
      <?oxy_insert_start author="radu_pisoi" timestamp="20160818T153408+0300"?>
      <p><?oxy_insert_end?>To change the styles of an element you need to create an additional CSS
        file that will store the customization rules. Once you have created this file, you need to
        instruct the editor how to use this additional CSS.<ph
          product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> This can be done in two
        ways:</ph></p>
      <ul id="ol_smb_pqr_zw">
        <li product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">Create an alternate CSS for the DITA
          document type:<ol>
            <li>Follow the procedure for adding an alternate CSS file in <xref
                href="dg-customize-default-CSS.dita#dg-customize-default-CSS"/>.</li>
            <li>Once you have configured your CSS as an additional layer, you can <xref
                href="selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles.dita#selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles"
                >select it from the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down menu (on the
                toolbar)</xref>.</li>
            <li>Run the <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - WYSIWYG</uicontrol> transformation scenario and
              the customization rules from the additional CSS will be visible in the produced
              PDF.</li>
          </ol><p>This method allows you to have many customization CSS files and simply select the
            one that you need at any time for both the output and rendering
              <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode while editing.</p></li>
        <li>Use the <codeph>args.css</codeph> parameter that allows you to specify a list of CSS
          URLs to be used in addition to the <codeph>dita.css.list</codeph> parameter:<ol>
            <li>Configure a <b>DITA map to PDF WYSIWYG</b> transformation scenario, as described in
              the procedure <xref href="#ditamap-pdf-css/creating_the_transformation_scenario"
                format="dita">above</xref>.</li>
            <li>In the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab, specify the path to your custom CSS
              files in the <codeph>args.css</codeph> parameter.</li>
            <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> and run the transformation scenario.</li>
          </ol><p>This method is appropriate if you just want to apply the styling customization to
            the
          output.</p><?oxy_insert_start author="radu_pisoi" timestamp="20160818T153408+0300"?></li>
      </ul>
      <?oxy_insert_end?>
      <note type="tip">For more information about customizing CSS styles for PDF output, see the
          <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-chemistry/" format="html" scope="external"
          >Oxygen PDF Chemistry User Guide</xref>. It offers numerous tips for customizing CSS
        styles even if you are not using the Chemistry processor.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="using_the_css_inspector_to_see_style_associated_w"
      product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">
      <title>Using the CSS Inspector to See Style Associated with an Element</title>
      <p>To find the styles associated with an element, follow this procedure:<ol>
          <li>Open a document in the editor and select <uicontrol>Inspect Styles</uicontrol> from
            the contextual menu. This opens the <xref
              href="author-css-inspector-view.dita#author-css-inspector-view"><uicontrol>CSS
                Inspector</uicontrol> view</xref> that shows all the CSS rules that apply to the
            selected element.</li>
          <li>Click the particular link for the CSS selector that you need to change and <ph
              keyref="product"/> will open the CSS file and position the cursor at that
            selector.</li>
          <li>After you identify the source of the styles you want to modify, copy the CSS rule in
            your customization CSS file and modify it according to your needs.<p>To see the changes
              in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, press <uicontrol
                conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/f5"/> to reload the document.</p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="how_to_make_remote_resources_appear_in_the_output">
      <title>How to Make Remote Resources Appear in the Output When Using the Prince
        Processor</title>
      <p>If your documentation references external resources (such as images that are stored on a
        Web-based repository) and your system is behind an HTTP(S) proxy, you may find that they do
        not appear in the output when using the <b>Prince Print with CSS</b> processor. To solve
        this, follow this procedure:<ol>
          <li>Edit the <b><filepath>build.xml</filepath></b> file that is located in <filepath><term
                keyref="glossentry_dita_ot_dir"/>/plugins/com.oxygenxml.pdf.css</filepath>.</li>
          <li>There are two instances in the file where a pair of arguments are commented
            out:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">   &lt;!-- Please remove the comment wrapping the following two arguments
   if you are behind a proxy and your documentation refers remote resources,
   for example images. 
      
   Note: You also need to remove the backslash '\' that appears before the 
   property name: "http-proxy". That backslash is there because a sequence of 
   two dashes ('-') is not permited inside a comment.
   -->
   &lt;!--
     &lt;arg value="-\-http-proxy=${http.proxyHost}:${http.proxyPort}"/>
     &lt;arg value="-\-http-proxy=${https.proxyHost}:${https.proxyPort}"/>
   --></codeblock></li>
          <li>Remove the comment in both instances.</li>
          <li>Make sure you also remove the slash that appears before the property name
              <codeph>http-proxy</codeph> in each instance.<p><b>Step Result:</b> The arguments
              should now look like
              this:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">  &lt;arg value="--http-proxy=${http.proxyHost}:${http.proxyPort}"/>
  &lt;arg value="--http-proxy=${https.proxyHost}:${https.proxyPort}"/></codeblock></p></li>
          <li>Save the <b><filepath>build.xml</filepath></b> file.</li>
          <li>Run the <xref href="#ditamap-pdf-css/creating_the_transformation_scenario"
              format="dita"><term>DITA map to PDF WYSIWYG</term> transformation
                scenario</xref>.<p><b>Result:</b> Your external resources should now appear in your
              output.</p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="customizing_css_styles_using_oxygen_pdf_chemistry">
      <title>Customizing CSS Styles Using Oxygen PDF Chemistry</title>
      <p><b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b> makes it very easy to style and customize the PDF output of
        your DITA projects without having to work with <i>xsl:fo</i> customizations. It allows you
        to style the PDF output by simply changing the CSS and then re-running the transformation
        scenario until you get the desired result. </p>
      <p>For more information, see the <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-chemistry/"
          format="html" scope="external">Oxygen PDF Chemistry User Guide</xref>. It also offers
        numerous tips for customizing CSS styles for PDF output even if you are not using the
        Chemistry processor.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="edit-scenario-dialog.dita#edit-scenario-dialog"/>
      <link href="configure-transformation-dialog.dita#configure-transformation-dialog"/>
      <link
        href="selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles.dita#selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles"
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"/>
      <link href="author-css-inspector-view.dita#author-css-inspector-view"
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"/>
      <link format="html" href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-chemistry/" scope="external">
        <linktext>Oxygen PDF Chemistry User Guide</linktext>
      </link>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
