<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-transformation-skins-tab">
  <title>Skins Tab (DITA OT Transformations)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA OT transformation scenario<indexterm>Skins tab</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/intro-for-transformation-tabs"/></p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Skins</uicontrol> tab is available for DITA OT transformations with
        <uicontrol>WebHelp Classic</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>WebHelp Classic with
        Feedback</uicontrol> output types and it provides a set of predefined skins that you can use
      as a base for your WebHelp system output. </p>
    <p>A <i>skin</i> is a collection of CSS properties that can alter the look of the output
      by changing colors, font types, borders, margins, and paddings. This allows you to rapidly
      adapt the look and feel of your output.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_cdx_hpj_14">
        <title>Skins Tab</title>
        <image href="../img/dita_transf_skins_tab.png" id="image_r5k_gpj_14"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Skins</uicontrol> tab includes the following sections:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><i>Predefined Skins</i></dt>
          <dd>This sections presents the predefined skins that are included in <ph keyref="product"
            />. The predefined skins cover a wide range of chromatic themes, ranging from a very
            light one to a high-contrast variant. To see how the <i>skin</i> looks when
            applied on a sample documentation project that is stored on the <ph keyref="product"/>
            website, press the <uicontrol>Online preview</uicontrol> link.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><i>Custom Skins</i></dt>
          <dd>You can use this section to customize the look of the output.<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>CSS File</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>You can set this field to point to a custom CSS stylesheet or customized skin.
                    A custom CSS file will overwrite a skin selection.<note>The output can also be
                      styled by setting the <codeph>args.csspath</codeph> parameter in the
                        <uicontrol>Parameters tab</uicontrol>. The properties taken from the
                      stylesheet referenced in this parameter take precedence over the properties
                      declared in the skin set in the <uicontrol>Skins tab</uicontrol>.</note></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Create custom skin</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Use this link to open the <xref
                      href="webhelp_skin_builder.dita#webhelp_skin_builder"><uicontrol>WebHelp Skin
                        Builder</uicontrol></xref> tool.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
