<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-ot-customization">
  <title>Customizing DITA Transformations</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Output<indexterm>Customizing
          Transformations</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>
      <ph keyref="product"/> includes a bundled copy of the DITA-OT as an <ph keyref="product"/>
      <xref keyref="customize_frameworks">framework</xref>. That <xref keyref="glossentry_framework"
          ><term>framework</term></xref> includes a number of transformation scenarios for common
      output formats. This section includes topics about customizing DITA transformations, such as
      using a custom build file, customizing PDF output, and using DITA OT <xref
        keyref="glossentry_plugin"><term>plugins</term></xref> to customize your needs.</p>
    <section id="customizing_output_transformations">
      <title>Customizing Output Transformations</title>
      <p>You can customize the appearance of any of the output types by customizing the output
        transformations. There are several ways to do this:</p>
      <ul id="ul_ftq_nmt_vp">
        <li>Most transformations are configurable by passing parameters to the transformation
          script. <ph keyref="product"/> allows you to <xref
            href="dita-map-edit-parameters.dita#dita-map-edit-parameters">set parameters</xref> on a
          transformation scenario and you can <xref
            href="transformation-scenarios-sharing.dita#transformation-scenarios-sharing">save and
            share them with others</xref>. You can also use the <xref
            href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables/edVar-ask"><varname>${ask}</varname> editor
            variable</xref> in the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab to instruct <ph
            keyref="product"/> to prompt you for a particular parameter whenever a transformation
          scenario is run. You can set up multiple transformation scenarios for a given output type,
          allowing you to maintain several customized transformation scenarios for multiple types of
          output configurations.</li>
        <li>If you want to customize an output in a way not supported by the customization options,
          you can create a modified version of the transformation code. Some transformation scripts
          export specific forms of extension or customization. You should consult the DITA Open
          Toolkit for the transformation type that you are interested in to see what customization
          options it supports. <ph product="editor editorEclipse"><ph keyref="product"/> provides
            full editing and <xref href="debugging.dita#debugging">debugging support from XSLT and
              CSS stylesheets</xref>, which you can use to modify transformation code.</ph>
        </li>
      </ul>
      <p>You can also write your own output transformation scripts to produce a type of output not
        supported by the DITA Open Toolkit. <ph product="editor editorEclipse"><ph keyref="product"
          /> provides a full source editing environment for developing such transformations.
        </ph>You can create <ph keyref="product"/> transformation scenarios to run these scripts
        once they are complete.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="dita-map-transform.dita"/><link format="html" href="http://www.dita-ot.org/" scope="external">
      <linktext>DITA Open Toolkit Documentation</linktext>
    </link></linklist>
    
  </related-links>
</topic>