<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-prolog-updater">
  <title>DITA Prolog Updater Add-on</title>
  <prolog>
    <author type="contributor">steven_higgs</author>
    <critdates>
      <!--steven_higgs-->
      <revised modified="2018/12/14"/>
    </critdates>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Add-ons<indexterm>DITA prolog updater</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA prolog updater add-on</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> offers an add-on that contributes a preferences page (<menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>DITA Prolog Updater</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>) that includes various options for updating the <i>prolog</i> section of a DITA
      topic or map.</p>
    <section id="installing_the_addon">
      <title>Installing the Add-on</title>
      <p>To install it the add-on, follow these instructions:<ol>
          <li>Go to <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Install new add-ons</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> to open an add-on selection dialog box.</li>
          <li>Enter or paste <b>https://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Addons/default/updateSite.xml</b>
            in the <uicontrol>Show add-ons from</uicontrol> field or select it from the drop-down
            menu.</li>
          <li>Select the <b>DITA Prolog Updater</b> add-on and click
            <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Select the <b>I accept all terms of the end user license agreement</b> option and
            click <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Restart the application.</li>
        </ol></p>
      <p><b>Result:</b> The <b>DITA Prolog Updater</b> preferences page will now be available in <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="dita_prolog_updater_preferences_page">
      <title>DITA Prolog Updater Preferences Page</title>
      <p>The contributed preferences page includes the following general options:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><b>Author</b></dt>
            <dd>Specifies the name of the author. By default, it is the system user name.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Date format</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Specifies the format of the date that will be added in the prolog section. If the
              date format entered is invalid, the <i>yyy/MM/dd</i> format is used by default.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
      <p>These options are followed by the following options that can be set for DITA topics or maps
        (or both):<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><b>Enable automatic prolog update on save</b></dt>
            <dd>When this option is selected, the prolog is updated anytime the document is
              saved.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><b>Set creator name</b></dt>
            <dd>When this option is selected, the author is set as the document's <i>creator</i> in
              the prolog when the document is saved. This option is only applicable for new
              documents.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><b>Set created date</b></dt>
            <dd>When this option is selected, a <i>created date</i> is added to the prolog when the
              document is saved. This option is only applicable for new documents.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><b>Update contributor names</b></dt>
            <dd>When this option is selected, the author is set as a <i>contributor</i> in the
              prolog when the document is saved. This option is only applicable for already existing
              documents.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><b>Update revised dates</b></dt>
            <dd>When this option is selected, a <i>revised date</i> is added to the prolog when the
              document is saved. This option is only applicable for already existing documents.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
    <p>For more information, see the <xref
        href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/oxygen-dita-prolog-updater" format="html"
        scope="external">details for this <b>DITA Prolog Updater</b> add-on in GitHub</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
