<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ditamap-pdf-css">
  <title>DITA Map to PDF WYSIWYG Transformation</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Transformation Scenarios<indexterm>DITA Map to PDF
          WYSIWYG</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA Map to PDF WYSIWYG transformation</indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Output<indexterm>DITA Map to PDF WYSIWYG
              transformation</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Prince Print with CSS processor</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Antenna House Formatter processor</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> comes bundled with a DITA OT plugin that converts DITA maps to PDF
      using a CSS layout processor. <ph keyref="product"/> supports the following processors (not
      included in the <ph keyref="product"/> installation kit):<ul id="ul_rhb_myq_vs">
        <li><b>Prince Print with CSS</b> - A third-party component that needs to be purchased from
            <xref href="http://www.princexml.com/" format="html" scope="external"
            >http://www.princexml.com</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>Antenna House Formatter</b> - A third-party component that needs to be purchased from
            <xref href="http://www.antennahouse.com/antenna1/formatter/" format="html"
            scope="external"/>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The DITA-OT plugin is located in the following directory: <filepath><term keyref="glossentry_dita_ot_dir"/>/plugins/com.oxygenxml.pdf.css</filepath>. </p>
    <p>Although it includes a set of CSS files in its <filepath>css</filepath> subfolder, when this
      plugin is used in <ph keyref="product"/>, the CSS files located in the
        <filepath>${frameworks}</filepath> directory take precedence.</p>
    <section id="creating_the_transformation_scenario">
      <title>Creating the Transformation Scenario</title>
      <p>To create an experimental DITA map to PDF WYSIWYG transformation scenario, follow these
          steps:<ol id="ol_z3j_gxq_vr">
          <li>Click the <uicontrol><image id="image_d3c_lxq_vr" href="../img/TransformConfig16.png"
              />Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> button from the <uicontrol>Dita
              Maps Manager</uicontrol> toolbar.</li>
          <li>Select <uicontrol>DITA Map PDF - WYSIWYG - Experimental</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>When applied, this new transformation scenario uses the currently selected CSS files
            for the opened topic files. These CSS files can be selected from the
              <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down menu from the toolbar.<note type="important"
              >The author could open the map in the editor and change its style, but this is ignored
              in the publishing stage. Since authors usually edit topics instead of the map, <ph
                keyref="product"/> uses the styles selected in the opened topics.</note></li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab, configure the following parameters:<ul
              id="ul_uqz_txq_vr">
              <li><codeph>css.processor.path.prince</codeph> (if you are using the <b>Prince Print
                  with CSS</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the Prince executable file that
                will be run to produce the PDF. If you installed Prince using its default settings,
                you can leave this blank.</li>
              <li><codeph>css.processor.path.antenna-house</codeph> (if you are using the <b>Antenna
                  House Formatter</b> processor) - Specifies the path to the Antenna House
                executable file that will be run to produce the PDF. If you installed Antenna House
                using its default settings, you can leave this blank.</li>
              <li><codeph
                  conref="../reusables/topics/webhelp-output-parameters.dita#webhelp-output-parameters/name_webhelp_show_changes_and_comments"
                /> - <ph
                  conref="../reusables/topics/webhelp-output-parameters.dita#webhelp-output-parameters/def_webhelp_show_changes_and_comments"
                /></li>
            </ul></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="customizing_the_styles_for_output_and_editing">
      <title>Customizing the Styles (for Output and Editing)</title>
      <p>If you need to change the styles in the associated CSS, make sure you install <ph
          keyref="product"/> in a folder in which you have full read and write privileges (for
        instance, your user home directory). This is due to the fact that all the installed files
        are usually read-only (for instance, in Windows, <ph keyref="product"/> is installed in the
          <filepath>Program Files</filepath> folder where the users do not have change rights).</p>
      <p product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">If you want to change the style of an
        element, open a document in the editor and select <uicontrol>Inspect Styles</uicontrol> from
        the contextual menu. <xref href="author-css-inspector-view.dita#author-css-inspector-view"
          >The <uicontrol>CSS Inspector</uicontrol> view</xref> that shows all the CSS rules that
        apply to the selected element will be displayed. Click the link for the CSS selector that
        you need to change and <ph keyref="product"/> will open the CSS file and position the cursor
        at that selector. Simply add the properties you need and to see the changes in the editor,
        press <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable_oxygen_shortcuts_list/f5"/> to reload the document.
        Once you are satisfied with how it looks, use the transformation scenario and check for the
        changes in the PDF output.</p>
      <note>This experimental transformation scenario also allows you to present colored highlights
        in the PDF output.</note>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
