<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-reusing-content">
  <title>Reusing Content</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Reuse</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The DITA framework allows reusing content from other DITA files with a content reference in
      the following ways:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>You can select content in a topic, create a reusable component from it and reference the
        component in other locations using the actions <uicontrol>Create Reusable
          Component</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Insert Reusable Component</uicontrol>. A reusable
        component is a file, usually shorter than a topic. You also have the option of replacing the
        selection with the component that you are in the process of creating. The created reusable
        component file is usually self-contained and it's automatically generated content can be
        fine tuned by modifying the resources located in the folder
          <filepath>OXYGEN_INSTALL_DIR\frameworks\dita\reuse</filepath>.</li>
      <li>You can add, edit, and remove a content reference (<codeph>conref</codeph>) attribute
        to/from an existing element. The actions <uicontrol>Add/Edit Content Reference</uicontrol>
        and <uicontrol>Remove Content Reference</uicontrol> are available on the contextual menu of
        the Author editor and on the DITA menu. When a content reference is added or an existing
        content reference is edited, you can select any topic ID or interval of topic IDs (set also
        the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> field in the dialog for adding/editing the content reference)
        from a target DITA topic file.</li>
      <li>You can insert an element with a content reference (<codeph>conref</codeph> or
          <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> ) attribute using one of the actions <uicontrol>Insert Content
          Reference</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Insert Content Key Reference</uicontrol> that are
        available on the DITA menu, the Author custom actions toolbar and the contextual menu of the
        Author editor.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>DITA makes the distinction between local content, that is the text and graphics that are
      actually present in the element, and referenced content that is referred by the element but is
      located in a different file. You have the option of displaying referenced content by setting
      the option <uicontrol>Display referred content</uicontrol> that is available from menu <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Edit modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
