<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-open-map-resolved-topics">
  <title>Opening a DITA Map With Topic Content Resolved</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA Map document type<indexterm>Open DITA map with content
          resolved</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Open DITA map with content resolved</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>It is possible to open a DITA map in the main editor with all the content from the referenced
      topics resolved and presented in one document. To do this, select the DITA map in the
        <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/OpenMapInEditorResolvedTopics16.png" id="image_irw_qg1_1nb"/>Open Map in
        Editor with Resolved Topics</uicontrol> toolbar button. This opens the <term>DITA map</term>
      in the main editor area with content from all topic references expanded in-place.</p>
    <p>Content from the resolved topics that is referenced using a <xmlatt>conref</xmlatt> or
        <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt> attribute is presented as read-only by default. To edit it, you
      must use the <b>Edit Reference</b> contextual menu action to open the source topic that
      contains the referenced content.</p>
    <section id="section_lv4_fj1_1nb">
      <title>Editing Referenced Content Directly</title>
      <p>If you want to edit the referenced content directly without having to open the source
        document, go to <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Edit Modes</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and select the <xref
          href="preferences-author.dita#preferences-author/allow-referenced-content"
            ><uicontrol>Allow referenced content to be edited (Experimental)</uicontrol>
          option</xref>. The referenced content becomes editable in-place and saving the document
        will save all other modified topics.<note type="other"
          othertype="Things to be Aware of When Enabling This Option">
          <ul id="ul_if1_sj1_1nb">
            <li>The references become editable only if the referenced topics are the root elements.
              If, for example, in the DITA map, there are references directly to subtopics embedded
              in a larger topic, those references will not be editable.</li>
            <li>If the content is stored in a CMS, you need to deselect the <xref
                href="preferences-author.dita#preferences-author/local-files-only"><uicontrol>Local
                  files only</uicontrol> option</xref> to edit such remote referenced topics
              directly but this feature might not function properly with remote resources (it
              depends on the capabilities of the CMS connector).</li>
            <li>Since a single topic may be referenced in multiple places in the DITA map, be careful not to make conflicting changes to that topic.</li>
            <li>When modified topics are saved, the <xref href="preferences-author-serialization.dita#preferences-author-serialization/only-modified-content"><uicontrol>Only modified content</uicontrol> option in the <menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Edit Modes</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Serialization</uicontrol>
                </menucascade> page</xref> is ignored.</li>
            <li>The toolbar has two DITA map-specific actions for inserting topic references and all
              DITA topic-specific actions that can be used to make changes in the referenced DITA
              topics.</li>
            <li>The content completion and schema-aware insertion strategies work in each referenced
              topic according to their respective schema.</li>
            <li>The contextual menu presents the relevant actions in each referenced topic.</li>
            <li>Validation works for each individual referenced topic but only if it contains
              modifications.</li>
          </ul>
        </note></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
