<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-transformation-skins-tab">
  <title>The Skins Tab</title>
  <body>
    <p>A <term>skin</term> is a collection of CSS properties that can alter the look of the output
      by changing colors, font types, borders, margins and paddings. This allows you to rapidly
      adapt the output look and feel to your organization's standard rules.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a set of predefined <term>skins</term> for the
        <uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp with
        Feedback</uicontrol> transformation scenarios.</p>
    <fig id="fig_cdx_hpj_14">
      <title>The Skins Tab</title>
      <image href="../img/dita_transf_skins_tab.png" id="image_r5k_gpj_14"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The predefined skins cover a wide range of chromatic themes, ranging from a very light one to
      a high-contrast variant. By default, the <uicontrol>Oxygen</uicontrol> skin is selected (note
      the light blue border around the skin's preview). If you want to obtain an output without any
      customization, deselect the currently selected skin.</p>
    <p>To see how the <term>skin</term> looks like applied on a documentation sample project stored
      on the <ph keyref="product"/> website, press the <uicontrol>Online preview</uicontrol>
        link.<note>Press the <uicontrol>Create custom skin</uicontrol> link to open the <xref
          href="webhelp_skin_builder.dita#webhelp_skin_builder"><uicontrol>WebHelp Skin
            Builder</uicontrol></xref> tool.</note></p>
    <p>To further customize the look of the output, set the <uicontrol>CSS File</uicontrol> field to
      point to your custom CSS stylesheet or to a customized skin.<note>A custom CSS file will
        overwrite a skin selection.</note><note>The output can also be styled by setting the
          <codeph>args.css</codeph> parameter in the <uicontrol>Parameters tab</uicontrol>. The
        properties taken from the stylesheet referred in this parameter take precedence over the
        properties declared in the skin set in the <uicontrol>Skins tab</uicontrol>.</note></p>
  </body>
</topic>
