<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-maps-editing-actions">
  <title>Editing Actions</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA Maps<indexterm>editing actions</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <note type="important">References can be made either by using the <codeph>href</codeph>
      attribute or by using the new <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute to point to a key defined in
      the map. <ph keyref="product"/> tries to
      resolve both cases. <codeph>keyref</codeph>s are solved relative to the current map.</note>
    <p product="editor author">In additional to being available on the toolbar and on the contextual
      menu, more navigation actions and all edit actions appear in the <uicontrol>DITA
        Maps</uicontrol> menu. The menu is only available when the view is active on screen.</p>
    <p>In addition to the edit actions described above, the contextual menu contains the following
      actions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> - opens in the editor the resources referred by the nodes you
        select;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Append Child/Insert After</uicontrol> - sub-menus containing the following actions:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Reference</uicontrol> - appends/Inserts a topic reference as a
            child/sibling of the selected node;</li>
          <li product="author editor"><uicontrol>Reference to the current edited file</uicontrol> -
            appends/Inserts a topic reference to the current edited file as a child/sibling of the
            selected node;</li>
          <li product="author editor"><uicontrol>New topic</uicontrol> - create a new topic from
            templates, saves it on disk and adds it into the DITA map;</li>
          <li product="authorEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>New topic</uicontrol> - create a new
            topic from templates, saves it on disk and adds it into the DITA map;<note>This action
              is available for the <uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol> action.</note></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Anchor Reference</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Key Definition</uicontrol>,
              <uicontrol>Map Reference</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Topic Reference</uicontrol>,
              <uicontrol>Topic Set</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Topic Set Reference</uicontrol> - allows
            you to insert a reference to a topic file, a map file, a topic set, or a key
            definition;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Topic heading</uicontrol> - appends/Inserts a topic heading as a
            child/sibling of the selected node;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Topic group</uicontrol> - appends/Inserts a topic group as a child/sibling
            of the selected node;</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li product="editor author"><uicontrol>Find/Replace in Files</uicontrol> - find and replace in
        files using the scope of the current edited map;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Check Spelling in Files</uicontrol> - checks the spelling of the files in the
        scope of the current edited map;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Search References</uicontrol> - finds in the current map all references to the
        selected topic reference (<codeph>topicref</codeph> or <codeph>mapref</codeph> element) and
        to each element with an ID attribute contained in the selected topic. If the current
        selection in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view is a <codeph>keydef</codeph>
        element the action will find any element with an attribute <codeph>idref</codeph>,
          <codeph>keyref</codeph>, <codeph>conref</codeph> or <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> that points
        to the selected <codeph>keydef</codeph>. <ph product="editor author developer">A shortcut
          can be set for this action in <xref
            href="preferences-menu-shortcut-keys.dita#preferences-menu-shortcut-keys" format="dita"
            >the <uicontrol>Menu Shortcut Keys</uicontrol> preferences</xref>.</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Cut, Copy, Paste, Undo, Redo</uicontrol> - common edit actions with the same
        functionality as those found in the text editor;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Paste Before, Paste After</uicontrol> - pastes the content of the clipboard
        before, respectively after, the selected node;</li>
    </ul>
    <p>You can also arrange the nodes by dragging and dropping one or more nodes at a time. Drop
      operations can be performed before, after or as child of the targeted node. The relative
      location of the drop is indicated while hovering the mouse over a node before releasing the
      mouse button for the drop.</p>
    <p>Drag and drop operations allow you to:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> - select the nodes you want to copy and start dragging them.
        Before dropping them in the appropriate place, press and hold the <uicontrol>
          <shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol> key
          (<uicontrol><shortcut>Meta</shortcut></uicontrol> key on Mac). The mouse pointer changes
        to indicate that a copy operation is performed;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Move</uicontrol> - select the nodes you want to move and drag and drop them in
        the appropriate place;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Promote</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_left_arrow"
          />)/<uicontrol>Demote</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_right_arrow"/>) - you can
        move nodes between child and parent nodes which ensures both <uicontrol>Promote</uicontrol>
          (<uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_left_arrow"/>)
        and <uicontrol>Demote</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_right_arrow"/>)
        operations.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Apart from the above actions, the contextual menu of the root of the map contains the
      following two options:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Open Map in Editor</uicontrol> - opens the ditamap in the
            <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol> view;<note>The bubble displayed on the
              <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol> tab of a DITA Map opened in the
              <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol> view is rendered blue.</note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Open Map in Editor with resolved topics</uicontrol> - opens the DITA Map in
          the editor view and displays the content referred by the links in the ditamap;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Export DITA Maps</uicontrol> - all the resources referred in a DITA Map are
          located and exported in a directory. You can also choose to export the resources as an
          archive.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note type="tip">
      <p>You can open and edit linked topics easily by double clicking the references or by
        right-clicking and choosing <uicontrol>Open in editor</uicontrol>. If the referenced file
        does not exist you are allowed to create it.</p>
      <p>By right clicking the map root element you can open and edit it in the main editor area for
        more complex operations.</p>
      <p>You can decide to open the reference directly in the Author mode and keep this setting as a
        default.</p>
    </note>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita"/>
    <link href="find-and-replace-text-in-files.dita" product="author editor"/>
    <link href="spell-check-in-files.dita"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
