<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-map-edit-advanced">
  <title>The <i>Advanced</i> Tab</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Out Of Memory<indexterm>memory allocated for a
          transformation</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body> 
    <p>In the <uicontrol>Advanced</uicontrol> tab, you can specify advanced options for the
      transformation.</p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>Advanced settings tab</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_advanced_tab_dita_scenario.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title>Advanced settings tab</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_advanced_tab_dita_scenario.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>You have several parameters that you can specify here:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Custom build file</uicontrol> - If you use a custom DITA-OT build file you can
        specify the path to the customized build file. If empty, the <filepath>build.xml</filepath>
        file from the <filepath>dita.dir</filepath> directory configured in the
          <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab is used.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Build target</uicontrol> - You can specify a build target to the build file. By
        default no target is necessary and the default <codeph>init</codeph> target is used.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Additional arguments</uicontrol> - You can specify additional command-line
        arguments to be passed to the ANT transformation like <parmname>-verbose</parmname>.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ant Home</uicontrol> - You can specify a custom ANT installation to run the
        DITA Map transformation. <ph product="author developer editor">By default it is the path
          configured in the <xref href="ant-preferences.dita#ant-preferences">Ant preferences
            page</xref>. A custom value can also be set</ph>;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Java Home</uicontrol> - You can specify a custom Java Virtual Machine to run
        the ANT transformation. By default it is the Java Virtual Machine used by <ph
          keyref="product"/>.</li>
      <li id="dita-jvm-args"><uicontrol>JVM Arguments</uicontrol> - This parameter allows you to set
        specific parameters to the Java Virtual Machine used by ANT. By default it is set to
          <parmname>-Xmx384m</parmname> which means the transformation process is allowed to use 384
        megabytes of memory. Sometimes, when performing a large DITA map transformation you may want
        to increase the memory allocated to the Java Virtual Machine from the default value (384 MB)
        to a higher value, like 512 MB. This way, you can avoid the Out of Memory error messages
          (<uicontrol>OutOfMemoryError</uicontrol>) received from the ANT process.<note>If you are
          publishing DITA to PDF and still experience problems, you should also increase the amount
          of memory allocated to the FO transformer. To do this, go to the
            <uicontrol>Advanced</uicontrol> tab and increase the value of the <uicontrol>Java
            Arguments</uicontrol> parameter.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Libraries</uicontrol> - <ph
          keyref="product"/> adds by default as high
        priority libraries which are not transformation-dependent and also patches for certain DITA
        Open Toolkit bugs. You can specify all the additional libraries (jar files or additional
        class paths) which are used by the ANT transformer. You can also decide to control all
        libraries added to the classpath.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>