<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-outgoing-references-addon">
  <title>DITA Outgoing References View Add-on</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Add-ons<indexterm>DITA Outgoing References View</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA Outgoing References View add-on</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> offers an add-on that contributes a <uicontrol>DITA
        References</uicontrol> side view that shows all outgoing references for the current DITA
      topic. Once the add-on is installed, the view is available in both <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
      and <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> modes. To open the view, select <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/DITAReferences16.png" id="image_vrn_nhw_sr"/>DITA References</uicontrol> in
      the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu. If this is your first time opening the view, <ph keyref="product"/> will
      present a dialog box asking if you want to install the add-on. Once installed, you need to
      restart <ph keyref="product"/> and the <uicontrol>DITA References</uicontrol> view will be
      available.</p>
    <p>The types of references that are presented in this view include:<ul id="ul_v4r_qlv_nkb">
        <li>Image references (referenced with an <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt>
          attribute)</li>
        <li>References to other media resources (DITA objects pointing to video, audio, or
          embeddable frames)</li>
        <li>Cross references (referenced in an <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> element with an
            <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute)</li>
        <li>Key references (referenced with a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute)</li>
        <li>Content references (referenced with a <xmlatt>conref</xmlatt> or
            <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt> attribute)</li>
        <li>Related links (referenced with an <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt>
          attribute)</li>
        <li>Related links defined in relationship tables</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>This side-view is synchronized with the main editor to make it easy to locate a reference in
      the current document. It also includes contextual menu actions for opening the target of an
      outgoing reference or showing its definition location. You can also double-click a reference
      to open its target.</p>
    <p>For more information, see the <xref
        href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/oxygen-dita-outgoing-references-view" format="html"
        scope="external">details for the <b>DITA Outgoing References View</b> add-on in
        GitHub</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
