<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-prolog-updater">
  <title>DITA Prolog Updater Add-on</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Add-ons<indexterm>DITA prolog updater</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA prolog updater add-on</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> offers an add-on that contributes a preferences page (<menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>DITA Prolog Updater</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>) that includes various options for updating the <i>prolog</i> section of a DITA
      topic or map. The preferences page includes the following options that can be set for DITA
      topics or maps (or both):<ul>
        <li><b>Author</b> - Specifies the name of the author. By default, it is the system user
          name.</li>
        <li><b>Enable automatic prolog update on save</b> - When this option is selected, the prolog
          is updated anytime the document is saved.</li>
        <li><b>Set creator name</b> - When this option is selected, the author is set as the
          document's <i>creator</i> in the prolog when the document is saved. This option is only
          applicable for new documents.</li>
        <li><b>Set created date</b> - When this option is selected, a <i>created date</i> is added
          to the prolog when the document is saved. This option is only applicable for new
          documents.</li>
        <li><b>Update contributor names</b> - When this option is selected, the author is set as a
            <i>contributor</i> in the prolog when the document is saved. This option is only
          applicable for already existing documents.</li>
        <li><b>Update revised dates</b>: When this option is selected, a <i>revised date</i> is
          added to the prolog when the document is saved. This option is only applicable for already
          existing documents.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To install it the add-on, follow these instructions:<ol>
        <li>Go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Install new add-ons</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> to open an add-on selection dialog box.</li>
        <li>Enter or paste <b>http://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Addons/default/updateSite.xml</b> in
          the <uicontrol>Show add-ons from</uicontrol> field or select it from the drop-down
          menu.</li>
        <li>Select the <b>DITA Prolog Updater</b> add-on and click <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li>Select the <b>I accept all terms of the end user license agreement</b> option and click
            <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li>Restart the application.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <p><b>Result:</b> The <b>DITA Prolog Updater</b> preferences page will now be available in <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>For more information, see the <xref
        href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/oxygen-dita-prolog-updater" format="html"
        scope="external">details for this <b>DITA Prolog Updater</b> add-on in GitHub</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
