<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-map-edit-parameters">
  <title>The Parameters Tab</title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <body>
    <p>This dialog allows you to configure the parameters sent to the DITA-OT build file.</p>
    <p>The table displays all the parameters that the DITA-OT documentation specifies as available
      for each chosen type of transformation (for example: XHTML or PDF), along with their
      description and current values. You can find more information about each parameter in the
        <xref
        href="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/1.5.3/quickstartguide/reference/dita-ot_ant_properties.html"
        scope="external" format="html">DITA OT Documentation</xref>. You can also add, edit, and
      remove parameters. Use the <uicontrol>Filter</uicontrol> text box to search for a specific
      term in the entire parameters collection. Note that edited parameters are displayed with the
      name in bold.</p>
    <p>Depending on the type of a parameter, its value can be one of the following:<ul>
        <li>A simple text field for simple parameter values.</li>
        <li>A combo box with some predefined values.</li>
        <li>A file chooser and an <xref href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables" format="dita"
            >editor variable</xref> selector to simplify setting a file path as the value of a
          parameter.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note>To input parameter values at runtime, use the <xref
        href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables/edVar-ask"><i>ask</i> editor variable</xref> in
      the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column.</note>
    <p>The following actions are available for managing parameters:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry
        conref="xslt-stylesheet-parameters.dita#xslt-stylesheet-parameters/new-action-dlentry">
        <dt/>
        <dd/>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Edit Parameter</uicontrol> dialog that allows you to change the
          value of the selected parameter by selecting it from a list of allowed values.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry
        conref="xslt-stylesheet-parameters.dita#xslt-stylesheet-parameters/unset-action-dlentry">
        <dt/>
        <dd/>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry
        conref="xslt-stylesheet-parameters.dita#xslt-stylesheet-parameters/delete-action-dlentry">
        <dt/>
        <dd/>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
  </body>
</topic>
