<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-profiling-conditional-text">
  <title>DITA Profiling / Conditional Text</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Profiling</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Filtering content</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>DITA offers support for conditionally profiling content by using profiling attributes. With
        <ph keyref="product"/>, you can define values for the DITA profiling attributes and they can
      be easily managed to filter content in the published output. You can switch between profile
      sets to see how the edited content looks like before publishing.<ph product="author editor">
        The profiling configuration can also be shared between content authors through the project
        file and there is no need for coding or editing configuration files. </ph></p>
    <section id="profiling_attributes">
      <title>Profiling Attributes</title>
      <p>You can profile content elements or map elements by adding one or more of the default DITA
        profiling attributes (<codeph>product</codeph>, <codeph>platform</codeph>,
          <codeph>audience</codeph>, <codeph>rev</codeph>, <codeph>props</codeph>, and
          <codeph>otherprops</codeph>). You can also create your own <xref
          href="../topics/profiling-attributes-management.dita#profiling-attributes-management"
          >custom profiling attributes</xref> and <xref
          href="../topics/condition-sets-management.dita#condition-sets-management">custom profiling
          condition sets</xref>. The profiling attributes may contain one or more tokens that
        represent conditions to be applied to the content when a publication is built. </p>
      <p>For example, you could define a section of a topic that would only be included for a
        publication related to the Windows platform by adding the <codeph>platform</codeph>
        profiling attribute:</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;section platform="windows"></codeblock>
    </section>
    <section id="profiling_conditions">
      <title>Profiling Conditions</title>
      <p>DITA allows you to conditionally profile parts of a topic so that certain parts of the
        topic are displayed when certain profiling conditions are set. Profiling conditions can be
        set both within topics and in maps. When set in a topic, they allow you to suppress an
        element (such as paragraph), step in a procedure, item in a list, or even a phrase within a
        sentence. When set in a map, they allow you to suppress an entire topic or group of topics.
        You can then create a variety of publications from a single map by applying profiling
        conditions to the build. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="profiling-content-section">
      <title>Apply Profiling to DITA Content</title>
      <p>To apply a profiling attribute to DITA content, highlight the content and select
          <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> from the contextual menu. To profile
        specific elements in a topic or map, right-click inside the element and select
          <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol>. The <wintitle>Edit Profiling
          Attributes</wintitle> dialog box is displayed, allowing you to select each of the
        profiling tokens that apply for each attribute.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="edit-profiling-image">
          <title>Edit Profiling Attributes Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/edit-profiling-attributes-dialog.png" id="image_dkz_hsd_bq"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The profiling attributes, and their potential values, that appear in this dialog box depend
        on what has been configured in <ph keyref="product"/>. If you have a large list of profiling
        attributes, you can use the text filter field to search for attributes or values, and you
        can expand or collapse attributes by using the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/ExpandAll16.png"/>Expand All/<image href="../img/CollapseAll16.png"
          />Collapse All</uicontrol> buttons to the right of the text filter or the arrow button to
        the left of the profiling attribute name.</p>
      <p>The attributes and values that appear in the dialog box are determined as follows:<ul
          id="ul_bsp_5sd_bq">
          <li>If your <xref keyref="glossentry_root-map"><term>root map</term></xref> references a
            DITA <xref keyref="glossentry_subject-scheme-map"><term>subject scheme map</term></xref>
            that <xref href="subject-scheme-map.dita#subject-scheme-map">defines values for the
              profiling attributes</xref>, those values are used. <ph keyref="product"/> collects
            all the profiling values from the <term>subject scheme map</term> that is referenced in
            the map that is currently opened in the <xref href="dita-maps-manager.dita"
                ><uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol></xref> (or <xref
              href="root-map.dita#root-map">set as the <term>root map</term></xref>). In the <xref
              href="#dita-profiling-conditional-text/edit-profiling-image" format="dita">image
              above</xref> (taken from the <ph keyref="product"/> documentation project), you see
            values for eight products. They are the only values that are defined in the
              s<term>ubject scheme map</term> and thus, are the only ones that appear in the dialog
            box.</li>
          <li product="author editor">If you have <xref
              href="profiling-attributes-management.dita#profiling-attributes-management">defined
              profiling attribute values</xref> for the DITA document type in the <xref
              href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                ><uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> and you
            store them at <xref keyref="glossentry_project-options">project-level</xref>, those
            values are displayed in the dialog box.</li>
          <li product="author editor">If you have <xref
              href="profiling-attributes-management.dita#profiling-attributes-management">defined
              profiling attribute values</xref> for the DITA document type in the <xref
              href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                ><uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> and you
            store them at <xref keyref="glossentry_global-options">global-level</xref>, those values
            are displayed in the dialog box.</li>
          <li product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">If you have <xref
              href="profiling-attributes-management.dita#profiling-attributes-management">defined
              profiling attribute values</xref> for the DITA document type in the <xref
              href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
                ><uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>, those
            values are displayed in the dialog box.</li>
          <li>Otherwise, a generic default set of profiling attributes and values are
            available.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="visualizing_profiled_content">
      <title>Visualizing Profiled Content</title>
      <p>You can visualize the effect of profiling content by using the profiling tools in the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingDrop.png" id="image_pm5_bzf_yr"
            placement="inline"/>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> drop-down menu that is
        located on the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> toolbar. You can select which
        profiles to show, or apply colors to text that is profiled in various ways, as shown in the
        following image:</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Example: Profiled Content</title>
          <image href="../img/profiling-styles-sample.png" id="image_s2j_vvd_bq" placement="inline"
          />
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>If the <uicontrol>Show Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> option (available in the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar16.png" placement="inline"/>Profiling /
          Conditional Text</uicontrol> drop-down menu) is selected, a green border is painted around
        profiled text in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. Also, all profiling attributes set
        on the current element are listed at the end of the highlighted block and in its tooltip
        message. To edit the attributes of a profiled fragment, click one of the listed attribute
        values. A form control pops up and allows you to add or remove attribute values.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Profiling Attribute Value Form Control Pop Up</title>
          <image href="../img/profiling_form_control.png" placement="inline"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about DITA profiling, go to <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/DITA_Profiling.html" format="html" scope="external"
      />.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="profiling-conditional-text.dita"/>
      <link href="../topics/profiling-attributes-management.dita"/>
      <link href="apply-profiling-attributes.dita#apply-profiling-attributes"/>
      <link href="../topics/condition-sets-management.dita"/>
      <link href="apply-profiling-conditional-set.dita#apply-profiling-conditional-set"/>
      <link href="dita-edit-properties.dita#dita-edit-properties"/>
      <link href="subject-scheme-map.dita#subject-scheme-map"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
