<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita-integrate-specialization">
  <title>Integration of a DITA Specialization</title>
  <body>
    <p>A DITA specialization usually includes:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>DTD definitions for new elements as extensions of existing DITA elements</li>
      <li>optionally specialized processing, that is new XSLT template rules that match the
        extension part of the <codeph>class</codeph> attribute values of the new elements and thus
        extend the default processing available in DITA Open Toolkit</li>
    </ul>
    <p>A specialization can be integrated in the application with minimum effort:<ol
        id="ol_ytk_nzn_l3">
        <li>If the DITA specialization is available as a DITA Open Toolkit plugin, copy the plugin
          to the location of the DITA OT you are using (by default
            <filepath>OXYGEN_INSTALL_DIR\frameworks\dita\DITA-OT\plugins</filepath>). Then run the
          DITA OT integrator to integrate the plugin. In the <xref
            href="scenarios-view.dita#scenarios-view"><b>Transformation Scenarios</b> view</xref>
          there is a predefined scenario called <b>Run DITA OT Integrator</b> which can be used for
            this.<note type="important">The folder where the DITA OT is located needs to have full
            write access permissions set to it.</note></li>
        <li>If the specialization is not available as a plugin, you have the following options:<ul
            id="ul_ddb_2g5_zn">
            <li>If the DTD's that define the extension elements are located in a folder outside the
              DITA Open Toolkit folder, add new rules to the DITA OT catalog file for resolving the
              DTD references from the DITA files that use the specialized elements to that folder.
              This allows correct resolution of DTD references to your local DTD files and is needed
              for both validation and transformation of the DITA maps or topics. The DITA OT catalog
              file is called <filepath>catalog-dita.xml</filepath> and is located in the root folder
              of the DITA Open Toolkit.</li>
            <li>If there is specialized processing provided by XSLT stylesheets that override the
              default stylesheets from DITA OT, these new stylesheets must be called from the Ant
              build scripts of DITA OT. <note type="important">If you are using DITA specialization
                elements in your DITA files, it is recommended that you activate the
                  <uicontrol>Enable DTD/XML Schema processing in document type detection</uicontrol>
                checkbox in the <xref href="preferences-document-type-association.dita"
                    ><uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol> page</xref>. </note></li>
          </ul></li>
      </ol></p>    
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="http://xiruss.org/tutorials/dita-specialization/" format="html" scope="external"><linktext>DITA
      Configuration and Specialization Tutorials</linktext></link>
    <link href="../concepts/transformation-scenario.dita#transformation-scenario"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
