<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="dita_open_toolkit_project">
    <title>DITA Open Toolkit Project</title>
    <body>
    <p conkeyref="reusables-author-for-dita/p-DITAOT-project-1"/>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> has special support for creating, editing, validating, and publishing
      DITA Open Toolkit project files represented in XML format. It can also use such files to
      detect connections between DITA resources in the entire project and to apply root map and
      filter pairs when editing.</p>
    </body>
  <topic id="dita_open_toolkit_project_edit">
    <title>Editing DITA Open Toolkit Project Files</title>
    <body>
      <p>The <xref href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa" product="author editor"><uicontrol>New
            Document</uicontrol> wizard</xref><xref
          href="new-dialog-eclipse.dita#new-dialog-eclipse" product="authorEclipse editorEclipse"
            ><uicontrol>New Document</uicontrol> wizard</xref> includes a template to help you
        create DITA Open Toolkit project files (with an <filepath>.xml</filepath> file extension).
        The template is located in the <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>DITA-OT</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> folder. There is also a sample project file that can be found in the
        application samples folder:
          <filepath>OXYGEN_INSTALL_DIR/samples/dita/mobile-phone/mobilePhoneProjectFile.xml</filepath>.</p>
      <p>Content completion is done according to the associated schema and it is enhanced with
        proposals for ID references, available transformation types, parameter names, and
        values.</p>
      <p>The validation support has enhanced Schematron rules that report invalid references to
        non-existing contexts.</p>
      <p>When working with a DITA-OT project file in the <b>Author</b> visual editing mode, you can
        see a compact representation of the file by default. You can switch to the
          <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> style in the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> toolbar drop-down
        menu to edit the file using form controls and inline buttons. The additional <uicontrol>View
          as YAML</uicontrol> style can be selected to see a visual representation of the same
        document in YAML.</p>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="dita_open_toolkit_project_publish">
    <title>Publishing DITA Open Toolkit Project Files</title>
    <body>
      <p conkeyref="reusables-author-for-dita/p-DITAOT-project-2"/>
      <p conkeyref="reusables-author-for-dita/p-DITAOT-project-3"/>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="dita_open_toolkit_project_master">
    <title>Master Files Support for DITA Open Toolkit Project Files </title>
    <body>
      <p>If you enable <xref href="dita-master-files.dita">master files support at project
          level</xref>, you can choose to detect all top-level DITA Open Toolkit project files and
        to add them to the Master Files folder. You could also manually add the top-level files for
        your DITA-OT project in the Master Files folder. The benefit of this is that whenever you
        rename or move files in the <uicontrol product="author editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
          product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">Project Explorer</uicontrol> view, the references to those
        resources will automatically be updated.<note type="tip">The <xref
            href="dita-resource-hierarchy-view.dita">Resource Hierarchy/Dependencies view</xref>
          also works for DITA-OT project files.</note></p>
      <section id="section_xw2_sjz_jkb">
        <title>Editing Contexts Detected from DITA Open Toolkit Project Files</title>
        <p>Once a DITA-OT project file is added to the Master Files folder, the
            <uicontrol>Context</uicontrol> drop-down menu on the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
            Manager</uicontrol> toolbar will contain context DITA maps defined in the project file
          and the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingDrop.png" id="image_r4g_tjz_jkb"
            />Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> menu will contain filter pairs gathered from
          the project file. When you select one of them in the drop-down menu, the application
          gathers the keys from the context DITA map and applies the filters specified in that
          context.</p>
      </section>
    </body>
  </topic>
</topic>
