<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="docbook-webhelp-plugin">
  <title>Running from Command Line</title>
  <body>
    <p>To run a DocBook to WebHelp transformation outside of <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>, use
      the following script file:<ul>
        <li><b>Windows</b> - <filepath>[DocBook XSL
            directory]\com.oxygenxml.webhelp.classic\docbook.bat</filepath></li>
        <li><b>Linux/Mac OS X</b> - <filepath>[DocBook XSL
            directory]/com.oxygenxml.webhelp.classic/docbook.sh</filepath></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>Before running the script to generate output, you must customize it to specify various paths
      and transformation type. To do this, open the script file and edit the following variables:<ul>
        <li><b>JVM_INSTALL_DIR</b> - Specifies the path to the Java Virtual Machine installation
          directory on your disk.</li>
        <li><b>ANT_INSTALL_DIR</b> - Specifies the path to the installation directory of Ant.</li>
        <li><b>SAXON_6_DIR</b> - Specifies the path to the installation directory of Saxon
          6.5.5.</li>
        <li><b>SAXON_9_DIR</b> - Specifies the path to the installation directory of Saxon
          9.1.0.8.</li>
        <li><b>DOCBOOK_XSL_DIR</b> - Specifies the path to the installation directory of the DocBook
          XSL distribution.</li>
        <li><b>TRANSTYPE</b> - Specifies the type of the transformation you want to apply. The
            <b>Oxygen XML WebHelp Plugin</b> contributes the following transformation types for
            DocBook:<ul id="webhelp-plugin-outputs">
            <li conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/webhelp-classic"></li>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/webhelp-classic-feedback"></li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b>INPUT_DIR</b> - Specifies the path to the input directory, containing the input XML
          file.</li>
        <li><b>XML_INPUT_FILE</b> - Specifies the name of the input XML file.</li>
        <li><b>OUTPUT_DIR</b> - Specifies the path to the output directory where the transformation
          output is generated.</li>
        <li><b>DOCBOOK_XSL_DIR_URL</b> - Specifies the path to the directory of the DocBook XSL
          distribution in URL format.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>You can also add <xref
        href="webhelp-plugin-additional-parameters-docbook.dita#webhelp-plugin-additional-parameters-docbook"
        >additional configuration parameters that are contributed by the <b>Oxygen XML WebHelp
          Plugin</b></xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
