<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="dockable-views-and-editors" >
    <title>Dockable Views and Editors</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Getting Started<indexterm>dockable views and
                editors</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>All the <ph keyref="product"/> views available in the <ph product="editor developer">
        <xref href="editor-perspective.dita">Editor Perspective</xref>, <xref
          href="xslt-debugger-perspective.dita">XSLT Debugger Perspective, and</xref>
        <xref href="xquery-debugger-perspective.dita">XQuery Debugger Perspective</xref>
      </ph>
      <ph product="author">Editor Perspective</ph> are dockable. </p>
    <p>You can drag any view to any margin of another view or editor inside the <ph keyref="product"
      /> window. Once you create a layout that suites your needs, you are able to save it from <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Save Layout...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. <ph keyref="product"/> creates a layout file containing the preferences of the
      saved layout. To load a layout, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Load Layout...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. To reset it, select <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Reset Layout</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.<note>The <uicontrol>Load Layout...</uicontrol> menu lets you select between
        the default layout, a predefined layout, or a custom layout. The changes you make using the
          <uicontrol>Load Layout...</uicontrol> menu are also reflected in the
          <uicontrol>Perspectives Layout</uicontrol> preferences page.</note></p>
    <p>The changes you make to any layout are preserved between working sessions. Also, changing to
      a different layout and returning to the previous one does not alter the changes you made to
      the first layout. The predefined layout files are saved in the preferences directory of <ph
        keyref="product"/>.</p>
        <p>To gain more editing space in the <ph keyref="product"/> window, click <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/toggle_auto_hide.png"/>Toggle auto-hide</uicontrol> in any view. This button
      sets the view in the <i>auto-hide</i> state, making it visible only as a vertical tab, at the
      margins of the <ph keyref="product"/> window. To display a view in the <term>auto-hide</term>
      state, hover its side-tab with your cursor, or click it to keep the view visible until you
      click elsewhere. A view can also be set to a floating state, making it independent from the
      rest of the <ph keyref="product"/> window.</p>
        <p>You can drag the editors and arrange them in any order you like, both horizontally and
      vertically. </p>
    <p>The next figure presents two editors arranged as horizontal tiles. To arrange them
      vertically, drag one of them on top of the other. In the example below, the
        <filepath>personal.xml</filepath> file was dragged over the
        <filepath>personal-schema.xml</filepath> file. When doing this, a dark grey rectangle marks
      the rearranged layout.<fig id="figure-split-editors-by-drag-and-drop">
        <title>Drag and Drop Editors</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_split_editor_pane_by_dnd.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
        <p>You can also tile all the opened editors horizontally, vertically, or stacked together,
      both in the <xref href="editor-perspective.dita">Editor Perspective</xref> or in the <xref
        href="database-perspective.dita#database-perspective" format="dita">Database
        Perspective</xref>, using these actions from the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu: <ul>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_tile_horizontally.png"/> Tile Editors
            Horizontally</uicontrol>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_tile_vertically.png"/> Tile Editors
            Vertically</uicontrol>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_stack.png"/> Stack Editors</uicontrol>.</li>
      </ul><note>
        <p>When tiled, you can still drag and drop the editors, but note that they are docked in the
          same way as a window/view (instead of just tabs). You are actually rearranging the editor
          windows, so drag the editor tab and drop it to one of the sides of an editor
          (left/right/top/bottom). While dragging, you will see the grey dark rectangle aligned to
          one of the sides of the editor, or around the entire editor window. If you drop it to one
          of the sides it will dock to that side of the editor. If you drop it when the rectangle is
          around the entire window of the editor it will get stacked on top of that editor. You can
          also grab one of the stacked editors and tile it to one of the sides.</p>
      </note></p>
    <p>To scroll through the tiled editors in the same time, enable the <uicontrol>
        <image href="../img/sa_synchronize_scrolling_enabled_on.png" id="image_jg3_jlr_r2"/>
        Synchronous scrolling</uicontrol> action (from the same <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu).</p>
        <p>You can divide the editing area vertically and horizontally using the actions available
      in the <uicontrol>Split</uicontrol> toolbar and in the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu: <uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_split_horizontal.png"/> Split
        horizontally</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_split_vertical.png"/> Split
        vertically</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_unsplit.png"/>
        Unsplit</uicontrol>. To maximize or restore the editors, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Maximize/Restore Editor Area</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
        <p product="editor developer">When the opened documents titles do not fit in the tab strip,
      the scroll wheel can be used to scroll the editor title tabs to the left or right the same way
      the two arrows on the right are acting. The following shortcuts can be used to switch between
      edited files: Ctrl-F6 (Meta-F6 on Mac OS X) and Ctrl-Shift-F6 (Meta-Shift-F6 on Mac OS X).
      These shortcuts display a small popup window that cycles through all opened files.</p>
        <p product="editor developer">The default layout of any of the <xref href="editor-perspective.dita"
                >Editor Perspectives</xref>, <xref href="xslt-debugger-perspective.dita">XSLT
                Debugger Perspective</xref> and <xref href="xquery-debugger-perspective.dita">XQuery
                Debugger Perspective</xref> can be restored at any time with the <uicontrol>Reset
                Layout</uicontrol> action found in the <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol> menu.</p>
        <p>Any <ph keyref="product"/> view or toolbar can be opened at any time from the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> and <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show Toolbar</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menus. The current (focused) dockable view is made invisible (switched to
      hidden state) using the <uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_f4"/> shortcut. The
      users who prefer to use the keyboard instead of the mouse may find this shortcut to be a
      faster way of closing a view than clicking the <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol> button from the
      title bar of the view. The complementary action (opening a view with a shortcut) requires
      setting a custom shortcut for each view in <xref
        href="preferences-menu-shortcut-keys.dita#preferences-menu-shortcut-keys" format="dita">the
          <uicontrol>Menu Shortcut Keys</uicontrol> preferences</xref>.</p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about dockable and floating views and editors in <ph
        keyref="product"/>, go to <xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Dockable_Views.html"
        format="html" scope="external">http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Dockable_Views.html</xref>.</p>
    </body>
</topic>