<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="documentumcms-actions-at-folder-level">
  <title>Actions Available on Cabinets / Folders</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Documentum (CMS)
            Support<indexterm>actions<indexterm>cabinets/folders</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The actions available on a <ph
        conref="../topics/oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/documentumCMS"/> cabinet in
      the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view are the following:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_new_folder_small.png"/> New Folder</uicontrol> - Creates
        a new folder in the current cabinet / folder. The folder properties are the following:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Path</uicontrol> - Shows the path where the new folder will be
            created.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - The type of the new folder (default is
              <uicontrol>dm_folder</uicontrol>).</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The name of the new folder.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> - The title property of the folder.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Subject</uicontrol> - The subject property of the folder.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_new_button.png"/> New Document</uicontrol> - Creates a
        new document in the current cabinet / folder. The document properties are the following:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Path</uicontrol> - Shows the path where the new document will be
            created.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The name of the new document.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - The type of the new document (default is
              <uicontrol>dm_document</uicontrol>).</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> - The document content type format.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Import</uicontrol> - Imports local files / folders in the selected cabinet /
        folder of the repository. Actions available in the import dialog:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Add Files</uicontrol> - Shows a file browse dialog and allows you to select
            files to add to the list.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Add Folders</uicontrol> - Shows a folder browse dialog that allows you to
            select folders to add to the list. The subfolders will be added recursively.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> - Shows a dialog where you can change the properties of
            the selected file / folder from the list.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> - Removes the selected files / folders from the
            list.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol> - Changes the name of the selected cabinet / folder.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> - Copies the selected folder to a different location in the
        tree (available only upon folders). This action can also be performed with drag and drop
        while holding the <uicontrol>
          <shortcut>(Ctrl (Meta on Mac OS))</shortcut></uicontrol> key pressed.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Move</uicontrol> - Moves the selected folder to a different location in the
        tree (available only upon folders). This action can also be performed with drag and
        drop.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif"/> Delete</uicontrol> - Deletes the selected
        cabinet / folder from the repository. The following options are available:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Folder(s)</uicontrol> - Allows you to delete only the selected folder or to
            delete recursively the folder and all subfolders and objects.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Version(s)</uicontrol> - Allows you to specify what versions of the
            resources will be deleted.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Virtual document(s)</uicontrol> - Here you can specify what happens when
            virtual documents are encountered. They can be either deleted either by themselves or
            together with their descendants.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_refresh.png"/> Refresh</uicontrol> - Performs a refresh
        of the selected node's subtree.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_edit_properties.png"/> Properties</uicontrol> - Displays
        the list of properties of the selected cabinet / folder.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>