<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="ec-file-comparison">
  <title>File Comparison Tool</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Compare Files tool</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Two-way file comparison</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Three-way file comparison</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Diff Files tool</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Diff tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a file comparison tool that provides a mechanism for
      comparing two XML-related resources, as well as the possibility for a three-way comparison.
      You can compare files in a visual comparison mode or in a text-based comparison mode. The
      supported XML file types include XSL, XSD, DTD, XProc, WSDL, RNG, and XSpec, as well as HTML
      documents.</p>
    <section id="section_gnn_3cl_rlb">
      <title>How to Start a File Comparison</title>
      <p>There are various ways to automatically start the file comparison, but the most common ways
          are:<ul id="ul_dhd_lcl_rlb">
          <li>You can select two files (or three file if one of them is a common ancestor) in the
              <uicontrol>Project Explorer</uicontrol> view, right-click, and select one of the
            options in the <uicontrol>Compare With</uicontrol> menu (e.g. <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Compare With</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Each Other</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> to compare the selected files).</li>
          <li>If you use a versioning system, you can compare files directly from the
              <uicontrol>Synchronize</uicontrol> view (e.g. double-click a file or right-click
            selected files and choose <uicontrol>Open In Compare Editor</uicontrol>) or the
              <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_wgn_1b4_wmb">
      <title>Visual Author Comparison Mode</title>
      <p>The visual <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> file comparison mode makes it easier to see how
        the compared changes will look in the final output. It includes unique features such as
        actions to control the tags display mode, the ability to do second-level comparisons, and it
        presents differences made with <i>Change Tracking</i> enabled.</p>
      <p>If there is a CSS associated with the documents (either directly in the document or in the
        framework definition), the visual comparison tool is presented automatically when you
        compare XML files in <ph keyref="product"/>. If the comparison is automatically started in
        the text-based mode, you can switch to the visual comparison mode by clicking the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/EC-Diff-Author16.png" id="image_pn5_yzn_wmb"/>Switch to
          Author Mode</uicontrol> toolbar button.</p>
      <note type="attention">If the documents do not have an associated CSS, the visual comparison
        mode cannot render the document properly, so the text-based mode is used in this
        situation.</note>
      <p>You can compare versions in the Workbench with versions in the repository, or with the
        local edit history. You can also compare three files if a common ancestor exists. The two
        editors are constantly synchronized and the differences are refreshed when you save the
        modified document.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_y1y_jyn_wmb">
          <title>Visual File Comparison Tool</title>
          <image href="../img/EC-file-compare.png" id="image_z1y_jyn_wmb"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_b4d_2b4_wmb">
      <title>Text-based Comparison Mode</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> also includes a text-based comparison mode. When in the
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> comparison mode, you can switch to the text-based mode by
        clicking the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Mode16.png" id="image_qtm_gzn_wmb"/>Switch
          to Text Mode</uicontrol> toolbar button.</p>
      <p>Most of the options, features, and actions that are available for the visual-based
        comparison mode are also available in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> comparison mode,
        although more <xref href="#ec-file-comparison/algorithms" format="dita">algorithms</xref>
        are available in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="twoway_comparisons">
      <title>Highlight Colors</title>
      <p>The differences are also highlighted in several colors, depending on the type of change.
        The highlighting colors can be customized in the <xref
          href="preferences-diff-appearance-EC.dita"><menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Appearance</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> preferences page</xref>. The default colors and their shades mean the
          following:<ul id="ul_hh2_32l_rlb">
          <li><b>Pink</b> - Identifies modifications on either side. For 3-way comparisons, it
            identifies blocks of changes that include conflicts.</li>
          <li><b>Gray</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the left side (your outgoing
            changes). For 3-way comparisons, it identifies your outgoing changes that do not include
            conflicts.</li>
          <li><b>Blue</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the right side (incoming changes).
            For 3-way comparisons, it identifies incoming changes that do not include
            conflicts.</li>
          <li><b>Lighter Shade</b> - Identifies blocks of changes that can be merged in their
            entirety.</li>
          <li><b>Darker Shade</b> - Identifies specific changes within the blocks that can be merged
            more precisely.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_xcn_phl_rlb">
      <title>Navigating Differences</title>
      <p>To navigate through differences, do one of the following:<ul id="ul_lrm_q3f_lf">
          <li>Use the navigation buttons on the toolbar.</li>
          <li>Select a block of differences by clicking its small colored marker in the overview
            ruler located in the right-most part of the window. At the top of the overview ruler
            there is a success indicator that turns green where there are no differences, or red if
            differences are found.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_pf2_rhl_rlb">
      <title>Toolbar Actions</title>
      <sectiondiv>
        <p>A variety of actions are available on the toolbar:<dl>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Mode16.png" id="image_njj_hkl_rlb"/>Switch to
                  Text Mode</uicontrol> (Only available in Author mode)</dt>
              <dd>Switches to the text-based file comparison mode.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/EC-Diff-Author16.png" id="image_vht_rsm_wmb"
                  />Switch to Author Mode</uicontrol> (Only available in Text mode)</dt>
              <dd>Switches to the visual <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> file comparison mode.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="tags-display-mode">
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TagsDrop.png" id="image_xsp_rkl_rlb"/>Tags Display
                  Mode</uicontrol> (Only available in Author mode)</dt>
              <dd>Allows you to select the amount of markup to be displayed in the editors. You can
                choose between: <uicontrol><image href="../img/FullTagsWithAttrs16.png"
                    id="image_gmv_lrm_wr"/> Full Tags with Attributes</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/FullTags16.png" id="image_y33_mrm_wr"/> Full Tags</uicontrol>,
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/BlockTags16.png" id="image_rcr_mrm_wr"/> Block
                  Tags</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image href="../img/InlineTags16.png"
                    id="image_usz_mrm_wr"/> Inline Tags</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/PartialTags16.png" id="image_qsh_nrm_wr"/> Partial
                Tags</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol><image href="../img/NoTags16.png"
                    id="image_ucq_nrm_wr"/> No Tags</uicontrol>.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Settings16.png" id="image_gvw_5kl_rlb"/>Diff
                  Options</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Opens the <xref href="preferences-diff-EC.dita"><uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol>
                  preferences page</xref> where you can configure various options.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="algorithm-drop-down">
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/EC-Diff-Alg-Drop-down.png" id="image_ykg_qtm_wmb"
                  />Algorithm Drop-down menu</uicontrol>  (Only available in Text mode)</dt>
              <dd>This drop-down menu allows you to select a <xref
                  href="#ec-file-comparison/algorithms" format="dita">diff algorithm</xref> to use
                for the comparison (depending on whether it is a two-way or three-way
                comparison).</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Swap16.png" id="image_pp1_fll_rlb"/>Swap Left
                  and Right View</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Swaps the file in the left pane with the one in the right pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyLR16.png" id="image_ky2_sll_rlb"/>Copy All
                  Non-Conflicting Changes from Left to Right</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies all non-conflicting changes from the file in the left pane to the file in
                the right pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyRL16.png" id="image_szn_wll_rlb"/>Copy All
                  Non-Conflicting Changes from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies all non-conflicting changes from the file in the right pane to the file in
                the left pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyCurLR16.png" id="image_w5v_xll_rlb"/>Copy
                  Current Change from Left to Right</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies the current change from the file in the left pane to the file in the right
                pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyCurRL16.png" id="image_kpf_yll_rlb"/>Copy
                  Current Change from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies the current change from the file in the right pane to the file in the left
                pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-NextDiff16.png" id="image_vrq_3k3_tc"/>Next
                  Difference</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Navigates to the next block of changes. This action is not available when the
                cursor is positioned on the last change block or when there are no changes.<note>A
                  change block groups one or more consecutive lines that contain at least one
                  change.</note></dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-PrevDiff16.png" id="image_lbz_hk3_tc"
                  />Previous Difference</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Jumps to the previous block of changes. This action is not available when the
                cursor is positioned on the first change block or when there are no changes.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-NextChange16.png" id="image_lbp_jk3_tc"/>Next
                  Change</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Jumps to the next change from the current block of changes. When the last change
                from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the next block of
                changes. This action is not available when the cursor is positioned on the last
                change or when there are no changes.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-PrevChange16.png" id="image_vc1_hk3_tc"
                  />Previous Change</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Jumps to the previous change from the current block of changes. When the first
                change from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the previous
                block of changes. This action is not available when the cursor is positioned on the
                first change or when there are no changes.</dd>
            </dlentry>
          </dl></p>
      </sectiondiv>
    </section>
    <section id="section_arf_4nl_rlb">
      <title>Contextual Menu Actions</title>
      <p>The following contextual menu actions are available in each editor pane:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Undo16.png" id="image_uw1_ggp_5r"
              />Undo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Undo changes in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Redo16.png" id="image_nzy_lgp_5r"
              />Redo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Redo changes in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Cut16.png" id="image_brg_3z1_5r"
              />Cut</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Cut the selection from the currently focused editor pane to the clipboard.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png" id="image_sf4_lst_tr"
              />Copy</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Copy the selection from the currently focused editor pane to the clipboard.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Paste16.png" id="image_cwr_cqt_tr"
              />Paste</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Paste content from the clipboard into the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Select all</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Selects all content in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Search16.png" id="image_kfr_14l_rlb"
                />Find/Replace</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Performs a <i>find/replace</i> operation in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="algorithms">
      <title>Algorithms</title>
      <p>In <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, you can select the diff algorithm to use for the
        comparison using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/EC-Diff-Alg-Drop-down.png"
            id="image_jsr_gc4_wmb"/>Algorithm Drop-down menu</uicontrol> that is available on the
        toolbar. The following diff algorithms are available (depending on whether it is a two-way
        or three-way comparison):<ul id="ul_fqm_b5m_wmb">
          <li id="auto">
            <uicontrol>Auto (only available for two-way comparisons)</uicontrol> - Selects the most
            appropriate algorithm, based on the compared content and its size (selected by
            default).</li>
          <li id="characters">
            <uicontrol>Characters (only available for two-way comparisons)</uicontrol> - Computes
            the differences at character level, meaning that it compares two files or fragments
            looking for identical characters.<ph product="author editor"> This algorithm is not
              available when the file comparison is in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
          <li id="words">
            <uicontrol>Words (only available for two-way comparisons)</uicontrol> - Computes the
            differences at word level, meaning that it compares two files or fragments looking for
            identical words.<ph product="author editor"> This algorithm is not available when the
              file comparison is in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
          <li id="lines">
            <uicontrol>Lines</uicontrol> - Computes the differences at line level, meaning that it
            compares two files or fragments looking for identical lines of text.<ph
              product="author editor"> This algorithm is not available when the file comparison is
              in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
          <li id="syntax-aware">
            <uicontrol>Syntax Aware (only available for two-way comparisons)</uicontrol> - Computes
            differences for the file types or fragments known by <ph keyref="product"/>, taking the
            syntax (the specific types of tokens) into consideration.<ph product="author editor">
              This algorithm is not available when the file comparison is in
                <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
          <li id="xml-fast">
            <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> - Comparison that works well on large files or
            fragments, but it is less precise than <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li id="xml-accurate">
            <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> - Comparison that is more precise than
              <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol>, at the expense of speed. It compares two XML files or
            fragments looking for identical XML nodes.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p> In <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, only the <uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol>,
          <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms are
        available and you can select them from the <xref href="preferences-diff-EC.dita"
            ><uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> (easily accessible by clicking the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Settings16.png" id="image_oly_g4l_rlb"/>Diff
          Options</uicontrol> toolbar button).</p>
    </section>
    <section id="second_level_comparisons_author">
      <title>Second-Level Comparisons</title>
      <p>The comparison tool automatically performs a second-level comparison for the <uicontrol>XML
          Fast</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms. After the first
        comparison is finished, the second-level comparisons is processed on text nodes using a
        word-level comparison, meaning that it looks for identical words. This second-level
        comparison makes it easier to spot precise differences and you can merge or reject the
        precise modifications.</p>
    </section>
    <p>For more information about the visual editing support for JSON, watch our video
      demonstration:</p>
    <p><object width="450" height="250" data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hkInwKhtqvQ"
        outputclass="iframe">
        <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
      </object></p>
  </body>
</topic>
