<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="ec-file-comparison">
  <title>Visual File Comparison Tool</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Compare Files tool</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Two-way file comparison</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Three-way file comparison</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Diff Files tool</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Diff tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a visual file comparison tool that can be used to compare XML
      files. It makes it easier to see how the compared changes will look in the final output. It
      includes unique features such as actions to control the tags display mode, the ability to do
      second-level comparisons, and it presents differences made with <i>Change Tracking</i>
      enabled.</p>
    <p>The visual comparison tool is integrated with the built-in Eclipse comparison support and the
      visual comparison is presented automatically when you compare XML files. You can compare
      versions in the Workbench with versions in the repository, or with the local edit history. You
      can also compare three files if a common ancestor exists. The two editors are constantly
      synchronized and the differences are refreshed when you save the modified document.</p>
    <note>For some Eclipse distributions (such as Eclipse for Web Developers) the comparison is
      started automatically in the built-in Eclipse text mode comparison, to switch to visual
      comparison mode you can select <uicontrol>XML Compare</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu next
      to the words <i>Text Compare</i> in the top-left corner.</note>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Visual File Comparison Tool</title>
        <image href="../img/EC-file-compare.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="section_gnn_3cl_rlb">
      <title>How to Start a File Comparison</title>
      <p>There are various ways to automatically start the file comparison, but the most common ways
          are:<ul id="ul_dhd_lcl_rlb">
          <li>You can select two files (or three file if one of them is a common ancestor) in the
              <uicontrol>Project Explorer</uicontrol> view, right-click, and select one of the options in
            the <uicontrol>Compare With</uicontrol> menu (e.g. <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Compare With</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Each Other</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> to compare the selected files).</li>
          <li>If you use a versioning system, you can compare files directly from the
              <uicontrol>Synchronize</uicontrol> view (e.g. double-click a file or right-click
            selected files and choose <uicontrol>Open In Compare Editor</uicontrol>) or the
              <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="twoway_comparisons">
      <title>Highlight Colors</title>
      <p>The differences are also highlighted in several colors, depending on the type of change.
        The highlighting colors can be customized in the <xref
          href="preferences-diff-appearance-EC.dita"><menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Appearance</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> preferences page</xref>. The default colors and their shades mean the
          following:<ul id="ul_hh2_32l_rlb">
          <li><b>Pink</b> - Identifies modifications on either side. For 3-way comparisons, it
            identifies blocks of changes that include conflicts.</li>
          <li><b>Gray</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the left side (your outgoing
            changes). For 3-way comparisons, it identifies your outgoing changes that do not include
            conflicts.</li>
          <li><b>Blue</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the right side (incoming changes).
            For 3-way comparisons, it identifies incoming changes that do not include
            conflicts.</li>
          <li><b>Lighter Shade</b> - Identifies blocks of changes that can be merged in their
            entirety.</li>
          <li><b>Darker Shade</b> - Identifies specific changes within the blocks that can be merged
            more precisely.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_xcn_phl_rlb">
      <title>Navigating Differences</title>
      <p>To navigate through differences, do one of the following:<ul id="ul_lrm_q3f_lf">
          <li>Use the navigation buttons on the toolbar.</li>
          <li>Select a block of differences by clicking its small colored marker in the overview
            ruler located in the right-most part of the window. At the top of the overview ruler
            there is a success indicator that turns green where there are no differences, or red if
            differences are found.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_pf2_rhl_rlb">
      <title>Toolbar Actions</title>
      <sectiondiv>
        <p>A variety of actions are available on the toolbar:<dl>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Mode16.png" id="image_njj_hkl_rlb"/>Switch to
                  Text Mode</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Switches to the built-in Eclipse text mode file comparison.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="tags-display-mode">
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TagsDrop.png" id="image_xsp_rkl_rlb"/>Tags Display
                  Mode</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Allows you to select the amount of markup to be displayed in the editors. You can
                choose between: <uicontrol><image href="../img/FullTagsWithAttrs16.png"
                    id="image_gmv_lrm_wr"/> Full Tags with Attributes</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/FullTags16.png" id="image_y33_mrm_wr"/> Full Tags</uicontrol>,
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/BlockTags16.png" id="image_rcr_mrm_wr"/> Block
                  Tags</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image href="../img/InlineTags16.png"
                    id="image_usz_mrm_wr"/> Inline Tags</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/PartialTags16.png" id="image_qsh_nrm_wr"/> Partial
                Tags</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol><image href="../img/NoTags16.png"
                    id="image_ucq_nrm_wr"/> No Tags</uicontrol>.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Settings16.png" id="image_gvw_5kl_rlb"/>Diff
                  Options</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Opens the <xref href="preferences-diff-EC.dita"><uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol>
                  preferences page</xref> where you can configure various options.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Swap16.png" id="image_pp1_fll_rlb"/>Swap Left
                  and Right View</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Swaps the file in the left pane with the one in the right pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyLR16.png" id="image_ky2_sll_rlb"/>Copy All
                  Non-Conflicting Changes from Left to Right</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies all non-conflicting changes from the file in the left pane to the file in
                the right pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyRL16.png" id="image_szn_wll_rlb"/>Copy All
                  Non-Conflicting Changes from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies all non-conflicting changes from the file in the right pane to the file in
                the left pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyCurLR16.png" id="image_w5v_xll_rlb"/>Copy
                  Current Change from Left to Right</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies the current change from the file in the left pane to the file in the right
                pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-CopyCurRL16.png" id="image_kpf_yll_rlb"/>Copy
                  Current Change from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies the current change from the file in the right pane to the file in the left
                pane.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-NextDiff16.png" id="image_vrq_3k3_tc"/>Next
                  Difference</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Navigates to the next block of changes. This action is not available when the
                cursor is positioned on the last change block or when there are no changes.<note>A
                  change block groups one or more consecutive lines that contain at least one
                  change.</note></dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-PrevDiff16.png" id="image_lbz_hk3_tc"
                  />Previous Difference</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Jumps to the previous block of changes. This action is not available when the
                cursor is positioned on the first change block or when there are no changes.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-NextChange16.png" id="image_lbp_jk3_tc"/>Next
                  Change</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Jumps to the next change from the current block of changes. When the last change
                from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the next block of
                changes. This action is not available when the cursor is positioned on the last
                change or when there are no changes.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-PrevChange16.png" id="image_vc1_hk3_tc"
                  />Previous Change</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Jumps to the previous change from the current block of changes. When the first
                change from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the previous
                block of changes. This action is not available when the cursor is positioned on the
                first change or when there are no changes.</dd>
            </dlentry>
          </dl></p>
      </sectiondiv>
    </section>
    <section id="section_arf_4nl_rlb">
      <title>Contextual Menu Actions</title>
      <p>The following contextual menu actions are available in each editor pane:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Undo16.png" id="image_uw1_ggp_5r"
              />Undo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Undo changes in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Redo16.png" id="image_nzy_lgp_5r"
              />Redo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Redo changes in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Cut16.png" id="image_brg_3z1_5r"
              />Cut</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Cut the selection from the currently focused editor pane to the clipboard.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png" id="image_sf4_lst_tr"
              />Copy</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Copy the selection from the currently focused editor pane to the clipboard.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Paste16.png" id="image_cwr_cqt_tr"
              />Paste</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Paste content from the clipboard into the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Select all</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Selects all content in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Search16.png" id="image_kfr_14l_rlb"
                />Find/Replace</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Performs a <i>find/replace</i> operation in the currently focused editor pane.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="author_mode_algorithms">
      <title>Algorithms</title>
      <p>In the <xref href="preferences-diff-EC.dita"><uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol> preferences
          page</xref> (easily accessible by clicking the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/ecvc-Settings16.png" id="image_oly_g4l_rlb"/>Diff Options</uicontrol>
        toolbar button), you can select from the following diff algorithms to compare files in the
        visual comparison tool:<ul id="ul_dcn_yjp_fbb">
          <li>
            <uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - Selects the most appropriate algorithm, based on the
            compared content and its size (selected by default).</li>
          <li>
            <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> - Comparison that works well on large files or
            fragments, but it is less precise than <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>
            <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> - Comparison that is more precise than
              <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol>, at the expense of speed. It compares two XML files or
            fragments looking for identical XML nodes. </li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="second_level_comparisons_author">
      <title>Second-Level Comparisons</title>
      <p>The visual comparison tool automatically performs a second-level comparison for the
          <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms. After
        the first comparison is finished, the second-level comparisons is processed on text nodes
        using a word-level comparison, meaning that it looks for identical words. This second-level
        comparison makes it easier to spot precise differences and you can merge or reject the
        precise modifications.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
