<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="ec-open-url-dialog">
    <title>Open URL</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Open using FTP/SFTP/WebDAV dialog box</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>To access the <ph><uicontrol>Open using FTP/SFTP/WebDAV</uicontrol></ph> dialog box, go
      to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Open URL</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu, then choose the <uicontrol><image href="../img/OpenURL16.png"
          id="image_eqq_tcw_sr"/>Browse for remote file</uicontrol> option from the drop-down action
      list.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Open URL Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_ftp_webdav.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
        <p>The displayed dialog box is composed of several parts:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>The editable <uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> combo box, in which you specify the URL to
        be opened or saved. <note type="tip"> If the file is accessible through an anonymous FTP,
          you can type a URL like:
          <filepath>ftp://anonymous@some.site/home/test.xml</filepath>.</note>This combo box also
        displays the current selection when you change selection by browsing the tree of folders and
        files on the server.</li>
            <li>The <uicontrol>Identification</uicontrol> section contains the access credentials.
        If you want to browse for a file on a server, you have to specify the user and password.
        This information is bound to the selected URL and is also used in opening or saving the
        file. If the <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> checkbox is selected, the user and password are
        saved between editing sessions. The password is encrypted and kept in the options
          file.<note>Your password is well protected. If the options file is used on another machine
          by a user with a different user name the password, it will become unreadable since the
          encryption is user-name dependent. This is also true if you add URLs to your project that
          include a user and password.</note></li>
            <li>The <uicontrol>Browse for remote file</uicontrol> section contains the
          <uicontrol>Server URL</uicontrol> combo box and <uicontrol>Autoconnect</uicontrol>
        checkbox. In the <uicontrol>Server URL</uicontrol> combo box, you can specify the protocol,
        the server host name, or server IP.<note type="tip">When accessing a FTP server, you only
          need to specify the protocol and the host (such as <filepath>ftp://server.com</filepath>
          or if using a non-standard port <filepath>ftp://server.com:7800/</filepath>).</note><p>By
          pressing the <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol> button, the directory listing will be shown in
          the component. When <uicontrol>Autoconnect</uicontrol> is selected, every time the dialog
          box is displayed, the browse action will be performed.</p></li>
            <li>The bottom part of the dialog box displays the tree view of the documents stored on
        the server. You can browse the directories and make multiple selections. Additionally, you
        can use the <uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>New
          Folder</uicontrol> actions to manage the file repository.<p>The file names are sorted in a
          case-insensitive manner.</p></li>
        </ul>
    </body>
</topic>
