<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="editingActions">
  <title>Editing Actions in <ph keyref="webappProduct"/></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebApp<indexterm>Review Panel view</indexterm><indexterm>Attributes
            view</indexterm><indexterm>Find/Replace view</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> allows you to not only review documents, but to also make
      changes to them. To activate this mode, tap or click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button in
      the upper toolbar. In mobile devices, you can also swipe left, or use the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/WebappMenu18.png" id="image_w4c_wwg_5r"/>Menu</uicontrol> button, to display
      a side panel at the right side of the editing area. This panel provides you with access to
      several views and a variety of editing actions.<fig id="fig_hvx_yyf_wr">
        <title>Web Author Right-Side Menu Panel</title>
        <image href="../img/webapp_edit_views.png" id="image_ifz_1zf_wr"/>
      </fig> The following views can be accessed by using the options in the side panel on the right
      side of the editor:<ul id="ul_egv_3pb_gr">
        <li><uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> - Displays the tracked changes and comments made to the
          document by the content authors. </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> - Displays all possible attributes and their value.
          You can also edit attribute values.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> - Provides <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol> actions for searching the current document.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="contextual_menu_actions_desktop_version">
      <title>Contextual Menu Actions (Desktop Version)</title>
      <p>In a desktop web browser, the contextual menu also offers the following actions, along with
        framework-specific actions:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png"/>Copy</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to preview the content to be copied. You can then
              use the <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable_oxygen_shortcuts_list/ctrl_c">(</uicontrol>
              keyboard shortcut to copy the selected content to the clipboard (or invoke the
              contextual menu from that dialog box and choose the <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>
              action).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Paste16.png"/>Paste</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Inserts the current clipboard content into the document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Paste Special</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to choose how to paste copied content. You have
              to use the <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable_oxygen_shortcuts_list/ctrl_v"/> keyboard
              shortcut (or select <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol> from the contextual menu) to paste
              the copied content into the preview window in this <uicontrol>Paste
                Special</uicontrol> dialog box and then you can choose to paste it into your
              document with one of the following choices:<ul
                conkeyref="reusables-webapp/paste-special-options">
                <li/>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Cut16.png"/>Cut</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to preview the content to be cut. You can then
              use the <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable_oxygen_shortcuts_list/ctrl_x"/> keyboard
              shortcut to cut the selected content and copy it to the clipboard (or invoke the
              contextual menu from that dialog box and choose the <uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol>
              action).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Undo16.png"/>Undo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>This action is available after you make a change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Redo16.png"/>Redo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>This action is available when you use the <uicontrol>Undo</uicontrol> action.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertElement16.png"/>Insert Element</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Inserts an element at current position.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RenameElement16.png" id="image_z52_xxz_tr"/>Rename
                Element</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Renames the current element.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SurroundWithTag16.png"/>Surround
              With</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Allows you to choose a tag to enclose the selected content.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/AcceptChange16.png" placement="inline"/>Accept
                Change(s)</uicontrol>
            </dt>
            <dd>Available on changes when <uicontrol>Change Tracking</uicontrol> is enabled. It
              accepts the tracked change located at the cursor position and moves to the next
              change. If you select a part of a <i>delete</i> or <i>insert</i> change, only the
              selected content is accepted. If you select multiple changes, all of them are
              accepted. For an <i>insert</i> change, it means keeping the inserted text and for a
                <i>delete</i> change, it means removing the content from the document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RejectChange16.png" placement="inline"/>Reject
                Change(s)</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available on changes when <uicontrol>Change Tracking</uicontrol> is enabled. Rejects
              the tracked change located at the cursor position and moves to the next change. If you
              select a part of a <i>delete</i> or <i>insert</i> change, only the selected content is
              rejected. If you select multiple changes, all of them are rejected. For an
                <i>insert</i> change, it means removing the inserted text and for a <i>delete</i>
              change, it means preserving the original content from the document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/AddComment16.png" placement="inline"/>Add
                Comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Allows you to insert a comment on a selected fragment of text.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveComment16.png" placement="inline"/>Remove
                comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Removes a selected comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/EditComment16.png" placement="inline"/>Edit
                comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Edit Comment</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you to edit the
              selected comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
    <section id="frameworkspecific_actions_desktop_version">
      <title>Framework-Specific Actions (Desktop Version)</title>
      <p>Depending on the type of document you are editing, the toolbar contains a series of actions
        defined at framework level. Some of these actions are also available in the contextual menu.
          <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes built-in actions for <ph
          id="webapp_supported_frameworks">DITA, DocBook, TEI, and XHTML document types</ph>. These
        actions include:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Styling actions</dt>
            <dd>Most common styling actions, such as <uicontrol>Bold</uicontrol>,
                <uicontrol>Italic</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Underline</uicontrol>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Insert actions</dt>
            <dd>Actions that allows you to insert a variety of framework-specific objects, such as
              images, tables, paragraphs, and other elements.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>List actions</dt>
            <dd>Actions that allow you to create ordered and unordered lists, and add new items in
              them.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Table actions</dt>
            <dd>Actions that allow you to create a table and manage its structure (insert and delete
              rows and columns).</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
