<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="editing-xml-documents-author">
  <title>Editing XML Documents in Author Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode</indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing mode in <ph keyref="product"/> allows you to
      visually edit XML documents in a user-friendly interface that is similar to a WYSIWYG word
      processor. This makes structured authoring easier for people who are not familiar with XML and
      it also provides easier access to the XML structure for XML experts. <ph keyref="product"/>
      provides support for visually editing the most commonly used XML vocabularies in
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, including DITA, DocBook, TEI, and XHTML.</p>
    <p>Adding text content in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode is as simple as doing so in a
      standard text editor but the content is rendered similar to how you will see it in the output.
      Tables, images, and media objects (such as videos) are also rendered comparable to the output.
      You can even play audio and video objects directly in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and
      it includes an intuitive <xref href="image-map-editor.dita#image-map-editor">Image Map
        Editor</xref>. You can easily change the rendering by selecting one of the preset <xref
        keyref="glossentry_main-css-style"><term>main styles</term></xref> from the <xref
        href="selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles.dita#selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles/using_the_styles_dropdown_menu"
          ><uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down menu</xref> (available on the toolbar) and
      combine multiple <xref keyref="glossentry_alternate-css-style"><term>alternate
        styles</term></xref> that behave like layers. You can also use the options in the <xref
        href="author-display-markup.dita#author-display-markup"><uicontrol><image
            href="../img/TagsDrop.png" id="image_pmr_mhm_1s"/> Tags Display Mode</uicontrol>
        drop-down menu</xref> to control how much XML markup is displayed in
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and there are various features and views that provide
      information about the XML structure based upon your current location within the document.</p>
    <p><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode provides numerous helpful editing actions, many of which
      are specific to the type of document you are editing and it includes a variety of other
      powerful editing features, such as keyboard shortcuts, <xref
        href="author-drag-drop.dita#author-drag-drop">drag and drop support</xref>, a <xref
        href="smart-paste-support.dita#smart-paste-support"><term>Smart Paste</term>
        mechanism</xref>, and an <xref
        href="content-completion-author-mode.dita#content-completion-author-mode">intelligent
          <term>Content Completion Assistant</term></xref>. <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode also
      allows you to visualize and <xref
        href="profiling-conditional-text.dita#profiling-conditional-text">manage profiled
        content</xref>, you can collaborate with others with various <xref
        href="author-change-tracking.dita#author-change-tracking">review features</xref> (such as
      the ability to add comments, track changes, or highlight content), and includes many other
      unique features.</p>
    <p>To switch to this mode, click the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> button at the bottom of the
      editing area. <image href="../img/author_mode_button.png"/></p>
    <p>For more information about some of the features available in the visual
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing mode, watch our video demonstration:</p>
    <p><object width="450" height="250" data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bnQwJZD58wY"
        outputclass="iframe">
        <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
      </object></p>
  </body>
</topic>