<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="editing-JSON5">
  <title>Editing JSON5 Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>JSON5 documents<indexterm>Editing features</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_okg_cgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> includes  support for working with <b>JSON5</b>
      documents (files that have the <codeph>json5</codeph> file extension). The <term>JSON5</term>
      format is a superset of JSON that aims to alleviate some of the limitations of JSON by
      expanding its syntax to include some productions from <i>ECMAScript 5.1</i>.</p>
    <section id="section_mp3_5ld_rtb">
      <title>Editing JSON5 Documents</title>
      <p id="p_np3_5ld_rtb">You can edit JSON5 documents in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode
        editor in <ph keyref="product"/> and you have access to its usual text editing actions,
        along with other JSON5 editor-specific actions, including syntax highlighting, validation,
        formatting and indenting.</p>
      <note id="note_qyz_wbw_41c">The <uicontrol><image href="../img/PrettyPrint16.png"
            id="image_ss5_12g_t1c"/>Format and Indent</uicontrol> action works for JSON5 documents
        with limitations being that quotes are removed for keys and values are always double quoted
        (regardless of the initial quotation).</note>
      <p>It also includes a document template to help you get started with JSON5 documents. The
        template is called <uicontrol>JSON5</uicontrol> and it can be found in the <uicontrol>New
          Document</uicontrol> folder in the <xref href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa"
          product="developer editor json"><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> document wizard</xref><xref
          href="creating-from-templates.dita#creating-from-templates"
          product="developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>New from templates</uicontrol>
          wizard</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_xgs_cgg_t1c">
      <title>Outline View</title>
      <p>The <b>Outline</b> view for JSON5 documents displays the list of all the components of the
        document you are editing in a hierarchical (tree-like) representation. It is synchronized
        with the main editor so you can use the view to navigate to specific parts of the document
        and move or delete components. By default, it is displayed on the left side of the editor.
        If the view is not displayed, it can be opened by selecting it from the <b>Window</b> >
          <b>Show View</b> menu.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_bfn_tld_rtb">
      <title>Validation</title>
      <p id="p_z3g_cgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> includes built-in validation engine for JSON5
        documents to help keep them well-formed. JSON5 documents are validated automatically as you
        type and the validation engine detects syntax errors, based on the <xref
          href="https://spec.json5.org/" format="html" scope="external">JSON5 specification</xref>.
        One limitation is that hexadecimal values are not supported.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
