<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="editingActions">
  <title>Editing Actions in <ph keyref="webappProduct"/></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebApp<indexterm>Review Panel view</indexterm><indexterm>Attributes
            view</indexterm><indexterm>Find/Replace view</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> allows you to not only review documents, but to also make
      changes to them. To activate this mode, tap or click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button in
      the upper toolbar. In mobile devices, you can also swipe left, or use the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/WebappMenu18.png" id="image_w4c_wwg_5r"/>Menu</uicontrol> button, to display
      a side panel at the right side of the editing area. This panel provides you with access to
      several views and a variety of editing actions.<fig id="fig_hvx_yyf_wr">
        <image href="../img/webapp_edit_views.png" id="image_ifz_1zf_wr"/>
      </fig> The following views can be accessed by using the options in the side panel on the right
      side of the editor:<ul id="ul_egv_3pb_gr">
        <li><uicontrol>Review Panel</uicontrol> - Displays the tracked changes and comments made to
          the document by the content authors. </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> - Displays all possible attributes and their value.
          You can also edit attribute values.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> - Provides <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol> actions for searching the current document.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>In a desktop web browser, the contextual menu also offers the following actions, along with
      framework-specific actions:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Undo</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This action is available in the contextual menu only after you make a change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Redo</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This action is available in the contextual menu only after you use the
              <uicontrol>Undo</uicontrol> action.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert Element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts an element at current position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Rename Element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Renames the current element.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Add Comment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to insert a comment on a selected fragment of text.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <section>
      <title>Framework Specific Actions</title>
      <p>Depending on the type of document you are editing, the toolbar contains a series of actions
        defined at framework level. <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> comes with built-in actions for <ph
          id="webapp_supported_frameworks">DITA, DocBook, TEI, and XHTML document types</ph>. These
        actions include:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Styling actions</dt>
            <dd>Most common styling actions, such as <uicontrol>Bold</uicontrol>,
                <uicontrol>Italic</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Underline</uicontrol>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Insert actions</dt>
            <dd>Actions that allows you to insert a variety of framework-specific objects, such as
              images, tables, paragraphs, and other elements.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>List actions</dt>
            <dd>Actions that allow you to create ordered and unordered lists, and add new items in
              them.</dd>
          </dlentry>
           <dlentry>
            <dt>Table actions</dt>
            <dd>Actions that allow you to create a table and manage its structure (insert and delete
              rows and columns).</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
