<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="editor-variables">
  <title>Editor Variables</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>editor variables</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>An editor variable is a shorthand notation for context-dependent information, like a file or
      folder path, a time-stamp, or a date. It is used in the definition of a command (for example
      the input URL of a transformation, the output file path of a transformation, the command line
      of an external tool) to make a command or a parameter generic and reusable with other input
      files. When the same command is applied to different files, the notation is expanded at the
      execution of the command so that the same command has different effects depending on the
      actual file.</p>
    <p>You can use the following editor variables in <ph
        keyref="product"/> commands of external
      engines or other external tools, in transformation scenarios, <ph product="authorSDK">and
        in</ph> validation scenarios<ph product="editor author editorEclipse authorEclipse">, and
        Author operations</ph>:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>${oxygenHome}</uicontrol> - <ph keyref="product"/> installation folder as
        URL;</li>
      <li id="edVar-oxygenInstallDir"><uicontrol>${oxygenInstallDir}</uicontrol> - <ph
          keyref="product"/> installation folder as file path;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${framework}</uicontrol> - The path (as URL) of the current framework, as part
        of the <filepath>frameworks</filepath> subfolder of the <ph keyref="product"/> install
        folder;</li>
      <li id="edVar-frameworks"><uicontrol>${frameworks}</uicontrol> - The path (as URL) of the
          <filepath>frameworks</filepath> subfolder of the <ph keyref="product"/> install
        folder;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${frameworkDir}</uicontrol> - The path (as file path) of the current framework,
        as part of the <filepath>frameworks</filepath> subfolder of the <ph keyref="product"/>
        install folder;</li>
      <li id="edVar-frameworksDir"><uicontrol>${frameworksDir}</uicontrol> - The path (as file path)
        of the <filepath>frameworks</filepath> subfolder of the <ph keyref="product"/> installation
        folder;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${home}</uicontrol> - The path (as URL) of the user home folder;</li>
      <li id="edVar-homeDir"><uicontrol>${homeDir}</uicontrol> - The path (as file path) of the user
        home folder;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${pdu}</uicontrol> - Current project folder as URL. Usually the current folder
        selected in the Project View;</li>
      <li id="edVar-pd"><uicontrol>${pd}</uicontrol> - Current project folder as file path. Usually
        the current folder selected in the Project View;</li>
      <li id="edVar-pn"><uicontrol>${pn}</uicontrol> - Current project name;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${cfdu}</uicontrol> - Current file folder as URL, that is the path of the
        current edited document up to the name of the parent folder, represented as a URL;</li>
      <li id="edVar-cfd"><uicontrol>${cfd}</uicontrol> - Current file folder as file path, that is
        the path of the current edited document up to the name of the parent folder;</li>
      <li id="edVar-cfn"><uicontrol>${cfn}</uicontrol> - Current file name without extension and
        without parent folder. The current file is the one currently opened and selected;</li>
      <li id="edVar-cfne"><uicontrol>${cfne}</uicontrol> - Current file name with extension. The
        current file is the one currently opened and selected;</li>
      <li id="edvar-cf"><uicontrol>${cf}</uicontrol> - Current file as file path, that is the
        absolute file path of the current edited document;</li>
      <li id="edVar-cfu"><uicontrol>${cfu}</uicontrol> - The path of the current file as a URL. The
        current file is the one currently opened and selected;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${af}</uicontrol> - The local file path of the ZIP archive that includes the
        current edited document;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${afu}</uicontrol> - The URL path of the ZIP archive that includes the current
        edited document;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${afd}</uicontrol> - The local directory path of the ZIP archive that includes
        the current edited document;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${afdu}</uicontrol> - The URL path of the directory of the ZIP archive that
        includes the current edited document;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${afn}</uicontrol> - The file name (without parent directory and without file
        extension) of the zip archive that includes the current edited file;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${afne}</uicontrol> - The file name (with file extension, for example
          <filepath>.zip</filepath> or <filepath>.epub</filepath>, but without parent directory) of
        the zip archive that includes the current edited file;</li>
      <li id="edVar-currentFileURL"><uicontrol>${currentFileURL}</uicontrol> - Current file as URL,
        that is the absolute file path of the current edited document represented as URL;</li>
      <li id="edVar-ps"><uicontrol>${ps}</uicontrol> - Path separator, that is the separator which
        can be used on the current platform (Windows, Mac OS X, Linux) between library files
        specified in the class path;</li>
      <li id="edvar-timestamp"><uicontrol>${timeStamp}</uicontrol> - Time stamp, that is the current
        time in Unix format. It can be used for example to save transformation results in different
        output files on each transform;</li>
      <li id="edVar-caret"><uicontrol>${caret}</uicontrol> - The position where the caret is
        inserted. This variable can be used in a code template, in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        operations, or in a selection plugin;</li>
      <li id="edvar-selection"><uicontrol>${selection}</uicontrol> - The current selected text
        content in the current edited document. This variable can be used in a code template, in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> operations, or in a selection plugin;</li>
      <li id="edVar-id"><ph id="id_editor_variable"><uicontrol>${id}</uicontrol> - Application-level
          unique identifier;A short sequence of 10-12 letters and digits which is not guaranteed to
          be universally unique</ph>;</li>
      <li id="edvar-uuid"><ph id="uuid_editor_variable"><uicontrol>${uuid}</uicontrol> - Universally
          unique identifier;An unique sequence of 32 hexadecimal digits generated by the Java <xref
            href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/util/UUID.html" format="html"
            scope="external">UUID</xref> class</ph>;</li>
      <li id="edvar-env"><uicontrol>${env(VAR_NAME)}</uicontrol> - Value of the
          <term>VAR_NAME</term> environment variable. The environment variables are managed by the
        operating system. If you are looking for Java System Properties, use the
          <uicontrol>${system(var.name)}</uicontrol> editor variable;</li>
      <li id="edVar-system"><uicontrol id="java_system_properties">${system(var.name)}</uicontrol> -
        Value of the <term>var.name</term> Java System Property. The Java system properties can be
        specified in the command line arguments of the Java runtime as
          <codeph>-Dvar.name=var.value</codeph>. If you are looking for operating system environment
        variables, use the<uicontrol>${env(VAR_NAME)}</uicontrol> editor variable instead;</li>
      <li id="edVar-ask"><uicontrol> ${ask('message', type, ('real_value1':'rendered_value1';
          'real_value2':'rendered_value2'; ...), 'default_value')} </uicontrol> - To prompt for
        values at runtime, use the <i>ask('message', type, ('real_value1':'rendered_value1';
          'real_value2':'rendered_value2'; ...), 'default-value'')</i> editor variable. You can set
        the following parameters:<ul>
          <li><codeph>'message'</codeph> - the displayed message. Note the quotes that enclose the
            message;</li>
          <li><codeph>type</codeph> - optional parameter. Can have one of the following values:<ul>
              <li><codeph>url</codeph> - input is considered an URL. <ph keyref="product"/> checks
                that the URL is valid before passing it to the transformation;</li>
              <li><codeph>password</codeph> - input characters are hidden;</li>
              <li><codeph>generic</codeph> - the input is treated as generic text that requires no
                special handling;</li>
              <li><codeph>relative_url</codeph> - input is considered an URL. <ph keyref="product"/>
                tries to make the URL relative to that of the document you are editing;<note>You can
                  use the <codeph>$ask</codeph> editor variable in file templates. In this case, <ph
                    keyref="product"/> keeps an absolute URL.</note></li>
              <li><codeph>combobox</codeph> - displays a dialog that contains a non-editable
                combo-box;</li>
              <li><codeph>editable_combobox</codeph> - displays a dialog that contains an editable
                combo-box;</li>
              <li><codeph>radio</codeph> - displays a dialog that contains radio buttons;</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><codeph>'default-value'</codeph> - optional parameter. Provides a default value in the
            input text box;<p id="edVar-ask-examples"><b>Examples:</b><ul>
                <li><codeph>${ask('message')}</codeph> - Only the message displayed for the user is
                  specified.</li>
                <li><codeph>${ask('message', generic, 'default')}</codeph> -
                    <codeph>'message'</codeph> is displayed, the type is not specified (the default
                  is string), the default value is <codeph>'default'</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph>${ask('message', password)}</codeph> - <codeph>'message'</codeph> is
                  displayed, the characters typed are masked with a circle symbol.</li>
                <li><codeph>${ask('message', password, 'default')}</codeph> - same as before, the
                  default value is <codeph>'default'</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph>${ask('message', url)}</codeph> - <codeph>'message'</codeph> is
                  displayed, the parameter type is URL.</li>
                <li><codeph>${ask('message', url, 'default')}</codeph> - same as before, the default
                  value is <codeph>'default'</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></p></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li id="edVar-date"><uicontrol>${date(pattern)}</uicontrol> - Current date. The allowed
        patterns are equivalent to the ones in the <xref
          href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/text/SimpleDateFormat.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Java SimpleDateFormat class</xref>. Example:
          yyyy-MM-dd;<note>This editor variable supports both the <parmname>xs:date</parmname> and
            <parmname>xs:datetime</parmname> parameters. For details about
            <parmname>xs:date</parmname>, go to <xref href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/#date"
            format="html" scope="external">http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/#date</xref>. For
          details about <parmname>xs:datetime</parmname>, go to <xref
            href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/#dateTime" format="html" scope="external"
            >http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/#dateTime</xref>.</note></li>
      <li id="edVar-dbgXML"><uicontrol>${dbgXML}</uicontrol> - The local file path to the XML
        document which is current selected in the Debugger source combo box (for tools started from
        the XSLT/XQuery Debugger);</li>
      <li id="edVar-dbgXSL"><uicontrol>${dbgXSL}</uicontrol> - The local file path to the XSL/XQuery
        document which is current selected in the Debugger stylesheet combo box (for tools started
        from the XSLT/XQuery Debugger);</li>
      <li id="edVar-tsf"><uicontrol>${tsf}</uicontrol> - The transformation result file path. If the
        current opened file has an associated scenario which specifies a transformation output file,
        this variable expands to it;</li>
      <li id="edVar-dsu"><uicontrol>${dsu}</uicontrol> - The path of the detected schema as an URL
        for the current validated XML document;</li>
      <li id="edVar-ds"><uicontrol>${ds}</uicontrol> - The path of the detected schema as a local
        file path for the current validated XML document;</li>
      <li id="edVar_cp"><uicontrol>${cp}</uicontrol> - Current page number. Used to display the
        current page number on each printed page in the <b>Editor / Print</b> Preferences page;</li>
      <li id="edVar_tp"><uicontrol>${tp}</uicontrol> - Total number of pages in the document. Used
        to display the total number of pages on each printed page in the <b>Editor / Print</b>
        Preferences page.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>${xpath_eval(expression)}</uicontrol> - Evaluates an XPath 3.0 expression.
        Depending on the context, the expression can be:<ul id="ul_bby_sss_wn">
          <li><term>static</term>, when executed in a non-XML context. For example, you can use such
            static expressions to perform string operations on other editor variables for composing
            the name of the output file in a transformation scenario's <b>Output</b>
                tab.<p><b>Example:</b></p><p>
              <codeblock>${xpath_eval(upper-case(substring('${cfn}', 1, 4)))}</codeblock>
            </p></li>
          <li><term>dynamic</term>, when executed in an XML context. For example, you can use such
            dynamic expression in a code template or as a value of an author operation's
                parameter.<p><b>Example:</b></p><p>
              <codeblock>${ask('Set new ID attribute', generic, '${xpath_eval(@id)}')}</codeblock>
            </p></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>${i18n(key)}</uicontrol> - Editor variable used only at document type/framework
        level to allow translating names and descriptions of Author actions in multiple actions.
        More details here:<xref href="localizing_frameworks.dita"/>.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
  <related-links product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse">
    <link href="code-templates.dita#code-templates"/>
    <link href="../concepts/selection-plugin.dita#selection-plugin" product="editor author"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
