<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="editing-dita-maps">
  <title>Editing DITA Maps</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>DITA Maps</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a special view for editing DITA Maps. The <uicontrol>DITA
        Maps Manager</uicontrol> view presents a DITA Map in a simplified table-of-contents manner.
      It allows you to navigate easily to the referred topics and maps, make changes, and apply
      transformation scenarios to obtain various output formats. The DITA-OT framework that is
      bundled with <ph keyref="product"/> is used.</p>
    <fig id="figure-dita-maps-manager-view-oxygen" product="editor author">
      <title>The DITA Maps Manager View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_dita_maps_manager_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="figure-dita-maps-manager-view-oxygenEclipse" product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
      <title>The DITA Maps Manager View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_dita_maps_manager_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p product="editor author">The view supports opening multiple documents at the same time.</p>
    <p product="editor author">All files that have the <filepath>.ditamap</filepath> or
        <filepath>.bookmap</filepath> extension are opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
        Manager</uicontrol> view. In addition, you can right click the file in the
        <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view and select <uicontrol>Open with</uicontrol>. If you
      opened the DITA Map file in the editor panel you can open it also in this special DITA Map
      view by right clicking on the title tab of the editor panel and selecting the <uicontrol>Open
        in DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> action from the popup menu.</p>
    <p product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">To open a DITA Map from the
        <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view,
      right click it and select <uicontrol>Open in DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>. The titles of the
      referenced resources are resolved and displayed in the view dynamically when navigating the
      tree. After the DITA Map is opened, you can open it in the main editor for further
      customization using the <uicontrol>Open Map in Editor</uicontrol> toolbar action.</p>
    <p>You can move topics in the same map or between different maps by dragging and dropping them
      into the desired position. Also, you can copy topics by dragging them while pressing the
        <b>Ctrl</b> (<b>Meta</b> on Mac OS) key.</p>
    <p>The toolbar includes the actions which are also available on menu <uicontrol>DITA
        Maps</uicontrol>:</p>
    <ul>
      <li product="author editor"><uicontrol><image href="../img/open_dropdown.png"/>
          Reopen</uicontrol> - You can use this drop-down to reopen recently viewed DITA Maps. Apart
        from the history of the recently viewed DITA Maps, the drop-down also contains the
          <uicontrol>Clear history</uicontrol> , <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/bt_open_local_file.png"/> Open</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/bt_open_remote_file.png"/> Open URL</uicontrol> actions;</li>
      <li product="author editor"><uicontrol>Clear history</uicontrol> - Removes the list with the
        recently viewed DITA Maps;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_local_file.png"/> Open</uicontrol> - Allows opening
        the map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view. You can also open a map by
        dragging it in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view from the file system
        explorer;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_remote_file.png"/> Open URL</uicontrol> - Allows
        opening remote maps in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view. See <xref
          href="opening-saving-ftp-webdav.dita">Open URL</xref> for details;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Open from Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> - Allows you to open a DITA Map from
        a data source explorer;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_svn_save_button.png"/> Save <shortcut>(Ctrl (Meta on Mac
            OS)+S)</shortcut></uicontrol> - Saves the current DITA Map;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_validate_and_check_button.png"/> Validate and Check for
          Completeness</uicontrol> - <xref href="dita-map-validate.dita#dita-map-validate"
          format="dita" product="editor editorEclipse author authorEclipse">Checks the validity and
          integrity</xref> of the map;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ApplyStyleSheet16.png"/> Apply Transformation
          Scenario(s)</uicontrol> - <xref
          href="dita-map-run-Ant-transform.dita#dita-map-run-Ant-transform" format="dita">Applies
          the DITA Map transformation scenario</xref> that is associated with the current map from
        the view;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_transform_config.png"/> Configure Transformation
          Scenario(s)...</uicontrol> - Allows <xref
          href="config-DITA-transformation.dita#config-DITA-transformation" format="dita"
          >associating a DITA Map transformation</xref> scenario with the current map;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_refresh_references.png"/> Refresh References</uicontrol>
        - You can use this action to manually trigger a refresh and update of all titles of referred
        topics. This action is useful when the referred topics are modified externally. When they
        are modified and saved from the <ph
          keyref="product"/> Author, the DITA Map is
        updated automatically;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_map_in_editor_resolved_topics.png"/> Open Map in
          Editor with Resolved Topics</uicontrol> - Opens the DITA Map in the main editor area with
        content from all topic references expanded in-place; Content from the referenced topics is
        presented as read-only and you have to use the contextual menu action <b>Edit Reference</b>
        to open the topic for editing.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_map_in_editor.png"/> Open Map in Editor</uicontrol>
        - For complex operations which cannot be performed in the simplified DITA Maps view (like
        editing a relationship table) you can open the map in the main editing area;<note>You can
          also use this action to open referenced DITA Maps in the
          <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_link_with_editor.png"/> Link with Editor</uicontrol> -
        Disables/Enables the synchronization between the file path of the current editor and the
        selected topic reference in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view;<note>This
          button is disabled automatically when you move to the <uicontrol>Debugger</uicontrol>
          perspective.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_profiling_button.png"/> Profiling/Conditional
          Text</uicontrol> menu with the following actions:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Show Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> - Enables/Disables displaying the
            values of the profiling attributes at the end of the titles of topic references. When
            enabled, the values of the profiling attributes are displayed both in the
              <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view and in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
            editor;</li>
          <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_options_shortcut.png"/> Configure Profiling
              Condition Sets ...</uicontrol> - Opens the preferences page for adding and editing the
            profiling conditions that you can apply in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>
            view and the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editor. When a profiling condition set is
            applied, the keys defined in the DITA map are gathered by filtering out the excluded
            content;</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
    <p>If your map references other DITA Maps they will be shown expanded in the DITA Maps tree and
      you will also be able to navigate their content. For editing you will have to open each
      referenced map in a separate editor. You can choose not to expand referenced maps in the
        <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view or referenced content in the opened editors by
      unchecking the <uicontrol>Display referred content</uicontrol> checkbox available in the <xref
        href="preferences-author.dita">Author preferences page</xref>.</p>
    <note type="tip" product="authorEclipse editorEclipse"> The additional edit toolbar can be shown
      by clicking the "Show/Hide additional toolbar" expand button located on the general
      toolbar.</note>
    <p> The following edit actions can be performed on an opened DITA Map: <ul>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_topic_ref.png"/> Insert Reference</uicontrol> -
          Inserts a reference to a topic file. You can find more details about this action in the
            <xref href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref" format="dita">Inserting a
            Reference, a Key Definition, a Topic Set</xref> topic;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Topichead20.png"/> Insert Topic Heading</uicontrol> -
          Inserts a topic heading. You can find more details about this action in the <xref
            href="dita-insert-topic-head.dita#dita-insert-topic-head" format="dita">Inserting a
            Topic Heading</xref> topic;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Topicgroup16.png"/> Insert Topic Group</uicontrol> -
          Inserts a topic group. You can find more details about this action in the <xref
            href="dita-insert-topic-group.dita#dita-insert-topic-group" format="dita"/> topic;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/DockableFrameProperties16.png"/> Edit
            Properties</uicontrol> - Edit the properties of a selected node. You can find more
          details about this action in the <xref
            href="dita-edit-properties.dita#dita-edit-properties" format="dita"/> topic;</li>
        <li conref="author-contextual-menu.dita#author-contextual-menu/edit_profiling_attributes"/>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_edit_attributes.png"/> Edit Attributes</uicontrol> -
          Allows you to edit all the attributes of a selected node. You can find more details about
          this action in the <xref href="author-attributes-view.dita#author-attributes-view"
            format="dita"/> topic;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Rename resource</uicontrol> - allows you to <xref
            href="move-rename-resource.dita#move-rename-resource">change the name of a resource
            linked in the edited DITA Map</xref>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Move resource</uicontrol> - allow you to <xref
            href="move-rename-resource.dita#move-rename-resource">change the location on disk of a
            resource linked in the edited DITA Map</xref>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif"/> Delete</uicontrol> - Deletes the
          selected node;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_up.png"/> Move Up</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_up_arrow"/>) - Moves the
          selected nodes in front of their respective previous siblings;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_down.png"/> Move Down</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_down_arrow"/>) - Moves the
          selected nodes after their next respective siblings;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_promote.png"/> Promote</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_left_arrow"/>) - Moves the
          selected nodes after their respective parents as siblings;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_demote.png"/> Demote</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
            conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_right_arrow"/>) - Moves the
          selected nodes as children to their respective previous siblings;<note>As an alternative
            to these actions, you can select one or multiple topics, then drag and drop them to the
            desired position inside the map.</note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Root map</uicontrol> - specifies a master DITA Map that <ph keyref="product"
          /> uses to establish a key space which you can use with any other DITA Map that the master
          one imports.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstrations about DITA editing and DITA Maps Manager view, go to <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/DITA_Editing.html" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://oxygenxml.com/demo/DITA_Editing.html</xref> and <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/DITA_Maps_Manager.html" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://oxygenxml.com/demo/DITA_Maps_Manager.html</xref> respectively.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="dita-map-validate.dita#dita-map-validate"/>
    <link href="config-DITA-transformation.dita#config-DITA-transformation"/>
    <link href="dita-map-run-Ant-transform.dita#dita-map-run-Ant-transform"/>
    <link href="author-dita-map-extensions.dita"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>