<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="editing-wsdl-documents">
  <title>Editing WSDL Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing WSDL Documents</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>WSDL is an XML format for describing network services as a set of endpoints operating on
      messages containing either document-oriented or procedure-oriented information. The operations
      and messages are described abstractly, and then bound to a concrete network protocol and
      message format to define an endpoint. Related concrete endpoints are combined into abstract
      endpoints (services).</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a special type of editor dedicated to WSDL documents. The
      WSDL editor offers support to check whether a WSDL document is valid, a specialized Content
      Completion Assistant, a component oriented <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view, searching and
      refactoring operations, and support to generate documentation.</p>
    <p>Both WSDL version 1.1 and 2.0 are supported and SOAP versions 1.1 and 1.2. That means that in
      the location where a SOAP extension can be inserted the <uicontrol>Content Completion
        Assistant</uicontrol> offers elements from both SOAP 1.1 and SOAP 1.2. Validation of SOAP
      requests is executed first against a SOAP 1.1 schema and then against a SOAP 1.2 schema. In
      addition to validation against the XSD schemas, <ph keyref="product"/> also checks if the WSDL
      file conforms with the WSDL specification (available only for WSDL 1.1 and SOAP 1.1).</p>
    <p>In the following example you can see how the errors are reported.</p>
    <fig product="editor developer">
      <title>Validating a WSDL file</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_validating_wsdl.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>Validating a WSDL file</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_validating_wsdl.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the WSDL editing support in <ph keyref="product"/>, go
      to <xref href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/Create_New_WSDL.html" format="html"
        scope="external">http://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/Create_New_WSDL.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
