<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="enabling-the-master-files-support">
  <title>Enabling the Master Files Support</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> stores the master files in a folder located in the <uicontrol
        product="author developer editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</uicontrol> view, as the
      first child of the project root. The <uicontrol>Master Files</uicontrol> support is disabled
      by default. <ph product="author developer editor">To enable the <uicontrol>Master
          Files</uicontrol> support, go to the <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> menu of the
          <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view and select <uicontrol>Enable Master Files
          Support</uicontrol>. You can also select <uicontrol>Enable Master Files
          Support</uicontrol> from the contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Master Files</uicontrol>
        directory, or from the contextual menu of the project itself.</ph><ph
        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">To enable the <uicontrol>Master
          Files</uicontrol> support, use the  <uicontrol>Enable Master Files Support</uicontrol>
        action from the contextual menu of the project itself.</ph>
      <ph keyref="product"/> allows you to enable/disable the <uicontrol>Master Files</uicontrol>
      support for each project you are working on.</p>
    <p product="author developer editor">When the master files support is disabled <ph
        keyref="product"/> displays a window tip located at the bottom of the project view. This
      window contains an <uicontrol>Enable</uicontrol> button and a <uicontrol>read
        more...</uicontrol> option. Clicking the <uicontrol>read more</uicontrol> option takes you
      to the user guide. Clicking the <uicontrol>Enable</uicontrol> button opens the
        <uicontrol>Enable Master Files</uicontrol> dialog. This dialog contains general information
      about the <uicontrol>Master Files</uicontrol> support and allows you to enable the support.
      You can also use the <uicontrol>Detect and Enable</uicontrol> option to detect the master
      files from the current project. <note>Once you close this window tip, <ph keyref="product"/>
        hides it for all projects. To make the window tip reappear, restore <ph keyref="product"/>
        to its default settings.</note><note> Restoring <ph keyref="product"/> to its default
        settings causes loss of your customized options.</note></p>
  </body>
</topic>
