<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-create-conkeyref">
  <title>Creating a DITA Content Key Reference</title>
  <body>
    <p>A DITA content key reference, or <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>, is a mechanism for inserting a
      piece of content from one topic into another. It is a version of the <xref
        keyref="dita.insert-conref">DITA content reference mechanism</xref> that uses <xref
        keyref="dita.background.keys">keys</xref> to locate the content to reuse rather than direct
      references to topics that contain reused content. </p>
    <p>As with a <term>conref</term>, a <term>conkeyref</term> requires that the element to be
      reused has an <codeph>id</codeph> attribute. It also requires the topic that contains the
      reusable content to be assigned a <xref keyref="dita.background.keys">key</xref> in a map. As
      with all uses of keys, you can substitute multiple maps or <xref keyref="dita.profiling">use
        profiling</xref> to create more than one definition of keys in a single map. </p>
    <p>This allows you to substitute different pieces of content for the same
        <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>. In other words, the same <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> can pull in
      content from various different sources, depending on how your build is configured. This can
      make it easier to create and manage sophisticated content reuse scenarios. </p>
    <p>To add a content key reference to a topic:</p>
    <ol id="ol_ocz_fcb_bq">
      <li>In <xref keyref="mode.author"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode</xref>, place the caret
        where you want the reused content to be inserted.</li>
      <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conkeyref20.png" id="image_zls_mrx_xr"/>Insert a
          DITA Content Key Reference</uicontrol> button on the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> toolbar.
        The <wintitle>Insert Content Key Reference</wintitle> dialog box is displayed.</li>
      <li>Select the key for the topic that contains the content you want to reuse and press the
          <uicontrol>Subtopic</uicontrol> button.</li>
      <li>Select the <uicontrol>Element ID</uicontrol> of the element that you want to insert, and
        verify the content in the <wintitle>Preview</wintitle> pane.</li>
      <li>Make any other selections you need in the <xref keyref="dita.insert-conref-dialog"
            ><wintitle>Insert Content Reference</wintitle> dialog box</xref>.</li>
      <li>Click <uicontrol>Insert and close</uicontrol>.</li>
    </ol>
  </body>
</topic>

