<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-inline-linking">
  <title>Inline Linking in DITA</title>
  <body>
    <p>You can create inline links in the content of a DITA topic using the <codeph>xref</codeph>
      element. To insert a link in <ph keyref="product"/>
      <xref keyref="mode_author"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode</xref>, use the actions
      available in the <uicontrol><image href="../img/LinkDrop.png" id="image_nbp_mkx_sr"
        />Link</uicontrol> drop-down menu from the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> Toolbar.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Linking Using Keys</title>
      <p>To make links easier to manage, you may choose to use <xref keyref="dita_background_keys"
          >keys</xref> for linking, rather than creating direct links to topics. By using keys, you
        avoid creating a direct dependency between topics, which can make it easier to reuse topics
        in various publications. It can also be helpful in verifying the completeness of a
        publication, by ensuring that a publication map provides a key definition for every key
        reference used in the content. </p>
      <p>Links based on keys require two pieces. The first piece is a key definition, which assigns
        a key to a topic so that other topics can link to it. The second piece is a key reference,
        which is created in an <codeph>xref</codeph> element and specifies the key to link to. Thus,
        the key reference points to a key definition, and the key definition points to a topic. </p>
      <p>Key definitions are created in maps, as an element on the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element
        that points to a topic. Thus, a key reference points to a key definition on a
          <codeph>topicref</codeph> that points to a topic. </p>
      <p>This allows you to assign a particular key to one topic in one map and to another topic in
        another map. When a topic that links to that key is used in each of these maps, the links
        work correctly in both maps.<note>You can define more than one key on the same topic
          reference. Topics can link to any of the keys. This allows you to have topics that link to
          various keys that are linked to the same topic in one map and to other topics in another
          map.</note></p>
    </section>
    <?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150709T114430+0300" comment="Revise once EXM-33518 is done."?>
    <section>
      <title>Adding a Key to a Map</title>
      <p>To add a key to a map:</p>
      <ol id="ol_g4q_xpm_1q">
        <li>In the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>, right-click the topic reference to which
          you want to add a key and choose <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>. The
            <wintitle>Edit Properties</wintitle> dialog box is displayed.</li>
        <li>Enter the key value in the <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> field. </li>
        <li>Make sure to save the changes to the DITA map before attempting to insert the key
          reference in your topic.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <?oxy_comment_end?>
    <section>
      <title>Creating a Link Using a Key</title>
      <p>To create a link using a key:</p>
      <ol id="ol_zzc_nrm_1q">
        <li>In <xref keyref="mode_author"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode</xref>, highlight the
          text you want to be a link.</li>
        <li>Select <uicontrol>Key Reference...</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/LinkDrop.png" id="image_srt_qkx_sr"/>Link</uicontrol> drop-down menu that
          is available in the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> Toolbar. The <wintitle>Insert Key
            Reference</wintitle> dialog box is displayed.</li>
        <li>Use the filter field to find the key you want to link to, then select it and click
            <uicontrol>Insert and close</uicontrol>. The link is created in your topic.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
