<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo.dita.tables">
  <title>Adding Tables to a DITA Topic</title>
  <body>
    <p>You can add a table to a DITA topic. By default, DITA supports two types of tables, the DITA
      simple table model, and the OASIS Exchange Table Model (a subset of the CALS table model). If
      you are using a specialized DITA vocabulary, it may contain specialized versions of these
      table models. </p>
    <p>Because DITA is a structured format, you can only insert a table in places in the structure
      of a topic where tables are allowed. The <ph keyref="product"/> DITA toolbar provides support
      for entering and editing tables. It also indicates where you are allowed to insert a table or
      its components by graying out the appropriate buttons.</p>
    <fig id="fig_z5n_k5q_zp">
      <title>The DITA Toolbar</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> toolbar showing the insert table button available and the
        table editing buttons grayed out:</p>
      <image href="../img/sa_dita_toolbar.png" id="image_hyq_wyr_zp"/>
    </fig>
    <section><title>Inserting a DITA Simple Table</title><ol id="ol_v5v_tsq_zp">
        <li>To insert a DITA simple table, click the table button on the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
          toolbar. The <wintitle>Insert Table</wintitle> dialog appears.</li>
        <li>Select the <uicontrol>Simple</uicontrol> model. </li>
        <li>Select the appropriate options for rows and columns, creating a header, column widths,
          and framing of cells.</li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>. The table is inserted.</li>
      </ol><image href="../img/simple_table.png" id="image_aj5_qxr_zp"/></section>
    <section><title>Inserting an OASIS Exchange Table Model (CALS) Table</title>To insert an OASIS
      Exchange Table, follow the same procedure as above, but choose the CALS model. Additional
      options for specifying row and column separators and alignment will be enabled.</section>
    <section><p>When you insert a CALS table, you see a link for setting the
          <codeph>colspecs</codeph> (column specifications) of your table. Click the link to open
        the <codeph>colspec</codeph> controls. Although they appear as part of the <xref
          keyref="mode.author"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> view</xref>, the
          <codeph>colspec</codeph> link and the <codeph>colspec</codeph> controls will not appear in
        your output. They are just there to make it easier to adjust how the columns of your table
        are formatted.</p><image href="../img/cals_table.png" id="image_ntl_fwr_zp"/></section>
    <section>
      <title>Editing an Existing Table</title>
      <p>You can edit the structure of an existing table using the table buttons on the
          <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> toolbar to add or remove cells, rows, or columns, and to set
        basic table properties. However, both the DITA simple table and the OASIS Exchange Table
        (CALS) have many additional attributes, on both the table elements and the row and cell
        elements, that can be used to fine-tune the formatting of your tables. The easiest way to
        adjust these attributes is to open the <xref keyref="edit.views.attributes"
            ><wintitle>Attributes</wintitle> view</xref> (<menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Attributes</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>). See the DITA documentation for a full explanation of these attributes.</p>
      <p>Also, remember that underneath the visual representation, both table models are really just
        XML, and, if necessary, you can edit the XML directly by switching to <xref
          keyref="mode.text"><b>Text</b> mode</xref>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
