<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-adding-images">
  <title>Adding Images in DITA Topics</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Topics<indexterm>Add images</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>There are several ways to add images to a DITA topic, depending on if you want to create a
      figure element (with a title and caption), just insert an image inline, or if you want to use
      multiple versions of a graphic depending on the situation. For instance, you might want to use
      a specific image for each different product version or output media.</p>
    <section id="adding-image-inline">
      <title>Adding an Image Inline</title>
      <p>Use the following procedure to add an image inline:</p>
      <ol id="ol_eb4_q5d_xp">
        <li>Place the cursor in the position you want the graphic to be inserted. </li>
        <li>Select the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Image16.gif" id="image_nt1_rzy_tr"/>Insert
            Image</uicontrol> action. The <wintitle>Insert Image</wintitle> dialog box appears.<p>
            <fig id="fig_gbc_c2z_jr">
              <title>Insert Image Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/insert_image_dialog.png" id="image_ssk_prz_jr"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
        <li>Configure the options in this dialog box and click <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>.<p>The
              <uicontrol>Insert Image</uicontrol> dialog box includes the following options for
            inserting images into a DITA document:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>URL</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Inserts an <codeph>image</codeph> element with an <codeph>href</codeph>
                  attribute. You can type the URL of the image you want to insert or use the
                      <uicontrol><image href="../img/BrowseDrop.png" id="image_img_v4q_sr"
                      />Browse</uicontrol> drop-down menu to select an image using one of the
                  following options:<ul id="ul_pqr_4tz_jr">
                    <li><uicontrol>Browse for local file</uicontrol> - Displays the
                        <wintitle>Open</wintitle> dialog box to select a local file.</li>
                    <li product="authorEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol><image
                          href="../img/OpenWS16.gif" id="image_jys_nch_5r"/>Browse
                        workspace</uicontrol> - Opens a file browser dialog box that allows you
                      to select a file from the local workspace.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Browse for remote file</uicontrol> - Displays the <wintitle>Open
                        URL</wintitle> dialog box to select a remote file.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Browse for archived file</uicontrol> - Opens the
                        <wintitle>Archive Browser</wintitle> to select a file from an archive.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Browse Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> - Opens the
                        <wintitle>Data Source Explorer</wintitle> to select a file from a connected
                      data source.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Search for file</uicontrol> - Displays the <wintitle>Find
                        Resource</wintitle> dialog box to search for a file.</li>
                  </ul></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol id="keyref-field">Keyref</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>You can use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conkeyref20.png"/>Choose Key
                    Reference</uicontrol> button to open the <uicontrol>Choose Key</uicontrol>
                  dialog box that presents the list of keys available in the selected root map. Use
                  this dialog box to insert an <codeph>image</codeph> element with a
                    <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute. All keys that are presented in the dialog box
                  are gathered from the root map of the current DITA map. Elements that have the
                    <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed as links. For more
                  information, see <xref href="#eppo-adding-images/adding-image-using-key"
                    format="dita"/>.<note>If your defined keys are not listed in this dialog box, it
                    is most likely trying to gather keys from the wrong root map. You can change the
                    root map by using the <uicontrol>Change Root Map</uicontrol> link.</note></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Figure title</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Use this text box to insert a <codeph>title</codeph> and <codeph>image</codeph>
                  element inside a <codeph>fig</codeph> element.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Alternate text</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Use this text box to insert an <codeph>alt</codeph> element inside the
                    <codeph>image</codeph> element. </dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Size</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Use this section to configure the <uicontrol>Width</uicontrol> and
                    <uicontrol>Height</uicontrol> of the image, or <uicontrol>Scale</uicontrol> the
                  image. Specifying a value in these options inserts a <codeph>width</codeph>,
                    <codeph>height</codeph>, and <codeph>scale</codeph> attribute, respectively.
                </dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Layout</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Use the options in this section to insert <codeph>placement</codeph> and
                    <codeph>align</codeph> attributes into the <codeph>image</codeph> element.
                </dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></p></li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section id="adding-image-in-figure">
      <title>Adding an Image in a Figure Element</title>
      <p>To add an image in a figure:</p>
      <ol id="ol_nhs_qf2_xp">
        <li>Add a <codeph>fig</codeph> element to your document at the appropriate place.</li>
        <li>Add a <codeph>title</codeph> and/or <codeph>desc</codeph> element to the
            <codeph>fig</codeph> element, according to your needs. </li>
        <li><xref href="#eppo-adding-images/adding-image-inline" format="dita">Add an
              <codeph>image</codeph> element</xref> to the <codeph>fig</codeph> element.</li>
      </ol>
      <note>The <codeph>fig</codeph> element has a number of other child elements that may be
        appropriate to your content. See the <xref
          href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.2/os/spec/langref/fig.html#fig" format="html"
          scope="external">DITA documentation</xref> for complete information about the
          <codeph>fig</codeph> element.</note>
      <note>The order in which the <codeph>image</codeph>, <codeph>title</codeph>, and
          <codeph>desc</codeph> content are presented in output is determined by the output
        transformation. If you want to change how they are output, you may have to modify the output
        transformation, rather than your source content.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="adding-image-using-key">
      <title>Adding an Image Using a Key Reference</title>
      <p>If you want to use a different version of the image depending on the situation (for
        example, screenshots for multiple platforms or types of output media), you can reference the
        image using a key reference:</p>
      <ol id="ol_lkz_vk2_xp">
        <li>Create a DITA map to hold your image keys. You can create one map for each use or create
          a single map and profile the key definitions for multiple uses. For instance, you might
          create one map of images to be used in PDF and one for images to be used in Web output, or
          you might use the platform profiling attribute to manage multiple versions of a screenshot
          (one for Macintosh and another for the Windows version of your product).</li>
        <li>For each image, create a <codeph>keydef</codeph> element with the following
            structure:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;keydef keys="image.test" href="img/test.png" format="png"></codeblock><note
            type="tip">You can easily create a <codeph>keydef</codeph> element that targets an image
            by using the <xref
              href="insert-define-keys.dita#insert-define-keys/keydef-target-section"><uicontrol>Key
                Definition</uicontrol> action from the <uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol> or
                <uicontrol>Insert After</uicontrol> submenus</xref>.</note></li>
        <li>If you are using profiling, add the alternative <codeph>keydef</codeph> elements and the
          appropriate profiling
            attributes:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;keydef keys="image.test" href="img/win/test.png" platform="windows" format="png">
&lt;keydef keys="image.test" href="img/mac/test.png" platform="mac" format="png"></codeblock><note
            type="tip">If you create the <codeph>keydef</codeph> element using the <xref
              href="insert-define-keys.dita#insert-define-keys/keydef-target-section"><uicontrol>Key
                Definition</uicontrol> action</xref>, you can use the <xref
              href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref/profiling-tab-section"
                ><uicontrol>Profiling</uicontrol> tab of the <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol>
              dialog box</xref> to easily add profiling attributes to the target.</note></li>
        <li>If you are using separate maps, repeat in each map. For instance, if you are using a
          separate map for images in PDF output, add a topic ref to that map like
          this:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;topicref href="images.ditamap" format="ditamap"></codeblock></li>
        <li>To insert an image by key, insert an <codeph>image</codeph> element and use a
            <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute to point to the
            image:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;image keyref="image.test"/></codeblock><note
            type="tip">You can also use the <xref href="#eppo-adding-images/keyref-field"
              format="dita"><uicontrol>Keyref</uicontrol> section of the <uicontrol>Insert
                Image</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> to insert a <codeph>keyref</codeph> attribute
            inside an <codeph>image</codeph> element.</note><ph keyref="product"/> displays the
          image in <xref href="author-editor.dita#author-editor"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
            mode</xref>. Which image is displayed depends on the current profiling set that is
          applied and which <xref keyref="dita_root-map">root map</xref> is being used to resolve
          references.</li>
        <li>Configure your build so that the appropriate image map is included for each output type
          and/or the appropriate profiling conditions are applied to each output. </li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="image-map-dita.dita#image-map-dita"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
