<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-add-topic-to-map">
  <title>Adding Topics to a DITA Map</title>
  <body>
    <p>When you are working in DITA, there are two approaches that you can use to create topics and
      maps. You can start by creating topics first, and then assemble your finished topics into one
      or more documents by creating one or more maps, or you can start by creating a map and then
      adding new topics to it as you work. </p>
    <p>The topics-first approach is generally more appropriate if you are intending to do a lot of
      content reuse, as it encourages you to think of each topic as an independent unit that can be
      combined with other topics in various ways. The map-first approach will be more familiar to
      you if you are used to creating books or manuals as a whole. <ph keyref="product"/> supports
      both approaches.</p>
    <p>A DITA map organizes content hierarchically, so you can add a topic as a child of the map
      root or of any item already in the map. Therefore, the first step to adding a topic to a map
      is always to choose the place it will be inserted into the map. </p>
    <section>
      <title>Adding Existing Topics to a Map</title>
      <p>At the XML-level, a topic is added to a map by adding a reference to the map that points to
        the topic. There are a number of different reference types that you can use. The default is
        the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element. See the <xref
          href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.2/os/spec/DITA1.2-spec.html" format="html"
          scope="external">DITA documentation</xref> for the full range of reference elements and
        their uses. <ph keyref="product"/> provides several different tools for inserting reference
        elements into a map:</p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Using the Insert Reference Dialog Box</dt>
          <dd>The <xref keyref="dita_insert-reference-dialog">Insert Reference dialog box</xref>
            allows you to create each of the different reference types and fill in the most commonly
            used attributes. You can open the <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog box in
            a number of ways:<ul id="ul_z4z_szf_1q">
              <li>By right-clicking on an item in the current map where you want to add the
                reference, selecting <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Insert
                  After</uicontrol>, and selecting the type of reference to enter</li>
              <li>If the topic you want to add is currently open in the editor, you can use the same
                procedure, but select <uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited
                  file...</uicontrol></li>
              <li>By selecting an item in the map and clicking the <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/Topicref16.png" id="image_lkm_2vx_sr"/>Insert Reference</uicontrol>
                button.</li>
              <li>By selecting <uicontrol><image href="../img/Topicref16.png" id="image_vwt_fvx_sr"
                  />Insert Reference...</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>DITA Maps</uicontrol>
                menu</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Dragging and Dropping a File into the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle></dt>
          <dd>You can add a topic to a DITA map by dragging and dropping the file into the
              <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>. You can drag and drop files from any of the
              following:<ul id="ul_b1c_mbg_1q">
              <li>Your OS file system explorer</li>
              <li>The <wintitle>Project</wintitle> view</li>
              <li product="author editor">The <wintitle>Open/Find Resource</wintitle> view</li>
            </ul>Adding topics this way will not open the <wintitle>Insert Reference</wintitle>
            dialog box, but you can adjust all the same properties by opening the <wintitle>Edit
              Reference</wintitle> dialog box. Right-click on the reference you want to edit and
            choose <uicontrol>Edit Properties...</uicontrol>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Adding a New Topic to a Map</title>
      <p>To add a new topic to a map:</p>
      <ol id="ol_xtr_d3g_1q">
        <li>Right-click on the place in the current map where you want to add the new topic.</li>
        <li>Select either <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Insert After</uicontrol>
          and then select <uicontrol>New topic...</uicontrol>.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
