<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-create-conkeyref">
  <title>Creating a DITA Content Key Reference</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Reusing content<indexterm>Content Key
            References</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Content Key References</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Conkeyref</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section id="dita_content_key_reference">
      <title>DITA Content Key Reference</title>
      <p>A DITA content key reference, or <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>, is a mechanism for inserting a
        piece of content from one topic into another. It is a version of the <xref
          keyref="dita_insert-conref">DITA content reference mechanism</xref> that uses <xref
          keyref="dita_background_keys">keys</xref> to locate the content to reuse rather than
        direct references to topics that contain reused content. </p>
      <p>As with a <term>conref</term>, a <term>conkeyref</term> requires that the element to be
        reused has an <codeph>id</codeph> attribute. It also requires the topic that contains the
        reusable content to be assigned a <xref keyref="dita_background_keys">key</xref> in a map.
        As with all uses of keys, you can substitute multiple maps or <xref
          href="dita-profiling-conditional-text.dita#dita-profiling-conditional-text">use
          profiling</xref> to create multiple definitions of keys in a single map. This allows the
        same <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> to pull in content from various sources, depending on how
        your build is configured. This can make it easier to create and manage sophisticated content
        reuse scenarios.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="creating_a_content_key_reference">
      <title>Creating a Content Key Reference</title>
      <p>To create a content key reference (<codeph>conkeyref</codeph>), follow these steps:</p>
      <ol id="ol_ocz_fcb_bq">
        <li>Make sure the topic that contains the reusable content is assigned a key in the DITA map
          and the element you want to reference has an <term>id</term> assigned to it.</li>
        <li>In <xref href="author-editor.dita#author-editor"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
            mode</xref>, place the cursor at the location where you want the reused content to be
          inserted.</li>
        <li>Select <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conref20.png" id="image_gmv_hrx_xr"/>Reuse
            Content</uicontrol> on the main toolbar (or from the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> menu or
            <uicontrol>Reuse</uicontrol> submenu of the contextual menu). The <xref
            href="insert-dita-content-reference.dita#insert-dita-content-reference"><wintitle>Reuse
              Content</wintitle> dialog box</xref> is displayed.</li>
        <li>Select the <uicontrol>Key</uicontrol> radio button for the content source and use the
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conkeyref20.png" id="image_yml_whf_ws"/>Choose Key
            Reference</uicontrol> button to select the key for the topic that contains the reusable
          content (you can also select one from the drop-down list in the <uicontrol>Key</uicontrol>
          field). The elements that you can reference from the source are presented in the table in
          the middle of the <uicontrol>Reuse Content</uicontrol> dialog box.</li>
        <li>Select the <uicontrol>Target ID</uicontrol> of the element (or elements) that you want
          to insert, and verify the content in the <wintitle>Preview</wintitle> pane. The
            <codeph>id</codeph> value of the element that you select is automatically added to the
            <uicontrol>Reference to (conkeyref)</uicontrol> field. </li>
        <li>Make any other selections you need in the <xref
            href="insert-dita-content-reference.dita#insert-dita-content-reference/conkeyref-section"
              ><wintitle>Reuse Content</wintitle> dialog box</xref>. If you select multiple
          elements, the <uicontrol>Expand to (conrefend)</uicontrol> field is automatically filled
          with the <codeph>id</codeph> value of the last element in your selection.</li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Insert and close</uicontrol> to create
          the content reference.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section id="using_copypaste_actions_to_create_a_content_refer">
      <title>Using Copy/Paste Actions to Create a Content Key Reference</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> also includes support for creating content key references with
        simple copy/paste actions. When the DITA content is processed, the key references are
        resolved using key definitions from DITA maps. The copied content must be an entire DITA XML
        element with an ID attribute and the topic that contains the reusable content must have a
        key assigned in a DITA map. Also, the location in the document where you paste the element
        must be valid, although as long as the <xref
          href="preferences-schema-aware.dita#preferences-schema-aware/smart-paste-drag-drop"
            ><uicontrol>Smart paste and drag and drop</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected in the
          <uicontrol>Schema Aware</uicontrol> preferences page, if you try to paste it in an invalid
        location, <ph keyref="product"/> will attempt to place it in a valid location, and may
        prompt you with one or more choices for where to place it.</p>
      <p>To create a content key reference (<codeph>conkeyref</codeph>) using copy/paste actions,
        follow these steps:<ol>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view, make sure that the <xref
              href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager/root-map"><uicontrol>Root
                map</uicontrol> combo box</xref> points to the correct map that stores the
            keys.</li>
          <li>Make sure the topic that contains the content you want to reference has a key assigned
            to it. To assign a key, right-click the topic with its parent map opened in the
              <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>, select <uicontrol>Edit
              Properties</uicontrol>, and enter a value in the <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol>
            field.</li>
          <li>In a topic with an assigned key, copy an entire DITA element that has an ID attribute
            assigned to it.</li>
          <li>Place the cursor at a location where the copied element will be valid.</li>
          <li>Select the <uicontrol>Paste as Content Key Reference</uicontrol> action from the
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/PasteSpecialDITA16.png"/>Paste Special</uicontrol>
            submenu from the contextual menu.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="insert-dita-content-reference.dita#insert-dita-content-reference"/><link href="dita-reusable-components.dita#dita-reusable-components"/><link href="edit-dita-content-reference.dita#edit-dita-content-reference"/></linklist>
    
    
  </related-links>
</topic>

