<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo.dita.create-conref">
  <title>Creating a DITA Content Reference</title>
  <body>
    <p>A DITA content reference, or <codeph>conref</codeph>, is a mechanism for inserting a piece of
      content from one topic into another topic. It is one of the main <xref
        keyref="dita.pathfinder.reuse">content reuse features of DITA</xref>. </p>
    <p>In order for a <codeph>conref</codeph> to be created, the source content must have an
        <codeph>id</codeph> attribute that the <codeph>conref</codeph> can reference. Therefore,
      creating a <codeph>conref</codeph> may require both adding an <codeph>id</codeph> to the
      content to be reused and inserting a <codeph>conref</codeph> into the topic that reuses the
      referenced content. </p>
    <p>To add an <codeph>id</codeph> to a DITA element in a topic, place the caret on the element
      and press <uicontrol>Alt+Enter</uicontrol> to bring up the in-place attribute editor. Enter
        <userinput>id</userinput> as the name of the attribute and a value of your choice in the
      value field. Note that the element may already have an <codeph>id</codeph> since in some cases
        <ph keyref="product"/> generates an <term>id</term> value when the <codeph>id</codeph>
      attribute is created. </p>
    <p>To create a content reference:</p>
    <ol id="ol_ocz_fcb_bq">
      <li>In <xref keyref="mode.author"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode</xref>, place the
        insertion point when you want the reused content to be inserted.</li>
      <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conref20.png" id="image_gtn_2rx_xr"/>Insert a
          DITA Content Reference</uicontrol> button on the DITA toolbar. The <wintitle>Insert
          Content Reference</wintitle> dialog is displayed.</li>
      <li>Select the <uicontrol>Element ID</uicontrol> of the element that you want to insert, and
        verify the content in the <wintitle>Preview</wintitle> pane.</li>
      <li>Make any other selections you need in the <xref keyref="dita.insert-conref-dialog"
            ><wintitle>Insert Content Reference</wintitle> dialog</xref>.</li>
      <li>Click <uicontrol>Insert and close</uicontrol>.</li>
    </ol>
    <p>An alternate way to reuse content is to use the <ph keyref="product"/>
      <xref keyref="dita.create-reusable-component"><uicontrol>Create Reusable
          Component...</uicontrol></xref> and <xref keyref="dita.insert-reusable-content"
          ><uicontrol>Insert Reusable Component...</uicontrol></xref> actions, which handle the
      details of creating an <term>id</term> and <term>conref</term> and creates reusable component
      files, which are separate from your normal content files. This can help you manage your
      reusable content more effectively.</p>
    <p>You can also <xref keyref="dita.insert-content-key-reference">insert reusable content using
        content key references</xref>, which may make reusable content easier to manage. </p>
  </body>
</topic>
