<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo.dita.profiling">
    <title>Profiling (Conditional Content) in DITA</title>
<body>
    <p>DITA provides a mechanism for profiling content (conditional). You can profile content
      elements or map elements by adding
      <?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20141209T114014+0200" comment="Perhaps we should include something about adding custom profiling attributes/values."?>one
      or more of the default DITA profiling attributes<?oxy_comment_end?> (<codeph>product</codeph>,
        <codeph>platform</codeph>, <codeph>audience</codeph>, <codeph>rev</codeph>,
        <codeph>props</codeph>, and <codeph>otherprops</codeph>). The profiling attributes may
      contain one or more tokens that represent conditions to be applied to the content when a
      publication is built. </p>
    <p>For example, you could define a section of a topic that would only be included for a
      publication related to the Windows platform by adding the <codeph>platform</codeph> profiling
      attribute:</p>
    <codeblock>&lt;section platform="windows"></codeblock>
    <section><title>Profiling Content</title><p>To apply a profiling attribute to an element in a
        topic or map, right-click on the element and select <uicontrol>Edit Profiling
          Attributes</uicontrol>. The <wintitle>Edit Profiling Attributes</wintitle> dialog is
        displayed, which allows you to check each of the profiling tokens that apply for each
        attribute.</p><image href="../img/edit-profiling-attributes-dialog.png"
        id="image_dkz_hsd_bq"/><p>The profiling attributes, and their potential values that appear
        in this dialog box, depend on what has been configured in your copy of <ph keyref="product"
        />. The content of the dialog is determined as follows:</p><ul id="ul_bsp_5sd_bq">
        <li>If your root DITA map references a DITA subject scheme map that defines values for the
          profiling attributes, those values are used. In the image above, which is taken from the
            <ph keyref="product"/> documentation project, values are defined for seven different
          products, but none for other profiling attributes, which are therefore omitted from the
          dialog.</li>
        <li>If your project defines <xref keyref="project.project-level-settings">project
            level</xref>
          <xref keyref="options.editor.profiling">configuration values for the profiling
            attributes</xref>, those values are used</li>
        <li>If your copy of <ph keyref="product"/> defines global level <xref
            keyref="options.editor.profiling">configuration values for the profiling
            attributes</xref>, they are used</li>
        <li>Otherwise, a basic default set of profiling attributes and values are available </li>
      </ul></section>
    <section><title>Visualizing Profiled Content</title><p>You can visualize the effect of profiling
        content by using the profiling tools in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>. Click
        the <uicontrol>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> button <image
          href="../img/ProfilingToolbar16.png" id="image_j3k_3vd_bq"/> to select which profiles to
        show, or to apply different colors to text that is profiled in various ways, as shown in the
        image below.</p><image href="../img/profiling-styles-sample.png" id="image_s2j_vvd_bq"
      /></section>
  </body>        
</topic>
