<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_pcw_smb_pp">
  <title>Your First DITA Topic</title>
  <body>
    <p>To create your first DITA topic, choose <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>New...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The <xref href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa"><uicontrol>New
          Document Wizard</uicontrol></xref> is displayed:</p>
    <image href="../img/NewDocumentWizard.png" id="image_odn_xh4_y4"/>
    <p>Go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>topics</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> and select the topic type that you want to create. </p>
    <note>Note that if you organization has created any kind of DITA customizations, the appropriate
      template files may be in another location, and different topic types may be provided for your
      use. Check with the person who manages your DITA system to see if you should be using
      templates from a different directory.</note>
    <p>Your DITA topic is an XML document. As such, all <xref keyref="get-started.xml-document">the
        editing features that <ph keyref="product"/> provides for editing XML documents</xref> apply
      to DITA topics. However, <ph keyref="product"/> also provides extensive additional support for
      editing DITA topics and their associated maps and other files, and for creating DITA
      outputs.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Understanding DITA topics</title>
      <p>It is important to understand the role that a DITA topic plays in a DITA system. A DITA
        topic is not associated with a single document. It is a separate entity that can potentially
        be included in many different documents, help systems, or websites. When you write a DITA
        topic, therefore, you are not writing a book or a help systems or a website, you are writing
        an individual topic. This affects how you approach the writing task and how <ph
          keyref="product"/> works to support you as you write.</p>
      <p>Of course, most of your topics are actually connected more or less strongly to other
        topics, and those connections can affect how you write and how you handle things like links
        and reuse as you write. <ph keyref="product"/> can help you manage those relationships.
        Depending on how tightly or loosely your topics are connected, you may use <ph
          keyref="product"/>'s tools (and features of DITA itself) in different ways.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>The role of maps</title>
      <p>The basic way that DITA expresses the relationship between topics is through a DITA map.
        Other relationships between topics, such as cross references, generally need to be between
        topics in the same map, as DITA uses maps to determine which topics will be part of any
        output set that you create. While customized DITA solutions can use other mechanisms,
        generally DITA does not provide a way to output individual topics. Output is created from a
        map and includes the topics referenced by the map. </p>
      <p>A publication is not always represented by a single map. For instance, if you are writing a
        book, you might use a map to create each chapter, and then collect the chapters together in
        another map to create the book. If you are writing help topics, you might use a map to
        combine several DITA topics to create a single help topic, and then create another map to
        organize your help topics into a help systems. In this way, you can potentially reuse a map
        that represents a chapter or a help topic in more than one book or help system.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Adding your topic to a map</title><p>To add your topic to a map, you must first
        create a map. A map is an XML document, just like a topic, so to create one, you choose  <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>New...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>map</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and select the type of map you want. (If in doubt, choose Map for now.) <ph
          keyref="product"/> will ask you if you want to open your map in the editor or in the
          <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>. Most of the time, opening it in the <wintitle>DITA
          Maps Manager</wintitle> is the best choice. You can also open the map in the editor from
        the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> if you need to.</p><image
        href="../img/sa_dita_maps_manager_new.png" id="image_zvn_nsj_pp"/><p>The DITA Maps Manager
        presents a view of the DITA map similar to a table of contents. To add a topic to a map, you
        add a topic reference to the map which points to your topic. The easiest way to do this it
        to have the topic open in the editor and  right-click on <uicontrol>DITA Topic
          Map</uicontrol> in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view and choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited file...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>. This brings up the <wintitle>Insert Reference</wintitle> dialogue with all
        of the required fields already filled in for you. You can fill in additional information
        here or add it to the map later. When you select <uicontrol>Insert and Close</uicontrol>, a
        reference to your topic is added to the map.</p><image
        href="../img/sa_insert_topic_ref_dialog.png" id="image_fqz_2ck_pp"/><p>If you want to see
        what the resulting map looks like in XML, save your map and then double click on
          <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol> in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view.
        The XML version of the map will open in the editor.  </p></section>
    <section>
      <title>Child topics</title>
      <p>As you add more topics to your map, you may want to make one topic the child of another
        topic. Making a topic a child of another is usually done at the map level, by making one
        topic reference the child of another. To create a child topic reference, right click on the
        parent topic in the DITA Maps Manager view and choose  <uicontrol>Append child.</uicontrol>
        You can then choose <uicontrol>New topic...</uicontrol> to create a new topic,
          <uicontrol>Reference...</uicontrol> to create a reference to an existing topic, or
          <uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited file...</uicontrol> to make the file
        currently open in the editor the child topic. </p>
      <p>How your parent and child topics are displayed relative to each other in any particular
        output will depend both on the configuration of those topics in the map and on the rules of
        the output transform that is applied to them. Also, don't assume that your topics have to
        have the same relationship to each other in all outputs. Only the map defines the
        relationship between the topics, not the topics themselves. It is perfectly possible to
        create different maps, with relationships, and different configuration options, to produce
        different outputs. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Child maps</title>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Root maps</title>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
