<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-first-dita-topic">
  <title>Your First DITA Topic</title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <body>
    <p>To create your first DITA topic, choose <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol><image href="../img/New16.png" id="image_fzz_qps_vs"/>New</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The <xref href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa"><uicontrol>New
          Document Wizard</uicontrol></xref> is displayed:</p>
    <image href="../img/NewDocumentWizard.png" id="image_odn_xh4_y4"/>
    <p>Go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>topic</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> and select the type of topic that you want to create. </p>
    <note>If your organization has created DITA customizations, the appropriate template files may
      be in another location, and various different types of topics may be provided for your use.
      Check with the person who manages your DITA system to see if you should be using templates
      from a different directory.</note>
    <p>Your DITA topic is an XML document, thus all <xref keyref="get-started_xml-document">the
        editing features that <ph keyref="product"/> provides for editing XML documents</xref> also
      apply to DITA topics. However, <ph keyref="product"/> also provides extensive additional
      support for <xref keyref="dita_edit-topics">editing DITA topics</xref>, <xref
        keyref="dita_pathfinder_documents">their associated DITA maps</xref>, and for <xref
        keyref="dita_pathfinder_output">creating DITA output</xref>.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Understanding DITA Topics</title>
      <p>It is important to understand the role that a DITA topic plays in a DITA project. A DITA
        topic is not associated with a single published document. It is a separate entity that can
        potentially be included in many different books, help systems, or websites. Therefore, when
        you write a DITA topic you are not writing a book, a help system, or a website. You are
        writing an individual piece of content. This affects how you approach the writing task and
        how <ph keyref="product"/> works to support you as you write.</p>
      <p>Most of your topics are actually related to other topics, and those relationships can
        affect how you write and handle things such as links and content reuse. <ph keyref="product"
        /> helps you manage those relationships. Depending on how your topics are related, you can
        use the tools provided in <ph keyref="product"/>, along with the features of DITA, in a
        variety of different ways.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>The Role of Maps</title>
      <p>The basic method that DITA uses to express the relationship between topics is through a
        DITA map. Other relationships between topics, such as cross references, generally need to be
        made between topics in the same map. DITA uses maps to determine which topics are part of
        any output that you create. While customized DITA solutions can use other mechanisms,
        generally DITA is not used as a way to publish individual topics. Output is created from a
        map and includes all the topics referenced by the map. </p>
      <p>A publication is not always represented by a single map. For instance, if you are writing a
        book, you might use a map to create each chapter and then organize the chapters in another
        map to create the book. If you are writing help topics, you might use a map to combine
        several DITA topics to create a single help topic and then create another map to organize
        your help topics in a help system. This allows you to reuse the content of a map in multiple
        projects.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Adding Your Topic to a Map</title><p>To add your topic to a map, you must first
        create the map. A map is an XML document, similar to a topic. To create a map, choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/New16.png" id="image_nrw_sps_vs"/>New</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>map</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and select the type of map (for example, Map or Bookmap). <ph
          keyref="product"/> asks if you want to open your map in the editor or in the
          <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>. Usually, opening it in the <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> is the best choice. You can also open the map in the editor from the
          <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>.</p><image
        href="../img/sa_dita_maps_manager_new.png" id="image_zvn_nsj_pp"/><p>The <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> presents a view of the DITA map that is similar to a table of contents.
        To add a topic to a map, add a topic reference to the map using a <codeph>topicref</codeph>
        element. The easiest way to do this is to open the topic in the editor, then right-click
          <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol> in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view
        and choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited file...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>. This opens the <xref href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref"
            ><wintitle>Insert Reference</wintitle> dialog box</xref> with all of the required fields
        already filled in for you. You can fill in additional information here or add it to the map
        later. When you select <uicontrol>Insert and close</uicontrol>, a reference to your topic is
        added to the
        map.</p><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150709T120550+0300" comment="Revise once EXM-33518 is done."?><image
        href="../img/sa_insert_topic_ref_dialog.png" id="image_fqz_2ck_pp"/><?oxy_comment_end?><p>If
        you want to see what the resulting map looks like in XML, save your map and then
        double-click <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol> in the <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> view. The XML version of the map opens in the editor. </p><note>The
        default title for maps in <ph keyref="product"/> is <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol>,
        which is displayed in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view. You can change the
        title by right-clicking the title of the map and selecting <uicontrol>Edit
          properties...</uicontrol>. For the purposes of this guide, we will continue to use the
        title <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol>.</note></section>
    <section>
      <title>Child Topics</title>
      <p>As you add topics to your map, you may want to make a topic the child of another topic.
        Making it a child of another is usually done at the map level. To create a child topic
        reference, right-click the parent topic in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view
        and choose <uicontrol>Append child.</uicontrol> You can then choose one of the following
        options:</p>
      <ul id="ul_vc4_rg4_pp">
        <li>
          <p><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> - Opens the <xref
              href="../tasks/create-topic-in-map.dita#create-topic-in-map"
                ><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> file wizard</xref> for creating a new topic. </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><uicontrol>Reference</uicontrol> - Opens the <xref
              href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref"><uicontrol>Insert
                Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> that allows you to create a reference to an
            existing topic.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited file</uicontrol> - Creates a reference to
            the file that is currently opened in the editor. </p>
        </li>
      </ul>
      <p>You can also change the order and nesting of topics in the <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> view by doing either of the following:<ul id="ul_ddp_brn_3q">
          <li>Select the topic to move while holding down the <uicontrol>Alt</uicontrol> key and use
            the arrow keys to move it around.</li>
          <li>Use the mouse to drag and drop the topic to the desired location.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>The way your parent and child topics are organized in any particular output depends on both
        the configuration of those topics in the map and the rules of the output transformation that
        is applied to them. Do not assume that your topics must have the same organization for all
        output types. The map defines the organization of the topics, not the topics themselves. It
        is possible to create a variety of different maps, each with different organization and
        configuration options to produce a variety of different outputs. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Child Maps</title>
      <p>If you have a large set of information, such as a long book or extensive help system, a
        single map can become long and difficult to manage. To make it easier to manage, you can
        break up the content into smaller maps. A smaller map might represent a chapter of a book, a
        section of a user manual, or a page on a website.</p>
      <p>To build a publication out of these smaller maps, you must add them to a map that
        represents the overall publication. To add a child map to the current map, right-click the
        title of the map (for example, <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol>) and choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Map reference...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Validating a Map</title>
      <p>Just as it is with your individual topics, it is important to validate your maps. <ph
          keyref="product"/> provides a validation function for DITA maps that does more than simply
        validating that the XML is correct. It also does the following: <ul id="ul_yp4_4bl_vp">
          <li>Validates all of the relationships defined in the maps.</li>
          <li>Validates all of the files that are included in the map.</li>
          <li>Validates all of the links that are expressed in the files.</li>
        </ul>Validating the map that describes your entire publication validates all the files that
        make up the publication and all of the relationships between them. To validate a map, click
        the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ValidateAndCheck16.png" id="image_wqb_3vv_sr"/>Validate
          and Check for Completeness</uicontrol> button in the <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> view.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Publishing Your Topics</title><p>As noted previously, in DITA standards you
        usually do not publish output from an individual topic. Instead, you create published output
        bu running a DITA transformation on a map. This collects all the topics that are referenced
        in the map, organizes them, and produces output in a particular format. By default, <ph
          keyref="product"/> uses the transformations provided by the <uicontrol>DITA Open
          Toolkit</uicontrol> for publishing to a variety of different output formats (such as PDF,
        WebHelp or EPUB). Your organization may have created various custom transformations or
        modified the built-in <uicontrol>DITA Open Toolkit</uicontrol> transformations. In either
        case, <ph keyref="product"/> manages them by using transformation scenarios. </p><p>To
        publish output for a map, select the transformation scenario you want to run and set any of
        the parameters it requires. To select a transformation, click the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/TransformConfig16.png" id="image_l5w_lvv_sr"/>Configure Transformation
          Scenario(s)...</uicontrol> button in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view. This
        opens the <wintitle>Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</wintitle> dialog box.</p><image
        href="../img/sa_scenario_list_dialog_ditamap.png" id="image_o3f_tb4_pp"/></section>
    <p>Choose the transformation scenarios you want to apply and click <uicontrol>Apply
        associated</uicontrol>. Depending on the configuration of the transformation scenario, when
      the transformation is finished, your output may automatically be opened in the appropriate
      application. To change or view the configuration or storage options for a transformation
      scenario, select the transformation and click <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
