<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-background-keys">
  <title>Working with Keys</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Keys</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>DITA uses keys to insert content that may have different values in various circumstances.
      Keys provide a way to reference something indirectly. This can make it easier to manage and to
      reuse content in a number of ways.</p>
    <p>You can think of keys as like renting a post office box. Instead of the mail going directly
      from the sender to your house, it now goes to the post office box. You then go to the post
      office box and bring the mail back to your house. If you move to a new house, your mail still
      gets to you because it comes to the same post office box. You do not have to send change of
      address cards to all the people who send you mail. Your mailbox address is the key that makes
      sure your mail always reaches you, even if you move.</p>
    <p>Similarly, if you use keys in your content to reference other content, you do not have to
      update the source content to change the value of the key or what it points to. You just change
      the <xref href="insert-define-keys.dita#insert-define-keys">definition of the key</xref>. </p>
    <section id="using_keys_for_values">
      <title>Using Keys for Values</title>
      <p>You can use keys to represent values that may vary depending on the type of output. For
        instance, you may have several products that share a common feature. When you want to
        describe that feature, you need a way to insert the name of the product, even though that
        name is different depending on which product the feature description is being used for. For
        more information, see <xref href="eppo-variables.dita#eppo-variables"/>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="assigning_keys_to_topics">
      <title>Assigning Keys to Topics</title>
      <p>You can assign a key to a topic and use that key to reference that topic for various
        purposes, such as reuse or linking. As always, keys are defined in maps, so the key
        definition is done using the keys attribute of the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element:</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;topicref href="quick-heat.dita" keys="feature.quick-heat"/></codeblock>
      <p>The easiest way to assign keys to a topic (and insert the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element
        in its <xref keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref>) is to use the <xref
          href="dita-edit-properties.dita#dita-edit-properties/keys_tab"><uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol>
          tab in the <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol> dialog box</xref>. In the <xref
          href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
          Manager</uicontrol></xref>, invoke the contextual menu on the topic for which you want to
        assign a key and select <uicontrol><image href="../img/DockableFrameProperties16.png"/> Edit
          Properties</uicontrol>. Go to the <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> tab and enter the name of
        the key in the <uicontrol>Define keys</uicontrol> field.</p>
      <p>Once a key is assigned to a topic, you can use it to reference that topic for various
          purposes:<ul id="ul_ubr_vwd_zp">
          <li>You can <xref keyref="dita_linking_inline">create a link</xref> to it using
              <codeph>&lt;xref keyref="feature.quick-heat"/></codeph>. This allows you to change the
            target of the link by changing the topic that is pointed to by the key (for example, by
            profiling). </li>
          <li>You can use it <xref keyref="dita_add-topic-to-map">in a map to create a reference to
              a topic</xref> by key: <codeph>&lt;topicref keyref="feature.quick-heat"</codeph>. This
            allows you to change which topic is inserted in the map by the build, by changing the
            topic that is pointed to by the key.</li>
          <li>You can use it to <xref keyref="dita_insert-content-key-reference">insert a content
              reference</xref>. In this case, the content reference uses the key to locate the topic
            to pull content from. It uses a <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute:
              <codeph>&lt;procedure conkeyref="feature.quick-heat/preheat-procedure"/></codeph>. In
            this example, <codeph>feature.quick-heat</codeph> is the key, and
              <codeph>preheat-procedure</codeph> is the ID of a procedure within the topic for that
            key. Using this mechanism, you could have multiple versions of the preheat procedure in
            various topics and control which one is inserted by changing the topic that is pointed
            to by the key.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="assigning_keys_to_graphics">
      <title>Assigning Keys to Graphics</title>
      <p>You can assign a key to an image (using a map to point to the image file) and <xref
          keyref="dita_images">insert the image using the key</xref>. </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="insert-define-keys.dita#insert-define-keys"/>
      <link href="eppo-create-conkeyref.dita#eppo-create-conkeyref"/>
      <link href="insert-dita-content-reference.dita#insert-dita-content-reference"/>
      <link href="dita-reusable-components-view.dita#dita-reusable-components-view"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
