<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-pathfinder-reuse">
  <title>Reusing DITA Content</title>
  <body>
    <p>Reusing content is one of the key features of DITA. DITA provides a number of different
      methods for reusing content. <ph keyref="product"/> provides support for each of these
      methods.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Reusing Topics</title>
      <p>A DITA topic does not belong to any one publication. You add a DITA topic to a publication
        by referencing it in a map. You can reference the same topic in more than one map. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Reusing Content Elements</title>
      <p>DITA allows you to reuse a content element by referencing it in another topic. DITA
        provides two mechanisms for including content by reference: <codeph>conref</codeph> and
          <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>. A <codeph>conref</codeph> creates a direct reference to a
        specific element of another topic. A <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> creates a reference to a
        key, which in turn points to a specific element of another topic. The advantage of using a
          <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> is that you can change the element that is included by changing
        the key reference. For example, since keys are defined in maps, a different key reference is
        used when you include your topic in a different map. </p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides support for both <codeph>conref</codeph> and
          <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>. </p>
      <p>While the <codeph>conref</codeph> and <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> mechanisms can be used to
        reference any content element, it is considered best practice to only <term>conref</term> or
          <term>conkeyref</term> content that is specifically set and managed as reusable content.
        This practice helps reduce expensive errors, such as an author accidentally deleting the
        source element that other topics are including by <codeph>conref</codeph>. <ph
          keyref="product"/> can help you create a reusable component from your current content.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Reusing Content with Conditions</title>
      <p>DITA allows you to conditionally profile parts of a topic so that certain parts of the
        topic are displayed when certain profiling conditions are set. Profiling conditions can be
        set both within topics and in maps. When set in a topic, they allow you to suppress an
        element (such as paragraph), step in a procedure, item in a list, or even a phrase within a
        sentence. When set in a map, they allow you to suppress an entire topic or group of topics.
        You can then create a variety of different publications from a single map by applying
        profiling conditions to the build. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Reusing Content with Variables</title>
      <p>DITA allows you to replace the content of certain elements with the value pointed to by a
        key. This mechanism effectively means that you can create variables in your content, which
        you can then output with various different values by changing the value the key points to.
        This is done by profiling the definition of the key value, or by substituting another map
        with various different key values that are defined.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>

