<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo.dita.profiling">
    <title>Profiling (Conditional Content) in DITA</title>
<body>
    <p>DITA provides a mechanism for profiling content (making it conditional). You can profile
      content elements or map elements by adding one or more of the DITA profiling attributes
      (product, platform, audience, rev, props, and other props). The profiling attributes may
      contain one or more tokens which represent conditions to be applied to the content when a
      publication is built. </p>
    <p>For example, you could define a section of a topic that will be included only for a
      publication related to the Windows platform by adding the product profiling attribute:</p>
    <codeblock>&lt;section platform="windows"></codeblock>
    <section><title>Profiling content</title><p>To apply a profiling attribute to an element in a
        topic or a map, right click on the element and choose <uicontrol>Edit Profiling
          Attributes</uicontrol>. The <wintitle>Edit Profiling Attributes</wintitle> dialog will be
        displayed, allowing you to check each of the profiling tokens that apply for each
        attribute.</p><image href="../img/edit-profiling-attributes-dialog.png"
        id="image_dkz_hsd_bq"/><p>The profiling attributes and their potential values that appear in
        this dialog box will depend on what has been configured in your copy of <ph keyref="product"
        />. The contents of the dialog will be determined as follows:</p><ul id="ul_bsp_5sd_bq">
        <li>If your root DITA map references a <xref keyref="dita.subject-scheme">DITA subject
            scheme map</xref> that defines values for the profiling attributes, those values will be
          used. In the image above, which is taken from the <ph keyref="product"/> documentation
          project, values are defined for seven different product version, but none for other
          profiling attributes, which are therefore omitted from the dialog.</li>
        <li>If your project defines <xref keyref="project.project-level-settings">project
            level</xref>
          <xref keyref="options.editor.profiling">configuration values for the profiling
            attributes</xref>, those values will be used.</li>
        <li>If your copy of <ph keyref="product"/> defines global level <xref
            keyref="options.editor.profiling">configuration values for the profiling
            attributes</xref>, they will be used.</li>
        <li>Otherwise a basic default set of profiling attributes and values will be available.</li>
      </ul></section>
    <section><title>Visualizing profiled content</title><p>You can visualize the effect of profiling
        content by using the profiling tools in the DITA Maps Manage. Click the
        Profiling/Conditional Text button <image href="../img/bt_profiling_button.png"
          id="image_j3k_3vd_bq"/>
        <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20141111T202239-0500" comment="This icon is not quite correct. Was there a change? Should check."?>to<?oxy_comment_end?>
        select which profiles to show or to apply different colors to text profiled in different
        ways, as shown in the image below.</p><image href="../img/profiling-styles-sample.png"
        id="image_s2j_vvd_bq"/></section>
  </body>        
</topic>
