<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo.dita.edit-topics">
  <title>Editing DITA Topics</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a number of features to help you edit your DITA topics.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Author mode</title>
      <p>DITA is an <xref keyref="get-started.xml-document">XML format</xref>, however, you do not
        have to write raw XML to create and edit DITA topics. <ph keyref="product"/> provides a
        graphical view of your topics in <xref keyref="mode.author">Author mode</xref>. Your topics
        will likely open in Author mode by default, so this is the first view you will see when you
        open or edit a DITA topic. If your topic does not open in Author mode, just click
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> at the bottom left of the editor window to switch to Author
        mode.</p>
      <p>Author mode presents a graphical view of the document you are editing, similar to the view
        you would see in a word processor. However, there are some differences:</p>
      <ul id="ul_sh1_wcs_zp">
        <li>Author mode is not a WYSIWYG view. It does not show you exactly what your content will
          look like when printed or displayed on screen. The appearance of your output is determined
          by the DITA publishing process, and your organization may have modified that process to
          change how the output is displayed. <ph keyref="product"/> has no way of telling what your
          final output will look like or of telling where line breaks or page breaks will fall.
          Treat Author mode as a friendly visual editing environment, not a faithful preview of your
          output.</li>
        <li>Your document is still an XML document. Author mode creates a visual representation of
          your document by applying a CSS stylesheet to the XML. You can see the XML at any time by
          switching to <xref keyref="mode.text">Text mode</xref>. You, or someone in your
          organization can change how Author view looks by changing the CSS stylesheet or providing
          an alternate stylesheet. </li>
        <li>Your aim in editing a DITA document is not to make it look right, but to create a
          complete and correct DITA XML document. Author mode keeps you informed of the correctness
          of your content by highlighting XML errors in the text and by showing you the current
          status in a box at the top right of the editor window. Green means your document is valid,
          yellow means valid with warnings, and red means invalid. Warnings and errors will be
          displayed when you place the caret on the error location.</li>
        <li>Your XML elements may have attributes on them. Conventionally, attributes are used to
          contain metadata that is not displayed to the reader, so attributes are not displayed by
          default in Author view (thought there are some exceptions) and cannot be edited directly
          in Author view (though in some cases the CSS that drives the display may use form controls
          to let you edit attributes directly). To edit the attributes of an element, place your
          cursor on the element and press <uicontrol>Alt+Enter</uicontrol> to bring up the attribute
          editor. Alternatively, you can use the <xref keyref="edit.views.attributes"
              ><wintitle>Attributes</wintitle> view</xref> to edit attributes.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section><title>Content completion assistance</title>Because it is a structured format, DITA
      only allows certain elements in certain places. The set of elements allowed will differ from
      one DITA topic type to another. (This is what makes one topic type different from another.) To
      help you figure out which elements you can add in any given place, and to help you understand
      what they mean, <ph keyref="product"/> has a number of content completion assistance
        features.<ul id="ul_r1m_kfs_zp">
        <li><p><b>The enter key:</b> In author mode, the Enter key does not create line breaks, it
            brings up the content completion assistant to help you enter a new element. (In XML, you
            don't use line breaks to separate paragraphs. You create paragraphs by creating
            paragraph elements (element <codeph>p</codeph> in DITA). tools insert the line breaks in
            the output and on screen.)</p>
          <image href="../img/bt_author_content_completion.png" id="image_jyk_xgs_zp"/><p>The
            content completion assistant not only suggests new elements you can add. If you hit
              <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> at the end of a block element (such as a paragraph) it
            will suggest creating a new element of the same type. If you hit
              <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> in the middle of a block element, it will suggest
            splitting that element into two elements. </p><p>A useful consequence of this behavior
            is that you can create a new paragraph simply by hitting <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol>
            twice (just as you might in a text editor).</p><p>As you highlight an element name, a
            basic description of the element will be displayed. Highlight the desired element and
            hit <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> to create it.</p><p>To wrap an element around an
            existing element or piece of text, simply highlight it and hit Enter and use the content
            completion assistance to choose the wrapper element.</p></li>
        <li><b>The model view:</b> You can see the entire model of the current element by opening
          the <wintitle>Model</wintitle> view (<menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Model</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>, if the view is not already open). The Model view will show you what type
          of content the current element can contain, all the child elements it can contain, all its
          permitted attributes and their types. </li>
      </ul></section>
    <section><title>The DITA Toolbar</title><p>The DITA Toolbar contains buttons for inserting a
        number of common DITA elements (elements that are found in most DITA topic types).
        </p><image href="../img/sa_dita_toolbar.png" id="image_bny_tjs_zp"/><p>If the DITA toolbar
        is not displayed, right click on the tool bar area and select it from the list displayed.
        </p><p>Note that the DITA toolbar contains a list of the most common elements and actions
        for DITA, such as inserting an image, creating a link, inserting a content reference, or
        creating a table. It does not contain a button for every possible DITA element. For a
        complete list of elements you can currently create, hit <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> to
        bring up the content completion assistant. </p></section>
    <section>
      <title>The DITA Menu</title>
      <p>Whenever the current document in the editor is a DITA document, the DITA Menu is displayed
        in the menu bar. It contains a large number of commands for inserting elements, creating
        content references and keys, edit DITA documents, and controlling the display. These
        commands are specific to DITA, and supplement the general editing command available for all
        document types. As with the DITA Toolbar, the DITA menu does not list every possible DITA
        element. </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
