<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="eppo-create-index">
  <title>Creating an Index in DITA</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Index creation</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>In DITA, indexes are created from <codeph>indexterm</codeph> elements. You can insert index
        term elements:<ul id="ul_tf2_tr1_bq">
          <li>In the header of a topic. In paginated media, such as a printed book or a PDF, this
            results in an index entry that points to the page in which the topic starts, even if it
            is not the page in which the indexed term occurs. </li>
          <li>In the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element in a map that references the topic. This
            applies those index terms to that topic only when used in that map, allowing you to
            index topics differently in various publications. In paginated media, index entries
            point to the page in which the topic starts.</li>
          <li>In the body of a topic. In paginated media, this results in an index entry that points
            to the page in which the <codeph>indexterm</codeph> element occurs, even if that is not
            the page in which the topic starts.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>To add index terms to the text of a topic of the topic header, <xref
          keyref="dita_edit-topics">create the elements, as you normally would, in <ph
            keyref="product"/></xref>. To add index terms to a map, open the map in the editor and
        add the elements, as you normally would, in a topic.</p>
      <p>In some media, indexes will be generated automatically when index entries are found in the
        source. For other media, such as books, you may need to tell DITA where to place the index.
        For instance, to add an index to a <xref keyref="glossentry_bookmap"
          ><term>bookmap</term></xref>, you need to add an <codeph>indexlist</codeph> element to the
          <codeph>backmatter</codeph> of the book.</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Open your <xref keyref="dita_book-map"><term>bookmap</term></xref> in the <xref
            href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
              Manager</uicontrol></xref>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Right-click the <term>bookmap</term> and select <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Backmatter</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</cmd>
        <stepresult>The <xref href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref"
              ><uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> appears.</stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Insert and Close</uicontrol> to insert the <codeph>backmatter</codeph>
          element.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Right-click the <codeph>backmatter</codeph> element and create a
            <codeph>booklists</codeph> element using <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Book Lists</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Use the same steps to create an <codeph>indexlist</codeph> element. </cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <note type="caution">Adding <codeph>index</codeph> entries and an <codeph>indexlist</codeph>
        to your project creates an instruction to the DITA publishing routines to create an index.
        There is no guarantee that all DITA output types or third-party customizations obey that
        instruction or create the index the way you want it. Modifying the output may be necessary
        to get the result you want. </note>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
