<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-manage-map">
  <title>Managing DITA Maps</title>
  <body>
    <p>You may want to manage your DITA maps in a variety of ways, such as:</p>
    <ul id="ul_b34_fhv_1q">
      <li>Change the order and nesting of topics in a map.</li>
      <li>Add or remove topics from the map.</li>
      <li>Add keys to the topics in the map.</li>
      <li>Add profiling (conditions) to the items in the map.</li>
      <li>Change other properties of the items in the map.</li>
    </ul>
    <section>
      <title>Changing the Order and Nesting of Topics in a Map</title>
      <p>You can change the order and nesting of the topics in a map in several ways:<ul
          id="ul_dsm_c3v_1q">
          <li>By dragging and dropping topics within the <wintitle>DITA Maps
            Manager</wintitle>.</li>
          <li product="author editor">By highlighting a topic in the <wintitle>DITA Maps
              Manager</wintitle>, holding down the <uicontrol>Alt</uicontrol> key, and pressing the
            arrow keys.</li>
          <li>By showing the extended <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> toolbar (press the
            settings icon <image href="../img/Settings16.png" id="image_xyt_t3v_1q"/> on the
              <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> toolbar and select the extended toolbar) and
            then using the arrow keys (<image href="../img/NodeUp16.png" id="image_phk_dmq_js"
              /><image href="../img/NodeDown16.png" id="image_yc5_dmq_js"/><image
              href="../img/NodePromote16.png" id="image_w2c_2mq_js"/><image
              href="../img/NodeDemote16.png" id="image_dnj_2mq_js"/>) on the toolbar to move topics
            around in the map.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Add and Remove Topics from a Map</title>
      <p>You can <xref keyref="dita_add-topic-to-map">add</xref> or remove topics from a map in a
        number of ways. Some ways to remove a topic from a map include:<ul id="ul_bwt_cjv_1q">
          <li>Highlight the topic and press <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Highlight the topic and click the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button <image
              href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif" id="image_as2_4jv_1q"/>on the <wintitle>DITA Maps
              Manager</wintitle> extended toolbar. </li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Add Keys to Topic in a Map</title>
      <p>You can <xref keyref="dita_background_keys">add keys to topics</xref> in a map by
        right-clicking an item in the map and choosing <uicontrol>Edit
        Properties</uicontrol>.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Profiling Sections of a Map</title>
      <p>You can profile (make conditional) any section of a map by <xref keyref="dita_profiling"
          >adding one or more profiling attributes to the topics in a map</xref>. In the
        hierarchical structure of a map, any profiling applied to a topic that has children applies
        to those children as well. You cannot include a child topic if its parent topic is
        excluded.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
