<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-pathfinder-reuse">
  <title>Reusing DITA Content</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Reusing content</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Reusing content is one of the key features of DITA. DITA provides several methods for reusing
      content. <ph keyref="product"/> provides support for each of these methods.</p>
    <section id="reusing_topics_in_dita_maps">
      <title>Reusing Topics in DITA Maps</title>
      <p>A DITA topic does not belong to any one publication. You add a DITA topic to a publication
        by referencing it in a map. You can reference the same topic in multiple maps. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="reusing_content_with_references_and_keys">
      <title>Reusing Content with References and Keys</title>
      <p>DITA allows you to reuse content by referencing it in another topic. DITA provides several
        mechanisms for including content by reference (<codeph>conref</codeph>,
          <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>, <codeph>coderef</codeph>). A <codeph>conref</codeph> creates a
        direct reference to a specific element of another topic. A <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>
        creates a reference to a key, which then points to a specific element in another topic. The
        advantage of using a <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> is that you can change the element that is
        included by changing the key reference. For example, since keys are defined in maps, if you
        include a topic in multiple maps, you can use a different key reference in each map. A
          <codeph>coderef</codeph> references an external file that contains literal code.</p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides support for all of these mechanisms. </p>
      <p>While the <codeph>conref</codeph> and <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> mechanisms can be used to
        reference any content element, it is considered best practice to only <i>conref</i> or
          <i>conkeyref</i> content that is specifically set and managed as reusable content.
        This practice helps reduce expensive errors, such as an author accidentally deleting the
        source element that other topics are including by <codeph>conref</codeph>. <ph
          keyref="product"/> can help you create a reusable component from your current content.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="reusing_content_with_reusable_components">
      <title>Reusing Content with Reusable Components</title>
      <p>DITA allows you to select content in a topic, create a reusable component from it and
        reference that component in other locations. Each reusable component is created as a
        separate file. Anytime the content needs to be edited, you only need to update it in the
        component file and all the locations in your topics that reference it will also be updated.
        This can help you to maintain continuity and accuracy throughout your documents.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="reusing_content_with_variables">
      <title>Reusing Content with Variables</title>
      <p>DITA allows you to replace the content of certain elements with a value that is pointed to
        by a key. This mechanism effectively means that you can create variables in your content,
        which you can then create multiple outputs by changing the value that the key points to.
        This is done by profiling the definition of the key value, or by substituting another map
        with a different key value.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="reusing_content_with_dita_13_concepts">
      <title>Reusing Content with DITA 1.3 Concepts</title>
      <p>DITA 1.3 allows you to use some advanced concepts to expand content reuse possibilities
        even further. <i>Key Scopes</i> (or scoped keys) allow you to reuse topics with
        variable content depending on the particular context and it maximizes reuse possibilities
        for keys. <i>Branch Filtering</i> allows you to reuse the same content that is
        profiled in multiple ways within the same publication, each time using a different
        filter.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="eppo-background-keys.dita#eppo-background-keys"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>

