<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo-add-topic-to-map">
  <title>Adding Topics to a DITA Map</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Maps<indexterm>Add topics</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Maps<indexterm>Remove topics</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>When you are working in DITA, there are several approaches that you can use to create topics
      and maps. You can start by first creating topics and then assembling your finished topics into
      one or more documents by creating one or more maps, or you can start by creating a map and
      then adding new topics to it as you work. </p>
    <p>The topics-first approach is generally more appropriate if you intend to do a lot of content
      reuse, as it encourages you to think of each topic as an independent unit that can be combined
      with other topics in various ways. The map-first approach will be more familiar to you if you
      are used to creating books or manuals as a whole. <ph keyref="product"/> supports both
      approaches.</p>
    <p>A <xref keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref> organizes content
      hierarchically, so you can add a topic as a child of the map root or as a child or sibling of
      any item already in the map. Therefore, the first step to adding a topic to a map is always to
      choose the place it will be inserted into the map. </p>
    <section id="adding_existing_topics_to_a_map">
      <title>Adding Existing Topics to a Map</title>
      <p>At the XML-level, a topic is added to a map by adding a reference to the map that points to
        the topic. There are a variety of reference types that you can use. The default type is the
          <codeph>topicref</codeph> element. See the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/dita/1.3/specs/langRef/base/map.html"
          format="html" scope="external">DITA documentation</xref> for the full range of reference
        elements and their uses. <ph keyref="product"/> provides several tools for inserting
        reference elements into a map:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Using the Insert Reference Dialog Box</dt>
            <dd>The <xref keyref="dita_insert-reference-dialog"><uicontrol>Insert
                  Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> allows you to create various reference
              types and configure the most commonly used attributes. You can open the
                <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog box with any of the following
                methods:<ul id="ul_z4z_szf_1q">
                <li>Right-click an item in the current map where you want to add the reference,
                  select <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Insert After</uicontrol>
                  and select the type of reference to enter.</li>
                <li>If the topic you want to add is currently open in the editor, you can
                  right-click an item in the current map where you want to add the reference and
                  select <uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited file</uicontrol>.</li>
                <li>Selecting an item in the map and click the <uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/Topicref16.png" id="image_lkm_2vx_sr"/>Insert
                    Reference</uicontrol> button from the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>
                  toolbar.</li>
                <li>Select <uicontrol><image href="../img/Topicref16.png" id="image_vwt_fvx_sr"
                    />Insert Reference</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>DITA Maps</uicontrol>
                  menu.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Dragging and Dropping a File into the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>You can add a topic to a <term>DITA map</term> by dragging and dropping the file
              into the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>. You can drag and drop files from
              any of the following:<ul id="ul_b1c_mbg_1q">
                <li>Your OS file system explorer.</li>
                <li>The <uicontrol product="author editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
                    product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</uicontrol> view.</li>
                <li product="author editor">The <uicontrol>Open/Find Resource</uicontrol> view.</li>
              </ul>Adding topics this way will not open the <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol>
              dialog box, but you can adjust all the same properties by invoking the contextual menu
              from the topic and selecting <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="adding_a_new_topic_to_a_map">
      <title>Adding a New Topic to a Map</title>
      <p>To add a new topic to a map, follow these steps:</p>
      <ol
        conkeyref="reusables-author-for-dita/new-dita-topic-ol">
        <li/>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section id="adding_multiple_references_to_the_same_topic_in_a">
      <title>Adding Multiple References to the Same Topic in a Map</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to reuse entire topics by adding multiple references to
        the same topic in a <term>DITA map</term>. Whenever multiple references to the same topic
        are detected in the context of the current map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
          Manager</uicontrol>, an indicator will appear in the top-right corner of the
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode editor that shows the number of times the topic is
        referenced in the <term>DITA map</term>. It also includes navigation arrows that allow you
        to jump to the next or previous reference.</p>
      <p>
        <image href="../img/sa_multiple_references.png" placement="break"/>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="remove_topics_from_a_map">
      <title>Remove Topics from a Map</title>
      <p>You can remove topics from a map in a number of ways. Some ways to remove a topic from a
        map include:<ul id="ul_bwt_cjv_1q">
          <li>Highlight the topic and press <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Highlight the topic and click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif"
                id="image_as2_4jv_1q"/>Delete</uicontrol> button on the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
              Manager</uicontrol> extended toolbar. </li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
