<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="eppo.first-dita-topic">
  <title>Your First DITA Topic</title>
  <body>
    <p>To create your first DITA topic, choose <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>New...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The <xref href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa"><uicontrol>New
          Document Wizard</uicontrol></xref> is displayed:</p>
    <image href="../img/NewDocumentWizard.png" id="image_odn_xh4_y4"/>
    <p>Go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>topic<?oxy_delete author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113204+0200" content="s"?></uicontrol>
      </menucascade> and select the topic type that you want to create. </p>
    <note>If your organization has created any DITA customizations, the appropriate template files
      may be in another location, and various different topic types may be provided for your use.
      Check with the person who manages your DITA system to see if you should be using templates
      from a different directory.</note>
    <p>Your DITA topic is an XML document, thus all <xref keyref="get-started.xml-document">the
        editing features that <ph keyref="product"/> provides for editing XML documents</xref> apply
      to DITA topics. However, <ph keyref="product"/> also provides extensive additional support for
        <xref keyref="dita.edit-topics">editing DITA topics</xref> and <xref
        keyref="dita.pathfinder.documents">their associated maps</xref> and other files, and for
        <xref keyref="dita.pathfinder.output">creating DITA output</xref>.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Understanding DITA Topics</title>
      <p>It is important to understand the role that a DITA topic plays in a
        <?oxy_comment_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113232+0200" comment="Maybe I would use instead: DITA Project"?>DITA
        system<?oxy_comment_end?>. A DITA topic is not associated with
        <?oxy_comment_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113304+0200" comment="What does &apos;document&apos; mean in this context? Maybe &apos;publication&apos; would be a better word?"?>a
        single document<?oxy_comment_end?>. It is a separate entity that can potentially be included
        in many different
        <?oxy_comment_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113321+0200" comment="Again, maybe &apos;publication&apos;"?>documents<?oxy_comment_end?>,
        help systems, or websites. Therefore, when you write a DITA topic you are not writing a
        book, a help system, or a website. You are writing an individual
        <?oxy_comment_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113352+0200" comment="Maybe &apos;piece of content&apos;"?>topic<?oxy_comment_end?>.
        This affects how you approach the writing task and how <ph keyref="product"/> works to
        <?oxy_comment_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113421+0200" comment="repetition of &quot;you&quot; might not sound very good
"?>support
        you as you write<?oxy_comment_end?>.</p>
      <p>Of course, most of your topics are actually related to other topics, and those
        relationships can affect how you write and handle things such as links and reuse
        (<?oxy_comment_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113544+0200" comment="I do not understand why the (as you write) was added."?>as
        you write<?oxy_comment_end?>). <ph keyref="product"/> can help you manage those
        relationships. Depending on how tightly or loosely your topics are related, you may use <ph
          keyref="product"/>'s tools (and features of DITA itself) in various ways.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>The Role of Maps</title>
      <p>The basic way that DITA expresses the relationship between topics is through a DITA map.
        Other relationships between topics, such as cross references, generally need to be made
        between topics in the same map. DITA uses maps to determine which topics are part of any
        output set that you create. While customized DITA solutions can use other mechanisms,
        <?oxy_comment_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T113705+0200" comment="DITA is the standard and DITA Open Toolkit is a publishing engine. It seems that the DITA keyword which for me means &quot;DITA Standard&quot; is sometimes used instead of &quot;DITA Publishing Engine&quot;
DITA OT allows publishing individual topics. It&apos;s not a very commonly used scenario but some still do this."?>generally
        DITA does not provide a way to output individual topics<?oxy_comment_end?>. Output is
        created from a map and includes the topics referenced by the map. </p>
      <p>A publication is not always represented by a single map. For instance, if you are writing a
        book, you might use a map to create each chapter, and then collect the chapters together in
        another map to create the book. If you are writing help topics, you might use a map to
        combine several DITA topics to create a single help topic, and then create another map to
        organize your help topics into a help system. By doing so you can potentially reuse a map
        that represents a chapter or help topic in more than one book or help system.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Adding Your Topic to a Map</title><p>To add your topic to a map, you must first
        create a map. A map is an XML document, just like a topic. To create a map, choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>New...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>map</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and select the type of map you want (if you're in doubt, choose Map for now).
          <ph keyref="product"/> asks you if you want to open your map in the editor or in the
          <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>. Most of the time, opening it in the <wintitle>DITA
          Maps Manager</wintitle> is the best choice. If needed, you can also open the map in the
        editor from the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle>.</p><image
        href="../img/sa_dita_maps_manager_new.png" id="image_zvn_nsj_pp"/><p>The <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> presents a view of the DITA map similar to a table of contents. To add
        a topic to a map, you add a topic reference to the map using a <codeph>topicref</codeph>
        element. The easiest way to do this it to have the topic open in the editor and right-click
        on <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol> in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view
        and choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited file...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>. This brings up the <wintitle>Insert Reference</wintitle> dialogue, with all
        of the required fields already filled in for you. You can fill in additional information
        here or add it to the map later. When you select <uicontrol>Insert and close</uicontrol>, a
        reference to your topic is added to the map.</p><image
        href="../img/sa_insert_topic_ref_dialog.png" id="image_fqz_2ck_pp"/><p>If you want to see
        what the resulting map looks like in XML, save your map and then double-click on
          <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol> in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view.
        The XML version of the map opens in the editor. </p><note>Maps have titles. The default
        title in <ph keyref="product"/> is <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol>, which is what is
        shown in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view. You can (and should) change the
        title by right-clicking on the default title, <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol>, and
        selecting <uicontrol>Edit properties...</uicontrol>. However, in this guide we will continue
        to use the title <uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol>.</note></section>
    <section>
      <title>Child Topics</title>
      <p>As you add more topics to your map, you may want to make one topic the child of another
        topic. Making a topic a child of another is usually done at the map level. To create a child
        topic reference, right-click on the parent topic in the <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> view and choose <uicontrol>Append child.</uicontrol> You can then
        choose one of the following options:</p>
      <ul id="ul_vc4_rg4_pp">
        <li>
          <p><uicontrol>New topic...</uicontrol>, to create a new topic </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><uicontrol>Reference...</uicontrol>, to create a reference to an existing topic</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><uicontrol>Reference to the currently edited file...</uicontrol>, to make the file that
            is currently open in the editor the child topic </p>
        </li>
      </ul>
      <p>You can also change the order and nesting of topics in the <wintitle>DITA Maps
          Manager</wintitle> view by either of the following:<ul id="ul_ddp_brn_3q">
          <li>Select the topic to move, holding down the <uicontrol>Alt</uicontrol> key, and using
            the arrow keys to move it around</li>
          <li>Use the mouse to drag and drop the topic to the desired location</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>How your parent and child topics are organized in any particular output depends on both the
        configuration of those topics in the map and the rules of the output transformation that is
        applied to them. Don't assume that your topics must have the same organization in all
        outputs. Only the map defines the organization of the topics, not the topics themselves. It
        is perfectly possible to create a variety of different maps each with different organization
        and configuration options to produce a variety of different outputs. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Child Maps</title>
      <p>If you have a large information set, such as a long book or extensive help system, a single
        map can become long and difficult to manage. You can break up content into smaller maps. A
        smaller map might represent a chapter of a book, a section of a reference, or even a single
        help topic or web page made up of a number of smaller DITA topics.</p>
      <p>To build a publication out of these smaller maps, you must add them to a map that
        represents the overall publication. To add a child map to the current map, right-click on
        the map title (<uicontrol>DITA Topic Map</uicontrol>, by default) and choose <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Map reference...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Validating a Map</title>
      <p>Just as you should validate your topics, you should validate your maps. <ph
          keyref="product"/> provides a validation function for DITA maps that does more than just
        validates that the XML is correct. It also: <ul id="ul_yp4_4bl_vp">
          <li>validates all of the relationships described by the maps</li>
          <li>validates all the topic files</li>
          <li>validates any links expressed in the topic files</li>
        </ul>Therefore, validating the map that describes your entire publication validates all the
        files that make up the publication and all of the relationships between them. To validate a
        map, click the <uicontrol>Validate and Check for Completeness</uicontrol> button (<image
          href="../img/bt_validate_and_check_button.png" id="image_z2b_p5n_pp"/>) in the
          <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Publishing Your Topics</title><p>As noted above, in DITA you do not
        <?oxy_insert_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T114411+0200"?>usually
        <?oxy_insert_end?>publish a topic by itself. To create published output, you run a DITA
        transformation on a map. This collects all the topics referenced in the map, organizes them,
        and produces output in a particular format. By default, <ph keyref="product"/> uses the
        transformations provided by the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T114316+0200" type="surround"?><uicontrol><?oxy_insert_end?>DITA
          Open Toolkit</uicontrol> for publishing to a number of different output
        formats<?oxy_insert_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T114338+0200"?> like PDF,
        WebHelp or EPUB<?oxy_insert_end?>. Your organization may have created various different
        transformations or modified the
          <?oxy_insert_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T114400+0200" type="surround"?><uicontrol><?oxy_insert_end?>DITA
          Open Toolkit</uicontrol> transformations. In either case, <ph keyref="product"/> manages
        them using transformation scenarios. </p><p>To publish a map, you must select the
        transformation scenario you want to run and set any of the parameters it requires. To select
        a transformation, click the <uicontrol>Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol>
        button in the <wintitle>DITA Maps Manager</wintitle> view (<image
          href="../img/bt_transform_config.png" id="image_jcs_q14_pp"/>). This brings up the
          <wintitle>Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</wintitle> dialog.</p><image
        href="../img/sa_scenario_list_dialog_ditamap.png" id="image_o3f_tb4_pp"/></section>
    <p>Choose the transformation (or transformations) you want to apply and click <uicontrol>Apply
        associated</uicontrol>. Depending on how the transformation scenario is configured,
      <?oxy_insert_start author="radu_coravu" timestamp="20150107T114607+0200"?>when the
      transformation is finished <?oxy_insert_end?>your output may be opened in the appropriate
      application automatically. To change how a transformation is configured (or just to figure out
      where this transformation places its output), select the transformation and press
        <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>