<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="export-to-excel">
    <title>Exporting XML Content to Excel</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Grid editing mode<indexterm>Export to Excel</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Grid Mode editing<indexterm>Export to
            Excel</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Export to Excel</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>For use-cases where you have XML content that needs to be exported to Excel (or any other
      spreadsheet application) but the content is not already in some sort of table format,
        <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode offers you a way to display the content of an XML document
      as a structured grid of nested tables and you can work with the cells in those tables much
      like you would with any spreadsheet application. This makes it possible to export content to
      Excel by copying cells that contain the specific content and then pasting the copied cells in
      Excel the same as you would when working with any table or spreadsheet.</p>
    <p>To export XML content from <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode to Excel or other spreadsheet
      applications, follow this procedure:<ol>
        <li>Open the XML document in <ph keyref="product"/> and switch to
            <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode.</li>
        <li><xref href="grid-actions.dita#grid-actions/expandingcollapsing_nodes">Expand the
            nodes</xref> to gain access to the particular nested table that contains the content you
          want to export.</li>
        <li>Copy the cells that contain the content you want to export (<uicontrol><image
              href="../img/Copy16.png" id="image_sf4_lst_tr"/> Copy</uicontrol> from the contextual
          menu or <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+C</shortcut></uicontrol>).</li>
        <li>Switch to your spreadsheet application and paste the copied cells.</li>
        <li>You may need to make some manual adjustments depending on the complexity of the
          structure in the original XML document. </li>
      </ol></p>
    <p>Note that <ph keyref="product"/> also supports the reverse scenario (copying cells from a
      spreadsheet application and pasting them in <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode). For more
      information, see <xref
        href="import-from-ms-excel-files.dita#import-from-ms-excel-files/paste_method_in_grid_mode"
        >Import from MS Excel Files – Grid Mode Method</xref>.</p>
    <p>For more information about exchanging data between <ph keyref="product"/> and spreadsheet
      applications, watch our video demonstration:</p>
    <p><object width="450" height="250" data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8VwsF58zLkU"
        outputclass="iframe">
        <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
      </object></p>
    </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link
        href="import-from-ms-excel-files.dita#import-from-ms-excel-files/paste_method_in_grid_mode">
        <linktext>Import from MS Excel Files - Grid Mode Method</linktext>
      </link>
      <link
        href="grid-copy-paste.dita#grid-copy-paste/pasting_content_from_other_editors_into_grid_mode"
      />
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
