<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="fast-create-topics">
  <title>Fast Create Multiple DITA Topics</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Topics<indexterm>Fast Create multiple
            topics</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <xref href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
          Manager</uicontrol></xref> includes a feature that allows you to quickly create multiple
      skeleton topics at once and you can specify their hierarchical structure within the <xref
        keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref>. A common use-case for using this
      feature is when you need to insert a new chapter or section that will include multiple topics
      and you have the structure and titles planned out in advance.</p>
    <p>To access this feature, right-click a node in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>
      where you want the new topics to be inserted and select <uicontrol>Fast Create
        Topics</uicontrol>. This opens the <uicontrol>Fast Create Topics</uicontrol> dialog box
      where you can configure the structure for the new topics.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Fast Create Topics Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/Fast_create_topics.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Fast Create Topics</uicontrol> dialog box includes the following features and
      options:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Hierarchy Text Pane</dt>
          <dd>Use this text area to enter the titles for your new topics, one per line, and specify
            the hierarchy by using indents (<uicontrol><shortcut>Tab</shortcut></uicontrol> or
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Space</shortcut></uicontrol>). Topic references will be created
            in the <term>DITA map</term> according to the hierarchy you enter in this section. Also,
            the titles that you enter in this text pane will not only be used for the topic titles
            but also to generate their file names and you can click the <xref
              href="preferences-dita.dita#preferences-dita/file-name-rules"><uicontrol>File name
                generation rules</uicontrol> link to configure the rules</xref> for how those file
            names will be generated.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Use the file name as the value of the root ID attribute</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Select this option to use the file name (without the file extension) as the value of
            the root <codeph>id</codeph> attribute for the new topics.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Topic type</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>All of the topics that will be created will have the same DITA topic type, which is
            detected from the most recently created topic. You can click the
              <uicontrol>Change</uicontrol> button to select a different type from a list of
            possible DITA templates.<note type="tip">You can convert any of these new files to a
              different DITA topic type at a later time by using another <xref
                href="dita-convert-topics.dita#dita-convert-topics">feature that allows you to
                easily convert DITA documents to other types</xref>.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Add created topic hierarchy relative to the selection as</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>By default, the hierarchy of topics will be added to the <term>DITA map</term> as
              <b>Children</b> to the node where the action was invoked. You can change this to
              <b>Siblings</b> if the selected node allows topics to be inserted as such.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Create</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When you click <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol>, the specified hierarchy is added as
            topic references in the <term>DITA map</term>. The new documents are created as bare
            skeleton topics with only the topic title and possibly the root ID populated.<note
              type="tip">You can easily <xref href="change-order-in-maps.dita#change-order-in-maps"
                >change the order of the topics in the <term>DITA map</term></xref> at a later
              time,</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="eppo-add-topic-to-map.dita#eppo-add-topic-to-map"/>
      <link href="dita-convert-topics.dita#dita-convert-topics"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
