<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="feedback_reusable_components">
  <title>Reusable Components in Oxygen Feedback Chapter</title>
  <body><!--Reusables for Feedback-->
    <p id="installation-options">
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Oxygen XML Editor</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Choose this option if you are adding the Feedback system to WebHelp Responsive
            documentation AND you will generate the documentation using a transformation scenario in
              <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>. When you select this option, instructions will be
            displayed to help you with the transformation.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Oxygen XML WebHelp</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Choose this option if you are adding the Feedback system to WebHelp Responsive
            documentation AND you will generate the documentation using a command-line script. When
            you select this option, instructions will be displayed to help you with the script.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Any Platform</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Choose this option if you are adding the Feedback system to a website. When you select
            this option, an HTML fragment will be displayed. You need to copy this fragment and
            paste it into your HTML code for each webpage that you want to have the Feedback system
            embedded.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p id="statistics-filters-p">
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="metrics">
          <dt>Metrics</dt>
          <dd>You can select the type of metric to be displayed. You can choose between
              <uicontrol>Page views</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol>, or both.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="sites">
          <dt>Sites</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>You can choose which site configurations to have their statistics displayed.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="date-chooser">
          <dt>Date Chooser</dt>
          <dd>You can select the time period to be displayed. You can choose a relative period
            (current month, last week, last month, last 3 months, last 6 months, and last year) or
            you can select a custom period.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="aggregate-chooser">
          <dt>Aggregate Chooser</dt>
          <dd>You can choose between <uicontrol>Daily</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Monthly</uicontrol>
            for the type of aggregation to be displayed.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="chart-type-chooser">
          <dt>Chart Type Chooser</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>You can select the type of the chart to be displayed. You can choose between
                <uicontrol>Line</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Bar</uicontrol>, and
                <uicontrol>Stack</uicontrol>.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p></body>
</topic>
