<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="file-comparison">
  <title>Files Comparison</title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Comparing and Merging Documents<indexterm>files comparison compare files
            fragments</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Compare Files</uicontrol> tool can be used to compare files or XML file
      fragments. To compare two files side by side, open the <uicontrol>Diff Files</uicontrol>
      dialog box from <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Compare Files</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. Using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/BrowseDrop.png" id="image_wbq_bpq_sr"
        />Browse</uicontrol> drop-down menu, open a file in the left side of the dialog box, and the
      file you want to compare it to in the right side. To highlight the differences between the two
      files, click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPerform16.png"/>Perform File
        Differencing</uicontrol> button. The line numbers on each side help you to quickly identify
      the locations of the differences.</p>
    <p>To compare XML file fragments, you need to copy and paste the fragments you want to compare
      into each side, without selecting a file. If a file is already selected, you need to close it,
      using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CloseQuickFind16.png" id="image_j1h_vbh_5r"/>Close
          (<shortcut conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_w_shortcut"
        />)</uicontrol> button, before pasting the fragments. </p>
    <p>You can edit both the source and the target file. The differences are refreshed when you save
      the modified document.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Compare Files Window</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_compare_files1.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>Adjacent changes are grouped into blocks of changes. This layout allows you to easily
      identify and focus on a group of related changes.</p>
    <p>When you select a change, a widget containing actions that can be used to copy or append
      changes from either of the two sides is displayed:<dl id="ul_qfx_vc3_tc">
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffAppendLeftToRight12.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_kjf_pdg_s4"/> Append left change to right</uicontrol> and
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffAppendRightToLeft12.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_mjf_pdg_s4"/> Append right change to left</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copies the content of the selected change from one side and appends it on the other,
            after the content of the corresponding change. As a result, the side that the arrows
            point to will contain the changes from both sides.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyLeftToRight12.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_ojf_pdg_s4"/> Copy change from left to right</uicontrol> and
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyRightToLeft12.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_rjf_pdg_s4"/> Copy change from right to left</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Replaces the content of a change from one side, with the content of the corresponding
            change from the other side.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
      <p product="author developer editor">
      <ph keyref="product"/> offers various diff algorithms to compare files or fragments:<ul>
        <li>
          <p>
            <uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - selects the most appropriate algorithm, based on the
            compared content and its size (selected by default).</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            <uicontrol>Characters</uicontrol> - computes the differences at character level.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            <uicontrol>Words</uicontrol> - computes the differences at word level.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            <uicontrol>Lines</uicontrol> - computes the differences at line level.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            <uicontrol>Syntax Aware</uicontrol> - computes differences for file types or XML
            fragments that are known by <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> - works well on large files or fragments at the expense
            of accuracy.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> - works best on small XML files or fragments and
            offers accurate results, at the expense of speed.</p>
        </li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
  <related-links product="author developer editor">
    <link href="preferences-diff-files.dita#preferences-diff-files">
      <linktext>Files Comparison Preferences Page</linktext>
    </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>
