<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="file-comparison">
  <title>Compare Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Compare Files tool</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Two-way file comparison</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Three-way file comparison</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Diff Files tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Compare Files</uicontrol> tool can be used to compare files or XML file
      fragments. The tool provides a mechanism for comparing two files or fragments, as well as the
      mechanism for a three-way comparison. <ph product="author developer editor">The utility is
        available from the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu or can be opened as a stand-alone
        application from the <ph keyref="product"/> installation folder
          (<filepath>diffFiles.exe</filepath>).</ph>
      <ph product="svnClient">The utility is available as a stand-alone application and can be
        opened by running its executable file (<filepath>diffFiles.exe</filepath>) from the Syncro
        SVN Client installation folder. The functionality of this standalone tool is similar to the
          <xref href="diff-view.dita#diff-view">comparison feature in the Syncro SVN client</xref>
        with a few slight differences in the interface and some options.</ph></p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Compare Files Tool</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_compare_files1.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="starting_the_tools_from_a_command_line">
      <title>Starting the Tool from a Command Line</title>
      <p>The file comparison tool can also be started by using command-line arguments. In the
        installation folder there is an executable shell (<filepath>diffFiles.bat</filepath> on
        Windows, <filepath>diffFiles.sh</filepath> on Unix/Linux,
          <filepath>diffFilesMac.sh</filepath> on OS X). To specify the files to compare, you can
        pass command-line arguments using the following construct:
          <codeph>diffFiles.bat/diffFiles.sh/diffFilesMac.sh [path to left file] [path to right
          file] [path to 3-way base file]</codeph>.</p>
      <p>If three files are specified, the tool will start in the <xref
          href="#file-comparison/threeway_comparisons" format="dita">3-way comparison mode</xref>.
        If only two files are specified, the tool will start in the <xref
          href="#file-comparison/twoway_comparisons">2-way comparison mode</xref>. The first
        specified file will be added to the left panel in the comparison tool, the second file to
        the right panel, and the optional third file will be the base (ancestor) file used for a
        3-way comparison. If you pass only one argument, you are prompted to manually choose another
        file.</p>
      <p>You can also start the file comparison tool from an external application by using the
          <codeph>[-ext]</codeph> argument and there are some additional arguments that are allowed.
        To see all the details for the command line construct, type <userinput>diffFiles.bat
          --help</userinput> in the command line.</p>
      <p>For example, to do a 3-way comparison on Windows, the command line might look like
        this:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">diffFiles.bat "c:\docs\file 1" "c:\docs\file 2" c:\docs\basefile</codeblock></p>
      <note type="tip">If there are spaces in the path names, surround the paths with quotes.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="twoway_comparisons">
      <title>Two-Way Comparisons</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Compare Files</uicontrol> tool can be used to compare the differences
        between two files or XML fragments.</p>
      <sectiondiv><b>Compare Files</b><p>To perform a two-way comparison, follow these steps:<ol>
            <li>Open a file in the left panel and the file you want to compare it to in the right
              panel. <ph conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path"/><p><b>Step Result:</b> The
                selected files are opened in the two side-by-side editors. A text editing mode is
                used to offer a better view of the differences.</p></li>
            <li>To highlight the differences between the two files, click the <uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/DiffPerform16.png"/>Perform File Differencing</uicontrol> button from
              the toolbar.</li>
            <li>You can use the drop-down menu on the left side of the toolbar to change the <xref
                href="#file-comparison/two-way-diff-algorithms" format="dita">algorithm</xref> for
              the operation.</li>
            <li>You can also use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/OptionsShortcut16.png"/>Diff
                Options</uicontrol> button to access the <uicontrol>Files Comparison</uicontrol>
              preferences page where you can choose to ignore certain types of markup and configure
              various options.</li>
            <li>If you are comparing XML documents using the <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> or
                <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms, you can enter an XPath 2.0
              expression in the <uicontrol>Ignore nodes by XPath</uicontrol> text field to ignore
              certain nodes from the comparison.</li>
          </ol>The resulting comparison will show you differences between the two files. The line
          numbers on each side and colored marks on the right-side vertical stripe help you to
          quickly identify the locations of the differences. Adjacent changes are grouped into
          blocks of changes. This layout allows you to easily identify and focus on a group of
          related changes.</p><p>
          <fig>
            <title>Two-Way Differences</title>
            <image href="../img/two-compare-source.png"/>
          </fig>
        </p></sectiondiv>
      <sectiondiv id="highlighting-colors"><b>Highlighting Colors</b><p>The differences are also
          highlighted in several colors, depending on the type of change, and dynamic lines connect
          the compared fragments in the middle section between the two panes. The highlighting
          colors can be customized in the <xref
            href="preferences-diff-appearance.dita#preferences-diff-appearance"><uicontrol>Files
              Comparison / Appearance</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>, but the default colors
          and their shades mean the following:<ul>
            <li><b>Pink</b> - Identifies modifications on either side.</li>
            <li><b>Gray</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the left side (your outgoing
              changes).</li>
            <li><b>Blue</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the right side (incoming
              changes).</li>
            <li><b>Lighter Shade</b> - Identifies blocks of changes that can be merged in their
              entirety.</li>
            <li><b>Darker Shade</b> - Identifies specific changes within the blocks that can be
              merged more precisely.</li>
          </ul></p></sectiondiv>
      <sectiondiv><b>Compare Fragments</b><p>To compare XML file fragments, you need to copy and
          paste the fragments you want to compare into each side, without selecting a file. If a
          file is already selected, you need to close it using the <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/CloseQuickFind16.png" id="image_j1h_vbh_5r"/>Close (<shortcut
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_w_shortcut"/>)</uicontrol> button,
          before pasting the fragments. If you save modified fragments, a dialog box opens that
          allows you to save the changes as a new document.</p></sectiondiv>
      <sectiondiv conkeyref="reusables-tools/navigate-differences"/>
      <sectiondiv conkeyref="reusables-tools/editing-actions"/>
      <sectiondiv id="two-way-diff-algorithms"><b>Two-Way Diff Algorithms</b><p><ph keyref="product"
          /> offers the following two-way diff algorithms to compare files or fragments:<ul>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/auto"/>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/characters"/>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/words"/>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/lines"/>
            <li id="syntax-aware-alg">
              <p>
                <uicontrol>Syntax Aware</uicontrol> - Computes differences for known file types or
                fragments. This algorithm splits the files or fragments into sequences of
                  <i>tokens</i> and computes the differences between them. The meaning of a
                  <i>token</i> depends on the type of compared files or fragments.</p>
              <p>Known file types include those listed in the <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> dialog box,
                such as XML file types (XSLT files, XSL-FO files, XSD files, RNG files, NVDL files,
                etc.), XQuery file types (<filepath>.xquery</filepath>, <filepath>.xq</filepath>,
                  <filepath>.xqy</filepath>, <filepath>.xqm</filepath> extensions), DTD file types
                  (<filepath>.dtd</filepath>, <filepath>.ent</filepath>, <filepath>.mod</filepath>
                extensions), TEXT file type (<filepath>.txt</filepath> extension), or PHP file type
                  (<filepath>.php</filepath> extension).</p>
              <p>For example:<ul>
                  <li>When comparing XML files or fragments, a token can be one of the following:<ul>
                      <li>The name of an XML tag</li>
                      <li>The <keyword>&lt;</keyword> character</li>
                      <li>The <keyword>/></keyword> sequence of characters</li>
                      <li>The name of an attribute inside an XML tag</li>
                      <li>The <keyword>=</keyword> sign</li>
                      <li>The <keyword>"</keyword> character</li>
                      <li>An attribute value</li>
                      <li>The text string between the start tag and the end tag (a text node that is
                        a child of the XML element corresponding to the XML tag that encloses the
                        text string)</li>
                    </ul></li>
                  <li>When comparing plain text, a token can be any continuous sequence of
                    characters or any continuous sequence of whitespaces, including a new line
                    character.</li>
                </ul></p>
            </li>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/xml-fast"/>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/xml-accurate"/>
          </ul></p></sectiondiv>
    </section>
    <section id="threeway_comparisons">
      <title>Three-Way Comparisons</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> also includes a three-way comparison feature to help you solve
        conflicts and merge changes between multiple modifications. It is especially helpful for
        teams who have multiple authors editing and committing the same documents. It provides a
        comparison between a local change, another change, and the original base revision. Some
        additional advantages include:<ul>
          <li>Visualize and merge content that was modified by you and another member of your
            team.</li>
          <li>Marks differences correctly even when the document structure is rearranged.</li>
          <li>Allows you to merge XML-relevant modifications.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Three-Way Comparison</title>
          <image href="../img/three-way-compare.png" placement="inline"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <sectiondiv><b>Compare Files</b><p>To perform a three-way comparison, follow these steps:<ol>
            <li>Open a file in the left panel and the file you want to compare it to in the right
              panel. <ph conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path"/><p><b>Step Result:</b> The
                selected files are opened in the two side-by-side editors. A text editing mode is
                used to offer a better view of the differences.</p></li>
            <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ThreeWayComparison16.png"/>Three-Way
                Comparison</uicontrol> button on the toolbar and select the base file in the
                <uicontrol>Base</uicontrol> field. <ph conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path"
              /></li>
            <li>To highlight the differences, click the <uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/DiffPerform16.png"/>Perform File Differencing</uicontrol> button on
              the toolbar.</li>
            <li>You can use the drop-down menu on the left side of the toolbar to change the <xref
                href="#file-comparison/two-way-diff-algorithms" format="dita">algorithm</xref> for
              the operation.</li>
            <li>You can also use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/OptionsShortcut16.png"/>Diff
                Options</uicontrol> button to access the <uicontrol>Files Comparison</uicontrol>
              preferences page where you can choose to ignore certain types of markup and configure
              various options.</li>
          </ol>The resulting comparison will show you differences between the two files, as well as
          differences between either of them and the base (ancestor) file. The line numbers on each
          side and colored marks on the right-side vertical stripe help you to quickly identify the
          locations of the differences. Adjacent changes are grouped into blocks of changes.</p><p>
          <fig>
            <title>Three-Way Differences</title>
            <image href="../img/three-way-compare-source.png"/>
          </fig>
        </p></sectiondiv>
      <sectiondiv conkeyref="reusables-tools/highlighting-colors"/>
      <sectiondiv conkeyref="reusables-tools/navigate-differences"/>
      <sectiondiv conkeyref="reusables-tools/editing-actions"/>
      <sectiondiv><b>Three-Way Diff Algorithms</b><p><ph keyref="product"/> offers the following
          three-way diff algorithms to compare files:<ul>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/auto"/>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/lines"/>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/xml-fast"/>
            <li conkeyref="reusables-tools/xml-accurate"/>
          </ul></p></sectiondiv>
    </section>
    <section id="second_level_comparisons">
      <title>Second Level Comparisons</title>
      <p>For both two-way and three-way comparisons, <ph keyref="product"/> automatically performs a
        second level comparison for the <uicontrol>Lines</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>XML
          Fast</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms. After the first
        comparison is finished, the second level comparisons for the <uicontrol>Lines</uicontrol>
        algorithm is processed on text nodes using a word level comparison, meaning that it looks
        for identical words. For the <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>XML
          Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms, the second level comparison is processed using a <xref
          href="#file-comparison/syntax-aware-alg" format="dita">syntax-aware comparison</xref>,
        meaning that it looks for identical <i>tokens</i>. This second level comparison makes it
        easier to spot precise differences and you can merge or reject the precise
        modifications.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Second Level Diff Comparison</title>
          <image href="../img/second-level-comparison.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <note>If a modified text fragment contains XML markup (such as processing instructions, XML
        comments, CData, or elements), the second level comparison will not automatically be
        performed. In this case you can manually select a second level comparison by doing a word
        level or character level comparison.<p>To do a word level comparison, select <uicontrol>Show
            word level details</uicontrol> from the contextual menu or
            <uicontrol>Compare</uicontrol> menu.</p><p>
          <fig>
            <title>Word Level Comparison</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_compare_files_word.png"/>
          </fig>
        </p><p>To do a character level comparison, select <uicontrol>Show Character Level
            details</uicontrol> from the contextual menu or <uicontrol>Compare</uicontrol> menu.</p><p>
          <fig>
            <title>Character Level Comparison</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_compare_files_char.png"/>
          </fig>
        </p></note>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="preferences-diff-files.dita#preferences-diff-files"
        product="author developer editor">
        <linktext>Files Comparison Preferences Page</linktext>
      </link>
      <link href="preferences-svn-diff.dita#preferences-svn-diff" product="svnClient">
        <linktext>Diff Preferences Page</linktext>
      </link>
      <link href="directories-comparison.dita#directories-comparison"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
