<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="file-operations-menu">
  <title>Compare Menu</title>
  <body>
    <p>The following actions are available in this menu:<dl>
      <dlentry id="action_perform_files_differencing">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPerform16.png" id="image_js3_2k3_tc"/> Perform
              Files Differencing</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Performs a comparison between the source and target files.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="action_go_next_diff">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffNextBlock16.png" id="image_vrq_3k3_tc"/> Next Block
              of Changes</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the next block of changes. This action is disabled when the cursor is
            positioned on the last change block or when there are no changes in the document; <ph
              product="diff">In Diff Directories, when the last block of changes in the current file
              is reached, the behavior of this action is controlled by <xref
                href="preferences-diff-dirs.dita#preferences-diff-dirs/preference_navigation"
                format="dita">Navigation</xref> options;</ph><note>A change block groups one or more
              consecutive lines that contain at least one change.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="action_go_prev_diff">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPreviousBlock16.png" id="image_lbz_hk3_tc"/>
              Previous Block of Changes</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the previous block of changes. This action is disabled when the cursor is
            positioned on the first change block or when there are no changes in the document; <ph
              product="diff">In Diff Directories, when the first block of changes in the current
              file is reached, the behavior of this action is controlled by <xref
                href="preferences-diff-dirs.dita#preferences-diff-dirs/preference_navigation"
                format="dita">Navigation</xref> options;</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
      <dlentry id="action_go_last_diff">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffNext16.png" id="image_lbp_jk3_tc"/> Next
              Change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the next change from the current block of changes. When the last change from
            the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the next block of changes. This
            action is disabled when the cursor is positioned on the last change. <ph product="diff"
              >In Diff Directories, when the last change in the current file is reached, the
              behavior of this action is controlled by <xref
                href="preferences-diff-dirs.dita#preferences-diff-dirs/preference_navigation"
                format="dita">Navigation</xref> options.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="action_go_first_diff">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPrevious16.png" id="image_vc1_hk3_tc"/> Previous
              Change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the previous change from the current block of changes. When the first change
            from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the previous block of
            changes. This action is disabled when the cursor is positioned on the first change. <ph
              product="diff">In Diff Directories, when the first modification in the current file is
              reached, the behavior of this action is controlled by <xref
                href="preferences-diff-dirs.dita#preferences-diff-dirs/preference_navigation"
                format="dita">Navigation</xref> options.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="go_last_change">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffLast16.png"/> Last Change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the last change from the current file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="go_first_change">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffFirst16.png"/> First Change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the first change from the current file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="action_copy_all_left_to_right">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyAllLeftToRight16.png" id="image_pfr_lk3_tc"/>
              Copy All Changes from Left to Right</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copies all changes from source to target file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyAllRightToLeft16.png" id="image_xbb_1dx_r2"/>
              Copy All Changes from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copies all changes from target to source file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="action_copy_left_to_right">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyLeftToRight16.png" id="image_n2r_nk3_tc"/> Copy
              Change from Left to Right</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copies the selected difference from source to target file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="action_copy_right_to_left">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyRightToLeft16.png" id="image_3hq_4k3_tc"/> Copy
              Change from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copies the selected difference from target to source file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="show_mod_word_level">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_diff_word_details.png"/> Show Word Level
              Details</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Provides a word-level comparison of the selected change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="show_mod_char_level">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_diff_char_details.png"/> Show Character Level
              Details</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Provides a character-level comparison of the selected change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
