<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="find-and-replace-text-in-files">
  <title>Finding and Replacing Text in Multiple Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Text Editing Mode<indexterm>find and replace text in multiple
            files</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Find / Replace in Files</uicontrol> dialog do one of the following:<ul>
        <li>go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Find / Replace in Files... </uicontrol>
          </menucascade>;</li>
        <li>click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_find_replace_in_files_button.png"/> Find /
            Replace in Files</uicontrol> toolbar button;</li>
        <li>go to the contextual menu of the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view;</li>
        <li>go to the contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view;</li>
        <li>go to the contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view for
          Documentum xDb (X-Hive/DB), eXist and WebDAV connections. This action is available for
          Documentum (CMS), but lacks the <i>replace</i> feature.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The operation works on both local and remote files from an (S)FTP, WebDAV or <xref
        href="cms-integration.dita#cms-integration" format="dita">CMS</xref> server.</p>
    <p>It enables you to define "search for" or "search for and replace" operations across a number
      of files. The find works at line level, which means a find match cannot cover characters on
      more than one line. The replace operation can bind <xref
        href="http://perldoc.perl.org/perlre.html#Regular-Expressions" format="html"
        scope="external">Perl 5</xref> regular expression group variables ($1, $2, etc.) from the
      find match. For example to replace the tag with attributes called <codeph>tag-name</codeph>
      with the tag <codeph>tag-name1</codeph> use as <uicontrol>Text to find</uicontrol> the
      expression <i>&lt;tag-name(\s+)(.*)&gt;</i> and as the <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol>
      expression <i>&lt;tag-name1$1$2&gt;</i>.</p>
    <p>The encoding used to read and write the files is detected from the XML header or from the
      BOM. If a file does not have an XML header or BOM <ph
        keyref="product"/> uses by default the UTF-8
      encoding for files of type XML, that is for files with one of the extensions:
        <filepath>.xml</filepath>, <filepath>.xsl</filepath>, <filepath>.fo</filepath>,
        <filepath>.xsd</filepath>, <filepath>.rng</filepath>, <filepath>.nvdl</filepath>,
        <filepath>.sch</filepath>, <filepath>.wsdl</filepath> or <xref
        href="preferences-file-types.dita">an extension associated with the XML editor type</xref>.
      For the other files it uses <xref href="preferences-encoding.dita">the encoding configured for
        non-XML files.</xref></p>
    <p>You can cancel a long operation at any time by pressing the <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol>
      button of the progress dialog displayed when the operation is executed.</p>
    <p>Because the content of read-only files cannot be modified, the <uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol>
      operation is not processing those files. For every such file, a warning message is displayed
      in the message panel.</p>
    <fig id="figure-find-replace-in-files-dialog">
      <title>Find / Replace in Files</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_find_replace_in_files.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The dialog contains the following options:</p>
    <ul>
      <li conref="find-replace-dialog.dita#find-replace-dialog/text-to-find"/>
      <li conref="find-replace-dialog.dita#find-replace-dialog/case-sensitive"/>
      <li conref="find-replace-dialog.dita#find-replace-dialog/whole-words"/>
      <li conref="find-replace-dialog.dita#find-replace-dialog/regexp"/>
      <li conref="find-replace-dialog.dita#find-replace-dialog/xpath"/>
      <li conref="find-replace-dialog.dita#find-replace-dialog/xml-search-options"/>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> - The character string with which to replace the
        target. It may contain regular expression group markers if the search expression is a
        regular expression and the <uicontrol>Regular expression</uicontrol> checkbox is
        checked.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Make backup files with extension</uicontrol> - In the replace process <ph
          keyref="product"/> makes backup files of
        the modified files. The default extension is <filepath>.bak</filepath> but you can change
        the extension as you prefer.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Selected project files</uicontrol> - Searches only in the selected files of the
        current opened project. Not displayed when dialog is started from <ph
          product="author editor">contextual menu of <xref
            href="editing-dita-maps.dita#editing-dita-maps" format="dita"><uicontrol>DITA
              Maps</uicontrol> view</xref> and</ph>
        <xref href="archive-browser-view.dita#archive-browser-view" format="dita">Archive
          Browser</xref> view.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Project files</uicontrol> - Searches in all files from the current project. Not
        displayed when dialog is started from <ph product="author editor">contextual menu of <xref
            href="editing-dita-maps.dita#editing-dita-maps" format="dita"><uicontrol>DITA
              Maps</uicontrol> view</xref> and</ph>
        <xref href="archive-browser-view.dita#archive-browser-view" format="dita">Archive
          Browser</xref> view.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>All opened files</uicontrol> - Searches in all files opened in <ph
          keyref="product"/>
        <ph product="author editor">(regular files or DITA Maps)</ph>. You are prompted to save all
        modified files before any operation is performed. Not displayed when dialog is started from
          <ph product="author editor">contextual menu of <xref
            href="editing-dita-maps.dita#editing-dita-maps" format="dita"><uicontrol>DITA
              Maps</uicontrol> view</xref> and </ph><xref
          href="archive-browser-view.dita#archive-browser-view" format="dita">Archive Browser</xref>
        view.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Current file directory</uicontrol> - The search is done in the directory of the
        file opened in the current editor panel. If there is no opened file, this option is disabled
        in the dialog. Not displayed when dialog is started from <ph product="author editor"
          >contextual menu of <xref href="editing-dita-maps.dita#editing-dita-maps" format="dita"
              ><uicontrol>DITA Maps</uicontrol> view</xref> and</ph>
        <xref href="archive-browser-view.dita#archive-browser-view" format="dita">Archive
          Browser</xref> view.</li>
      <li product="author editor"><uicontrol>Current DITA Map hierarchy</uicontrol> - The search is
        done in all maps and topics referenced by the current edited DITA Map. If <uicontrol>Recurse
          referenced maps</uicontrol> option is checked, the references from the maps referenced in
        the main DITA map are also searched in. If there is no opened DITA Map, this option is
        disabled in the dialog. You are prompted to save all modified files before any operation is
        performed. Displayed only when dialog is opened from <xref
          href="editing-dita-maps.dita#editing-dita-maps" format="dita"><uicontrol>DITA
            Maps</uicontrol> view</xref>.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Opened archive</uicontrol> - The search is done in archive opened in <xref
          href="archive-browser-view.dita#archive-browser-view" format="dita">Archive Browser</xref>
        view. Displayed only when dialog is opened from <xref
          href="archive-browser-view.dita#archive-browser-view" format="dita">Archive Browser</xref>
        view.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Specified path</uicontrol> - Chooses the search path.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Include files</uicontrol> - Narrows the scope of the operation only to the
        files that match the given filters.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Recurse subdirectories</uicontrol> - When checked, the search is performed
        recursively in the sub directories found in the specified directory path.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Include hidden files</uicontrol> - When checked, the search is performed also
        in the hidden files.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Include archives</uicontrol> - When checked, the search is also done in all
        individual file entries from all supported ZIP-type archives.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show separate results for each search expression</uicontrol> - When checked,
        the application opens a new tab to display the result of each new search expression. When
        the option is unchecked, the search results are displayed in the <i>Find in Files</i> tab,
        replacing any previous search results.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Find All</uicontrol> - Executes a find operation and returns the result list to
        the message panel. The results are <xref href="results-view.dita#results-view" format="dita"
          >displayed in a view</xref> that allows grouping the results as a tree with two
        levels.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace All</uicontrol> - Replaces all occurrences of the target contained in
        the specified files.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>When you replace a fragment of text, <ph
        keyref="product"/> provides a preview of the
      changes you make. The <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> dialog is divided in two sections. The
      first section presents a list of all the documents containing the fragment of text you want to
      modify. The second section offers a view of the original file and a view of the final result.
      It also allows you to highlight all changes using the vertical bar from the right side of the
      view. The <uicontrol>Next change</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Previous change</uicontrol>
      buttons allow you to navigate through the changes displayed in the
        <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> dialog.</p>
    <note type="caution">Use this option with caution. Global search and replace across all project
      files does not open the files containing the targets, nor does it prompt on a per occurrence
      basis, to confirm that a replace operation must be performed. As the operation simply matches
      the string defined in the find field, this may result in replacement of matching strings that
      were not originally intended to be replaced.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
