<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="find-all-elements-dialog">
  <title>The Find All Elements / Attributes Dialog</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Find/Replace<indexterm>Find All Elements/Attributes dialog</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Find All Elements / Attributes</uicontrol> dialog, go to <ph
        product="author developer editor"><menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Find All Elements...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>(<uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_e"/>)</ph>
      <menucascade product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Find All Elements...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>
      <ph product="editor author developer">or from the shortcut <uicontrol>Find All Elements /
          Attributes</uicontrol> that is available in <xref
          href="find-replace-dialog.dita#find-replace-dialog" format="dita">the <uicontrol>Find /
            Replace</uicontrol> dialog</xref></ph> . It assists you in defining XML elements /
      attributes search operations on the current document.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Find All Elements / Attributes dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_find_all_elements.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The dialog can perform the following actions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Find all the elements with a specified name;</li>
      <li>Find all the elements which contain or not a specified string in their text content;</li>
      <li>Find all the elements which have a specified attribute;</li>
      <li>Find all the elements which have an attribute with or without a specified value.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>You can combine all these search criteria to fine filter your results.</p>
    <p>The results of all the operations in the <uicontrol>Find All Elements /
        Attributes</uicontrol> dialog will be presented as a list in the message panel.</p>
    <p>The following fields are available in the dialog:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Element name</uicontrol> - the target element name to search for. Only the
        elements with this exact name are returned. For any element name just leave the field
        empty;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Element text</uicontrol> - the target element text to search for. The combo box
        beside this field allows you to specify that you are looking for an exact or partial match
        of the element text. For any element text, select <uicontrol>contains</uicontrol> in the
        combo box and leave the field empty. If you leave the field empty but select
          <uicontrol>equals</uicontrol> in the combo box, only elements with no text will be found.
        Select <uicontrol>not contains</uicontrol> to find all elements which do not have the
        specified text inside;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Attribute name</uicontrol> - the name of the attribute which needs to be
        present in the elements. Only the elements which have an attribute with this name will be
        returned. For any / no attribute name just leave the field empty;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Attribute value</uicontrol> - the combo box beside this field allows you to
        specify that you are looking for an exact or partial match of the attribute value. For any /
        no attribute value select <uicontrol>contains</uicontrol> in the combo box and leave the
        field empty. If you leave the field empty but select <uicontrol>equals</uicontrol> in the
        combo box, only elements that have at least an attribute with an empty value will be found.
        Select <uicontrol>not contains</uicontrol> to find all elements which have attributes
        without a specified value;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Case sensitive</uicontrol> - When this option is checked, operations are case
        sensitive.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>