<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="find-replace-dialog">
  <title>The Find / Replace Dialog</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Find/Replace</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit<indexterm>find/replace</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Find / Replace</uicontrol> dialog, either go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author diff developer">Find</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="svnClient">Edit</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Find / Replace... </uicontrol>
      </menucascade> or click the <ph product="editor author developer">
        <uicontrol>
          <image href="../img/sa_find_replace_button.png"/> Find / Replace</uicontrol></ph> toolbar
      button. You can also press <uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_f"/> keys on your keyboard to
      display the <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> dialog.</p>
    <fig id="figure-find-replace-dialog-developer" product="developer">
      <title>Find / Replace Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_find_replace_developer.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editor">
      <title>Find / Replace Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_find_replace.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="author">
      <title>Find / Replace Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_author_find_replace.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="svnClient">
      <title>Find / Replace Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_svn_find_replace.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="diff">
      <title>Find / Replace Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_diff_find_replace.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>You can use the <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> dialog to perform the following operations:<ul>
        <li>Replace occurrences of target defined in the <uicontrol>Text to find</uicontrol> area
          with a new fragment of text defined in <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> area.</li>
        <li>Find all the occurrences of a word or string of characters (that can span over multiple
          lines) in the document you are editing. This operation also takes into account all the
          white spaces contained in the fragment you are searching for.</li>
      </ul><note>The <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> dialog counts the number of occurrences of
        the text you are searching for and displays it at the bottom of the dialog, above the
          <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol> button. <ph product="editor author developer">This number is
          also displayed in <xref href="results-view.dita#results-view">the
              <uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> view</xref>.</ph></note></p>
    <p>The <term>find</term> operation works on multiple lines, meaning that a find match can cover
      characters on more than one line of text. To input multiple-line text in the <uicontrol>Text
        to find</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> areas, do one of the following:<ul>
        <li>press <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_eneter"/>
          keys on your keyboard;</li>
        <li>use the <uicontrol>Insert newline</uicontrol> contextual menu action.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>You can use <xref href="http://perldoc.perl.org/perlre.html#Regular-Expressions"
        format="html" scope="external"><term>Perl 5</term></xref> regular expressions to define
      patterns. A content completion assistant window is available in the <uicontrol>Text to
        find</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> areas to help you edit regular
      expressions. It is activated every time you type <b>\</b>(backslash key) or on demand if you
      press <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_space"/> keys
      on your keyboard.</p>
    <p>The <term>replace</term> operation can bind <xref
        href="http://perldoc.perl.org/perlre.html#Regular-Expressions" format="html"
        scope="external">Perl 5</xref> regular expression group variables ($1, $2, and so on.) from
      the find match. </p>
    <example>To replace an XML tag called <codeph>tag-name</codeph> with the tag
        <codeph>tag-name1</codeph>, use <i>&lt;tag-name(\s+)(.*)&gt;</i> in the <uicontrol>Text to
        find</uicontrol> area and <i>&lt;tag-name1$1$2&gt;</i> in the <uicontrol>Replace
        with</uicontrol> area. </example>
    <p>The dialog contains the following options:</p>
    <ul>
      <li id="text-to-find"><uicontrol>Text to find</uicontrol> - The target character string to
        search for. You can search for Unicode characters specified in the <codeph>\uNNNN</codeph>
        format. Also, hexadecimal notation (<codeph>\xNNNN</codeph>) and octal notation
          (<codeph>\0NNNN</codeph>) can be used. In this case you have to select the
          <uicontrol>Regular expression</uicontrol> option. For example, to search for a space
        character you can use the <codeph>\u0020</codeph> code.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> - The character string with which to replace the
        target. The string for replace can be on a line or on multiple lines. It can contain <xref
          href="http://perldoc.perl.org/perlre.html#Regular-Expressions" format="html"
          scope="external">Perl 5</xref> regular expression group markers, only if the search
        expression is a regular expression and the <uicontrol>Regular expression</uicontrol> option
        is selected.<p><note><ph id="regexp_interrupt_dialog">Some regular expressions can block
              indefinitely the application. If the execution of the regular expression does not end
              in about 5 seconds, the application displays a dialog that allows you to interrupt the
              operation.</ph></note><note>Special characters like <term>newline</term> and
              <term>tab</term> can be inserted in the <uicontrol>Text to find</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> text boxes using dedicated actions in the
            contextual menu (<uicontrol>Insert newline</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Insert
              tab</uicontrol>).</note>Unicode characters can also be used in the <uicontrol>Replace
            with</uicontrol> area.</p></li>
      <li>The history buttons <uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_find_history16.png"/></uicontrol> -
        Contain lists of the last find and replace expressions.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer" id="xpath"><uicontrol>XPath</uicontrol> - The XPath 2.0
        expression you input in this combo is used for restricting the search scope.<note>The
            <uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol> helps you input XPath expressions,
          valid in the current context.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Direction</uicontrol> - Specifies if the search direction is from current
        position to end of file (<uicontrol>Forward</uicontrol>) or to start of file
          (<uicontrol>Backward</uicontrol>).</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> - <ph product="developer editor">Specifies whether the
            <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> operation is executed over the entire content of the
          edited document (<uicontrol>All</uicontrol> option), or  over the selected lines of text
            (<uicontrol>Only selected lines</uicontrol> option). In case the selection spans across
          multiple lines, when you open the <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> dialog box, the
          scope is set to <uicontrol>Only selected lines</uicontrol>. </ph><ph product="author">In
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the search scope is restricted to the entire
          document only.</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Find</uicontrol> - Executes a find operation for the next occurrence of the
        target. It stops after highlighting the find match in the editor panel.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol> - Executes a replace operation for the target followed by a
        find operation for the next occurrence.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Find All</uicontrol> - Executes a find
        operation and displays all results in the <xref href="results-view.dita#results-view"
          format="dita"><uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> view</xref>. The results are
          <xref href="results-view.dita#results-view" format="dita">displayed in the Results
          view</xref>.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace All</uicontrol> - Executes a replace operation in the entire scope of
        the document.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace to End</uicontrol> - Executes a replace operation starting from current
        target until the end of the document, in the direction specified by the current selection of
        the <uicontrol>Direction</uicontrol> switch (<uicontrol>Forward</uicontrol> or
          <uicontrol>Backward</uicontrol>).</li>
      <li id="case-sensitive"><uicontrol>Case sensitive</uicontrol> - When checked, the search
        operation follows the exact letter case of the <uicontrol>Text to find</uicontrol>.</li>
      <li id="whole-words"><uicontrol>Whole words only</uicontrol> - Only entire occurrences of a
        word are included in the search operation.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Incremental</uicontrol> - The search operation is started every time you type
        or delete a letter in the <uicontrol>Text to find</uicontrol> text box.</li>
      <li id="regexp"><uicontrol>Regular expression</uicontrol> - When this option is enabled, you
        can use regular expressions in <xref
          href="http://perldoc.perl.org/perlre.html#Regular-Expressions" format="html"
          scope="external">Perl 5</xref> syntax to look for specific pieces of text. A match can
        span over multiple lines of text.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Dot matches all</uicontrol> - A dot used in a regular expression matches also
        end of line characters.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Wrap around</uicontrol> - When the end of the document is reached, the search
        operation is continued from the start of the document, until its entire content is
        covered.</li>
      <li product="author developer editor" id="xml-search-options"><uicontrol>Enable XML search
          options</uicontrol> - Provides access to a set of options that allow you to search
        specific XML component types when editing in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Element names</uicontrol> - Only the element names are included in the
            search operation which ignores XML-tag notations ('&lt;', '/', '&gt;'), attributes or
            white-spaces.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Element contents</uicontrol> - Search in the text content of XML
            elements.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Attribute names</uicontrol> - Only the attribute names are included in the
            search operation, without the leading or trailing white-spaces.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Attribute values</uicontrol> - Only the attribute values are included in
            the search operation, without single quotes(') or double quotes(").</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> - Only the content of comments are included in the
            search operation, excluding the XML comment delimiters ('&lt;!--', '--&gt;').</li>
          <li>Processing Instructions (<uicontrol>PIs</uicontrol>) - Only the content are searched,
            skipping '&lt;?', '?&gt;'. e. g.: &lt;?<u>processing instruction</u>?&gt;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>CDATA</uicontrol> - Searches inside content of CDATA sections.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>DOCTYPE</uicontrol> - Searches inside content of DOCTYPE sections.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Entities</uicontrol> - Only the entity names are searched.</li>
        </ul><p>The two buttons <uicontrol>Select All</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Deselect
            All</uicontrol> allow a simple activation and deactivation of all types of XML
          components.</p><note>Please note that since searching in some XML component types is
          performed only on their content skipping some of their headers / footers (see the list
          above), even if all the XML component types are checked, some filtering is still
          performed. To disable it completely,  uncheck <uicontrol>Enable XML search
            options</uicontrol>.</note></li>
      <li product="author editor"><uicontrol>Find All Elements / Attributes ...</uicontrol> - While
        editing in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, press the <uicontrol>Find All Elements /
          Attributes ...</uicontrol> to extend the search scope to XML-specific markup (names and
        values of both attributes and elements). </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
