<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="finishing_tasks">
    <title>Finalizing Tasks</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Reviewer Guide<indexterm>Finalizing tasks</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Finalize My Review</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Finalizing tasks</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p id="p_fzt_dgk_54b">Content Fusion includes a <uicontrol>Finalize My Review</uicontrol> button
      (available in the top stripe when a file is open in the <xref
        href="making_changes_to_uploaded_files.dita#making_changes_to_uploaded_files">Visual Editor
        page</xref>) that can be used to indicate that the user has finished the task review
      process. Note that all files attached to the task should be reviewed before finalizing the
      task.</p>
    <p id="p_gzt_dgk_54b">Using the <uicontrol>Finalize My Review</uicontrol> button adds a
      predefined message to the task, informing the <b>Content Author</b> that you have reviewed all
      the files attached and you are finished with the review process. The resulting dialog box also
      has an option to add an additional message to provide more details, if desired.<note
        type="other" othertype="Notes" id="note_kzt_dgk_54b">
        <ul id="ul_fmz_4vz_2mb">
          <li id="li_lzt_dgk_54b">Using the <uicontrol>Finalize My Review</uicontrol> button does
            not delete or lock the task. It is simply meant to be a way to notify others that your
            review process is finished.</li>
          <li id="li_mzt_dgk_54b">You can see all your finalized review tasks by going to the <xref
              href="content_fusion_task_details.dita"><uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol>
              page</xref> (click the <uicontrol>Review Tasks</uicontrol> button in the top header
            stripe or select <uicontrol>My Review Tasks</uicontrol> from the user name drop-down
            menu in the top-right corner). Then go to the <uicontrol>Assigned To Me</uicontrol> tab
            and if the finalized tasks category is not shown, click the <uicontrol>Show finalized
              review tasks</uicontrol> link at the bottom of the page.</li>
          <li id="li_bzv_1dl_b1c">When you finalize a review task, it remains in the
              <uicontrol>Finalized</uicontrol> state if other collaborators make changes to
            documents within the task. The <uicontrol>Finalized</uicontrol> state does reset for a
            particular user if they make changes within the task, or if a task owner either <xref
              href="cf-closing-tasks.dita">re-opens a closed task</xref> or <xref
              href="content_fusion_task_details.dita#content_fusion_task_details/p_yfw_x22_h1c"
              >requests another review of the task</xref>. That particular user will need to use the
              <uicontrol>Finalize My Review</uicontrol> button to finalize the review again once
            they are done making changes.</li>
        </ul>
      </note></p>
  </body>
</topic>
