<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="framework-location">
  <title>Locations Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Locations</uicontrol> preferences page allows you to specify the main
        <filepath>frameworks</filepath> folder location. You can choose between the default
      directory (<filepath>OXYGEN_INSTALLATION_FOLDER/frameworks</filepath>) or a custom specified
      directory. You can also change the current <filepath>frameworks</filepath> folder location
      value using the <codeph>com.oxygenxml.editor.frameworks.url</codeph> property set either in
      the application's <xref
        href="set-parameter-in-startup-script.dita#set-parameter-in-startup-script" format="dita"
          ><filepath>.vmoptions</filepath> configuration files or in the startup scripts</xref>;</p>
    <p>You can also specify a list of additional <filepath>frameworks</filepath> directories. The
      application will look in each of those folders for additional document type configurations to
      load. Use the <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> and
        <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> buttons to manage the list of folders.</p>
    <p>A document type (configuration) can be loaded from the following locations:<ul
        id="ul_ox2_rfs_f4">
        <li>internal preferences - The document type configuration is stored in the application's
            <xref href="the-document-type-dialog.dita#the-document-type-dialog/storage-definition"
              ><uicontrol>Internal</uicontrol> preferences</xref>;</li>
        <li>additional frameworks directories - The document type configuration is loaded from one
          of the specified <uicontrol>Additional frameworks directories</uicontrol> list;</li>
        <li>add-ons - An add-on can contribute a framework. You can manage the add-ons locations in
          the <xref href="preferences-extensions.dita#preferences-extensions">Add-ons preferences
            page</xref>;</li>
        <li>the <filepath>frameworks</filepath> folder - The main folder containing framework
          configurations.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>All loaded document type configurations are first sorted by priority, then by document type
      name and then by load location (in the exact order specified above). When an XML document is
      opened, the application chooses the first document type configuration from the sorted list
      which matches the specific document.</p>
    <p>All loaded document type configurations are first sorted by priority, then by document type </p>
  </body>
</topic>
