<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="generate-ids">
  <title>Generating IDs for Elements in Author Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Generating IDs</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Generating
            IDs</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Generate IDs in Author mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to manually assign or edit values of <codeph>id</codeph>
      attributes in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode by using the <xref
        href="author-attributes-view.dita"><uicontrol>Attributes View</uicontrol></xref> or an <xref
        href="editing-attributes-author-mode.dita#editing-attributes-author-mode">in-place attribute
        editor</xref>. <ph keyref="product"/> also includes mechanisms to generate ID values for
      elements, either on-request or automatically, in DITA, DocBook, or TEI documents.</p>
    <section id="generate_ids_onrequest">
      <title>Generate IDs On-Request</title>
      <p>You can generate ID values for specific elements on-request. To do so, select the element
        for which you want to generate an ID (or place the cursor inside the element) and select the
          <uicontrol>Generate IDs</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu or the
        framework-specific menu (<uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>DocBook</uicontrol>, or
          <uicontrol>TEI</uicontrol>). This action generates a unique ID for the current element. If
        you invoke the action on a block of selected content, the action will generate IDs for all
        top-level elements and elements that are listed in the <xref
          href="#generate-ids/id-options-dialog-section" format="dita"><uicontrol>ID
            Options</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> that are found in the current selection.<note
          conkeyref="reusables-author-actions/generate-id-note"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="automatically_generate_ids">
      <title>Automatically Generate IDs</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes an option to automatically add unique ID values to certain
        elements when they are created in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. The <uicontrol>Auto
          generate IDs for elements</uicontrol> option can be found in the <xref
          href="#generate-ids/id-options-dialog-section" format="dita"><uicontrol>ID
            Options</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> that is displayed when you select the
          <uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol> action from the framework-specific menu
          (<uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>DocBook</uicontrol>, or
          <uicontrol>TEI</uicontrol>). If this <uicontrol>Auto generate IDs for elements</uicontrol>
        option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> automatically generates unique ID values for
        elements that are listed in this dialog box. You can use this dialog box to customize the
        format of the ID values and choose which elements will have their ID values automatically
        generated (for example, you can customize the list of elements to include those that you
        most often need to identify).</p>
    </section>
    <section id="id-options-dialog-section">
      <title>ID Options Dialog Box</title>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_gjm_vwy_xs">
          <title>ID Options Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/id_options_dialog.png" id="image_w4r_wwy_xs"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The <uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol> dialog box allows you to configure the following
        options in regards to generating ID values:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry conkeyref="reusables-author-actions/id-pattern-dlentry"
            conrefend="../reusables/topics/author-actions.dita#author-actions/remove-ids-dlentry"
            id="id-options">
            <dt/>
            <dd/>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="duplicating_elements_with_existing_ids">
      <title>Duplicating Elements with Existing IDs</title>
      <p>If you duplicate elements with existing IDs (for example, through copy/paste or drag/drop
        actions), all IDs are removed at the resolution of the operation. However, you can use the
        options in the <uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol> dialog box to change this behavior. The
        options in this dialog box affect duplicated elements with existing IDs in the following
          ways:<note>Only the elements listed in this dialog box are affected by these options.
          Therefore, if you want to use these options to preserve IDs or generate new ones, you must
          first add the elements to be duplicated to the list in this dialog box. </note><ul>
          <li>If the <xref href="#generate-ids/id-options" format="dita"><uicontrol>Auto generate
                IDs for elements</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected and you duplicate elements
            with existing IDs, <ph keyref="product"/> assigns new, unique ID values to the
            duplicates.</li>
          <li>If the <xref href="#generate-ids/id-options" format="dita"><uicontrol>Auto generate
                IDs for elements</uicontrol> option</xref> is not selected and you duplicate
            elements with existing IDs, the ID values are removed from the duplicates. However, when
            elements are duplicated in the same document, this option has no effect and IDs are
            preserved if the <xref href="#generate-ids/id-options" format="dita"><uicontrol>Remove
                IDs when copying content in the same document</uicontrol> option</xref> is not
            selected.</li>
          <li>If the <xref href="#generate-ids/id-options" format="dita"><uicontrol>Remove IDs when
                copying content in the same document</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected, the ID
            values are removed from elements that are duplicated in the same document. However,
            selecting this option has no effect if the <uicontrol>Auto generate IDs for
              elements</uicontrol> option is selected.</li>
          <li>If the <xref href="#generate-ids/id-options" format="dita"><uicontrol>Remove IDs when
                copying content in the same document</uicontrol> option</xref> is not selected, the
            ID values are preserved when elements are duplicated in the same document. This option
            has no affect on elements that are duplicated in other documents.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="controlling_the_default_id_generation_options">
      <title>Controlling the Default ID Generation Options</title>
      <p>It is possible to configure the default ID generation options for DITA, DocBook, and TEI
        document types. In the <filepath>frameworks</filepath> folder for each of those document
        types, there is an XML configuration file called
          <filepath>idGenerationDefaultOptions.xml</filepath> that contains the default settings for
        generating IDs in each particular type of document. To configure the default settings, you
        can edit this file and save it back to the same directory.</p>
      <p>The configuration file can be found in the <filepath>resources</filepath> folder within the
        particular framework. For example, the configuration file for the DITA framework is located
        in: <filepath><term conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"
          />/frameworks/dita/resources/idGenerationDefaultOptions.xml</filepath>.</p>
      <sectiondiv><b>Sharing Default ID Generation Options</b><p>If you want to share your
          configured default ID generation settings with other member of your team, follow these steps:<ol>
            <li>Configure the <filepath>idGenerationDefaultOptions.xml</filepath> file for your
              framework according to your needs.</li>
            <li>Bundle a modified version of the entire framework folder (for example,
                  <filepath><term conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"
                />/frameworks/dita/</filepath>). To do this:<ol>
                <li><ph conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/Open-the-preferences-page"/> and go
                  to <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol>.</li>
                <li>Select your framework and click the <uicontrol>Extend</uicontrol> button.</li>
                <li>In the <xref href="the-document-type-dialog.dita#the-document-type-dialog"
                      ><uicontrol>Document type</uicontrol> configuration dialog box</xref> that is
                  now displayed, select <uicontrol>External</uicontrol> for the
                    <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option. By default, this will save the extension
                  in a new folder in the <filepath>frameworks</filepath> folder (for example,
                      <filepath><term conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"
                    />/frameworks/dita-extension (1)</filepath>), but you can also use the
                      <uicontrol><image href="../img/Open16.png"/>Browse</uicontrol> button to
                  specify a specific name and folder.</li>
                <li>In this new extension folder, create a new folder called
                    <filepath>resources</filepath> and add your modified
                    <filepath>idGenerationDefaultOptions.xml</filepath> file to this new
                    <filepath>resources</filepath> folder.</li>
                <li>Go back to the <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol> preferences
                  page, select the extended framework, and click <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>.</li>
                <li>Go to the <xref
                    href="document-type-classpath-tab.dita#document-type-classpath-tab"
                      ><uicontrol>Classpath</uicontrol> tab</xref>, add a reference to your new
                    <filepath>resources</filepath> folder, and move this reference up (using the
                      <uicontrol><image href="../img/MoveUpEntry16.gif" id="image_fpb_rr1_5r"/>Move
                    Up</uicontrol> button) so that it is the first one that appears in the
                  list.</li>
                <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> and exit out of the preferences page.</li>
              </ol></li>
            <li>Distribute your newly extended folder to other team members by using one of the
              methods described in <xref
                href="author-document-type-sharing.dita#author-document-type-sharing"/>.</li>
          </ol></p></sectiondiv>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
