<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="generate-html-report-for-directory-comparison">
  <title>Generate HTML Report for Directory Comparison</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Generate HTML report for directory comparison tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_w3v_bgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Generate HTML report for directory comparison</uicontrol>
      tool can be used to generate a report in the form of an HTML file that contains the results of
      a directory comparison (for either 2-way or 3-way comparisons). The <uicontrol>Generate HTML
        report for directory comparison</uicontrol> action for invoking the tool can be found in the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Comparison Tools</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu. It opens a dialog box where you can specify the directories to compare as
      well as some other options.</p>
    <p id="p_uh1_zfx_5pb">
      <fig id="fig_uwg_zfx_5pb">
        <title>Generate HTML Report for Directory Comparison Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/html-report-dialog-box.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_x5d_hgx_5pb">The <uicontrol>Generate HTML report for directory comparison</uicontrol>
      dialog box contains the following options:</p>
    <p id="p_p3d_5vj_vpb">
      <dl id="dl_q5g_5vj_vpb">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_r5g_5vj_vpb">
          <dt>Base directory</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the path of the base directory that the other two directories will be
            compared against in a 3-way comparison. This field should be left empty for 2-way
            comparisons.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_jv1_bwj_vpb">
          <dt>First directory</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the path of the first directory to be included in the comparison.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_owv_kwj_vpb">
          <dt>Second directory</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the path of the second directory to be included in the comparison.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_nkr_lwj_vpb">
          <dt>Diff options</dt>
          <dd>Specifies which option set to use for generating the comparison report. If you choose
              <uicontrol>Use the current settings from Preferences</uicontrol>, the options set in
            the <xref href="preferences-diff-dirs.dita"><uicontrol>Directories
                Comparison</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> and the <xref
              href="dir-compare-toolbar.dita#dir-compare-toolbar/dlentry_yhv_bgk_54b"
              >include/exclude filter options in the <uicontrol>Compare Directories</uicontrol>
              tool</xref> are taken into account when generating the comparison result. You can also
            click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ecvc-Settings16.png"/>Diff options</uicontrol>
            button to open the <uicontrol>Directories Comparison</uicontrol> preferences page where
            you can see or modify the current settings. If you choose <uicontrol>Use the default
              settings</uicontrol>, the default values for all settings are used.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_esx_djc_kqb">
          <dt>Generate additional file comparison reports</dt>
          <dd>Generates further comparison reports for all non-binary modified file pairs and
            provides links to them in the main report (in the middle cells of the results table).
              <xref href="#generate-html-report-for-directory-comparison/p_additional-file-reports"
              format="dita">See the example below</xref>. These additional file comparison reports
            are saved to a directory that will have the same parent directory and the same name as
            the output file provided, suffixed by <uicontrol>"-OXY-FC-REPORTS"</uicontrol>. The
            links created in the main report are relative to this directory. If the main HTML report
            is later copied or moved to another location, to retain full functionality in the
            browser, the directory with the additional file comparison reports must also be
            copied/moved to the same location.<note id="note_s14_kjc_kqb">Generating additional file
              comparison reports could significantly increase the execution time. A progress tracker
              for the whole operation is available.</note><note id="note_o2l_x2b_4yb" type="tip">An
              XPath expression specified in the <uicontrol>Ignore nodes by XPath</uicontrol> text
              field within the <xref href="preferences-diff-files.dita"><uicontrol>Files
                  Comparison</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> is now taken into account if you
              enable the <uicontrol>Generate additional file comparison reports</uicontrol>
              option.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_zzs_4yj_vpb">
          <dt>Output file</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the path for an output file to save the comparison results file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_e3v_bgk_54b">
          <dt>Open in Browser/System Application</dt>
          <dd>Opens the comparison results file in the browser or system application that is
            associated with HTML files.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p id="p_mzx_czj_vpb">After clicking the <uicontrol>Generate report</uicontrol> button, a report
      in the form of an HTML file is generated with details about the comparison results.</p>
    <p id="p_jnw_hgx_5pb">
      <fig id="fig_knw_hgx_5pb">
        <title>HTML Report for Directory Comparison</title>
        <image href="../img/html-report-results.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_additional-file-reports">
      <fig id="fig_sw1_jfg_kqb">
        <title>Example of an Additional File Comparison Report</title>
        <image href="../img/html-report-results-files.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="section_vvs_vvd_1rb">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p id="p_nll_dgk_54bc">For more information about how to generate HTML comparison reports,
        watch our video demonstration:</p>
      <p id="p_oll_dgk_54bd"><object width="450" height="250"
        data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6jPccHKUNNk" outputclass="iframe">
        <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
      </object></p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
      <link href="directories-comparison.dita#directories-comparison"/>
    <link href="compare-directories-3-way.dita"/>
      <link href="file-comparison.dita#file-comparison"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
