<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="getting-started-first-XML-document">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140805T172929-0400" comment="This is a getting started topic. Its purpose is to give a new user just enough information to get them through their first document. The aim is to give them confidence and an early success with the product. This will encourage them to explore the features of the product further. 

A gettting started topic does not exhaustively list all the ways to do something, nor does it give all the opitons of the controls and views it mentions. Its focus is on getting the new user through the basics. Learning all the options will come later for them -- when they decide they are ready or that they need them."?><?oxy_comment_start author="George" timestamp="20140906T021427+0300" comment="It may be easier to create separate topics for Eclipse, maybe we can start from a similar topic and change it. If we end up with only a few changes we can come back and integrate them with profiling in the original topic, otherwise we can leave two separate topics." mid="1"?><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150611T102153+0300" comment="Test and profile everything in this topic for Eclipse (author,editor). Also, I think this topic should also be for Developer but it would obviously need to be heavily profiled since only some of the content here is for Developer."?><?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140804T150114-0400" comment="Currently this topic is profiled to SA Author and Editor only. (Not Developer, because no Author mode, and not Eclipse plugin because different UI. Question is whether to profile parts of it for Eclipse or create a separate topic for Eclipse. " mid="3"?>Y<?oxy_comment_end?>our<?oxy_comment_end?>
    First XML Document<?oxy_comment_end mid="1"?><?oxy_comment_end mid="3"?></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Getting Started</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To create your first XML document, select <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol><image href="../img/New16.png" id="image_nmg_12p_sr"/>New...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The <xref href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa"><uicontrol>New
          Document Wizard</uicontrol></xref> is displayed:</p>
    <image href="../img/NewDocumentWizard.png" id="image_odn_xh4_y4"/>
    <p>You can either create a new XML document from scratch by choosing one of the available types
      in the <uicontrol>New Document</uicontrol> folder, or you can create one from a template by
      choosing a template from the <uicontrol>Global templates</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Framework
        templates</uicontrol> folders. If you are looking for a common document type, such as DITA
      or DocBook, you can find templates for these document types in the <uicontrol>Framework
        templates</uicontrol> folder. If your company has created its own templates, you can also
      find them there. After you use this dialog box to create a few documents, those document types
      will appear in the <uicontrol>Recently used</uicontrol> folder, which allows you to easily
      create other new documents of those types.</p>
    <p>For some document types, you may find a number of different templates. For example, there are
      numerous templates for DocBook documents, and DITA topic types and maps. Choose the template
      that best meets your needs.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Writing Your First Document</title>
      <p>Depending on the type of document you choose, the <ph keyref="product"/> interface changes
        to support editing that document type. This may include new menus, toolbar buttons, and
        items in the contextual menus. </p>
      <p>Also, depending on the type of document you choose, <ph keyref="product"/> may open your
        document in <xref keyref="mode.text"><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol></xref> or <xref
          keyref="mode.author"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol></xref> mode.
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode shows the raw XML source file, while
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode shows a graphical view of the document. </p>
      <p>Whether there is an <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode view available for your document
        type depends on the type you choose and if there is a CSS stylesheet available to create the
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> view. <ph keyref="product"/> includes default
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode views for most of the document types it supports. If
        your company has created its own document types, <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode
        stylesheets may have also been created for that type. However, if you create a plain XML
        file, or one based on a schema that is not included in the <ph keyref="product"/> built-in
        support, you need to edit it in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode or <xref
          keyref="customize.css-stylesheet">create your own <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode style
          sheet</xref> for it. </p>
      <p>You can switch back and forth between <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode at any time by clicking the buttons at the bottom left of
        the editor window. You do not lose any formatting when switching from
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode.
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> modes are just different
        views for the same XML document. There is also a <xref keyref="mode.grid"
            ><uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode</xref> available, which is useful for certain kinds of
        documents, particularly those that are structured like databases. You can also use it to
          <xref keyref="grid-sort">sort things such as list items and table rows</xref>.</p>
      <p>If you use <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, you might find that it is similar to word
        processors that you are used to. Likewise, the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode is similar
        to many typical text editors. If you are new to XML, the biggest difference is that XML
        documents have a particular structure that you have to follow. <ph keyref="product"/>
        assists you with a continuous validation of the XML markup.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Structuring Your First Document</title>
      <p>Each XML document type has a particular structure that you have to follow as you write and
        edit the document. Some document types give you a lot of choices, while others give you very
        few. In either case, you need to make sure that your document follows the particular
        structure for the document type you are creating. This means:</p>
      <ul id="ul_q4x_zr4_y4">
        <li>At any given location in the document, there are only certain XML elements allowed. <ph
            keyref="product"/> helps you determine which elements are allowed. In
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, when you press <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol>, <ph
            keyref="product"/> assumes that you want to enter a new element and shows you a list of
          elements that can be created in this location. Keep typing until the element you want is
          highlighted and press <uicontrol>Enter</uicontrol> to insert the element. If you want to
          view the overall structure of a document and see what is allowed (and where), you can use
          the <uicontrol>Model</uicontrol> view (<menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Model</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>).</li>
        <li>When you create certain elements, you may find that your text gets a jagged red
          underline and you get a warning that your content is invalid. This is usually because the
          element you have just created requires certain other elements inside of it. Your document
          will be invalid until you create those elements. <ph keyref="product"/> does its best to
          help you with this. If there is only one possible element that can go inside the element
          you just created, <ph keyref="product"/> creates it for you. However, if there is more
          than one possibility you have to create the appropriate elements yourself. </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Editing Your First Document</title>
      <p>Once you have completed the first draft of your document, you may need to edit it. As with
        any editor, <ph keyref="product"/> provides the normal cut, copy, and paste options as well
        as drag and drop editing. However, when you are editing an XML document, you have to make
        sure that your edits respect the structure of the XML document type. In fact, you are often
        editing the structure as well as the content of your document.</p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides many tools to help you edit your structure and to keep your
        structure correct while editing text. </p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>The Document Breadcrumbs</dt>
          <dd>Across the top of the editor window, there is a set of breadcrumbs that shows you
            exactly were the insertion point is in the structure of the document. <image
              href="../img/author_top_stripe.png" id="image_ehd_s1d_z4"/>. You can click on any
            element in the breadcrumbs to select that entire element in the document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Showing Tags</dt>
          <dd>To see exactly where you are in the structure of the document, you can show the tags
            graphically in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> view. There are several levels of tag
            visibility that you can choose using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/TagsDrop.png"
                id="image_ay4_shm_1s"/>Display tags mode</uicontrol> drop-down menu on the toolbar
            (the button may look a little different as it changes to reflect the level of tags
            currently displayed).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Outline View</dt>
          <dd>The <wintitle>Outline</wintitle> view shows you the structure of your document in
            outline format. You can use it to select elements, or to move elements around in the
            document. <fig id="fig_ezd_5hd_z4">
              <image href="../img/sa_XMLOutlineView.png" id="image_v3c_shd_z4"/>
            </fig><p>You can configure the <wintitle>Outline</wintitle> view to determine what is
              shown, such as element names, attributes, and comments. Certain choices may work
              better for particular document types. You can also filter the
                <wintitle>Outline</wintitle> view to show only elements with a certain name.
              </p><fig id="fig_rfm_34r_z4">
              <image href="../img/sa_filtered_xml_outline.png" id="image_j1d_k4r_z4"/>
            </fig></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Cut and Paste, Drag and Drop</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>You can cut and paste or drag and drop text, just as you would in any other editor.
              However, when you do this in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> view, it is important to
              remember that you are actually moving blocks of XML. When you cut and paste or drag
              and drop a block of XML, the result has to be valid both where the content is
              inserted, and where it is removed from. </p>
            <p>A big part of doing this correctly is to make sure that you pick up the right block
              of text in the first place. Using the breadcrumbs or <wintitle>Outline</wintitle>
              view, or showing tags and using them to select content, can help ensure that you are
              selecting the right chunk of XML.</p>
            <p>If you do try to paste or drop a chunk of XML somewhere that is not valid, <ph
                keyref="product"/> warns you and tries to suggest actions that make it valid (such
              as by removing surrounding elements from the chunk you are moving, by creating a new
              element at the destination, or by inserting it in a nearby location). </p>
            <p>You can also switch to <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> view to see exactly which bits of
              XML you are selecting and moving. </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Refactoring actions</dt>
          <dd>You can perform many common structure edits, such as renaming an element or wrapping
            text in an element, using the actions in the <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Markup</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu. The refactoring actions are also available from the contextual menu
            and on the <uicontrol>Markup</uicontrol> toolbar (right-click the toolbar area to choose
            which toolbars to show).</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Validating Your First Document</title>
      <p>Validation is the process of making sure that an XML document abides by the rules of its
        schema. If <ph keyref="product"/> knows how to find the schema, it validates the document
        for you as you type. (<ph keyref="product"/> finds the schema automatically for most of the
        document types created from templates. However, in some cases you may have to <xref
          keyref="validating-XML-documents-against-schema">tell it how to find the
        schema</xref>.)</p>
      <p>When <ph keyref="product"/> validates as you type, there is a small bar at the right edge
        of the editor that shows you if the document is invalid and where errors are found. If the
        indicator at the top of that bar is green, your document is valid. If the document is
        invalid, the indicator turns red and a red flag shows you where the errors are found. Click
        that flag to jump to the error. Remember that sometimes your document is invalid simply
        because the structure you are creating is not yet complete. </p>
      <p>In addition to problems with the validity of the XML document itself, <ph keyref="product"
        /> also reports warnings for a number of conditions, such as if your document contains a
        cross reference that cannot be resolved, or if <ph keyref="product"/> cannot find the schema
        specified by the document. The location of these warnings is marked in yellow on the
        validation bar. If the document contains warnings, but no errors, the validity indicator
        turns yellow. </p>
      <p>You can also validate your document at any time by selecting the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/Validate16.png" id="image_eqy_hrv_sr"/>Validate</uicontrol> action from the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ValidateDrop.png" id="image_nmy_5rv_sr"
          />Validation</uicontrol> toolbar drop-down menu or the <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> menu.. When you validate in this manner, the validation result opens in a new
        pane and it shows each validation error on a separate line. Clicking on the error takes you
        to the location in your document where the error was detected. Be aware that the problem is
        sometimes in a different location from where the validator detects the error.</p>
      <p>To get more information on a validation error, right-click on a validation error message,
        and select <uicontrol>Show Message</uicontrol>.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Proofing Your First Document</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides spell checking support. You can check the spelling of your
        document by pressing the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CheckSpelling16.png"
            id="image_ftc_kvh_5r"/>Check Spelling...</uicontrol> button or selecting <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Check Spelling...</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>. Interactive spell checking is also available, although it is disabled by
        default. You may notice that validation errors are marked the same way spelling errors are
        marked in ordinary word processors. To turn it on, <ph
          conkeyref="reusable_menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Spell Check</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol> Automatic spell check</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Transforming Your First Document</title>
      <p>An XML document must be transformed in order to be published. Transformations are specific
        to the particular type of document you have created. A DITA transformation cannot be used on
        a DocBook file, or vice versa. A single document type may have many different
        transformations that produce different kinds of outputs. For some document types, such a
        DITA, many different content files may be combined together by a transformation. You need to
        locate and launch a transformation that is appropriate for your document type and the kind
        of output you want to generate.</p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> uses <xref keyref="transformation-scenario">transformation
          scenarios</xref> to control the transformation process. Depending on the document type you
        have created, there may be several transformation scenarios already configured for your use.
        This may include the default transformation scenarios supplied by <ph keyref="product"/> or
        ones created by your organization. </p>
      <p>To see the list of transformations available for your document, select the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ApplyStyleSheet16.png" id="image_yhg_svc_jp"/>Apply
          Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> action from the toolbar or the <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Transformation</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> menu. A list of available transformation scenarios are displayed. Choose one
        or more scenarios to apply, and click <uicontrol>Apply associated</uicontrol>. Exactly how
        your transformed content appears depends on how the transformation scenario is
        configured.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
