<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="getting-started-first-XML-document">
  <title>Your First XML Document</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Getting Started with Oxygen <indexterm>Your first XML
          document</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To create your first XML document, select <ph product="author developer editor"><menucascade>
          <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/New16.png" id="image_owg_fqs_vs"/>New</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> or click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/New16.png" id="image_hy1_zdp_sr"
          />New</uicontrol></ph><ph product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"><menucascade>
          <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Other</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Oxygen</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> or click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/EclipseNew.png"
            id="image_nbd_fkf_wr"/>New </uicontrol></ph> button on the toolbar. The <xref
        keyref="wizard_new-document"><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> document wizard</xref> is
      displayed:</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_ngk_55q_js" product="author developer editor">
        <title>New Document Wizard</title>
        <image href="../img/NewDocumentWizard.png" id="image_odn_xh4_y4"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>You can either create a new XML document from scratch by choosing one of the available types
      in the wizard. You can also create one from a template by <ph
        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">selecting <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>New from Templates</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and </ph>choosing a template from the <uicontrol>Global templates</uicontrol>
      or <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol> folders. If you are looking for a common
      document type, such as DITA or DocBook, you can find templates for these document types in the
        <uicontrol>Framework templates</uicontrol> folder. If your company has created its own
      templates, you can also find them there.<ph product="author developer editor"> After you use
        this dialog box to create a few documents, those document types will appear in the
          <uicontrol>Recently used</uicontrol> folder, which allows you to easily create other new
        documents of those types.</ph></p>
    <p>For some document types, you may find a lot of different templates. For example, there are
      numerous templates for DocBook documents, and DITA topic types and maps. Choose the template
      that best meets your needs.</p>
    <section id="writing_your_first_document">
      <title>Writing Your First Document</title>
      <p>Depending on the type of document you choose, the <ph keyref="product"/> interface changes
        to support editing that document type. This may include new menus, toolbar buttons, and
        items in the contextual menus. </p>
      <p product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">Also, depending on the type of document
        you choose, <ph keyref="product"/> may open your document in <xref
          href="text-mode-editor.dita#text-mode-editor"><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol></xref> or <xref
          href="author-editor.dita#author-editor"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol></xref> mode.
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode shows the raw XML source file, while
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode shows a graphical view of the document. </p>
      <p product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">The availability of
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode for your document type depends on the type you choose
        and if there is a CSS stylesheet available to create the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.
          <ph keyref="product"/> includes default <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode views for most
        of the document types it supports. If your company has created its own document types,
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode stylesheets may have also been created for that type.
        However, if you create a plain XML file, or one based on a schema that is not included in
        the <ph keyref="product"/> built-in support, you need to edit it in
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode or <xref keyref="customize_css-stylesheet">create your
          own <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode style sheet</xref> for it. </p>
      <p product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">You can switch back and forth between
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode at any time by
        clicking the buttons at the bottom left of the editor window. You do not lose any formatting
        when switching from <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> to <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode.
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> modes are just different
        views for the same XML document.</p>
      <p>There is also a <xref href="grid-mode-editor.dita#grid-mode-editor"
            ><uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode</xref> available that displays all content in an XML
        document as a structured grid of nested tables. This is useful for certain kinds of
        documents, particularly those that are structured like databases. You can also use it when
        you want to display XML content in a table-like manner (for example, if you need to <xref
          href="export-to-excel.dita#export-to-excel">extract XML content to a
        spreadsheet</xref>).</p>
      <p product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">If you use
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, you might find that it is similar to word processors
        that you are used to. Likewise, the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode is similar to many
        typical text editors. If you are new to XML, the biggest difference is that XML documents
        have a particular structure that you have to follow. <ph keyref="product"/> assists you with
        a continuous validation of the XML markup.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="structuring_your_first_document">
      <title>Structuring Your First Document</title>
      <p>Each XML document type has a particular structure that you have to follow as you write and
        edit the document. Some document types give you a lot of choices, while others give you very
        few. In either case, you need to make sure that your document follows the particular
        structure for the document type you are creating. This means:</p>
      <ul id="ul_q4x_zr4_y4">
        <li>At any given location in the document, there are only certain XML elements allowed. <ph
            product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"><ph keyref="product"/> helps you
            determine which elements are allowed. In <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, when you
            press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>, <ph keyref="product"/> assumes
            that you want to enter a new element and shows you a list of elements that can be
            created in this location. Keep typing until the element you want is highlighted and
            press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> to insert the element. </ph>If
          you want to view the overall structure of a document and see what is allowed (and where),
          you can use the <xref href="model-panel.dita#model-panel"><uicontrol>Model</uicontrol>
            view</xref> (<menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Model</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>).</li>
        <li>When you create certain elements, you may find that your text gets a jagged red
          underline and you get a warning that your content is invalid. This is usually because the
          element you have just created requires certain other elements inside of it. Your document
          will be invalid until you create those elements. <ph keyref="product"/> does its best to
          help you with this. If there is only one possible element that can go inside the element
          you just created, <ph keyref="product"/> creates it for you. However, if there is more
          than one possibility, you have to create the appropriate elements yourself. In many cases,
            <ph keyref="product"/> presents <xref href="xml-quick-fixes.dita#xml-quick-fixes">XML
              <term>Quick Fixes</term></xref> that help you resolve errors by offering proposals to
          quickly fix problems such as missing required attributes or invalid elements.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="editing_your_first_document">
      <title>Editing Your First Document</title>
      <p>Once you have completed the first draft of your document, you may need to edit it. As with
        any editor, <ph keyref="product"/> provides the normal cut, copy, and paste options as well
        as drag and drop editing. However, when you are editing an XML document, you have to make
        sure that your edits respect the structure of the XML document type. In fact, you are often
        editing the structure as well as the content of your document.</p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides many tools to help you edit your structure and to keep your
        structure valid while editing text. </p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>The Document Breadcrumbs</dt>
            <dd>Across the top of the editor window<ph
                product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"> (in
                  <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode)</ph>, there is a set of breadcrumbs that shows
              you exactly were the insertion point is in the structure of the document. You can
              click any element in the breadcrumbs to select that entire element in the
              document.
            <p>
              <image href="../img/author_top_stripe.png" id="image_ehd_s1d_z4"
                product="author developer editor" placement="break"/>
            </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">
            <dt>Showing Tags</dt>
            <dd>To see exactly where you are in the structure of the document, you can show the tags
              graphically in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> view. There are several levels of tag
              visibility that you can choose using the <xref
                href="author-display-markup.dita#author-display-markup"><uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/TagsDrop.png" id="image_ay4_shm_1s"/>Tags Display Mode</uicontrol>
                drop-down menu</xref> on the toolbar (the button may look a little different than
              this, as it changes to reflect the level of tags currently displayed).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Outline View</dt>
            <dd>The <xref href="author-outline-view.dita#author-outline-view"
                  ><uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view</xref> shows you the structure of your
              document in outline format. You can use it to select elements, or to move elements
              around in the document. <p>
                <fig id="fig_ezd_5hd_z4">
                  <title>Outline View</title>
                  <image href="../img/sa_XMLOutlineView.png" id="image_v3c_shd_z4"/>
                </fig>
              </p><p>You can configure the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view to determine what is
                shown, such as element names, attributes, and comments. Certain choices may work
                better for particular document types. You can also filter the
                  <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view to show only elements with a certain name. </p><p>
                <fig id="fig_rfm_34r_z4">
                  <title>Outline View Filtered to only Show Element Names</title>
                  <image href="../img/sa_filtered_xml_outline.png" id="image_j1d_k4r_z4"/>
                </fig>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Cut and Paste, Drag and Drop</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>You can cut and paste or drag and drop text, just as you would in any other editor.
                  <ph product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">However, when you do this
                  in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> view, it is important to remember that you are
                  actually moving blocks of XML. </ph>When you cut and paste or drag and drop a
                block of XML, the result has to be valid both where the content is inserted, and
                where it is removed from. </p>
              <p>A big part of doing this correctly is to make sure that you pick up the right block
                of text in the first place. Using the breadcrumbs or <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol>
                view, or showing tags and using them to select content, can help ensure that you are
                selecting the right chunk of XML.</p>
              <p>If you do try to paste or drop a chunk of XML somewhere that is not valid, <ph
                  keyref="product"/> warns you and tries to suggest actions that make it valid (such
                as by removing surrounding elements from the chunk you are moving, by creating a new
                element at the destination, or by inserting it in a nearby location). </p>
              <p><ph product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">If you are using
                    <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, you can also switch to
                    <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode to see exactly which bits of XML you are
                  selecting and moving.</ph>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Refactoring actions</dt>
            <dd>You can perform many common structure edits, such as renaming an element or wrapping
              text in an element, using the actions in the <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> menu
              of the contextual menu<ph product="author developer editor"> (or the <menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Markup</uicontrol>
                </menucascade> menu)</ph>. More advanced refactoring operations are also available
              using the <xref href="refactoring-xml-documents.dita#refactoring-xml-documents"
                  ><uicontrol>XML Refactoring</uicontrol> tool</xref> that is available in the
                <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol
                product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">XML Tools</uicontrol>
              menu.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="validating_your_first_document">
      <title>Validating Your First Document</title>
      <p>Validation is the process of making sure that an XML document abides by the rules of its
        schema. If <ph keyref="product"/> knows how to find the schema, it validates the document
        for you as you type. <ph keyref="product"/> finds the schema automatically for most of the
        document types created from templates. However, in some cases you may have to <xref
          keyref="validating-XML-documents-against-schema">tell it how to find the
        schema</xref>.</p>
      <p>When <ph keyref="product"/> validates as you type, there is a small bar at the right edge
        of the editor that shows you if the document is invalid and where errors are found. If the
        indicator at the top of that bar is green, your document is valid. If the document is
        invalid, the indicator turns red and a red flag shows you where the errors are found. Click
        that flag to jump to the error. Remember that sometimes your document is invalid simply
        because the structure you are creating is not yet complete. </p>
      <p>In addition to problems with the validity of the XML document itself, <ph keyref="product"
        /> also reports warnings for a number of conditions, such as if your document contains a
        cross reference that cannot be resolved, or if <ph keyref="product"/> cannot find the schema
        specified by the document. The location of these warnings is marked in yellow on the
        validation bar. If the document contains warnings, but no errors, the validity indicator
        turns yellow. </p>
      <p>You can also validate your document at any time by selecting the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/Validate16.png" id="image_eqy_hrv_sr"/>Validate</uicontrol> action from the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ValidateDrop.png" id="image_nmy_5rv_sr"
          />Validation</uicontrol> toolbar drop-down menu or the <menucascade
          product="author developer editor">
          <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol>
        </menucascade><uicontrol product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          >XML</uicontrol> menu.. When you validate in this manner, if errors are found, the
        validation result opens in a new pane at the bottom of the editor that shows each validation
        error on a separate line. Clicking the error takes you to the location in your document
        where the error was detected.<note>Be aware that the problem is sometimes in a different
          location from where the validator detects the error. To get more information about a
          validation error, right-click a validation error message, and select <uicontrol>Show
            Message</uicontrol>.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="proofing_your_first_document">
      <title>Proofing Your First Document</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes an <xref
          href="spell-check-as-you-type.dita#spell-check-as-you-type">automatic (as-you-type) spell
          checking feature</xref>, as well as a manual spell checking action. To check the spelling
        of your document manually, use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CheckSpelling16.png"
            id="image_ftc_kvh_5r"/>Check Spelling</uicontrol> action on the toolbar<ph
          product="author developer editor"> or from the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> menu</ph>. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="transforming_your_first_document">
      <title>Transforming Your First Document</title>
      <p>An XML document must be transformed to be published. Transformations are specific to the
        particular type of document you have created. For example, a DITA transformation cannot be
        used on a DocBook file, or vice versa. A single document type may have many multiple
        transformations that produce different kinds of outputs. For some document types, such a
        DITA, many different content files may be combined together by a transformation. You need to
        locate and launch a transformation that is appropriate for your document type and the kind
        of output you want to generate.</p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> uses <xref keyref="transformation-scenario">transformation
          scenarios</xref> to control the transformation process. Depending on the document type you
        have created, there may be several transformation scenarios already configured for your use.
        This may include the default transformation scenarios supplied by <ph keyref="product"/> or
        ones created by your organization. </p>
      <p>To see the list of transformations available for your document, select the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ApplyStyleSheet16.png" id="image_yhg_svc_jp"/>Apply
          Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> action from the toolbar or the <menucascade
          product="author developer editor">
          <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Transformation</uicontrol>
        </menucascade><uicontrol product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          >XML</uicontrol> menu. A list of available transformation scenarios are displayed. Choose
        one or more scenarios to apply, and click <uicontrol>Apply associated</uicontrol>. Exactly
        how your transformed content appears depends on how the transformation scenario is
        configured.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
