<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="getting-familiar">
  <title>Getting Familiar with the Layout</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Getting Started with Oxygen <indexterm>Layout</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes several <xref keyref="glossentry_perspective"
          ><term>perspectives</term></xref> and <xref
        href="oxygen-editing-modes.dita#oxygen-editing-modes">editing modes</xref> to help you
      accomplish a wide range of tasks. Each <term>perspective</term> and editing mode also includes
      a large variety of helper view, menu actions, toolbars, and contextual menu functions.</p>
    <p>Regardless of the <xref keyref="glossentry_perspective"><term>perspective</term></xref> or
        <xref href="oxygen-editing-modes.dita#oxygen-editing-modes">editing mode</xref> that you are
      working with, the default layout is comprised of the following areas:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><b>Menus</b></dt>
          <dd>Menu driven access to all the features and functions available in <ph keyref="product"
            />. Most of the menus are common for all types of documents, but <ph keyref="product"/>
            also includes some context-sensitive and <term>framework</term>-specific menus and
            actions that are only available for a specific context or type of document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><b>Toolbars</b></dt>
          <dd>Easy access to common and frequently used functions. Each icon is a button that acts
            as a shortcut to a related function. Some of the toolbars are common for all
              <term>perspectives</term>, editing modes, and types of documents, while others are
            specific to the particular <term>perspective</term> or mode. Some toolbars are also
              <term>framework</term>-specific, depending on the type of document that is being
            edited. <ph product="author developer editor">All the <xref
                href="configure-toolbars.dita#configure-toolbars">toolbars can be configured</xref>
              to suit your specific needs.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><b>Helper Views</b></dt>
          <dd><ph keyref="product"/> includes a large variety of <xref keyref="glossentry_dockable"
                ><term>dockable</term></xref> views to assist you with editing, viewing, searching,
            validating, transforming, and organizing your documents. Many of the views also contain
            useful contextual menu actions, toolbar buttons, or menus. The most commonly used views
            for each <term>perspective</term> and editing mode are displayed by default and you can
            choose to display others to suit your specific needs. <ph
              product="author developer editor">The <xref
                href="dockable-views-and-editors.dita#dockable-views-and-editors">layout of the
                views can also be configured</xref> according to your preferences. \</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><b>Editor Pane</b></dt>
          <dd>The main editing area in the center of the application. Each <xref
              href="oxygen-editing-modes.dita#oxygen-editing-modes">editing mode</xref> provides a
            main editor pane where you spend most of your time reading, editing, applying markup,
            and validating your documents. The editor pane in each <xref
              href="oxygen-editing-modes.dita#oxygen-editing-modes">editing mode</xref> also
            includes a variety of contextual menu actions and other features to help streamline your
            editing tasks.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><b>Perspectives</b></dt>
          <dd><ph keyref="product"/> includes <xref
              href="editing-perspectives.dita#editing-perspectives">several different
                <term>perspectives</term></xref> that you can use to work with your documents. The
              <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Editor</uicontrol><uicontrol
              product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Oxygen XML</uicontrol>
            <term>perspective</term> is the most commonly used <term>perspective</term> used for
            displaying and editing the content of your XML documents, and it is the default
              <term>perspective</term> when you start <ph keyref="product"/> for the first time. <ph
              keyref="product"/> also includes a <uicontrol>Database</uicontrol>
            <term>perspective</term> that allows you to manage databases<ph
              product="developer editor developerEclipse editorEclipse"> and their connections and a
              few debugging <term>perspectives</term> that allow you to detect problems in XSLT or
              XQuery transformations</ph>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt><b>Status Bar</b></dt>
          <dd>The status bar at the bottom of the application contains some useful information when
            your working with documents. It includes the following information, in the order it is
            displayed from left to right:<ul>
              <li>The path of the current document.</li>
              <li>The <xref href="working-with-unicode.dita#working-with-unicode"
                    ><term>Unicode</term> value</xref> for the character directly to the right of
                the current cursor position.</li>
              <li>The status of the current document. The status of <uicontrol>Modified</uicontrol>
                is displayed for documents that have not yet been saved. Otherwise, this section is
                left blank.</li>
              <li>In <xref href="text-mode-editor.dita#text-mode-editor"><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
                  editing mode</xref>, the current line and character position is displayed.</li>
              <li>If the <xref
                  href="preferences-global.dita#preferences-global/check-for-notifications"
                    ><uicontrol>Check for notifications</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected, this
                section will show you when new messages have been received. The types of messages
                include the addition of new videos on the <ph keyref="product"/> website, the
                announcement of upcoming webinars and conferences where the <ph keyref="product"/>
                team will participate, and more.</li>
              <li>The memory consumption, including the memory used by the application and the
                maximum amount that is allocated to the application.</li>
              <li>If the <xref href="preferences-global.dita#preferences-global/show-memory-status"
                    ><uicontrol>Show memory status</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected, a
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/TrashIcon16.gif"/>Free unused memory</uicontrol>
                icon is displayed in the bottom-right corner and you can use this icon to free up
                unused memory.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
