<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="grid-copy-paste">
  <title>Copy and Paste in the Grid Editing Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Grid editing mode<indexterm>Copy/Paste</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Grid Mode
            editing<indexterm>Copy/Paste</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Copy/Paste in Grid Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The selection in the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode is a bit complex compared to the
      selection in a text component. It consists of a currently selected cell and additional
      selected cells. These additional cells are either selected with the cursor, or implied by the
      currently selected cell. To be more specific, consider that you click the name of the column
      (this becomes the current selected cell), but the editor automatically extends the selection
      so that it contains all the cells from that column. The currently selected cell is painted
      with a color that is different from the rest of the selection.</p>
    <p>You can also select discontinuous regions of nodes and place them in the clipboard with the
      copy action. To deselect one of the selected fragments, use <uicontrol
        conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_click"/>.</p>
    <section id="pasting_content_within_grid_mode">
      <title>Pasting Content Within Grid Mode</title>
      <p>You can paste copied nodes relative to the currently selected cell using one of the
        following actions (available in the contextual menu):<ul>
          <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Paste16.png" id="image_cwr_cqt_tr"/> Paste (<shortcut
                conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_v_shortcut"/>)</uicontrol> - Pastes
            copied content, as a sibling, just below (after) the current selection.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Paste as Child</uicontrol> - Pastes copied content as the last child of the
            current selection.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="pasting_content_from_grid_mode_to_other_edtiors">
      <title>Pasting Content from Grid Mode to Other Editors</title>
      <p>Nodes that are copied from the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> editor can also be pasted into
        the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editor or other applications. When copying from the
          <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> into the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editor or other text
        based applications, the inserted string represents the nodes serialization. The nodes from
        tables can be copied using HTML or RTF in table format. The resulting cells contain only the
        concatenated values of the text nodes.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Copying from Grid to Other Editors</title>
          <image href="../img/grid_copy_to_other_editors.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="pasting_content_from_other_editors_into_grid_mode">
      <title>Pasting Content from Other Editors into Grid Mode</title>
      <p>You can also paste well-formed XML content or tab separated values from other editors into
        the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> editor. If you paste XML content, the result will be the
        insertion of the nodes obtained by parsing this content.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Pasting XML Data into Grid</title>
          <image href="../img/copy_xml_to_grid.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>If the pasted text contains multiple lines of tab-separated values, it can be considered as
        a matrix of values. By pasting this matrix of values into the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol>
        editor, the result will be a matrix of cells. If the operation is performed inside existing
        cells, the existing values will be overwritten and new cells will be created when
        needed.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Pasting Tab-Separated Values into Grid</title>
          <image href="../img/copy_excel_to_grid.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>If you need to add copied content to your existing content (rather than overwriting existing
        cells), you need to first insert new cells by using the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/TableRow16.gif" id="image_xsq_2xz_tr"/> Insert row</uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/TableColumn16.gif" id="image_ypw_cxz_tr"/> Insert
          column</uicontrol> actions from the contextual menu. This is useful, for example, when
        trying to transfer data from spreadsheet-like editors to the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol>
        editor.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
