<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="grid-copy-paste">
  <title>Copy and Paste in the Grid Editor</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Grid Editor<indexterm>copy/paste</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm>Copy/Paste<indexterm>grid editor</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The selection in the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode is a bit complex compared to the
      selection in a text component. It consists of a current selected cell and additional selected
      cells. These additional cells are either hand picked by you with the cursor, or implied by the
      current selected cell. To be more specific, let's consider you click the name of the column -
      this becomes the current selected cell, but the editor automatically extends the selection so
      that it contains all the cells from that column. The current selected cell is painted with a
      color that is different from the rest of the selection.</p>
    <p>You can select discontinuous regions of nodes and place them in the clipboard using the copy
      action. To deselect one of the selected fragments, use <uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_click"/>. Pasting these nodes
      relative to the current selected cell may be done in two ways: just below (after) as a
      brother, which is the default behavior, or as the last child of the selected cell.</p>
    <p>The <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Paste as Child</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action is available in the contextual menu. </p>
    <p product="editor author developer">The same action can be found in the menu <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Grid Edit</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Paste as Child</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The nodes copied from the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> editor can also be pasted into the
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editor or other applications. When copying from the
        <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> into the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editor or other text based
      applications, the inserted string represents the nodes serialization. The nodes from tables
      can be copied using HTML or RTF in table format. The resulting cells contain only the
      concatenated values of the text nodes.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Copying from Grid to Other Editors</title>
      <image href="../img/bt_grid_copy_to_other_editors.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>In the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> editor you can paste well-formed XML content or tab
      separated values from other editors. If you paste XML content, the result will be the
      insertion of the nodes obtained by parsing this content.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Copying XML Data into Grid</title>
      <image href="../img/bt_copy_xml_to_grid.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>If the pasted text contains multiple lines of tab separated values it can be considered as a
      matrix of values. By pasting this matrix of values into the <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> editor
      the result will be a matrix of cells. If the operation is performed inside existing cells, the
      existing values will be overwritten and new cells will be created when needed. This is useful,
      for example, when trying to transfer data from Excel like editors into the
        <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> editor.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Copying Tab Separated Values into Grid</title>
      <image href="../img/bt_copy_excel_to_grid.png"/>
    </fig>
  </body>
</topic>
