<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="grid-actions">
  <title>Editing Actions in Grid Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Grid editing mode<indexterm>Contextual menu actions</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Grid Mode editing<indexterm>Contextual menu
              actions</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Contextual menu actions in Grid Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Since <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode presents XML content in a structured grid of nested
      tables, editing content in this mode can be done with a combination of the <xref
        href="grid-mode-cc.dita#grid-mode-cc"><term>Content Completion Assistant</term></xref> and
      actions that allow you to work with the structure or content of the nested tables much like
      you would with any table. <ph keyref="product"/> provides ways to edit content in the cells of
      the nested tables or to edit the structure of the tables.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Editing Elements or Attributes</title>
      <p>To edit elements or attributes in <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode, simply double-click the
        cell that contains the element or attribute (or select the cell and press
            <uicontrol><shortcut>(Enter)</shortcut></uicontrol>) to invoke the <xref
          href="grid-mode-cc.dita#grid-mode-cc"><term>Content Completion Assistant</term></xref>.
        This opens a pop-up window that offers a list of proposals that are valid for that
        particular node.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Editing Text Content in Cells</title>
      <p>To edit the text value of a cell, simply select the grid cell, press
            <uicontrol><shortcut>(Enter)</shortcut></uicontrol>, and start editing.</p>
      <p>To stop editing a cell value, press <uicontrol><shortcut>(Enter)</shortcut></uicontrol>
        again.</p>
      <p>To cancel the editing without saving the current changes in the document, press the
            <uicontrol><shortcut>(Esc)</shortcut></uicontrol> key.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Editing the Structure of the Nested Tables</title>
      <p>To edit the structure of the nested tables in <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode, <ph
          keyref="product"/> provides the following actions in the contextual menu (many of them
        also appear in the submenus of the <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol> menu, the toolbar, or
        with shortcut keys):</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt/>
            <dd/>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <p/>
    <p>...</p>
    <p>You can sort certain table columns by using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Sort16.png" id="image_ydk_1z1_5r"/> Sort Ascending</uicontrol> or <uicontrol><image href="../img/SortDescending16.png" id="image_xyn_5cv_5r"/> Sort Descending</uicontrol>
      actions that are available on the toolbar or from the contextual menu.</p>
    <p>The sorting result depends on the data type of the column content. It could be a numerical
      sorting for numbers or an alphabetical sorting for text information. The editor automatically
      analyzes the content and decides what type of sorting to apply. When a mixed set of values is
      present in the sorted column, a dialog box is displayed that allows you to choose the desired
      type of sorting between <i>numerical</i> and <i>alphabetical</i>.</p>
    <p>...</p>
    <p>You can add a new row using the <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>/<uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol>
      actions, or by selecting <uicontrol><image href="../img/TableRow16.gif" id="image_xsq_2xz_tr"/> Insert row</uicontrol> from the contextual menu or the toolbar.</p>
    <p>For a faster way to insert a new row, move the selection over the row header, and then press
        <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/enter"/>. The row header is the zone in
      the left of the row that holds the row number. The new row is inserted below the
      selection.</p>
    <p>...</p>
    <p>You can insert a column after the selected column by using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/TableColumn16.gif" id="image_ypw_cxz_tr"/> Insert column</uicontrol> action
      from the contextual menu or the toolbar.</p>
    <p>...</p>
    <p>You can clear all the cells from a column by using the <uicontrol>Clear content</uicontrol>
      action from the contextual menu.</p>
    <p>...</p>
    <p>You can add nodes before, after, or as a child of the currently selected node by using the
      various actions in the following submenus of the contextual menu:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Insert before</uicontrol> - Offers a list of valid nodes, depending on the
        context, and inserts your selection before the currently selected node, as a sibling.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Insert after</uicontrol> - Offers a list of valid nodes, depending on the
        context, and inserts your selection after the currently selected node, as a sibling.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol> - Offers a list of valid nodes, depending on the
        context, and appends your selection as a child of the currently selected node.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>...</p>
    <p>You can quickly create new nodes by duplicating existing ones. The
        <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> action is available in the contextual menu and in the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Grid Edit</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu.</p>
    <p>...</p>
    <p>When using drag and drop to reorganize the document, the resulting layout can be different
      from the expected one. For instance, the layout can contain a set of sibling tables that can
      be joined together. To force the layout to be recomputed, you can use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Refresh16.png" id="image_shy_vbv_5r"/> Refresh selected</uicontrol> action
      that is available in the contextual menu and in the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Grid Edit</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu.</p>
    <p>...</p>
  </body>
</topic>
