<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="help-menu">
  <title>Help Menu</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Help <indexterm>Using the Help menu</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <ph keyref="product"/>
      <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> menu provides various resources to assist you with your tasks.</p>
    <p>This menu includes the following actions or options:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Welcome</dt>
          <dd>This option opens the <uicontrol>Welcome</uicontrol> screen that includes some
            resources to assist you with using <ph keyref="product"/>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="help-dialog">
          <dt><uicontrol product="author developer editor">Help
              (<shortcut>F1</shortcut>)</uicontrol><uicontrol
              product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Help Contents</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action<ph product="author developer editor"> (or the
                  <uicontrol><shortcut>F1</shortcut></uicontrol> key)</ph> to open a dialog box that
              presents<ph product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"> Eclipse help
              topics and it includes a section that is specific to <ph keyref="product"/>. Also, you
              can use the <uicontrol><shortcut>F1</shortcut></uicontrol> key to open a
                <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> view that presents</ph><ph> a section in the User Manual
              that is appropriate for the context of the current cursor position.<ph
                product="author developer editor"> If the <uicontrol>Use online help</uicontrol>
                option is selected, this action will open the User Manual in an online
              mode.</ph></ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Use online help</dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, the <uicontrol>Help (<shortcut>F1</shortcut>)</uicontrol>
            action will open the <ph keyref="product"/> User Manual in an online mode.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor" id="dynamic-help">
          <dt><uicontrol>Show Dynamic Help view</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action to open a view that loads the latest online WebHelp version of the <ph
              keyref="product"/> User Manual, and dynamically opens a topic that is relevant to the
            focused editor, view, or dialog box. It requires Java 1.8 and an online connection. In
            Windows, if a Java 1.8 version is not detected, you will be advised to upgrade, while in
            Linux and Mac OS X with Java 1.7 and lower, <ph keyref="product"/> will attempt to load
            an offline version of the documentation. In all three operating systems, with Java 1.8,
            if an online connection is not detected, you will receive an error message advising you
            to check your proxy settings.<p>You can also open the <uicontrol>Dynamic
                Help</uicontrol> view by selecting it from the <menucascade>
                <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
              </menucascade> menu.</p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Install new add-ons</dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to install new <xref keyref="glossentry_plugin"
                ><term>add-ons</term></xref> to extend the functionality of <ph keyref="product"
            />.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Check for add-ons updates</dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to check for updates on installed <xref
              keyref="glossentry_plugin"><term>add-ons</term></xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Manage add-ons</dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to manage installed <xref
              keyref="glossentry_plugin"><term>add-ons</term></xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Check for a New Version</dt>
          <dd>Use this action to view information about the latest version of <ph keyref="product"
            />.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Browse Oxygen Website</dt>
          <dd>Opens the <ph keyref="product"/> website in your default internet browser.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Register</dt>
          <dd>If you encounter problems with your <ph keyref="product"/> license, you can use this
            option to open a dialog box that provides options for obtaining or using a license
            key.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt>Lock/Unlock floating license</dt>
          <dd>If you are using a <term>Floating License</term>, you can lock it so that it does not
            get <xref href="release-floating-license.dita#release-floating-license">released to the
              pool</xref> unless you or the system administrator unlocks it. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="report-problem">
          <dt><uicontrol product="author developer editor">Report problem</uicontrol><uicontrol
              product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Report Oxygen
              problem</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>You can use this option to open a dialog box that allows you to write the description
            of a problem that was encountered while using the application. You can also select
            additional information to be sent to the technical support team in the five tabs:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>General info</uicontrol> - You can edit your contact details in case
                you want to be contacted for further details or to be notified of a resolution.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Class Loader URLs</uicontrol> - You can choose whether or not to
                include the listed <i>Class Loader URLs</i> with your report.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>System properties</uicontrol> - You can choose whether or not to
                include the listed system property details with your report.<note type="tip">You are
                  able to change the URL where the reported problem is sent by using the
                    <i>com.oxygenxml.report.problems.url</i> system property. The report is sent in
                  XML format through the <codeph>report</codeph> parameter of the POST HTTP
                  method.</note></li>
              <li><uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol> - You can choose whether or not to include details
                about your installed <xref keyref="glossentry_plugin"><term>plugins</term></xref>
                with your report.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Frameworks</uicontrol> - You can choose whether or not to include
                details about your installed <xref keyref="glossentry_framework"
                    ><term>frameworks</term></xref> with your report.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Support Center</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this option to open the <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/support.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><ph keyref="product"/> Support Section of the
              Website</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Support Tools</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Clipboard Inspector</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that displays extensive details of all the transferable objects
            from the clipboard. This is helpful if you experience problems while copying content
            from other applications and pasting it into <ph keyref="product"/>. You can use the
              <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> button to copy all of this data and then paste it into an
            email to be sent to the Oxygen support team.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="randomize-xml-text">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Support Tools</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Randomize XML text content</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Use this action when you need to send samples to the Oxygen support team and you want
            to keep the text content confidential. It opens a dialog box that allows you to select
            the resources for which the text content will be randomized. You can then save the
            resources and send them to the Oxygen support team without fear of compromising
            sensitive or private data. For more information, see <xref
              href="randomize-xml-content.dita#randomize-xml-content"/>.<note type="warning">Before
              using this action, it is highly recommended that you copy the XML resources to be
              processed, save them in a separate folder, and then process this operation on the
              copies instead of the original files. Otherwise, you may lose your original content.
            </note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor" id="tip-of-the-day">
          <dt>Tip of the Day</dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that offers tips for using <ph keyref="product"/>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol product="author developer editor">About</uicontrol><ph
              product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">About Eclipse</ph></dt>
          <dd>
            <p>Use this option<ph product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"> and then
                click the <ph keyref="product"/> icon</ph> to open a dialog box that contains
              information about <ph keyref="product"/> and the installed version.<ph
                product="author developer editor"> This dialog box includes the following
                tabs:</ph><ul product="author developer editor">
                <li><uicontrol>Copyright</uicontrol> - This tab contains general information about
                  the product and the version of the product you are using, along with contact
                  details and the <i>SGN</i> number. Details regarding the memory usage are
                  also presented at the bottom of the dialog box.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Libraries</uicontrol> - This tab presents the list of third party
                  libraries that <ph keyref="product"/> uses. To view the End User Licence Agreement
                  of each library, double-click it.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Frameworks</uicontrol> - This tab contains a list with the <xref
                    keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>framework</term></xref> that are bundled
                  with <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>System Properties</uicontrol> - This tab contains a list with system
                  properties and their values. The contextual menu allows you to select and copy the
                  properties.</li>
              </ul></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="problem-report-submitted-on-technical-support-form.dita#problem-report-submitted-on-technical-support-form"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
