<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="history-actions">
  <title>History View Contextual Menu Actions</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view contains the following contextual menu actions:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Compare with working copy</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Compares the selected revision with your working copy file. It is available only when
            you select a file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Open</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens the selected revision of the file into the Editor. This is available only for
            files.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Open with</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays the <uicontrol>Open with</uicontrol> dialog box to specify the editor in
            which the selected file will be opened. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Get Contents</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Replaces the current version from the working copy with the contents of the selected
            revision from the history of the file. The <i>BASE</i> version of the file is not
            changed in the working copy so that after this action the file will appear as modified
            in a synchronization operation, that is newer than the <i>BASE</i> version, even if the
            contents is from an older version from history. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to save the contents of a file as it was committed at a certain revision.
            This option is available only when you access the history of a file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Copy to</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copies to the repository the item whose history is displayed, using the selected
            revision. This option is active only when presenting the history for a repository item
            (URL). <note>This action can be used to resurrect deleted items also.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Revert changes from this revision</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Reverts changes that were made in the selected revisions. The changes are reverted
            only in your working copy and does not affect the repository items. It does not replace
            your working copy items with those from the selected revisions. This action is available
            when the resource history was launched for a local working copy resource.<note>For items
              displayed in the <uicontrol>Affected Paths</uicontrol> section that were <i>added</i>,
                <i>deleted</i>, or <i>replaced</i>, this action has no effect because such changes
              are considered to be changes to the parent directory. To revert these type of changes,
              follow these steps:<ol id="ul_ur2_ysd_4r">
                <li>Request the history for the parent directory.</li>
                <li>Identify the revision that contains the changes you want to revert.</li>
                <li>Invoke the action on that revision.</li>
              </ol></note><note type="warning">There are instances where the SVN Client is not able
              to identify the corresponding working copy item for the selected item in the
                <uicontrol>Affected Paths</uicontrol> section. In this case, the action does not
              proceed and an error message is displayed. For example, the selected item in the
                <uicontrol>Affected Paths</uicontrol> section is from a different repository
              location than the working copy item for which the history is displayed.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="update-to-revision">
          <dt><uicontrol>Update to revision</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Updates your working copy resource to the selected revision. This is useful if you
            want your working copy to reflect a time in the past. It is best to update a whole
            directory in your working copy, not just one file. Otherwise, your working copy is
            inconsistent and you are unable to commit your changes.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNCheckOut16.gif" id="image_c53_zcp_5r"/> Check
              out</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Checks out a new working copy of the directory for which the history is presented,
            from the selected revision.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="export-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Export</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens <xref href="export-repos.dita#export-repos">the <uicontrol>Export</uicontrol>
              dialog box</xref> that allows you to configure options for exporting a folder from the
            repository to the local file system.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="show-annotation-action-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNAnnotationsView16.gif" id="image_ufv_db3_5r"/> Show
              Annotation</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_a"/>)</dt>
          <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Show Annotation</uicontrol> dialog box that computes <xref
              href="annotations-view.dita#annotations-view">the annotations for a file and displays
              them in the <uicontrol>Annotations</uicontrol> view</xref>, along with the history of
            the file in the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to change commit data for a file: <ul>
              <li><i>Author</i> - Changes the name of the SVN user that committed the selected
                revision.</li>
              <li><i>Message</i> - Changes the commit message of the selected revision.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p>When two resources are selected in the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view, the contextual
      menu contains the following actions:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Compare revisions</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When the resource is a file, the action compares the two selected revisions using the
              <uicontrol>Compare</uicontrol> view. When the resource is a folder, the action
            displays the set of all resources from that folder that were changed between the two
            revision numbers.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Revert changes from these revisions</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Similar to the <codeph>svn merge</codeph> command, it merges two selected revisions
            into the working copy resource. This action is only available when the resource history
            was requested for a working copy item.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p>For more information about the <uicontrol>History view</uicontrol> and its features, see the
        <xref href="show-history.dita">Request history for a resource</xref> and <xref
        href="history-view.dita">Using the resource history view</xref> sections.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
