<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="history-actions">
  <title>Features</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>History view<indexterm>history actions</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Single selection actions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Compare with working copy</uicontrol> - Compares the selected revision with
          your working copy file. It is enabled only when you select a file.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> - Opens the selected revision of the file into the Editor.
          This is enabled only for files.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Open with</uicontrol> - Displays the <xref
            href="preferences-svn-file-editors.dita#preferences-svn-file-editors/figure-svn-open-with-dialog-preferences"
            >Open with...</xref> dialog to specify the editor in which the selected file will be
          opened.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Get Contents</uicontrol> - Replaces the current version from the working copy
          with the contents of the selected revision from the history of the file. The <i>BASE</i>
          version of the file is not changed in the working copy so that after this action the file
          will appear as modified in a synchronization operation, that is newer than the <i>BASE</i>
          version, even if the contents is from an older version from history.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> - Allows you to save the contents of a file as it was
          committed at a certain revision. This option is available only when you access the history
          of a file.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Copy to</uicontrol> - Copies to the repository the item whose history is
          displayed, using the selected revision. This option is active only when presenting the
          history for a repository item (URL).<note>This action can be used to resurrect deleted
            items also.</note></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Revert changes from this revision</uicontrol> - Reverts changes which were
          made in the selected revision. The changes are reverted only in your working copy file, so
          it does not affect the repository file. It does not replace your working copy file with
          the entire file at the earlier revision, but only rolls-back earlier changes when other
          unrelated changes have been made since the date of the revision. This action is enabled
          when the resource history was launched for a local working copy resource.</p>
      </li>
      <li id="update-to-revision">
        <p><uicontrol>Update to revision</uicontrol> - Updates your working copy resource to the
          selected revision. This is useful if you want your working copy to reflect a time in the
          past. It is best to update a whole directory in your working copy, not just one file,
          otherwise your working copy is inconsistent and you are unable to commit your changes.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_svn_check_out_button.png"/> Check out</uicontrol> -
          Checks out a new working copy of the directory for which the history is presented, from
          the selected revision.</p>
      </li>
      <li id="change-history-author-message">
        <p><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_svn_show_annotation.png"/></uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Show Annotation</uicontrol> - Computes the latest revision number and author
          name that modified each line of the file up to the selected revision, that is no
          modification later than the selected revision is taken into account.</p>
      </li>
      <li><uicontrol>Change</uicontrol> - Allows you to change commit data for a file:<ul>
          <li><i>Author</i> - Changes the name of the SVN user that committed the selected
            revision.</li>
          <li><i>Message</i> - Changes the commit message of the selected revision.</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
    <p><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Resource History view<indexterm>popup menu on double
            selection</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>When two resources are selected in the
        <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view, the contextual menu contains the following actions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Compare revisions</uicontrol> - When the resource is a file, the action
          compares the two selected revisions using the <uicontrol>Compare</uicontrol> view. When
          the resource is a folder, the action displays the set of all resources from that folder
          that were changed between the two revision numbers.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><uicontrol>Revert changes from these revisions</uicontrol> - Similar to the
            <codeph>svn-merge</codeph> command, it merges two selected revisions into the working
          copy resource. This action is only enabled when the resource history was requested for a
          working copy item.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p>For more information about the <uicontrol>History view</uicontrol> and its features please
      read the sections <xref href="show-history.dita">Request history for a resource</xref> and
        <xref href="history-view.dita">Using the resource history view</xref>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>