<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="hotspots-view">
  <title>Hotspots View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Profiling XSLT Stylesheets and XQuery Documents<indexterm>profiling
              information<indexterm>Hotspots view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>This view shows a list of all instruction calls which lie above the threshold defined in the
        <xref href="preferences-profiler.dita">
        <uicontrol>XSLT/XQuery profiler settings</uicontrol>
      </xref>.</p>
    <fig id="figure-hotspots-view-oxygen" product="editor developer">
      <title>Hotspots View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_hotspots_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="figure-hotspots-view-oxygenEclipse" product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>Hotspots View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_hotspots_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>By opening a hotspot instruction entry, the tree of back-traces leading to that instruction
      call are calculated and shown.</p>
    <p>Every hotspot is described by the values from the following columns: </p>
    <ul>
      <li>The instruction name.</li>
      <li>The inherent time in milliseconds or microseconds of how much time has been spent in the
        hotspot together with a bar whose length is proportional to this value. All calls into this
        instruction are summed up regardless of the particular call sequence.</li>
      <li>The invocation count of the hotspot.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>If you click on the <uicontrol>
        <image href="../img/bt_hotspot16.png"/>
      </uicontrol> handle on the left side of a hotspot, a tree of back-traces will be shown.</p>
    <p>Every entry in the backtrace tree has textual information attached to it which depends on the
        <xref href="preferences-profiler.dita">
        <uicontrol>XSLT/XQuery profiler settings</uicontrol></xref>: </p>
    <ul>
      <li>A percentage number which is calculated with respect either to the total time or the
        called instruction.</li>
      <li>A time measured in milliseconds or microseconds of how much time has been contributed to
        the parent hotspot on this call-path.</li>
      <li>An invocation count which shows how often the hotspot has been invoked on this
          call-path.<note>This is not the number of invocations of this instruction.</note></li>
      <li>An instruction name which contains also its attributes.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>