<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="html-editor">
    <title>HTML Editor</title>
    <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a specialized HTML editor and various editing features for
      files that have the <codeph>html</codeph> or <codeph>htm</codeph> file extensions. The
      encoding is detected automatically based on the value specified in the
        <xmlatt>charset</xmlatt> attribute of the <xmlelement>meta</xmlelement> element.<note>If an
        HTML document has an XHTML namespace, or there is an XSD schema declared, or there is a
        PUBLIC ID specified in a DOCTYPE, or there is a SYSTEM ID with a value other than
          <i>"about:legacy-compat"</i>, then the document will be opened as an XHTML
      file.</note></p>
    <section id="section_e5s_r2w_thb">
      <title>New Document Template</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a new document template to help you get started creating
        HTML content. It is available when creating <xref href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa"
          product="author developer editor">new documents from templates</xref><xref
          href="creating-from-templates.dita#creating-from-templates"
          product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">new documents from templates</xref>
        and can be found in the <uicontrol>New Document</uicontrol> folder or by typing <i>html</i>
        in the search field.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_zpk_gfw_thb">
      <title>Text Mode Editor</title>
      <p>You can edit HTML files in the <xref
          href="xml-editor-specific-actions.dita#xml-editor-specific-actions"
            ><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editing mode</xref> using all of its <xref
          href="xml-editor-specific-actions.dita#xml-editor-specific-actions">useful
        features</xref>. It includes <xref href="html-content-completion.dita">content
          completion</xref> based on a special HTML schema, <xref href="html-syntax-highlight.dita"
          >syntax highlighting</xref>, a specialized <xref href="html-outline-view.dita">Outline
          view</xref> that presents the structure, <xref href="folding-in-HTML.dita">folding
          support</xref>, and you can pretty print (format and indent) HTML documents even if they
        are not XML well-formed.</p>
      <p>In addition, there is a <uicontrol><image href="../img/OpenInBrowser16.png"
            id="image_at3_hby_sr"/>View in Browser/System Application</uicontrol> action available
        when you right-click anywhere in an HTML document opened in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode
        and it opens the document in your default browser.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_oxn_jfw_thb">
      <title>Grid Mode</title>
      <p>You can use the <xref href="editing-docs-grid-mode.dita"><uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol>
          mode</xref> where the document is displayed as a structured grid of nested tables where
        the text content can be modified without directly interacting with the markup, but the
        documents must be XML well-formed.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_vbc_lfw_thb" product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">
      <title>Author Visual Editor</title>
      <p>You can edit HTML files in the <xref
          href="editing-xml-documents-author.dita#editing-xml-documents-author">visual
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing mode</xref>. When opening an HTML document in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, if it is not XML well-formed, you will see a warning
        message at the top of the editor that once you make a modification, the document will be
        automatically converted to proper XML structure (XHTML structure). Examples of things that
        are automatically converted include:<ul id="ul_yv4_d5b_nkb">
          <li>Missing end tags are added to applicable elements.</li>
          <li>Empty tags are closed.</li>
          <li>Missing quote characters are added to applicable attributes.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>When editing HTML documents in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, you have access to the
        same <xref href="author-xhtml-extensions.dita">authoring features and actions as you have
          with XHTML documents</xref>. You also have the benefit of CSS rendering and you can <xref
          href="associating-css-html.dita">specify a CSS file to be associated with an HTML
          document</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
