<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="html-documentation-xquery-documents">
  <title>Generating HTML Documentation for an XQuery Document</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing XQuery Documents<indexterm>generate HTML
          documentation</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To generate HTML documentation for an XQuery document, use the dialog <uicontrol>XQuery
        Documentation</uicontrol>. It is opened with the action <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor developer">Tools</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">XML Tools</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Generate Documentation</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XQuery Documentation...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. <ph product="editor developer">. It can be also opened from the
          <uicontrol>Project Tree</uicontrol>'s <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>contextual menu</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Generate Documentation</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XQuery Documentation... </uicontrol>
        </menucascade></ph>. <ph product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">It can be also opened from
        the <uicontrol>Navigator</uicontrol>'s <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>contextual menu</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Generate XQuery Documentation</uicontrol>
        </menucascade></ph>. The dialog enables the user to configure a set of parameters of the
      process of generating the HTML documentation. The parameters are:</p>
    <fig product="editor developer">
      <title>The XQuery Documentation Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_xq_doc_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The XQuery Documentation Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_xq_doc_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Input</uicontrol> - The <uicontrol>Input</uicontrol> panel allows the user to
        specify either the <uicontrol>File</uicontrol> or the <uicontrol>Folder</uicontrol> which
        contains the files for which to generate the documentation. One of the two text fields of
        the <uicontrol>Input</uicontrol> panel must contain the full path to the XQuery file.
        Extensions for the XQuery files contained in the specified directory can be added as
        comma-separated values. Default there are offered xquery, xq, xqy.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Default function namespace</uicontrol> - Optional URI for the default namespace
        for the submitted XQuery, only if it exists.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Predefined function namespaces</uicontrol> - Optional engine dependent,
        predefined namespaces that the submitted XQuery refers to. They allow the conversion to
        generate annotation information to support the presentation component hypertext linking,
        only if the predefined modules have been loaded into the local xqDoc XML repository.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Open in Browser/System Application</uicontrol> - Select this option if you want
        the result to be opened in the system application associated with that file
            type.<note><ph>If you already set the <uicontrol>Default Internet browser</uicontrol>
            option in the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> preferences page, it takes precedence over
            the default system application settings.</ph></note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Output</uicontrol> - Allows the user to specify where the generated
        documentation is saved on disk.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
