<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="HTML-documentation-XML-Schema">
  <title>Generate Documentation in HTML Format</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Editing XML Schemas<indexterm>generate documentation for XML
            Schema<indexterm>as HTML</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The HTML documentation contains images corresponding to the schema definitions as the ones
      displayed by <xref href="xml-schema-diagram-introduction.dita">the schema diagram
        editor.</xref> These images are divided in clickable areas which are linked to the
      definitions of the clicked names of types or elements. The documentation of a definition
      includes a <uicontrol>Used By</uicontrol> section with links to the other definitions which
      refer to it. If the <uicontrol>Escape XML Content</uicontrol> option is unchecked, the HTML or
      XHTML tags used inside the <codeph>xs:documentation</codeph> elements of the input XML Schema
      for formatting the documentation text (for example <codeph>&lt;b&gt;</codeph>,
        <codeph>&lt;i&gt;</codeph>, <codeph>&lt;u&gt;</codeph>, <codeph>&lt;ul&gt;</codeph>,
        <codeph>&lt;li&gt;</codeph>, etc.) are rendered in the generated HTML documentation.</p>
    <p>The generated images format is <b>PNG</b>. The image of an XML Schema component contains the
      graphical representation of that component as it is rendered in <xref
        href="xml-schema-diagram-introduction.dita#xml-schema-diagram-introduction/figure-schema-diagram-example"
        >the Schema Diagram panel of the <ph
          keyref="product"/>'s XSD editor
        panel.</xref>
      <fig>
        <title>XML Schema Documentation Example</title>
        <image href="../img/schema_doc_browser_view.png"/>
      </fig></p>
    <p>The generated documentation includes a table of contents. You can group the contents by
      namespace, location, or component type. After the table of contents there is presented some
      information about the main schema, the imported, included, and redefined schemas. This
      information contains the schema target namespace, schema properties (attribute form default,
      element form default, version) and schema location. </p>
    <fig>
      <title>Information About a Schema</title>
      <image href="../img/xml_schema_doc_main_schema.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>If you choose to split the output into multiple files, the table of contents is displayed in
      the left frame. The contents are grouped in the same mode. If you split the output by
      location, each file contains a schema description and the components that you have chosen to
      include. If you split the output by namespace, each file contains information about schemas
      from that namespace and the list with all included components. If you choose to split the
      output by component, each file contains information about a schema component.</p>
    <p>After the documentation is generated you can collapse details for some schema components.
      This can be done using the <uicontrol>Showing</uicontrol> view:</p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Showing View</title>
      <image href="../img/xml_schema_doc_showing_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>For each component included in the documentation, the section presents the component type
      follow by the component name. For local elements and attributes, the name of the component is
      specified as <i>parent name/component name</i>. You can easily go to the parent documentation
      by clicking the parent name.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Documentation for a Schema Component</title>
      <image href="../img/xml_schema_doc_component_info.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>If the schema contains imported or included modules, their dependencies tree is generated in
      the documentation.</p>
    <image href="../img/schema-documentation-import-include.png"/>
  </body>
</topic>