<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="https-webdav-preferences">
  <title>HTTP(S)<ph product="author developer diff editor">/WebDAV</ph> Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>HTTP(S)/WebDAV
          preferences</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>HTTP(S)/WebDAV</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Connection settings</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> HTTP(S)/WebDAV</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The following options are available:<ul>
        <li product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Enable the
            HTTP(S)/WebDAV Protocols</uicontrol> - .</li>
        <li product="author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"
            ><uicontrol>Internal Apache HttpClient Version</uicontrol> - Oxygen uses the Apache
          HttpClient to establish connections to HTTP servers. To enable oXygen to benefit from
          particular sets of features provided by different versions, you may choose between v3 and
            v4.<note>For a full list of features, go to <xref
              href="http://hc.apache.org/httpclient-3.x/" format="html" scope="external"
              >http://hc.apache.org/httpclient-3.x/</xref> and <xref
              href="http://hc.apache.org/httpcomponents-client-ga/" format="html" scope="external"
              >http://hc.apache.org/httpcomponents-client-ga/</xref>
          </note></li>
        <li product="author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"
            ><uicontrol>Maximum number of simultaneous connections per host</uicontrol> - Defines
          the maximum number of simultaneous connections established by the application with a
          distinct host. Servers might consider multiple connections opened from the same source to
          be a <b>Denial of Service</b> attack. You can avoid that by lowering the value of this
            option.<note>This option accepts a minimum value of 5.</note></li>
        <li><ph id="read-timeout"><uicontrol>Read Timeout (seconds)</uicontrol> - The period in
            seconds after which the application considers that an HTTP server is unreachable if it
            does not receive any response to a request sent to that server</ph>.</li>
        <li product="author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"
            ><uicontrol>Enable HTTP 'Expect: 100-continue ' handshake for HTTP/1.1
            protocol</uicontrol> - Activates <i>Expect: 100-Continue</i> handshake. The purpose of
          the <i>Expect: 100-Continue</i> handshake is to allow a client that is sending a request
          message with a request body to determine if the origin server is willing to accept the
          request (based on the request headers) before the client sends the request body. The use
          of the <i>Expect: 100-continue</i> handshake can result in noticeable performance
          improvement when working with databases. The <i>Expect: 100-continue</i> handshake should
          be used with caution, as it may cause problems with HTTP servers and proxies that do not
          support the HTTP/1.1 protocol.</li>
        <li product="author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"
            ><uicontrol>Use the 'Content-Type' header field to determine the content
            type</uicontrol> - When checked, <ph product="editor author diff developer"><ph
              keyref="product"/></ph> tries to determine a resource type using the
            <uicontrol>Content-Type</uicontrol> header field. This header indicates the <i>Internet
            media type</i> of the message content, consisting of a type and subtype, for example:
          <codeblock>Content-Type: text/xml</codeblock>When unchecked, the resource type is
          determined by analyzing its extension. For example, a file ending in <i>.xml</i> is
          considered to be an XML file.</li>
        <li product="author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"
            ><uicontrol>Automatic retry on recoverable error</uicontrol> - If enabled, if an HTTP
          error occurs when <ph product="editor author diff developer"><ph keyref="product"/></ph>
          communicates with a server via HTTP, for example sending / receiving a SOAP request /
          response to / from a Web services server, and the error is recoverable, <ph
            product="editor author diff developer"><ph keyref="product"/></ph> tries to send again
          the request to the server.</li>
        <li product="author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"
            ><uicontrol>Automatically accept a security certificate, even if invalid</uicontrol> -
          When enabled, the HTTPS connections that <ph keyref="product"/> attempts to establish will
          accept all security certificates, even if they are invalid.<note type="important">By
            accepting an invalid certificate, you accept at your own risk a potential security
            threat, since you cannot verify the integrity of the certificate's issuer.</note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Encryption protocols (SVN Client only)</uicontrol> - this option is available
          only if you run the application with Java 1.6 or older. Sets a specific encryption
          protocol used when a repository is accessed through HTTPS protocol. You can choose one of
          the following values:<ul id="ul_4qd_ycm_lf">
            <li><uicontrol>SSLv3, TLSv1</uicontrol> (default value);</li>
            <li><uicontrol>SSLv3 only</uicontrol>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>TLSv1 only</uicontrol>.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li product="author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"><ph
            id="lock-webdav"><uicontrol>Lock WebDAV files on open</uicontrol> - If checked, the
            files opened through WebDAV are locked on the server so that they cannot be edited by
            other users while the lock placed by the current user still exists on the
          server</ph>.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
