<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="huge-file-editor">
  <title>XML file sizes greater than 300 MB</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit Large Documents<indexterm>larger than 300 MB</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>XML files tend to become larger and larger mostly because they are frequently used as a
      format for database export or for porting between different database formats. Traditional XML
      text editors simply cannot handle opening these huge export files, some having sizes exceeding
      one gigabyte, because all the file content must be loaded in memory before the user can
      actually view it.</p>
    <p>The loaded file is split in multiple pages (each having about 1MB in size). Each page is
      individually loaded (and edited) in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode by using the special
      horizontal slider located at  the top of the editing area. The loading operation is very fast
      and has no upper limit for the size of the loaded file.</p>
    <p>The increase of the maximum size of editable files comes with the following restrictions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>only XML files UTF-8, UTF-16, and ASCII encoded are loaded;</li>
      <li>a file larger than the value of the above option is edited only in Text mode;</li>
      <li>the <xref href="automatic-validation.dita">automatic validation</xref> is not available
        when editing a very large file;</li>
      <li>the XPath filter is disabled in <xref href="find-replace-dialog.dita">the Find/Replace
          dialog</xref>;</li>
      <li>the bidirectional Unicode support (right-to-left writing) is disabled;</li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <xref href="preferences-editor-format.dita">the option <uicontrol>Format and indent the
              document on open</uicontrol>
          </xref> is disabled for non-XML documents. For XML documents, it is done optimizing the
          memory usage but without respecting the options set in <xref
            href="preferences-editor-format.dita">the <uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> preferences
            page</xref>;</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view is not supported;</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>the editor is wrapped by default;</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>the <uicontrol>Find/Replace</uicontrol> dialog only supports the
            <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol> action;</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>saving changes is possible if <uicontrol>Safe save</uicontrol> is activated;</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>the <uicontrol>undo</uicontrol> operation is not available if you go to other pages and
          come back to the modified page.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
