<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="ignore-resources-working-copy">
  <title>Ignore Resources Not Under Version Control</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Working Copy Resources<indexterm>ignore resources</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Some resources inside your working copy do not need to be subject to version control. These
      resources can be files created by the compiler, <filepath>*.obj</filepath>,
        <filepath>*.class</filepath>, <filepath>*.lst</filepath>, or output folders used to store
      temporary files. Whenever you <xref href="send-changes.dita">commit changes</xref>, <ph
        conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/apacheSubversion"/> shows your modified
      files but also the unversioned files, which fill up the file list in the commit dialog. Though
      the unversioned files are committed unless otherwise specified, it is difficult to see exactly
      what you are committing.</p>
    <p>The best way to avoid these problems is to add the derived files to the Subversion's ignore
      list. That way they are never displayed in the commit dialog and only genuine unversioned
      files which must be committed are shown.</p>
    <p>You can choose to ignore a resource by using the <uicontrol>Add to svn:ignore</uicontrol>
      action in the contextual menu of the <xref href="working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working
          Copy</uicontrol> view</xref>.</p>
    <p>In the <uicontrol>Add to svn:ignore</uicontrol> dialog you can specify the resource to be
      ignored by name or by a custom pattern. The custom pattern can contain the following wildcard
      characters:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>* - Matches any string of characters of any size, including the empty string.</li>
      <li>? - Matches any single character.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>For example, you can choose to ignore all text documents by using the pattern:
      <i>*.txt</i>.</p>
    <p>The action <uicontrol>Add to svn:ignore</uicontrol> adds a predefined Subversion property
      called <codeph>svn:ignore</codeph> to the parent directory of the specified resource. In this
      property, there are specified all the child resources of that directory that must be ignored.
      The result is visible in the <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view. The ignored resources
      are represented with grayed icons.</p>
  </body>
</topic>