<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="image-map-xhtml">
  <title>Image Maps in XHTML</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Image Map
            Editor<indexterm>XHTML</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Image Map
                Editor<indexterm>XHTML</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Image Map Editor in XHTML</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes support for <b>image maps</b> in XHTML documents. This
      feature provides an easy way to create hyperlinks in various parts of an image without having
      to divide the image into separate image files. In HTML, an image (in the form of an
        <codeph>img</codeph> element) may be associated with an image map (in the form of a
        <codeph>map</codeph> element) by specifying a <codeph>usemap</codeph> attribute on the
        <codeph>img</codeph> element. The visual <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing mode includes
      an <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> that helps you to easily create and configure image
      maps.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Image Map Editor in XHTML</title>
        <image href="../img/image_map_xhtml.png" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="image_map_editor_interface_in_xhtml">
      <title>Image Map Editor Interface in XHTML</title>
      <p>The interface of the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> consists of the following
        sections and actions:<dl>
          <dlentry
            conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/image-map-toolbar"
            id="toolbar">
            <dt/>
            <dd/>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="image-map-image-pane">
            <dt>Image Pane</dt>
            <dd
              conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/image-pane-dd"/>
            <dd>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/contextual-actions-dlentry"
                    id="contextual-menu">
                    <dt/>
                    <dd/>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="shape-table">
            <dt>Shape Table</dt>
            <dd>The table at the right of the <i>Image Pane</i> is a sequential list of all the
              areas (shapes) that have been added in the image. It shows their number, type, and
              description (value of the <uicontrol>Alternative</uicontrol> property). If you select
              one of the entries in the table, the corresponding shape will be selected in the
                <i>Image Pane</i>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Properties</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Displays information about the selected coordinate.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="href">
                    <dt><uicontrol>Href</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Specifies the hyperlink target for the selected area. This will become the
                      value of the <codeph>href</codeph> attribute for the particular
                        <codeph>area</codeph> element. The possible values are:<ul>
                        <li><b>An Absolute URL</b> - A URL of another web site (for example,
                            <codeph>http://www.example.com/index.htm</codeph>).</li>
                        <li><b>A Relative URL</b> - A link to a file within your web site (for
                          example, <codeph>index.htm</codeph>).</li>
                        <li><b>An Element</b> - A link to the ID of an element within the page (for
                          example, <codeph>#top</codeph>).</li>
                        <li><b>Other Protocols</b> - A specified path using other protocols (such as
                            <codeph>https://</codeph>, <codeph>ftp://</codeph>,
                            <codeph>mailto:</codeph>, <codeph>file:</codeph>).</li>
                        <li><b>A Script</b> - A link to a script (for example,
                            <codeph>javascript:alert('Hello');</codeph>) </li>
                      </ul></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="alt">
                    <dt><uicontrol>Alternate</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>The description for the selected area. The value is inserted in an
                        <codeph>alt</codeph> attribute in the particular <codeph>area</codeph>
                      element. This is a required attribute to present a text alternative for
                      browsers that do not display images.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="target">
                    <dt><uicontrol>Target</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Specifies where to open the linked resource. The allowed values are:<ul>
                        <li><b>_blank</b> - Opens the linked resource in a new window or tab.</li>
                        <li><b>_self</b> - Opens the linked resource in the same frame as it was
                          clicked.</li>
                        <li><b>_parent</b> - Opens the linked resource in the full body of the
                          window.</li>
                        <li><b>framename</b> - Opens the linked resource in the named frame.</li>
                      </ul></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
    <section id="how_to_create_an_image_map_in_xhtml">
      <title>How to Create an Image Map in XHTML</title>
      <p>To create an image map on an existing image in an XHTML document, follow these steps:<ol>
          <li>Right-click the image and select <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol>.<p>
              <b>Result:</b> This action will apply an <i>image map</i> to the current image
              and open the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> dialog box.</p></li>
          <li>Add hyperlinks to the image by selecting one of the shape buttons (<uicontrol><image
                href="../img/NewRectangle20.png"/> New Rectangle</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/NewCircle20.png"/> New Circle</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/NewPolygon20.png"/> New Polygon</uicontrol>).</li>
          <li>Move the shape to the desired area in the image and drag any of the points on the
            shape to adjust its size or form. You can use the <xref href="#image-map-xhtml/toolbar"
              format="dita">other buttons on the toolbar</xref> to adjust its layer and color, or to
            perform other editing actions.<note type="tip">You can right-click any of the points,
              shapes, or anywhere in the Image Pane to access various helpful <xref
                href="#image-map-xhtml/contextual-menu" format="dita">contextual menu
              actions</xref>. For example, the easiest way to remove a point is to right-click the
              point and select <uicontrol><image href="../img/Remove16.png"/> Remove
                Point</uicontrol>.</note></li>
          <li>With the shape selected, specify the hyperlink target in the <xref
              href="#image-map-xhtml/href" format="dita"><uicontrol>Href</uicontrol> field</xref>
            and enter a description for the selected area in the <xref href="#image-map-xhtml/alt"
              format="dita"><uicontrol>Alternate</uicontrol> field</xref>.</li>
          <li>(Optional) Specify where the hyperlink resource will be opened in the <xref
              href="#image-map-xhtml/target" format="dita"><uicontrol>Target</uicontrol>
              field</xref>.</li>
          <li>If you want to add more hyperlinks to the image, select a shape button again and
            repeat the appropriate steps.</li>
          <li>When you are finished creating hyperlinks, click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to process
            your changes.</li>
        </ol></p>
      <p><b>Result:</b> The <i>image map</i> is applied on the image and the appropriate
        elements and attributes are automatically added. In <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the
        image map is now rendered over the image and its properties are displayed in a section below
        the image.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="how_to_edit_an_existing_image_map_in_xhtml">
      <title>How to Edit an Existing Image Map in XHTML</title>
      <p>To edit an existing image map, use any of the following methods:<ul>
          <li>Simply double-click the image.</li>
          <li>Right-click the image and select <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> button below the image.</li>
        </ul>All three methods open the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> where you can make
        changes to the image map using the various features described above. You can also make
        changes to the XML structure of the image map in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editing
        mode.</p>
      <p>In <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the details of the image map are also displayed
        below the image and you can edit the description, href, shape, and coordinates of the
        hyperlinked areas. Keep in mind that if you change the shape in this section, you also need
        to add or remove coordinates to match the requirements of the new shape.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="overlapping_areas">
      <title>Overlapping Areas</title>
      <p>If shapes overlap one another in the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol>, the one on
        the top layer takes precedence. The number shown inside each shape represent its layer (if
        the numbers are not displayed, click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowLayers20.png"/>
          Show/Hide Numbers</uicontrol> button on the <xref href="#image-map-xhtml/toolbar"
          format="dita"><uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> toolbar</xref>). To change the layer
        order for a shape, use the layer buttons on the <xref href="#image-map-xhtml/toolbar"
          format="dita"><uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> toolbar</xref> (<image
          href="../img/BringShapeToFront20.png"/>, <image href="../img/BringShapeForward20.png"/>,
          <image href="../img/SendShapeBackward20.png"/>, <image href="../img/SendShapeToBack20.png"
        />).</p>
      <p>If you insert a shape and all of its coordinates are completely inside another shape, the
          <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> will display a warning to let you know that the
        shape is entirely covered by a bigger shape. Keep in mind that if a shape is completely
        inside another shape, its hyperlink will only be accessible if its layer is on top of the
        bigger shape.</p>
      <p>
        <note type="warning">PDF output is limited to rectangular shaped image map objects.
          Therefore, if your image contains circles or polygons, those objects will be redrawn as
          rectangles in the PDF output. Keep in mind that this might affect overlaps in the
          output.</note>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link format="html" href="http://w3c.github.io/html/semantics-embedded-content.html#embedded-content-image-maps" scope="external">
      <linktext>HTML Image Map Specifications</linktext>
    </link></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
