<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="import-from-ms-excel-files">
    <title>Import from MS Excel Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Importing data from Excel</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides several methods for importing MS Excel files into an XML
        file.<ph product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> The first method is to use the
          <ph keyref="product"/>
        <xref href="../topics/smart-paste-support.dita#smart-paste-support"><b>Smart Paste</b>
          mechanism</xref> by simply copying data from Excel and pasting it into a document in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode (note that this is only supported in DITA, DocBook,
        TEI, JATS, and XHTML documents).</ph> You can <ph
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">also </ph>copy data from Excel and paste
      it into inserted cells in <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode<ph
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">, but this is a more manual
      process</ph>. If you want to import an entire Excel file, <ph keyref="product"/> also offers a
      configurable import wizard that works with any type of XML document.</p>
    <section id="smart_paste_method" product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">
      <title>Smart Paste Method in Author Mode</title>
      <p>If you are importing data into DITA, DocBook, TEI, JATS, or XHTML documents, you can open
        the Excel spreadsheet in your office application, copy its content, and simply paste it into
        your document in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. </p>
      <p
        conref="../reusables/topics/reusables-importing-data.dita#reusables-importing-data/smart-paste-para"
      />
    </section>
    <section id="paste_method_in_grid_mode">
      <title>Grid Mode Method</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode in <ph keyref="product"/> displays all content in an
        XML document as a structured grid of nested tables and you can work with the cells in those
        tables much like you would with any spreadsheet application. When importing Excel data into
          <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode, you first need to insert new cells in the particular
        nested table and then you can paste data from Excel the same as you would in any table or spreadsheet.<ol>
          <li>Copy the particular cells from your Excel spreadsheet that you want to import into an
            XML file.</li>
          <li>Switch to <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode in <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
          <li>Expand the particular nodes and locate the nested table where you want to insert the
            copied cells.</li>
          <li>Right-click a particular row or column where you want to insert the data and select
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/TableRow16.gif" id="image_xsq_2xz_tr"/> Insert
              row</uicontrol> or <uicontrol><image href="../img/TableColumn16.gif"
                id="image_ypw_cxz_tr"/> Insert column</uicontrol>, depending on the structure of the
            copied cells.</li>
          <li>Paste the copied cells from the clipboard into the newly inserted cells in
              <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode.</li>
          <li>You may need to make some manual adjustments. For example, if the selection of copied
            cells contained an empty cell, <ph keyref="product"/> might ignore that cell.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="import_dialog_box_method">
      <title>Import Wizard Method</title>
      <p>By default, this method supports importing Excel 97/2000/XP/2003 formats out-of-the-box. To
        import spreadsheet data from Excel 2007 or newer, additional libraries are needed before
        using this procedure. See <xref href="import-excel-new-format.dita#import-excel-new-format"
        /> for instructions on adding more libraries.</p>
      <p>To use the <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol> wizard to import an Excel file into an XML file,
        follow these steps:</p>
      <ol>
        <li> Go to <menucascade product="author developer editor">
            <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>MS Excel file</uicontrol>
          </menucascade><menucascade product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">
            <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol keyref="product"/>
            <uicontrol>MS Excel file</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>. </li>
        <li> Select the URL of the Excel file. <itemgroup>The sheets of the document you are
            importing are presented in the <uicontrol>Available Sheets</uicontrol> section of this
            dialog box. </itemgroup></li>
        <li> Click the <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol> button to proceed to the next stage of the
          wizard. <itemgroup>
            <p>
              <fig id="fig_nv3_l3x_ls" product="author developer editor">
                <title>Import Wizard</title>
                <image href="../img/sa_import_excel_file.png" id="image_zjb_43x_ls"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
            <p>
              <fig id="fig_k24_53x_ls" product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">
                <title>Import Wizard</title>
                <image href="../img/ec_import_excel_file.png" id="image_rzs_v3x_ls"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
          </itemgroup>
        </li>
        <li> Configure the settings for the conversion. This stage of the wizard offers the
          following options:<p>
            <dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Import settings</uicontrol> section</dt>
                <dd>Presents the input data in a tabular form. By default, all data items are
                  converted to element content (<uicontrol><image href="../img/ConvertToElement.png"
                      id="image_zk2_kqw_ls"/></uicontrol> symbol), but this can be overridden by
                  clicking the individual column headers. Clicking a column header once causes the
                  data from this column to be converted to attribute values (<uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/ConvertToAttribute.png" id="image_al2_kqw_ls"/></uicontrol>
                  symbol). Clicking a second time causes the column data to be ignored
                      (<uicontrol><image href="../img/IgnoreData.png" id="image_bl2_kqw_ls"
                    /></uicontrol> symbol) when generating the XML file. You can cycle through these
                  three options by continuing to click the column header.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>First row contains field names</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>If this option is selected, the default column headers are replaced (where such
                  information is available) by the content of the first row. In other words, the
                  first row is interpreted as containing the field names. The changes are also
                  visible in the preview panel.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Customize</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>This button opens a <uicontrol>Presentation Names</uicontrol> dialog box that
                  allows you to edit the name, XML name, and conversion criterion for the root and
                  row elements. The XML names can be edited by double-clicking the desired item and
                  entering the label. The conversion criteria can also be modified by selecting one
                  of the following option in the drop-down menu: <userinput>ELEMENT</userinput>,
                    <userinput>ATTRIBUTE</userinput>, or <userinput>SKIPPED</userinput>.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Options16.png" id="image_zfm_4qw_ls"/> Import
                    Settings</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Clicking this button opens the <xref
                    href="preferences-xml-import.dita#preferences-xml-import"
                      ><uicontrol>Import</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> that allows you to
                  configure more import options.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Import formatted data (as displayed in Excel)</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>If this option is selected, the imported data retains the Excel data formatting
                  (such as the representation of numeric values or dates). If deselected, the data
                  formatting is not imported.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>XML Import Preview</uicontrol> panel</dt>
                <dd>Contains an example of what the generated XML document will look like.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry product="author developer editor">
                <dt><uicontrol>Open in editor</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>If selected, the new XML document created from the imported file is opened in
                  the editor.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Save in file</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>If selected, the new XML document is saved in the specified path.</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl>
          </p></li>
        <li>
          <ph>Click <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Import</uicontrol><uicontrol
              product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Finish</uicontrol> to generate
            the XML document.</ph></li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <p>For more information about exchanging data between <ph keyref="product"/> and spreadsheet
      applications, watch our video demonstration:</p>
    <p><object width="450" height="250" data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8VwsF58zLkU"
        outputclass="iframe">
        <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
      </object></p>
    </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="export-to-excel.dita#export-to-excel"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
