<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="import-excel">
  <title>Import from MS Excel Files</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Importing Data<indexterm>from MS Excel</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> offers
      support for importing MS Excel Files. To import Excel files, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Import</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> MS Excel file</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> and in the <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol> dialog box select the file you want to
      import. In the <uicontrol>Available Sheets</uicontrol> section of this dialog, the sheets of
      the document you are importing are presented. Select a sheet and click next to move on to the
      second <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol> dialog box. <fig>
        <title>The "Import" Dialog Box - Import Criteria</title>
        <image href="../img/import_excel_file.png"/>
      </fig></p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> section presents the data from the Excel sheet in a
      tabular form. It also contains the following options:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>First row contains field names</uicontrol> - uses the content from the first
          row to name the columns;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Import formatted data (as displayed in Excel)</uicontrol> - keeps the Excel
          styling; </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Change labels</uicontrol> - opens the <uicontrol>Presentation
            Names</uicontrol>  dialog box;<fig>
            <title>The "Presentation Names" Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/presentation_names.png"/>
          </fig> The following options are available in this dialog:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Root Element</uicontrol> - allows you to edit the name of the Root
              element;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Row Element</uicontrol> - allows you to edit the name of the Row
              element;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Real Name</uicontrol> - contains the original name of each Heading;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>XML Name</uicontrol> - allows you to modify the names of the
              Headings;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Criterion</uicontrol> - allows you to transform the Heading elements to
              attributes of the Root element.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_options_shortcut.png"/>Import settings</uicontrol> -
          opens the XML / Import preferences page. </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>XML Import Preview</uicontrol> section displays the Excel document in an XML
      format.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Output File</uicontrol> section contains the following options:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Open in Editor</uicontrol> - opens the imported document in the Editor;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Save in File</uicontrol> - saves the imported documented in the specified
          location.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>When you finish configuring the options in these dialogs, click
      <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
