<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="insert-dita-content-reference">
  <title>The Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog lets you reuse content by
      inserting references to the DITA elements that hold the content you want to reuse.<note>To
        refer the content inside a DITA element you first have to set an ID for that
      element.</note></p>
    <p>The DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of content
      fragments. The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute stores a reference to another element and is
      processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The element
      containing the content reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced element. The
      identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable in the context of
      the referencing element. For more details, go to <xref
        href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.0/archspec/conref.html" scope="external"
        format="html">http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.0/archspec/conref.html</xref>.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/>
      <xref href="author-displaying-referred-content.dita">displays the referred content</xref> of a
      DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid resource. If you have URI's
      instead of local paths in the XML documents and your DITA OT transformation needs an XML
      catalog to map the URI's to local paths you have to <xref href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita">add
        the catalog to <ph keyref="product"/></xref>. If the URI's can be resolved, the referred
      content is displayed in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and in the transformation
      output.</p>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog, do one of the following:<ul>
        <li>go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_conref.png"/> Insert a DITA Content
              Reference</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>;</li>
        <li>click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_conref.png"/> Insert a DITA Content
            Reference</uicontrol> action on the main toolbar;</li>
        <li>in the contextual menu of the editing area, go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Reuse</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_conref.png"/> Insert a DITA Content
              Reference</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>The Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conref.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">
      <title>The Insert Content Reference Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conref.png"/>
    </fig>
    <note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog is not modal. The dialog is
      closed automatically in case you switch to a different editor.</note>
    <p>The following fields are available in this dialog:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> - specifies the path to the topic that holds the content you
          want to refer;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Target type</uicontrol> - specifies the type of the element to which you are
          targeting your <codeph>conref</codeph>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Target ID</uicontrol> - presents all the element IDs defined in the source
          topic;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> - displays a preview of the content in the element that
          you select in the <uicontrol>Target ID</uicontrol> list;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> - displays the source of the element your want to
          refer;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> - displays the value of the <codeph/> attribute;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Conrefend</uicontrol> - in case you select an interval of elements, this
          field displays the end value of the <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
