<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="insert-dita-content-reference">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150615T110743+0300" comment="This will need to be updated once EXM-32714 is done."?>Insert
    Content Reference Dialog Box<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog box lets you reuse content by
      inserting references to the DITA elements that hold the content you want to reuse.<note>To
        reference the content inside a DITA element you first have to set an ID for that
        element.</note></p>
    <p>The DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of content
      fragments. The <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute stores a reference to another element and is
      processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The element
      containing the content reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced element. The
      identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable in the context of
      the referencing element. For more details, go to <xref
        href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.0/archspec/conref.html" scope="external"
        format="html"/>.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/>
      <xref href="author-displaying-referenced-content.dita">displays the referenced content</xref> of
      a DITA <codeph>conref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid resource. If you have URI's
      instead of local paths in the XML documents and your DITA OT transformation needs an XML
      catalog to map the URI's to local paths you have to <xref href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita">add
        the catalog to <ph keyref="product"/></xref>. If the URI's can be resolved, the referenced
      content is displayed in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and in the transformation
      output.</p>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog box, do one of the following:<ul>
        <li>Go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conref16.png" id="image_mdc_zvx_sr"/>Insert Content
              Reference</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</li>
        <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conref20.png" id="image_jgl_grx_xr"/>Insert
            Content Reference</uicontrol> action on the main toolbar.</li>
        <li>In the contextual menu of the editing area, go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Reuse</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/Conref16.png" id="image_yd4_zvx_sr"/>Insert Content
              Reference</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <fig product="editor author">
      <title>The Insert Content Reference Dialog Box</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_dita_insert_conref.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">
      <title>The Insert Content Reference Dialog Box</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_dita_insert_conref.png"/>
    </fig>
    <note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Reference</uicontrol> dialog box is not modal. The dialog
      box is closed automatically if you switch to a different editor.</note>
    <p>This dialog box includes the following:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Location</uicontrol> - Specifies the path to the topic that holds the content
          you want to reference.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Target type</uicontrol> - Specifies the type of the element to which you are
          targeting your <codeph>conref</codeph>.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Element table</uicontrol> - Presents all the element IDs defined in the
          source topic.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> - Displays a preview of the content in the element that
          you select in the <uicontrol>Target ID</uicontrol> list.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> - Displays the source of the element your want to
          reference.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Conref</uicontrol> - Displays the value of the <codeph>conref</codeph>
          attribute.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Conrefend</uicontrol> - If you select an interval of elements, this field
          displays the end value of the <codeph>conref</codeph> attribute.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Push</uicontrol> - This option enables you to push content into DITA topics
          and maps, provided that the topics and maps contain elements with <codeph>id</codeph>
          attributes that identify the places where the content is to be pushed.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
