<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="installation-dita-webhelp-feedback">
  <title>Installation</title>
  <body id="installation">
    <section id="system-requirements">
      <title>System Requirements</title>
      <p>The feedback-enabled WebHelp system of <ph
                    keyref="product"/> demands the
                following system requirements:<ul>
          <li>
            <p>Apache Web Server running;</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>MySQL server running;</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>PHP Version&gt;= 5.1.6;</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>PHP MySQL Support;</p>
          </li>
          <li>
                        <p>oXygen WebHelp system supports the following browsers:IE7+, Chrome 19+,
                            Firefox 11+, Safari 5+, Opera 11+.</p>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="installation-requirements">
      <title>Installation Instructions</title>
            <note>These instructions were written for XAMPP 1.7.7 with PHP 5.3.8 and for
                    <term>phpMyAdmin</term> 3.4.5. Later versions of these packages may change the
                location or name of some options, however the following installation steps should
                remain valid and basically the same.</note>
            <p>In case you have a web server configured with PHP, MySQL, you can deploy the WebHelp
                output directly. Otherwise, install XAMPP. XAMPP is a free and open source
                cross-platform web server solution stack package. It consists mainly of the Apache
                HTTP Server, MySQL database, and interpreters for scripts written in the PHP.</p>
      <p>Install XAMPP:<ul>
        <li>Go to <xref href="https://www.apachefriends.org/download.html"
                            format="html" scope="external"/> and download XAMPP, for instance for a
                        Windows system;</li>
          <li>Install it in C:\xampp;</li>
          <li>From the XAMPP control panel, start "MySQL", and then "Apache";</li>
                    <li>Open <codeph>http://localhost/xampp/index.php</codeph> in your browser to
            check whether the HTTP server is working.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>Create a database for the feedback system and a MySQL user with privileges on that
                database. The feedback system uses the MySQL user to connect to the database. The
                username and password for the database administrator are pre-required. For XAMPP,
                the defaults are <codeph>root</codeph> for the username and the password is empty. </p>
      <p>Use <term>phpMyAdmin</term> to create a database: <ul>
          <li>Type <term>localhost</term> in your browser;</li>
          <li>In the left area, select: <term>phpMyAdmin</term>;</li>
                    <li>Click <i>Databases</i> (in the right frame) and then create a
                            <i>database</i>. You can give any name you want to your database, for
                        example <i>comments</i>;</li>
          <li>Create a user with connection privileges for this database. In the
              <uicontrol>SQL</uicontrol> tab, paste the following
            text:<codeblock outputclass="language-sql">  INSERT INTO `mysql`.`user` (`Host`,`User`,`Password`,`Select_priv`,`Insert_priv`,`Update_priv`,`Delete_priv`,`Create_priv`,
      `Drop_priv`,`Reload_priv`,`Shutdown_priv`,`Process_priv`,`File_priv`,`Grant_priv`,`References_priv`,`Index_priv`,`Alter_priv`, 
      `Show_db_priv`,`Super_priv`,`Create_tmp_table_priv`,`Lock_tables_priv`,`Execute_priv`,`Repl_slave_priv`,`Repl_client_priv`,         
      `Create_view_priv`, `Show_view_priv`,`Create_routine_priv`,`Alter_routine_priv`,`Create_user_priv`,`Event_priv`,`Trigger_priv`,
      `Create_tablespace_priv`,`ssl_type`,`max_questions`,`max_updates`,`max_connections`,`max_user_connections`,`plugin`, 
      `authentication_string`) VALUES ('localhost', 'user_name', PASSWORD('user_password'), 'Y','Y','Y','Y','Y','Y','Y', 'N','N','N',
      'N','Y','Y','Y','Y','N','Y','Y','Y', 'Y', 'Y', 'Y', 'Y', 'Y', 'Y', 'N', 'Y', 'Y', 'Y','', '0', '0', '0', '0', '', '');  </codeblock></li>
          <li>Change the <i>user_name</i> and the <i>user_password</i> values;</li>
                    <li>Under <i>localhost</i> in the right frame click <i>Privileges</i> and then
                        at the bottom of the page click the <i>reload the privileges</i> link. </li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="deploying-webhelp">
      <title>Deploying the WebHelp output</title>
      <p>To deploy the WebHelp output, follow these steps:<ul>
          <li>Locate the directory of the HTML documents. Open
              <codeph>http://localhost/xampp/phpinfo.php</codeph> in your browser and see the value
            of the DOCUMENT_ROOT variable. In case you installed XAMPP in C:\xampp, the value of
            DOCUMENT_ROOT is <filepath>C:/xampp/htdocs</filepath>;</li>
          <li>Copy the transformation output folder in the DOCUMENT_ROOT;</li>
          <li>Rename it to a relevant name, for example, webhelp_1;</li>
          <li>Open <codeph>http://localhost/webhelp_1/</codeph>. You are redirected to
              <codeph>http://localhost/webhelp_1/install/</codeph>;<ul>
              <li>Verify that the prerequisites are fulfilled;</li>
              <li>Press <uicontrol>Start Installation</uicontrol>;</li>
              <li>Configure the e-mail addresses, username, and password. Enter the WebHelp system
                administrator password. This special user is able to moderate new posts and manage
                WebHelp users;<p>The address and port of the SMTP mail server that will send the
                  email notifications for the user registration and for the user comments are
                  displayed in the WebHelp installation wizard. They can be modified later in the
                  PHP Runtime Configuration which is usually stored in the
                    <filepath>php.ini</filepath> file in the XAMPP installation.</p><p>You can
                  choose to share comments with other products using the same database. After
                  configuring the database connection, enable the <uicontrol>Display comments from
                    other products</uicontrol> option. In the <uicontrol>Display comments
                    from</uicontrol> section a list with the products sharing the same database is
                  displayed. You can choose one or more products from this list to share comments
                  with. <note>You can restrict the displayed comments of a product depending on its
                    version. In case you have two products that use the same database and you
                    restrict one of them to display comments starting from a certain version, the
                    comments of the other product are also displayed from the specified version
                    onwards. </note>
                </p></li>
              <li>Press Next Step;</li>
              <li>Remove the installation folder from your web server; </li>
              <li>Click the link pointing to the index of the documentation, or visit:
                  <codeph>http://localhost/webhelp_1/</codeph>.</li>
            </ul></li>
        </ul></p>
            <p>To test your system, create a user or post as anonymous. Check that the notification
                emails are delivered to your inbox.<note>To read debug messages, do one of the following:<ul>
            <li>open the <filepath>log.js</filepath> file, locate the <codeph>var log= new
                Log(Level.NONE);</codeph> line, and change the logging level to:
                <codeph>Level.INFO</codeph>, <codeph>Level.DEBUG</codeph>,
                <codeph>Level.WARN</codeph>, or <codeph>Level.ERROR</codeph>;</li>
            <li>append <codeph>?log=true</codeph> to the WebHelp URL.</li>
          </ul></note>
            </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
