<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="installation.reusables">
  <title>Installation reusables</title>
  <body>
    <p>This topic contains reuable fragments for the installation topics</p>
    <section>
      <title>Installation requirements reusables</title>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="osrequirements-windows">
          <dt>Operating system requirements</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows Server 2003, Windows Server
              2008, Windows Server 2012.<draft-comment author="Mark">Are the listings of Windows
                Server 2003, Windows Server 2008, Windows Server 2012 for desktop installs or for
                server installs? Why is NT Server not on this list, since there is a server install
                procedure for it?</draft-comment></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>CPU</dt>
          <dd>
            <ul id="ul_lym_bqd_x4">
              <li>Minimum - <tm tmtype="tm">Intel Pentium III</tm>/<tm tmtype="tm">AMD Athlon</tm>
                class processor, 500 <term>Mhz</term></li>
              <li>Recommended - Dual Core class processor.</li>
            </ul>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Memory</dt>
          <dd>
            <ul id="ul_rym_bqd_x4">
              <li>Minimum - <ph
                  product="editor editorEclipse author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse">512
                  MB of RAM (1 GB on <tm tmtype="tm">Windows Vista</tm>, Windows 7)</ph>
                <ph product="svnClient">512 MB of RAM (1 GB on Windows Vista and Windows
                7)</ph></li>
              <li>Recommended - <ph
                  product="editor editorEclipse author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse">2
                  GB of RAM</ph><ph product="svnClient">512 MB of RAM (2 GB on Windows Vista and
                  Windows 7)</ph>.<draft-comment author="Mark">Need figures for Windows
                  8.</draft-comment></li>
            </ul>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Storage</dt>
          <dd>
            <ul id="ul_yym_bqd_x4">
              <li>Minimum - <ph
                  product="editor editorEclipse author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse">300
                  MB free disk space</ph>
                <ph product="svnClient">100 MB free disk space</ph></li>
              <li>Recommended - <ph
                  product="editor editorEclipse author authorEclipse developer developerEclipse">500
                  MB free disk space</ph><ph product="svnClient">200 MB free disk space</ph>.</li>
            </ul>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Tools</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>Installation packages are supplied in compressed archives. Ensure you have installed
              a suitable archive extraction utility with which to extract the archive. The MD5 sum
              is available at <xref
                product="editor author editorEclipse authorEclipse developer developerEclipse"
                href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/download.html" scope="external" format="html">the
                Download page</xref>
              <xref product="svnClient" href="http://www.syncrosvnClient.com/download.html"
                scope="external" format="html">the Download page</xref> for every archive. You
              should check the MD5 sum of the downloaded archive with an MD5 checking tool available
              on your platform.<draft-comment author="Mark B">This does not appear to be true of all
                platforms. The Windows installer is an EXE. The Linux is a shell script. And I'm
                pretty sure most platforms come with support for the typical archieve formats used
                on them built in, so I am not sure that this needs saying. If a reader downloaded a
                .zip file and did not know what to do with it, however, this topic does not give
                them enough information to figure it out. So this topic should either go away or be
                expanded. </draft-comment></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Java</dt>
          <dd>
            <ph keyref="product"/> requires Java to run. If you use the native Windows installer,
              <ph keyref="product"/> will be installed with its own copy of Java. If you use the all
            platforms installer, your system must have a compatible Java virtual machine installed.<p>
              <ph keyref="product"/> supports only official and stable Java Virtual Machines with
              the version number <ph
                conref="../topics/oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/minimumJavaVersion"/>
              or later (the recommended version is <ph id="recommendedJavaVersion">1.6.0</ph>) from
              Oracle, formerly Sun Microsystems (available at <xref
                href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html"
                scope="external" format="html"
                >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html</xref>). <ph
                keyref="product"/> may work with JVM implementations from other vendors, but there
              is no guarantee that other implementations will work with future <ph keyref="product"
              /> updates or releases. <ph keyref="product"/> does not work with the GNU libgcj Java
              Virtual Machine.</p><p>To ensure that the correct version of Java is used:</p><ul
              id="ul_e1y_wtf_v4">
              <li>
                <p>Make sure that the PATH environment variable is set to the most current Java
                  Virtual Machine installation.</p>
              </li>
              <li>
                <p>Make sure that references to older Java Virtual Machine installations are removed
                  from the PATH.</p>
              </li>
            </ul><p>To specify a different Java Virtual Machine for <ph keyref="product"/> to use,
              set the home folder of the desired Java Virtual Machine in one of the
                <codeph>JAVA_HOME</codeph> or <codeph>JDK_HOME</codeph> Windows variables. In case
                <codeph>JAVA_HOME</codeph> and <codeph>JDK_HOME</codeph> are not set, the <ph
                keyref="product"/> launcher looks for a JVM installed in a standard location on your
              computer and uses it to start the application. If you use an installer that includes a
              Java Virtual Machine, rename or remove the <filepath>jre</filepath> subdirectory of
              the installation directory for the <codeph>JAVA_HOME</codeph> or
                <codeph>JDK_HOME</codeph> variables to take effect.<draft-comment author="Mark">This
                probably belongs in a troubleshooting topic. Either installtion specific
                troubleshooting or general troubleshooting.</draft-comment></p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
