<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="installing-and-updating-add-ons">
  <title>Installing and Updating Add-ons</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Add-ons <indexterm>Install new add-ons</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Install new add-ons</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Add-ons <indexterm>Manage add-ons</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Manage add-ons</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Add-ons <indexterm>Check for add-on updates</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Check for add-on updates</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_knn_bgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> provides an <xref keyref="glossentry_plugin"
          ><term>add-on</term></xref> mechanism that can automatically discover and install <ph
        product="author editor json"><xref
          href="packing-and-deploying-addons.dita#packing-and-deploying-addons"
            ><term>frameworks</term></xref> and </ph><xref
        href="packing-and-deploying-plugins-as-addons.dita#packing-and-deploying-plugins-as-addons"
          ><term>plugins</term></xref> from a remote location. <note id="note_lnn_bgk_54b"
          ><term>Frameworks</term> that you install through the add-ons system are read-only.
      </note></p>
    <section id="installing_add_ons">
      <title>Installing Add-ons</title>
      <p conkeyref="reusables-installation/p_installing_add_ons" id="p_mnn_bgk_54b"/>
    </section>
    <section id="managing_installed_addons">
      <title>Managing Installed Add-ons</title>
      <p id="p_nnn_bgk_54b">To manage the installed add-ons, follow these steps:<ol id="ol_onn_bgk_54b">
          <li id="li_pnn_bgk_54b">Go to <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Manage add-ons</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></li>
          <li id="li_qnn_bgk_54b">The displayed dialog box presents a list of your installed add-ons along with various
            information (such as the installed version, the compatible <term>Oxygen</term> version,
            and more). The <uicontrol>Status</uicontrol> column will indicate if an update is
            available for a particular add-on. Also, you can click on the row for any particular
            add-on that has an update available to see details for the update (displayed in the
            preview pane below the list of add-ons).</li>
          <li id="li_rnn_bgk_54b">To update an add-on, select the checkbox for the specific add-on, then click
              <uicontrol>Update</uicontrol> to update it (or <uicontrol>Uninstall</uicontrol> to
            remove it). If there is a newer version of the add-on available, <ph keyref="product"/>
            will download the package and install it. Follow the on-screen instructions to complete
            the installation process.<note id="note_snn_bgk_54b">Accepting the license agreement of the add-on is a
              mandatory step in the installation process.</note></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="checking_for_addon_updates">
      <title>Checking for Add-on Updates</title>
      <p id="p_tnn_bgk_54b">To check if there are available updates for the installed add-ons, go to <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Check for add-ons updates</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>. This action displays updates that are compatible with the current <ph
          keyref="product"/> version.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_vx2_trb_t4b">
      <title>Preserving Installed Add-ons After Upgrading Oxygen to a New Version</title>
      <p id="p_wx2_trb_t4b">After installing or upgrading to a new version of <ph keyref="product"
        />, when you re-start the application, a dialog box will be displayed where you can decide
        which previously installed versions of add-ons should be imported and used for the new
        version of the product. </p>
      <p id="p_gjn_3xj_t4b">After you make the decision to import previous add-ons to the new
        application version, add-ons installed for previous versions remain present in the
        application settings folder and can still be used with those older application versions. The
        application may advise you to cleanup your previously installed add-on by displaying a
        dialog box where you can decide which previously installed versions of add-ons should be
        preserved or removed. To remove all add-ons for a particular application version (to free up
        disk space), select it in the main pane of the dialog box and click the <uicontrol>Remove
          add-ons</uicontrol> button.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
      <link href="packing-and-deploying-plugins-as-addons.dita#packing-and-deploying-plugins-as-addons"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
