<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="installing-and-updating-add-ons">
  <title>Installing and Updating Add-ons</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides a framework and plugin deployment support which allows
      frameworks and plugins to be automatically discovered and installed from a remote location.
      Two types of add-ons are supported:<ul>
        <li>
          <p>framework - a collection of files (CSS stylesheets, XML schemas, transformation
            scenarios, specific actions, just to name a few) which provide custom functionality for
            a specific type of document;<note>Frameworks that you install through the add-ons system
              are read-only. </note></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>plugin - a software component that adds extended functionality using a series of
            extension points provided by <ph keyref="product"/>. </p>
        </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To open the add-ons preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Add-ons</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The following options are available in the Add-ons preferences page:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Enable automatic updates checking</uicontrol> - allows <ph keyref="product"/>
          to search for available updates automatically;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Update Sites URLs</uicontrol> - this list contains the URLs of the update
          sites. An update site is an XML descriptor file which stores all the information about an
          add-on. You can add, edit, and delete URLs in this list.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To manage the add-ons, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Manage add-ons...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. <ph keyref="product"/> reads the update site, detects the add-ons, and
      displays them.<note>
        <p>By default, only the latest versions of the add-ons that are compatible with the current
          version of <ph keyref="product"/> are displayed. </p>
      </note></p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Manage add-ons dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/manage_addons_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Manage add-ons dialog</uicontrol> contains two tabs: <ul>
        <li>the <uicontrol>Install/Update</uicontrol> tab - this tab presents the list of available
          updates that are compatible with the current version of <ph keyref="product"/>. The
          updates list contains the name, the status, the update version, the oxygen version, and
          the type of the add-on (either framework, or plugin). A short description of each update
          is presented under the updates list. To visualize all the add-ons from the remote update
          site, disable <uicontrol>Show only compatible add-ons</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Show only
            the latest version of the add-ons</uicontrol>;</li>
        <li>the <uicontrol>Manage</uicontrol> tab - this tab presents a list with the available
          updates (compatible with the current version of oxygen) and with the already installed
          updates. From the manage tab, you are able to install new updates, or remove installed
          ones. Under the updates list, <ph keyref="product"/> presents a short description of each
          update.</li>
      </ul>To install an add-on, enable its check-box and click the <uicontrol>Install</uicontrol>
      button. <ph keyref="product"/> opens the <uicontrol>License and signature</uicontrol> dialog.
      This dialog contains two sections. The first section presents a list with the add-ons you
      chose and the second section is composed of two tabs:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>License</uicontrol> - presents the End User License Agreement; </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Signature</uicontrol> - lets you know whether the add-on has a valid
          signature and presents information regrading the certificate. </li>
      </ul>After reading the information in the two tabs, enable <uicontrol>I accept all terms of
        the end user license agreement</uicontrol> and select <uicontrol>Update</uicontrol> to
      complete the operation.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> menu also contains the <uicontrol>Check for add-ons
        updates...</uicontrol> option. This option also opens the <uicontrol>Manage add-ons
        dialog</uicontrol>, but only presents the updates compatible with the current oxygen
      version.</p>
    <p>When you install a new version of <ph keyref="product"/>, you can import add-ons from the
      previous version. <ph keyref="product"/> presents all the add-ons of the previous version,
      compatible or not.</p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the Add-ons support in <ph keyref="product"/>, go to
        <xref href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/AddonsSupport.html" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/AddonsSupport.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="../tasks/deploying-addons.dita#deploying-addons"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
