<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="installation.options">
 <title>Installation Options</title>
 <shortdesc></shortdesc>
 <conbody>
  <section> 
    <title>Choosing how <ph keyref="product"/> runs</title>
  <p>You can install <ph keyref="product"/> to run in a number of ways:</p>
   <ul>
     <li><p>As a desktop application on Windows, Linux, or Mac.</p></li>
      <li>As a server-based application on a Unix or Linux server or on Windows NT Terminal
        Server.</li>
     <li><p>As a portable application on a USB stick.</p></li>
     <li><p>As an Eclipse plugin.</p></li>
     <li><p>Within a browser as a Java Webstart Application.</p></li>
   </ul>
</section>   
   <section>
     <title>Choosing an installer</title>
     <p>You have a choice of installers. </p>
    <p>
      <ul id="ul_scm_tfx_54">
        <li>
          <p>You can use the native installer for your platform.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>You can use the unattended installer (on Windows and Linux only).</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>You can use the universal (Java-based) installer on any supported platform.</p>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </p>
     <p>The installation kits and the executable files packaged inside the installation kits were checked before publication with an antivirus program to make sure they are not infected with viruses, trojan horses or other malicious software.</p>
   </section>
   <section>
     <title>Choosing a license option</title>
     <p>You must obtain and register a license key to run <ph keyref="product"/>. You can choose from two kinds of license:</p>
     <ul>
       <li>A named person license, that can be used by a single person on mutiple computers.</li>
       <li>A floating license, that can be used by differnt people at different times. Only one person can use a floating license at a time.</li>
     </ul>
   </section>
<section>
  <title>Upgrading, transferring, and uninstalling.</title>
  <p>You can also upgrade <ph keyref="product"/>, transfer a license, or uninstall <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
</section>       
   <section>
     <title>Getting help with installation</title>
   <p>If you need help at any point
     during these procedures, please send us an email at <ph keyref="supportEmail"/>. </p>
   </section>
 </conbody>
</concept>
