<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="integrate-ibm-plugin">
  <title>Editing documents from an IBM Content Navigator Instance</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Web Author <indexterm>Connect to IBM FileNet</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can edit documents from an <i>IBM Content Navigator</i> with the <ph
        keyref="webappProduct"/>. This can be achieved with the use  of two plugins. The first one
      is a plugin for the <i>IBM Content Navigator</i>, which contributes an "Open" action that
      launches <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> for supported XML files. The  second  is a <ph
        keyref="webappProduct"/> plugin that connects to <i>IBM FileNet P8</i> to access files.</p>
    <section id="installing_the_ibm_content_navigator_plugin">
      <title>Installing the IBM Content Navigator Plugin</title>
      <p>To enable this, you need to use the plugin located in the
          <filepath>icn-plugin.jar</filepath> file. To install the plugin, use the following
        instructions:</p>
      <ol>
        <li>Open the Administration Desktop and go to the <i>plug-ins</i> tab. It lists all the
          plugins that are already installed in your environment.</li>
        <li>Click <i>New Plug-in</i> and specify the path to <filepath>icn-plugin.jar</filepath>. </li>
        <li>Click <i>Load</i>.</li>
        <li>Configure the <uicontrol>oXygen Webapp URL</uicontrol> to  the URL of your <ph
            keyref="webappProduct"/> deployment
          (<filepath>http://web-author-domain/</filepath>).</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section id="installing_the_plugin">
      <title>Installing the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> Plugin</title>
      <p>Deploy the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> following the instruction <xref
          href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen_webapp_running_and_testing.html" format="html"
          scope="external">here</xref>. </p>
      <p>Go to the Web Author's Administration Page in the Plugins section ,upload the
          <b>web-author-filenet-plugin</b> jar file and restart the Web Author in order to finish
        installing the plugin.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="using_the_integration">
      <title>Using the Integration</title>
      <p>Every time you open a file that is supported by <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>, it will open
        in a new window in the editor. The behavior depends on the version status of the document,
        as follows:<ul>
          <li>Superseded Versions - The file will be opened in read-only mode.</li>
          <li>Released Versions - in read-only mode. Editing the file is not allowed unless the file
            is checked out  (you can use the <uicontrol>Check out</uicontrol> action on the
            toolbar). <note>If you plan to make changes to a document, you are strongly encouraged
              to check out the file as soon as possible. In fact, it is best is to check it out
              before opening it in the application.</note></li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>When you save a checked-out file, you actually save the content of the "Reserved" version
        of the document. When you are happy with your changes, you can use the Web author's <b>Check
          In</b> action to check it in</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
