<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="introduction">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <body>
    <p>Welcome to the User Manual of <ph keyref="product"/>
      <ph conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/minorVersion"/>!</p>
    <p product="editor editorEclipse author authorEclipse svnClient diff">
      <ph keyref="product"/> is a cross-platform
      application designed for <ph product="editor editorEclipse">document development using
        structured mark-up languages such as <ph>XML </ph>, XSD, Relax NG, <ph>XSL</ph>,
          <ph>DTD</ph>. </ph>
      <ph product="diff">comparing and finding the differences between two XML files or two sets of
        XML files. It offers a complete diff and merge solution with six different diff algorithms
        and multiple levels of comparison.</ph>
      <ph product="author authorEclipse">authors who want to edit XML documents visually without
        extensive knowledge about XML and XML related technologies. The WYSIWYG-like editor is
        driven by CSS stylesheets associated with the XML documents and offers the option to switch
        off XML tags completely when editing an XML document.</ph>
      <ph product="svnClient">managing the history of a set of files that change over time and are
        stored in a central repository using a version control system.</ph>
    </p>
    <p product="editor editorEclipse">It offers developers and authors a powerful Integrated
      Development Environment. Based on proven Java technology, the intuitive Graphical User
      Interface of <ph keyref="product"/> is easy to
      use and provides robust functionality for content editing, project management, and validation
      of structured mark-up sources. Coupled with <i>XSLT</i> and <i>FOP</i> transformation
      technologies, <ph keyref="product"/> offers
      support to generate output to multiple target formats, including: <i>PDF</i>, <i>PS</i>,
        <i>TXT</i>, <i>HTML</i>, <i>JavaHelp</i> and <i>XML</i>.</p>
    <p product="editor"><ph keyref="product"/> is the
      XML Editor of choice for developers, authors, and integrators that demand high-quality output
      with a flexible and robust, single-source, structured mark-up environment.</p>
    <p>This user guide is focused mainly at describing features, functionality and application
      interface to help you get started in no time. <ph product="editor editorEclipse">It also
        describes the basic process of authoring, management, validation of structured mark-up
        documents and their transformation to multiple target outputs. It is assumed that you are
        familiar with the use of your operating system and the concepts related to structured
        mark-up.</ph>
      <ph product="svnClient">It is assumed that you are familiar with the basic concepts of a
        version control system.</ph></p>
  </body>
</topic>
