<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="json-querying-xpath-xquery">
  <title>Querying JSON Documents with XPath or XQuery</title>
  <body>
    <p product="developer editor json" id="p_w2g_cgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> provides an XPath
      toolbar that makes it easy to quickly query JSON documents using XPath expressions. You can
      also use the dedicated <uicontrol>XPath/XQuery Builder</uicontrol> view that allows you to
      compose more complex XPath or XQuery expressions and execute them over JSON documents in
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol><ph product="editor"> or <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol></ph>
      mode.</p>
    <p product="developerEclipse editorEclipse" id="p_x2g_cgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> provides a dedicated
        <uicontrol>XPath/XQuery Builder</uicontrol> view that allows you to compose complex XPath or
      XQuery expressions and execute them over JSON documents.</p>
    <section id="xpath_toolbar" product="developer editor">
      <title>XPath Toolbar</title>
      <p id="p_y2g_cgk_54b">When an XPath expression is run over a JSON document, the document is
        converted to XML and the XPath is executed over the converted XML document. For more
        information about this toolbar, see <xref href="xpath-toolbar.dita"/>.</p>
      <p id="p_z2g_cgk_54b">
        <fig id="fig_afg_cgk_54b">
          <title>XPath Toolbar for JSON</title>
          <image href="../img/JSONXPath_results.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="xpathxquery_builder_view">
      <title>XPath/XQuery Builder View</title>
      <p id="p_bfg_cgk_54b">You can also use the <uicontrol>XPath/XQuery</uicontrol> view to run XPath and XQuery
        expressions over a JSON document. For XQuery, you need to reference the JSON document in
        your XQuery content. For more information about this view, see <xref
          href="xpath-builder-view.dita"/>.</p>
      <p id="p_cfg_cgk_54b">
        <fig id="fig_dfg_cgk_54b">
          <title>XPath/XQuery Builder View for JSON</title>
          <image href="../img/json-xquery-builder.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="details_about_querying_using_xpath_expressions">
      <title>Details About Querying JSON Documents Using XPath Expressions</title>
      <p id="p_efg_cgk_54b">To execute XPath expressions over a JSON document, the document is converted to XML and the
        XPath is executed over the converted XML document. For this conversion, <ph keyref="product"
        /> uses the built-in <xref href="convert-JSON-to-XML.dita">JSON to XML Converter
        tool</xref>. The results are mapped back to the original JSON document.</p>
      <p id="p_ffg_cgk_54b">For example, if you have the following JSON
        document:<codeblock outputclass="language-json" id="codeblock_gfg_cgk_54b">{
   "personnel": {
    "person": [
      {"name": "Boss"},
      {"name": "Worker"}
    ]
  },
  "id":"personnel-id"
}</codeblock>and
        you want to match the name of the second person, the XPath expression would look like
        this:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml" id="codeblock_hfg_cgk_54b">/JSON/personnel/person[2]/name</codeblock></p>
      <p id="p_ifg_cgk_54b">The reason why the first element is <codeph>JSON</codeph> is because if the JSON document
        contains more than one property on the first level, the converted XML document will have an
        additional root element called <xmlelement>JSON</xmlelement>. For more information, see
          <xref href="convert-JSON-to-XML.dita#convert-JSON-to-XML/section_t2q_dxv_llb">JSON to XML
          Conversion Details</xref>.</p>
      <p id="p_jfg_cgk_54b">The <codeph>[2]</codeph> in the expression represents the index of the
          <codeph>person</codeph> in the array and in this case, it matches the second
          <codeph>person</codeph> because the index counting starts with 1. </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
