<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="json-schema-contextual-menu-actions">
  <title>Contextual Menu Actions in the JSON Schema Design Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>JSON Schema diagram editor<indexterm>Contextual menu
          actions</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>JSON Schema Design mode<indexterm>Contextual menu actions</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_arb_cgk_54b">The contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol> mode includes the following
      actions:</p>
    <p id="p_brb_cgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_crb_cgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_avc_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowDefinition16.png" id="image_rgn_4wp_zr"/>Go to
              Definition</uicontrol> [<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_enter"/>]</dt>
          <dd>Navigates to the referenced schema component. This action is also available by
            clicking the arrow displayed in its bottom right corner.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_frb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_asd_f4t_tsb">Allows you to edit the properties of the selected component in a
              in-place editor.</p>
          </dd>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_tbm_34t_tsb">Properties that have set values are rendered in bold while unset
              properties are rendered with a gray foreground. You can edit any property (set or
              unset) by double-clicking or by pressing <uicontrol
                conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_enter"/>.</p>
            <p id="p_hpj_k4t_tsb">You can delete any property already set by pressing <uicontrol
                conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/delete"/>. This operation does not mean
              the selected property is deleted from the table. It means the property is <i>unset</i>
              (rendered with gray foreground). The <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> and
                <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> actions are also available on the contextual menu in
              the table.</p>
            <p>If the <codeph>type</codeph> property changes as a result of an editing/removal
              action, then the list of properties presented in the table is updated according to the
              new schema type. </p>
          </dd>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_ttb_d4t_tsb">
              <note id="note_xxf_d4t_tsb">When filling in string values they should not be enclosed
                in quotation marks, these are added automatically. </note>
              <note id="note_rg4_b1x_5sb">For array values simply fill in the items that will
                constitute the array, separated by commas. </note>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Edit Annotations</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_mrb_cgk_54b">Allows you to edit the annotations for the selected schema
              component in the <uicontrol>Edit Annotations</uicontrol> dialog box. Annotations are
              not required, but they are encouraged as a good practice and can make the schema
              “self-documenting”. </p>
            <p>The <uicontrol>title</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>description</uicontrol> must be
              strings. A <uicontrol>title</uicontrol> is preferably short, whereas a
                <uicontrol>description</uicontrol> provides a more lengthy explanation about the
              data described by the schema. The <uicontrol>default</uicontrol> keyword specifies a
              default schema value that can be anything. The <uicontrol>examples</uicontrol> keyword
              is meant to provide an array of examples that validate against the schema. Its items
              must be separated by a comma.</p>
            <p>Annotations that have set values are rendered in bold while unset annotations are
              rendered with a gray foreground. You can unset an annotation by using the
                  <uicontrol><shortcut>Delete</shortcut></uicontrol> key or the
                <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> action that is available in the contextual menu of the
              table.</p>
            <p>By default, annotations are rendered under the graphical representation of the
              component. To edit the annotations, use the <uicontrol>Edit Annotations</uicontrol>
              action from the contextual menu or simply double-click the annotations area (if
              any).</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_grb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Offers a list of valid components, depending on the context, and appends your
            selection as a child of the currently selected component. You can set a name for a named
            component after it has been added in the diagram.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_hrb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert before</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Offers a list of valid components, depending on the context, and inserts your
            selection before the selected component, as a sibling. You can set a name for a named
            component after it has been added in the diagram.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_irb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert after</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Offers a list of valid components, depending on the context, and inserts your
            selection after the selected component, as a sibling. You can set a name for a named
            component after it has been added in the diagram.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_dtb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Cut16.png" id="image_bkf_rz1_5r"/>Cut</uicontrol>
              [<uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_x"/>]</dt>
          <dd>Cuts the selected component(s).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_etb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png" id="image_ppk_pst_tr"/>Copy</uicontrol>
              [<uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_c"/>]</dt>
          <dd>Copies the selected component(s) to the clipboard.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_htb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Paste16.png" id="image_i3z_bqt_tr"/>Paste</uicontrol>
              [<uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_v"/>]</dt>
          <dd>Pastes the component(s) from the clipboard as children of the selected component.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_jtb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove <shortcut>Delete</shortcut></uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Removes the selected component(s).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_mks_djb_jsb">
          <dt><uicontrol>Make Required</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Marks the selected property as being required in the parent object. By default, the
            defined properties are not required in the JSON schema. You can set a list of required
            properties in the <codeph>required</codeph> keyword. By invoking the action, the name of
            the property is added in the parent object's <codeph>required</codeph> keyword.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_u4c_hjb_jsb">
          <dt><uicontrol>Make Optional</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Marks the selected property as being optional in the parent object. By default, the
            defined properties are optional in the JSON schema. You can set a list of required
            properties in the <codeph>required</codeph> keyword. By invoking the action, the name of
            the property is deleted from the parent object's <codeph>required</codeph> keyword.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_hx3_vhq_4sb">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Extract definition</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to extract a definition as a global definition and reference it. It can be
            used on a property to extract its definition (in case you want to reuse it) or on a
            local definition to extract it as global one. Note that this action is not available for
            global definitions.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_bdh_c3k_jsb">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Convert type to 'any' type</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Converts the <codeph>type</codeph> for the selected property, definition, or
            conditional into an <codeph>any type</codeph> with the value <codeph>true</codeph> or
              <codeph>false</codeph>. You can set <codeph>true</codeph> value to represent a schema
            that matches anything, or <codeph>false</codeph> for a schema that matches nothing.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_dym_h3k_jsb">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Convert 'any' type to standard type</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Converts the <codeph>any type</codeph> for the selected property, definition, or
            conditional into a standard <codeph>type</codeph>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Move Up</uicontrol> [<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_up"/>]</dt>
          <dd>Moves a component up in its parent.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Move Down</uicontrol> [<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_down"/>]</dt>
          <dd>Moves a component down in its parent.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_j1k_tcc_15b">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Search References</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>Searches all references of the selected definition in a scope determined by the
            schemas referenced in the file and the schemas declared in the validation scenarios
            associated with them.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_znd_sbc_15b">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Search References in</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></dt>
          <dd>An extension of the <uicontrol>Search References</uicontrol> action, the search for
            references of the definition currently selected is additionally done in the file(s)
            specified when defining a scope in the resulting dialog box.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_erd_3vz_vtb">
          <dt><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Search Occurrences in File</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> [<uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_u"
            />]</dt>
          <dd>Searches all occurrences of the currently selected definition in the current file. The
            action is available on all components that have a <i>Definition</i> type in the
            diagram.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_vtb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ExpandAll16.png" placement="inline"/>Expand
              All</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Recursively expands all sub-components of the selected component.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_wtb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/CollapseAll16.png" id="image_yl1_r3t_tr"/>Collapse
              All</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Recursively collapses all sub-components of the selected component.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Print Selection</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Prints the selected component diagram.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_xtb_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Save as Image</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Saves the selected component diagram as image, in JPEG, BMP, SVG or PNG format.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_a5b_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Options16.png" id="image_gbx_rpt_tr"/>Options</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens the <xref href="preferences-editor-json-properties.dita">JSON Schema preferences
              page</xref> where you can control which properties to display for JSON Schema
            components in the JSON Schema <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol> mode.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
