<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="json-schema-diagram-editing-actions">
  <title>Editing Actions in JSON Schema Design Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>JSON Schema diagram editor<indexterm>Editing actions</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>JSON Schema Design Mode<indexterm>Editing actions</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_jqb_cgk_54b">The JSON Schema <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol> mode includes various
      editing features, including:<ul id="ul_y1c_xxh_2rb">
        <li id="li_sv5_zb3_2rb">You can edit a JSON Schema using various <xref
            href="json-schema-contextual-menu-actions.dita">contextual menu actions</xref>.</li>
        <li id="li_z1c_xxh_2rb">You can edit a JSON Schema using drag and drop operations. Drag and
          drop is the easiest way to move the existing components to other locations in the schema.
          Depending on the drop area, various actions are available:<ul id="ul_nqb_cgk_54b">
            <li id="li_oqb_cgk_54b"><b>Move</b> - Context dependent, the selected component is moved
              to the destination.</li>
            <li id="li_pqb_cgk_54b"><b>Reference</b> - Context dependent, the selected component is
              referenced from the parent.</li>
            <li id="li_qqb_cgk_54b"><b>Copy</b> - If the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl (Meta on
                  macOS)</shortcut></uicontrol> key is pressed, a copy of the selected component is
              inserted to the destination.</li>
          </ul><p id="p_rqb_cgk_54b">Visual clues about the operation type are indicated by the
            mouse pointer shape:<ul id="ul_sqb_cgk_54b">
              <li id="li_tqb_cgk_54b"><image href="../img/cursor_move.png"/> - When moving a
                component.</li>
              <li id="li_uqb_cgk_54b"><image href="../img/cursor_refer.png"/> - When referencing a
                component.</li>
              <li id="li_vqb_cgk_54b"><image href="../img/cursor_copy.png"/> - When copying a
                component.</li>
            </ul></p></li>
        <li id="li_lcr_jb3_2rb">You can edit some schema components directly in the diagram. For
          these components, you can edit the name and the additional properties presented in the
          diagram by double-clicking the value you want to edit. If you want to edit the name of a
          selected component, you can also press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>. The list of
      properties that can be displayed for each component can be customized <xref
        href="preferences-editor-json-properties.dita">in the JSON Schema Properties preferences
            page</xref>.</li>
    <li id="li_xhg_pb3_2rb">
          <p id="p_zqb_cgk_54b"
            ><?oxy_comment_start author="Steven" timestamp="20211007T032232-0400" comment="Tavi- Is this list item relevant for JSON?"?>There
            are some components that cannot be edited directly in the diagram: imports, includes,
            redefines<?oxy_comment_end?>. The editing action can be performed if you double-click or
            press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> on an import/include/redefine
            component. An edit dialog box is displayed, allowing you to customize the directives.<ul
              id="ol_fr5_qb3_2rb">
    <li id="li_d4b_cgk_54b">Move/reference components in the diagram using drag-and-drop
                actions.</li>
  <li id="li_e4b_cgk_54b">Select consecutive components on the diagram (components from
                the same level) using the <i>Shift</i> key. You can also make discontinuous
                selections in the schema diagram using the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl (Meta on
                    macOS)</shortcut></uicontrol> key. To deselect one of the components, use
                  <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_click"/>. </li>
      <li id="li_n4b_cgk_54b">Copy, reference, or move global components, attributes, and
                identity constraints to another position and from one schema to another using the
                  <uicontrol>Cut/Copy</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Paste/Paste as
                  Reference</uicontrol> actions.</li>
      </ul></p>
        </li>
      <li id="li_grm_fc3_2rb">When switching between editing modes, the cursor position is
          synchronized. For example, if you switch from <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol> to
            <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, the cursor will be in the same position within the
          document in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode as it was in <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol>
          mode, and vice versa.</li>
    </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
