<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="keep-tracking-deleted-content">
  <title>Keep Tracking of Deleted Content</title>
  <body>
    <p>When <uicontrol>Track</uicontrol> changes is disabled and you delete selected content, the
      following cases are possible:<ul>
        <li>the selection contains an entire <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> change - the change
          disappears and the content is deleted;</li>
        <li>the selection intersects with a <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> change (starts or ends in
          one) - nothing happens;</li>
        <li>the selection contains an entire <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> change - the change
          disappears and the content is deleted ;</li>
        <li>the selection intersects with an <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> change (starts or ends in
          one), the <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> change is shrieked and the content is deleted.
        </li>
      </ul>When <uicontrol>Track</uicontrol> changes is enabled and you delete selected content, the
      following cases are possible:<ul>
        <li>the selection contains an entire <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> change - the change is
          considered as rejected and then marked as deleted by the current author, along with the
          other selected content;</li>
        <li>the selection intersects a <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> change (starts or ends in one)
          - the change is considered as rejected and marked as deleted by the current author, along
          with the other selected content;</li>
        <li>the selection contains an entire <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> change:<ul>
            <li>if the <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> is made by the same author, the change
              disappears and the content is deleted;</li>
            <li>if the <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> is made by another author, the change is
              considered as accepted and then marked as deleted by the current author, along with
              the other selected content;</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul><ul>
        <li>if the selection intersects an <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> change (starts or ends in
          one), the <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> change shrinks and the part of the
            <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> change that intersects with the selection is deleted.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
