<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="known_issues">
    <title>Technical Issues</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Known issues</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Technical issues</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Problems</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Error messages</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>This topic contains information about error messages, possible known issues, and other
      things that you might want to be aware of in regards to <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
    <section id="an_error_icon_appears_in_the_topleft_corner_of_t">
      <title>An Error Icon Appears in the Top-Left Corner of the Tasks Manager View</title>
      <p>If an error exception is detected, a warning icon (<image href="../img/Error18.png"/>) will
        be displayed at the top-left corner of the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks
          Manager</uicontrol> view. Clicking the icon will display details about the particular
        exception in the <uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> panel at the bottom of <term>Oxygen XML
          Editor/Author</term>. If you need to report a problem to the <term>Oxygen</term> technical
        support team, right-click the entry in the <uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> panel and select
          <uicontrol>Report problem</uicontrol>. This opens a dialog box that allows you to select
        and configure information that will be sent to the technical support team.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="connection_to_the_server_cannot_be_established">
      <title>Connection to the Server Cannot Be Established</title>
      <p>If this message is displayed at the top of the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks
          Manager</uicontrol> view, it means that there was a problem connecting to the server and
        more details should be displayed in the <uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> panel at the bottom
        of <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>. To report this problem to the <term>Oxygen</term>
        technical support team, right-click the entry in the <uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> panel
        and select <uicontrol>Report problem</uicontrol>. This opens a dialog box that allows you to
        select and configure information that will be sent to the technical support team.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="your_account_no_longer_exists">
      <title>Connection to the Server Cannot Be Established (Your Account No Longer Exists on the
        Oxygen Content Fusion Server)</title>
      <p>If this message is displayed at the top of the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks
          Manager</uicontrol> view after you try to upload a task, it means that there is a problem
        with your user account (for example, if you chose to delete your account in the <xref
          href="account_management.dita#account_management/profile_page"
            ><uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> page</xref>). To solve this, click
          <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> to open the <ph keyref="product"/> interface in your most
        recently used browser, then click on <xref href="account_management.dita#account_management"
            ><uicontrol>SIGN UP</uicontrol> and follow the instructions to re-create your
          account</xref>. After verifying your email address, don't forget to click the
          <uicontrol>Authorize</uicontrol> button in the <ph keyref="product"/> interface.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="review_task_details_not_available">
      <title>Review Task Details Not Available</title>
      <p>If you see this message in the <ph keyref="product"/> interface when clicking on the name
        of a task, it means that the task has been deleted from the server by the <b>Content
          Author</b>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="oxygen_needs_more_memory_to_upload_the_task">
      <title>Oxygen Needs More Memory to Upload the Task</title>
      <p>If uploading a task fails and the error message suggests that a possible cause may be that
          <term>Oxygen</term> needs more memory to upload the task, see <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/increase-memory.html" format="html"
          scope="external">How to Increase the Amount of Available Memory</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="get_changes_warning_the_following_resource_was_no">
      <title>Get Changes Warning: <i>The following resource was not created</i></title>
      <p>When <xref href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes">merging changes</xref>, if this
        message appears in the <uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> panel at the bottom of <term>Oxygen
          XML Editor/Author</term>, it means that a new external resource was detected in the list
        of changed files. You can try to create it manually with the content displayed in the <xref
          href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes/get-changes-dialog-box"><uicontrol>Get
            Changes</uicontrol> dialog box</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="get_changes_warning_the_original_folder_of_the_up">
      <title>Get Changes Warning: <i>The original folder of the uploaded files cannot be
        found</i></title>
      <p>When <xref href="merging_changes.dita#merging_changes">merging changes</xref>, if this
        message appears, it means that the original file(s) could not be found in the location where
        they were at the time the task was uploaded to the <uicontrol>Content Fusion</uicontrol>
        server. If you know the new location of the folder where the original file(s) now reside,
        click <uicontrol>Choose directory</uicontrol> and select that folder (in this case, the
        merge tool will perform a three-way comparison between the original file(s), your changes
        after the task was uploaded, and the incoming changes). You can also choose an empty folder
        and the incoming files will be saved to that folder (in this case, the merge tool will only
        offer the option of accepting the incoming changes without any comparison). </p>
    </section>
    <section id="reviewers_see_variable_key_references_expanded_as">
      <title>Reviewers see Variable Key References Expanded as an Unexpected Value</title>
      <p>Since the <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term> editor that the <b>Reviewers</b> use to
        proofread and make changes to uploaded files is a lightweight version of <term>Oxygen XML
          Editor/Author</term>, it does not have all of the features that the <b>Content Author</b>
        has access to. For example, in <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>, the <b>Content
          Author</b> can select which value they want to see expanded for defined variable key
        references. In the <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term> editor, the <b>Reviewers</b> will only
        see the first value that is detected.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="signup_email_confirmation_messages_not_being_rece">
      <title>Sign-up Email Confirmation Messages Not Being Received</title>
      <p>When signing up for <ph keyref="product"/>, if you do not receive the confirmation emails,
        there is an option in the server configuration to disable these emails. The server
        administrator can go to the <xref
          href="cf-enterprise-configuration.dita#cf-enterprise-configuration"><uicontrol>Content
            Fusion Adminstration Page</uicontrol></xref> and in the <uicontrol>Mail</uicontrol> tab,
        select the <uicontrol>Disable e-mail address validation on sign-up</uicontrol> option.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="content_fusion_connector_addon_doesnt_recognize_c">
      <title>Content Fusion Connector Add-on Doesn't Recognize Changes to the Server</title>
      <p>If you know changes have been made to your tasks on the server, but the add-on does not
        notify you about those changes (for example, the number of messages or file changes were not
        updated in the <uicontrol>Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view), follow this procedure to report
        the problem:<ol>
          <li>Select <uicontrol>Connection status</uicontrol> from the drop-down menu at the
            top-right corner of the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Copy and close</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li>Go to <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Report problem</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> and paste the copied information in the <uicontrol>Problem
              description</uicontrol> area.</li>
          <li>Add your contact details and any other information that might be helpful.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Submit</uicontrol> to send the report to the <term>Oxygen</term>
            technical support team.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
