<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="large-file-viewer">
  <title>Large File Viewer</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Out Of Memory error</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Large File Viewer tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>XML files tend to become larger and larger mostly because they are frequently used as a
      format for database export or for porting between multiple database formats. Traditional XML
      text editors simply cannot handle opening these huge export files, some having sizes exceeding
      one gigabyte, because all of the file content must be loaded in memory before the user can
      actually view it.</p>
    <p>The best performance of the viewer is obtained for encodings that use a fixed number of bytes
      per character (such as UTF-16 or ASCII). The performance for UTF-8 is very good for documents
      that use mostly characters of the European languages. For the same encoding, the rendering
      performance is higher for files consisting of long lines (up to few thousands characters) and
      may degrade for short lines. In fact, the maximum size of a file that can be rendered in the
      Large File Viewer decreases when the total number of the text lines of the file increases.
      Trying to open a very large file (for example, a file of 4 GB) with a very high number of
      short lines (100 or 200 characters per line) may produce an <i>out of memory</i> error
        (<uicontrol>OutOfMemoryError</uicontrol>) that would require either increasing the Java heap
      memory with the <b>-Xmx</b> startup parameter or decreasing the total number of lines in the
      file.</p>
    <p>The powerful <uicontrol>Large File Viewer</uicontrol> is available from the
        <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu or as a standalone application. You can also right-click a
      file in your project and choose to open it with the viewer. It uses an efficient structure for
      indexing the opened document. No information from the file is stored in the main memory, just
      a list of indexes in the file. In this way the viewer can open very large files, up to 10
      gigabytes. If the opened file is XML, the encoding used to display the text is detected from
      the XML prolog of the file. For other file types, the encoding is taken from the <ph
        keyref="product"/> options. See <xref href="preferences-encoding.dita">Encoding for non-XML
        files</xref>.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Large File Viewer</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_large_file_viewer.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p><uicontrol>Large File Viewer</uicontrol> components:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>The menu bar provides menu driven access to all the features and functions that are
        available in <uicontrol>Large File Viewer</uicontrol>:<p>
          <dl>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>
                </menucascade></dt>
              <dd>Opens files in the viewer (also available in the contextual menu).</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Exit</uicontrol>
                </menucascade></dt>
              <dd>Closes the viewer.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>
                </menucascade></dt>
              <dd>Copies the selected text to clipboard (also available in the contextual
                menu).</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol>
                </menucascade></dt>
              <dd>Opens a reduced <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol> dialog box that provides some basic
                search options, such as: <ul>
                  <li><uicontrol>Case sensitive</uicontrol> - When selected, operations are
                    case-sensitive.</li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Regular Expression</uicontrol> - When selected, allows you to use
                    any regular expression in <xref
                      href="regular-expressions.dita#regular-expressions">Perl-like
                    syntax</xref>.</li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Wrap around</uicontrol> - Continues the find operation from the
                    start/end of the document after reaching the end/, depending on whether the
                    search is in forward or backward direction.</li>
                </ul></dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
                </menucascade></dt>
              <dd>Provides access to the User Manual.</dd>
            </dlentry>
          </dl>
        </p></li>
      <li>The status bar provides information about the current opened file path, the Unicode
        representation of the character at cursor position and the line and column in the opened
        document where the cursor is located.</li>
    </ul>
    <note type="attention">For faster computation the <uicontrol>Large File Viewer</uicontrol> uses
      a fixed font (plain, monospace font of size 12) to display characters. The font is <i>not</i>
      configurable from the <xref keyref="options_preferences"><uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        page</xref>.</note>
    <note type="tip">The best performance of the viewer is accomplished for encodings that use a
      fixed number of bytes per character (such as UTF-16 or ASCII). The performance for UTF-8 is
      very good for documents that use mostly characters of the European languages. For the same
      encoding the rendering performance is high for files consisting of short lines (up to a few
      thousand characters) and may degrade for long lines.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
