<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="layout-dita-webhelp-feedback">
  <title>Layout of the Feedback-Enabled WebHelp System</title>
  <body id="layout-webhelp-feedback">
    <p>The layout of the feedback-enabled WebHelp system resembles the layout of the basic WebHelp,
      the left frame remaining the same. However, the bottom of the right frame contains a
        <uicontrol>comments</uicontrol> bar. Select <uicontrol>Log in</uicontrol> from this bar to
      authenticate as a user of the WebHelp system. In case you do not have a user name, complete
      the fields in the dialog box that opens to create a user. Under the
        <uicontrol>comments</uicontrol> bar, you can click the <uicontrol>Add New
        Comment</uicontrol> button to add a comment whether you are logged in or not. The tabs in
      the left frame have the same functionality as the Content, Search, and Index tab of the basic
          WebHelp.<note><ph conref="web-help.dita#web-help-output-format/toc-highlight"/></note>
    </p>
    <fig>
      <title>The layout of the Feedback-Enabled WebHelp System</title>
      <image href="../img/dita-layout-webhelp-feedback.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>After you log in, your name and user name are displayed in the
        <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> bar together with the <uicontrol>Log of</uicontrol> and
        <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> buttons. Click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button to open
      the <uicontrol>User Profile</uicontrol> dialog. In this dialog you can customize the following options:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Your Name</uicontrol> - you can use this field to edit the initial name that
          you used to create your user profile;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Your e-mail address</uicontrol> - you can use this field to edit the initial
          e-mail address that you used to create your profile;</li>
        <li>When to receive an e-mail:<ul>
            <li>when a comment is left on a page that you commented on;</li>
            <li>when a comment is left on any topic in the Help system ;</li>
            <li>when a reply is left to one of my comments.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>New Password</uicontrol> - allows you to enter a new password for your user
            account.<note>The <uicontrol>Current Password</uicontrol> field from the top of the
              <uicontrol>User Profile</uicontrol> is mandatory in case you want to save the changes
            you make. </note></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
