<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE troubleshooting PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Troubleshooting//EN" "troubleshooting.dtd">
<troubleshooting id="machine-signature-mismatch">
  <title>Machine Signature Mismatch Error</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Installing Oxygen<indexterm>Floating license servers<indexterm>Machine signature
              does not match</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Machine signature does not match</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Current license was already activated</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <troublebody>
    <condition id="problem">
      <title>Problem</title>
      <p>I receive an error indicating that <i>the current license was already activated on a
          License Server</i> or that the <i>License Server's Machine Signature does not
        match</i>.</p>
      <p>During the license activation process, the license key becomes bound to a particular
        license server deployment. This means that a code that uniquely identifies your license
        server deployment (called <term>Machine Signature</term>) is sent to the <ph
          keyref="product"/> servers, which in turn will sign the license key. The <term>Machine
          Signature</term> is computed from the list of network interfaces of the machine where you
        deployed the license.</p>
    </condition>
    <troubleSolution>
      <cause id="cause">
        <title>Causes</title>
        <p>When starting the license server, if you receive an error stating that your server's
          Machine Signature does not match, there are several possible causes:<ol>
            <li>The license key was moved to a new machine that hosts your license server.</li>
            <li>A new network interface was changed, added, or activated in the machine that hosts
              your license server.<note>A specific example of when this could happen is if the
                Bluetooth or the WiFi module is activated/deactivated.</note></li>
            <li>The license server was restarted from a different location as the previous restart.
              For example, some server configurations will have the Apache Tomcat server installed
              in a versioned folder (<filepath>/usr/local/apache-tomcat-V.V.V</filepath>) with a
              symbolic link to the typical folder (<filepath>/usr/local/tomcat</filepath>). The
              server can be restarted from either location, but it is recommended to always restart
              from the typical folder (<filepath>/usr/local/tomcat</filepath>) and always restart
              from the same location.</li>
          </ol></p>
      </cause>
      <remedy id="solution">
        <title>Solutions</title>
        <steps-unordered>
          <step>
            <cmd>Revert to your previous configuration.</cmd>
          </step>
          <step>
            <cmd>If reverting is not possible, contact the <xref keyref="url_support">Oxygen support
                team</xref>.</cmd>
          </step>
          <step>
            <cmd>In the case of the 3rd cause listed above, the server simply needs to always be
              restarted from the same location.</cmd>
          </step>
        </steps-unordered>
      </remedy>
    </troubleSolution>
  </troublebody>
</troubleshooting>
