<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="making_changes_to_uploaded_files">
  <title>Visual Editor</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Proposing changes to files</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Visual Editor</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_oqt_dgk_54b">When you click on a file attached to a task, that particular file is
      opened in the <ph keyref="product"/> visual editor. This is where reviewers can proofread,
      propose changes, and add comments in the files. The task owner can also use this visual editor
      to view or manage the proposed changes and comments, or to make their own changes. For
      example, the task owner can accept or reject changes proposed by reviewers, add new comments,
      reply to existing comments, or edit the document directly in the browser interface.</p>
    <p id="p_pqt_dgk_54b">The <ph keyref="product"/> visual editor includes a variety of panes,
      components, and features. The main editing pane and many of the components and features
      inherit functionality from <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/xml_web_author.html"
        format="html" scope="external"><b>Oxygen XML Web Author</b></xref>.</p>
    <p id="p_qqt_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_rqt_dgk_54b">
        <title>Content Fusion Visual Editor Page</title>
        <image href="../img/CF_editing_interface.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="task_files_panel">
      <title>Left Side Pane</title>
      <p id="p_sqt_dgk_54b">When a file is open in the visual editor, clicking on the
        buttons/actions in the left navigation stripe opens the corresponding feature in a
        resizeable pane in between the left stripe and the visual editor.<ul id="ul_cdb_kk3_zxb">
          <li id="li_ddb_kk3_zxb"><u><uicontrol>Files</uicontrol></u><p id="p_v3l_th4_g1c">Opens the
                <uicontrol>Task files</uicontrol> side-pane. It lists all the files that are
              attached to the task. You can switch files simply by clicking on the file in this left
              panel. For DITA projects, if the task owner specified a context DITA map, this panel
              shows the hierarchy of all the attached files as they appear in the specified DITA
              map. The topic title hierarchy from the DITA map is also displayed underneath each
              topic and if part of it is not shown, you can hover over it to see the entire title
              hierarchy in a tooltip.</p></li>
          <li id="li_ezm_vk3_zxb"><u><uicontrol>Task Activity</uicontrol></u><p id="p_x23_5h4_g1c"
              >Opens the <uicontrol>Task activity</uicontrol> side-pane. It lists the history of the
              activity that has occurred for the task (e.g. changes and comments). Each activity
              includes an icon that indicates the type of activity, the name of the user who made a
              change within the task, and when it was processed. For added files (denoted with this
              icon: <image href="../img/CF-AddedFiles16.png"/>), you can click the highlighted file
              name to open the file. For changed files (denoted with this icon: <image
                href="../img/CF-ChangedFiles16.png"/>), you can click the highlighted file name to
              open the two versions of the document in a file comparison view so that you can
              clearly see the differences. You can also hover over the highlighted file name for
              changed files, click the ellipsis (3 vertical dots), and select <uicontrol>Open
                file</uicontrol> to simply open the current version of the file in the visual editor
              (rather than the file comparison).</p><p id="p_ijz_rh4_g1c">To add a comment to the
              task, click the ellipsis (3 vertical dots) button in the header and select
                <uicontrol>Add message</uicontrol>. Keep in mind that all messages in this panel are
              attached to the task and not to individual files (to annotate individual files, use
              the <xref href="#making_changes_to_uploaded_files/add-comment" format="dita"
                  ><uicontrol>Add Comment</uicontrol> button</xref> in the editor). For more
              information, see <xref href="cf-task-activity.dita"/>.</p></li>
          <li id="li_q5s_zk3_zxb"><u><uicontrol>Search</uicontrol></u><p id="p_zk4_vh4_g1c">Opens
              the <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> side-pane. It allows you to search for specific
              content in all files attached to the task. You can click on the <uicontrol>In
                reviews</uicontrol> tab to filter you search by the <uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> of
              content, <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>, and/or <uicontrol>Time</uicontrol>
            frame.</p></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="visual_editor">
      <title>Main Editing Pane</title>
      <p id="p_uqt_dgk_54b">This editor allows you to review and edit content similar to other
        common online editors. In most cases, the <term>tracked changes</term> feature will always
        be on so you and the task owner can see exactly what was changed and will be able to easily
        accept or reject the changes.</p>
      <p id="p_vqt_dgk_54b">The visual editor includes a variety of useful editing features:<ul
          id="ul_zb4_zcx_4jb">
          <li id="li_wqt_dgk_54b"><b>Smart Paste</b> - When you use copy/paste actions, the built-in
              <term>Smart Paste</term> feature preserves certain style and structure
            information.</li>
          <li id="li_xqt_dgk_54b"><b>Contextual Menu Actions</b> - The contextual menu offers some
            editing actions that are specific to the type of document you are working with,
            depending on the specific location within the document.</li>
          <li id="li_yqt_dgk_54b"><b>Content Completion Assistant</b> - The <term>Content Completion
              Assistant</term> helps you insert valid XML content. It offers a list of elements,
            attributes, attribute values, and other options that are valid at the current location.
            It tries to determine the most logical choice in the current editing context and
            displays that proposal at the beginning of the list. The feature is activated when you
            press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> on your keyboard and you can
            navigate through the list of proposals by using the
              <uicontrol><shortcut>Up</shortcut></uicontrol> and
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Down</shortcut></uicontrol> arrow keys and to insert the
            selection, simply press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> again.</li>
          <li id="li_zqt_dgk_54b"><b>Breadcrumb</b> - The main editing pane includes a
              <i>breadcrumb</i> stripe that shows the hierarchical XML structure of the current
            document, from the document root to the current element. By default, it is displayed at
            the bottom of the main editing area. You can click the double arrow button (<image
              href="../img/BreadcrumbTop16.png" id="image_cd5_1cx_4jb"/>) on the right side of the
            breadcrumb to move it to the top. The last element listed in the <term>breadcrumb</term>
            is the element at the current cursor position. Clicking an element from the
              <term>breadcrumb</term> selects the entire element in the editor area.</li>
          <li id="li_art_dgk_54b"><b>Automatic Spell Checking</b> - The visual editor automatically
            checks for spelling errors when a document is loaded and every time a modification is
            made in the document. Words that are detected as spelling errors are underlined with a
            jagged red line. If you right-click on the word, you are presented with a list of
            suggestions that you can select from to replace the word and an
              <uicontrol>Ignore</uicontrol> option.</li>
          <li id="li_qdp_s2n_zxb"><b>Supported Document Types</b> - The visual editor will open any
            of the supported XML document types, including <b>DITA</b>, <b>DITA maps</b>,
              <b>DocBook</b>, <b>XHTML</b>, and <b>TEI</b>. It also provides limited support for
            some other document types (for example, <b>Markdown</b> documents can opened as
            read-only in the visual editor).</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="toolbar_actions">
      <title>Toolbar Actions</title>
      <p id="p_brt_dgk_54b">The editor also includes a toolbar with some common actions along with
        others that are specific to the type of document (framework):</p>
      <p id="p_crt_dgk_54b">
        <dl id="dl_drt_dgk_54b">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_jjs_lfq_ypb">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Save16.png"/>Save</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Saves the current document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_ert_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Undo16.png"/>Undo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>This action is available after you make a change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_frt_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Redo16.png"/>Redo</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>This action is available when you use the <uicontrol>Undo</uicontrol> action.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_grt_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Search16.png"/>Search</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens a popup window that helps you find and replace content in the current
              document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_hrt_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/cf_more_drop.png"/>More</uicontrol> drop-down
              menu</dt>
            <dd>Gives you access to additional general actions:, such as options to save, download,
              or print the document. The <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol> option allows you to
              select a <uicontrol>Tags Display Mode</uicontrol> to control the amount of XML markup
              that is displayed, and you can change the interface language or enable automatic spell
              checking.</dd>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_z1x_qwz_bfc">
                <dl id="dl_t5d_rwz_bfc">
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_u5d_rwz_bfc">
                    <dt>Save as</dt>
                    <dd>Save the document in a specified location.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_psx_5wz_bfc">
                    <dt>Download</dt>
                    <dd>Downloads a copy of the current document.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_zdq_xwz_bfc">
                    <dt>Compare with another file</dt>
                    <dd>Opens a file browser dialog box where you can select a file to compare with
                      the current document.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_wl3_4xz_bfc">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/XmlIcon16.gif" id="image_amc_ms5_vhb"/>Edit
                        XML Source</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Switches to the text editing mode.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_ibp_pyz_bfc">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DitamapIcon16.png"/>Edit DITA Map Tree
                        Structure</uicontrol> (only available when editing a DITA map)</dt>
                    <dd>Opens a <xref href="CF-dita-map-tree-editor.dita">specialized DITA map tree
                        editor</xref> where you can easily modify the structure of a publication
                      using various mouse, keyboard, toolbar, and contextual menu actions.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_bgl_xyz_bfc">
                    <dt>Choose Style</dt>
                    <dd>Opens a dialog box where you can select a <term>main css style</term> that
                      applies to the whole document and one or more <term>additional css
                        styles</term> that behave like layers and are merged sequentially with the
                        <term>main style</term>.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="IX-Print">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/WAPrint16.png" id="image_nlh_2vj_kjb"/>Print
                          (<shortcut>Ctrl+P)</shortcut></uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Opens a print preview pane that allows you to configure printing options for
                      the current document.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="dlentry_ltv_lzz_bfc">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/OptionsShortcut16.png" id="image_bmc_ms5_vhb"
                        />Preferences</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Allows you to select a <uicontrol>Tags Display Mode</uicontrol> to control
                      the amount of XML markup that is displayed, and you can change the interface
                      language or enable automatic spell checking.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="report-problem">
                    <dt><uicontrol>Report Problem</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>You can use this option to open a dialog box that allows you to write the
                      description of a problem that was encountered while using the application. You
                      can also select additional information to be sent to the technical support
                      team in the various tabs.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="add-comment">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/AddComment16.png" id="image_pmh_5jg_wr"/>Add
                comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Allows you to insert a comment on a selected fragment of text. After you add a
              comment, the content where the comment was added is highlighted in the document and
              you can see the comment by hovering over the highlighted content or in the <xref
                href="#making_changes_to_uploaded_files/side-panel" format="dita"
                  ><uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view</xref>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="edit-comment">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/EditComment16.png" placement="inline"
                  id="image_gb1_t5d_4v"/>Edit Comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Edit Comment</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you to edit the
              selected comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="remove-comment">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveComment16.png" placement="inline"
                  id="image_hb1_t5d_4v"/>Remove Comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Removes a selected comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_irt_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/WebAuthorPrevious16.png"/>Previous
              Marker</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Navigates to the previous change or comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_jrt_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/WebAuthorNext16.png"/>Next Marker</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Navigates to the next change or comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_krt_dgk_54b">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/TrackChangesViewDrop.png"/>Track Changes
                Visualization Modes</uicontrol> drop-down menu</dt>
            <dd>This drop-down menu includes specialized actions that allow you to switch between
              the following visualization modes for the <term>Tracked Changes</term> feature:<ul
                id="ul_lrt_dgk_54b">
                <li id="li_mrt_dgk_54b"><uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/TrackChangesFinalWithChanges16.gif" id="image_why_x4v_5r"/>View
                    All Changes/Comments</uicontrol> - This mode is active by default. When you use
                  this mode, all tracked changes are represented.</li>
                <li id="li_nrt_dgk_54b"><uicontrol><image href="../img/TrackChangesFinal16.gif"
                      id="image_zvl_y4v_5r"/>View Final</uicontrol> - This mode offers a preview of
                  the document as if all tracked changes (both inserted and deleted) were
                  accepted.</li>
                <li id="li_ort_dgk_54b"><uicontrol><image href="../img/TrackChangesOriginal16.gif"
                      id="image_kqc_z4v_5r"/>View Original</uicontrol> - This mode offers a preview
                  of the document as if all tracked changes (both inserted and deleted) were
                  rejected. If you attempt to edit the document in this mode, the view mode will
                  switch to <uicontrol>View All Changes/Comments</uicontrol>.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_prt_dgk_54b">
            <dt>Framework-Specific Actions</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_qrt_dgk_54b">Depending on the type of document you are editing, the final
                section of buttons on the toolbar includes a series of actions defined at
                  <term>framework</term> level. Many of these actions are also available in the
                contextual menu. <ph keyref="product"/> includes built-in actions for <xref
                  href="WA-dita-topic-doc-type.dita">DITA</xref>, <xref
                  href="WA-dita-map-doc-type.dita">DITA Map</xref>, DocBook, TEI, and XHTML document
                types.</p>
              <p id="p_rrt_dgk_54b">
                <fig id="fig_srt_dgk_54b">
                  <title>Example: DITA Toolbar Actions</title>
                  <image href="../img/CF_DITA_toolbar.png"/>
                  <p id="p_trt_dgk_54b">The framework-specific actions include:<dl
                      id="dl_urt_dgk_54b">
                      <dlentry id="styling_actions">
                        <dt>Styling actions</dt>
                        <dd>Most common styling actions, such as <uicontrol>Bold</uicontrol>,
                            <uicontrol>Italic</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Underline</uicontrol>.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry id="dlentry_wrt_dgk_54b">
                        <dt>Insert actions</dt>
                        <dd>Actions that allow you to insert a variety of
                          <term>framework</term>-specific objects, such as images, equations,
                          tables, paragraphs, links (for example, cross references, file references,
                          or web links in DITA), topic references (<term>DITA map</term>), reusable
                          content references (DITA), relationship tables (<term>DITA map</term>),
                          and others.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry id="list_actions">
                        <dt>List actions</dt>
                        <dd>Actions that allow you to create ordered and unordered lists, and add
                          new items in them.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry id="table_actions">
                        <dt>Table actions</dt>
                        <dd>Actions that allow you to create a table and manage its structure
                          (insert and delete rows and columns).</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry id="insert_special_char">
                        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/WASpecChar16.png"/>Insert Special
                            Character</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to select from a large variety of
                          special characters to insert at the current cursor position. The various
                          types of characters include symbols, emoticons, punctuation, and many
                          more.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                    </dl></p>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <note id="note_vnc_s1n_42c" type="notice">For a complete list of actions for DITA topics, see
          <xref href="WA-dita-topic-doc-type.dita"/>. For a complete list of actions for DITA maps,
        see <xref href="WA-dita-map-doc-type.dita"/>.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="side-panel">
      <title>Right Side Pane</title>
      <p id="p_xrt_dgk_54b">The pane to the right of the editor provides some helper views, each in
        its own tab. If the pane is not displayed, click the arrow button (<image
          href="../img/WA_open_arrow.png"/>) on the bottom of the right-side vertical header stripe.
        The right pane includes the following tabs (panes):</p>
      <p id="p_svx_1cw_qtb">
        <dl id="dl_arb_bcw_qtb">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_zbj_sv5_frb">
            <dt>Review</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_pj1_5v5_frb">Displays the <term>tracked changes</term> and comments that have
                been added to the document by you or other collaborators. Each change or comment
                includes actions such as <uicontrol>Reply</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Mark as
                  Done</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Accept</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Reject</uicontrol>
                changes, and <uicontrol>Change</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol>
                comments.</p>
              <p id="p-fig-WA-Review-Panel">
                <fig id="fig_xpr_myk_cr">
                  <title>Review Pane</title>
                  <image href="../img/oxygen_webapp_addon_review.png" id="image_ypr_myk_cr"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_op2_zv5_frb">
            <dt>Attributes</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_b45_1w5_frb">Displays the attributes of the selected element and their
                values. You can also add or edit attributes and their values.</p>
              <p id="p_l44_dgk_54b">
                <fig id="fig_m44_dgk_54b">
                  <title>Attributes Pane</title>
                  <image href="../img/oxygen_webapp_attributes_panel.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_kwf_cw5_frb">
            <dt>Validation</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_vc1_dw5_frb">Provides information about validation problems and offers
                proposals for resolving them (if a <term>Quick Fix</term> is available). If you
                click on a problem in the <uicontrol>Validation</uicontrol> tab, the cursor
                automatically moves to the particular location of the issue within the document in
                the editor pane.</p>
              <p id="p_mbp_dgk_54b">
                <fig id="fig_nbp_dgk_54b">
                  <title>Validation Pane</title>
                  <image href="../img/wa-dita-img3.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_mdg_j1l_5sb">
            <dt>Find/Replace</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_wv5_p1l_5sb">Provides the ability to search the current file and replace the
                search terms. It makes it possible to see both the search UI and the document with
                the results highlighted and without having to scroll through the document. </p>
              <p id="p_hry_p1l_5sb">
                <fig id="fig_oxb_q1l_5sb">
                  <title>Find/Replace Pane</title>
                  <image href="../img/WA_find_replace_popup.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_yt2_hdw_qtb">
            <dt>DITA Map</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_zt2_hdw_qtb">Presents a DITA map as a hierarchical tree. The pane is
                automatically displayed (collapsed, by default) when you open a DITA map in the
                editor.</p>
              <p id="p_a52_hdw_qtb">
                <fig id="fig_b52_hdw_qtb">
                  <title>DITA Map Pane</title>
                  <image href="../img/CF-DITA-Map-View.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_gzy_djf_m2c">
            <dt>AI Positron Assistant</dt>
            <dd>
              <note id="note_of4_gwh_42c" type="notice">The <uicontrol>AI Positron
                  Assistant</uicontrol> is only accessible for Content Fusion users with a <xref
                  href="platform-user-roles.dita#platform-user-roles/li_qlp_3hx_sdc">platform user
                  role of <b>Author</b></xref>.</note>
              <p id="p_hzy_djf_m2c">Provides various ways to use AI-generated content or suggestions
                while editing or reviewing content.<ph product="fusion"> For the <uicontrol>AI
                    Positron Assistant</uicontrol> side-pane to appear in the UI, the <xref
                    href="cf-integrate-ai-positron-enterprise.dita"><uicontrol>Oxygen AI Positron
                      Assistant Enterprise for Web Author</uicontrol> plugin must be installed and
                    configured</xref> by an administrator.</ph></p>
              <p id="p_ox2_mkf_m2c">For details about its features and how to use it, see <xref
                  href="wa-ai-positron.dita"/>.</p>
              <p id="p_hw2_hjf_m2c">
                <fig id="fig_iw2_hjf_m2c">
                  <title>AI Positron Assistant Pane</title>
                  <image href="../img/wa-positron.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_wcq_wqw_vhb">
      <title>Referenced Content</title>
      <p id="p_zrt_dgk_54b">If a DITA document contains references to other content (for example,
        through a <xmlatt>conref</xmlatt> or <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt>), as long as the task owner
          <xref href="creating_and_uploading_tasks.dita">specified a <uicontrol>Context DITA
            Map</uicontrol> when creating the task</xref>, the referenced content will be displayed
        in the document but it will be displayed in with a gray background and cannot be edited
        directly in the document. It can only be edited from the source document. To edit the source
        of the referenced content, click the <image href="../img/editContent.png"
          id="image_p2t_wwm_wr"/> icon at the beginning of the referenced content. This will display
        the source document above the task files on the left side of the interface and automatically
        open it in the editor, but in read-only mode. To work with the content of this source
        document, click the <uicontrol>Start editing</uicontrol> link at the top-right corner of the
        editor. Once you start editing the source document, it becomes part of the task files and
        the task owner will see your changes and comments in this document along with any changes or
        comments in the rest of the task files.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="saving_files">
      <title>Saving Files</title>
      <p id="p_ast_dgk_54b">All of your changes are saved automatically on the <ph keyref="product"
        /> server. If you want to save a file manually, use the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/Save16.png"/>Save</uicontrol> button on the toolbar or the <uicontrol
          conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_s"/> keyboard shortcut. You can also
        download the file to your local file system by selecting <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/cf_more_drop.png"/>More</uicontrol> / <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/WebAppDownload18.png"/>Download</uicontrol>.</p>
    </section>
    <p id="p_est_dgk_54b">
      <note id="note_es2_z33_zxb" type="tip">For more advanced information about using the visual
        editor, see the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-webauthor/topics/webauthor-editing-docs.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Editing Documents section</xref> of the <term>Oxygen XML
          Web Author</term> online user manual, but keep in mind that this version of the editor is
        slightly different than the full, licensed version of <term>Oxygen XML Web
        Author</term>.</note>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
