<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="managing-webhelp-responsive-feedback">
  <title>Managing Users and Comments in a Feedback-Enabled WebHelp System</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Responsive with Feedback system<indexterm>Manage
          comments</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Responsive with Feedback system<indexterm>Admin
          Panel</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Classic with Feedback system<indexterm>Manage
          comments</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Classic with Feedback system<indexterm>Admin
          Panel</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>When you installed the <b>WebHelp with Feedback</b> system the first time (assuming the
        <xref
        href="deploying-webhelp-responsive-feedback.dita#deploying-webhelp-responsive-feedback/create-db-note"
          ><uicontrol>Create new database structure</uicontrol> option</xref> was selected), you
      should have been prompted to create an administrator account (or a user named
        <userinput>administrator</userinput> was created by default). As an administrator, you have
      access to manage comments posted in your feedback-enabled WebHelp system. You can also manage
      the user information (such as role, status, or notification options).</p>
    <p>To manage comments and user information, follow these steps:<ol id="ol_ahq_fvj_vs">
        <li>At the bottom of each specific topic there is a <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol>
          navigation bar and on the right side there is a <uicontrol>Log in</uicontrol> button.
          Click this button and log in with your administrator credentials. This gives you access to
          an <uicontrol>Admin Panel</uicontrol> button.</li>
        <li>Click the <uicontrol>Admin Panel</uicontrol> button to display an administration page.<p>
            <fig id="fig_xr3_mn3_xs">
              <title>Administrative Page</title>
              <image href="../img/webhelp-admin-page.png" id="image_yr3_mn3_xs"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
        <li>Use this page to manage the following options:<p>
            <dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Delete Orphaned Comments</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Allows you to delete comments that are no longer associated with a topic in your
                  WebHelp system.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Delete Pending Users</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Allows you to delete user accounts that you do not wish to activate.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>View All Posts</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Allows you to view all the comments that are associated with topics in your
                  WebHelp system.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Export Comments</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Allows you to export all posts associated with topics in your WebHelp system
                  into an XML file.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Set Version</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Use this action to display comments starting with a particular version.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Manage User Information</dt>
                <dd>To edit the details for a user, click on the corresponding row. This opens a
                  window that allows you to customize the following information associated with the user:<p>
                    <dl>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>The full name of the user.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>Level</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>Use this field to modify the privilege level (role) for the selected
                          user. You can choose from the following:<ul id="ul_qw3_cv3_xs">
                            <li><uicontrol>User</uicontrol> - Regular user, able to post comments
                              and receive e-mail notifications.</li>
                            <li><uicontrol>Moderator</uicontrol> - In addition to the regular
                                <uicontrol>User</uicontrol> rights, this type of user has access to
                              the <uicontrol>Admin Panel</uicontrol> where a moderator can view,
                              delete, export comments, and set the version of the feedback-enabled
                              WebHelp system.</li>
                            <li><uicontrol>Admin</uicontrol> - Full administrative privileges. Can
                              manage WebHelp-specific settings, users, and their comments.</li>
                          </ul></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>Company</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>The name of the organization associated with the user.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>E-Mail</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>The contact email address for the user. This is also the address where
                          the WebHelp system sends notifications.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>WebHelp Notification</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>When selected, the user receives notifications when comments are posted
                          anywhere in your feedback-enabled WebHelp system.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>Reply Notification</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>When selected, the user receives notifications when comments are posted
                          as a reply to one of their comments.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>Page Notification</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>When selected, the user receives notifications when comments are posted
                          on a topic where they previously posted a comment.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>Date</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>The date the user registered is displayed.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><uicontrol>Status</uicontrol></dt>
                        <dd>Use this drop-down list to change the status of the user. You can choose
                          from the following:<ul id="ul_n1g_nw3_xs">
                            <li><uicontrol>Created</uicontrol> - The user is created but does not
                              yet have any rights for the feedback-enabled WebHelp system.</li>
                            <li><uicontrol>Validated</uicontrol> - The user is able to use the
                              feedback-enabled WebHelp system.</li>
                            <li><uicontrol>Suspended</uicontrol> - The user has no rights for the
                              feedback-enabled WebHelp system.</li>
                          </ul></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                    </dl>
                  </p></dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl>
          </p></li>
      </ol></p>
    <note type="warning">The key used for identifying the page a comment is attached to is the
      relative file path to the output page. Since the output file and folder names mirror the
      source, any change to the file name (or its folder) in the source will affect the comments
      associated with that WebHelp page. If you change the file name or path, the comment history
      for that topic will become orphaned (a change to the topic ID does not affect the comment
      history).</note>
  </body>
</topic>
