<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="managing-dita-webhelp-feedback">
  <title>Advanced Customization and Management</title>
  <body>
    <p>As an administrator, you have full access to all the features of the feedback-enabled WebHelp
      system. Apart from the options available for a regular user, you can also use the
      administrative page for advanced customization and management. To access the administrative
      page, select <uicontrol>Admin Panel</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> bar. </p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Administrative Page</title>
      <image href="../img/webhelp-admin-page.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>This page allows you to view all posts, export comments and set the version of the WebHelp.
      You can also view the details of each user and search through these details using the
        <uicontrol>Search User Information</uicontrol> filter.<note>When you delete a comment, all
        the replies to that comment are deleted. </note></p>
    <p>To edit the details of a user, click its row and use the <uicontrol>Edit User
        admin</uicontrol> dialog. In this dialog, you can customize all the information of an user,
      including is <uicontrol>Status</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Level</uicontrol>. The following
      options are available:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>User Name</uicontrol> - specifies the User Name of the currently edited
          user;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - specifies the name of the currently edited user;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Level</uicontrol> - use this field to modify the level of the currently
          edited user. You can choose from <uicontrol>Admin</uicontrol>,
          <uicontrol>User</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Moderator</uicontrol>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Company</uicontrol> - specifies the company of the selected user;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>E-mail</uicontrol> - specifies the e-mail address that the currently edited
          user used ti create his account. This is also the address where notifications  are
          sent;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Date</uicontrol> - specifies the date when the currently edited user created
          his account;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Web Help Notification</uicontrol> - specifies whether the currently edited
          user receives notifications when comments are posted anywhere in the feedback-enabled
          WebHelp system;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Reply Notification</uicontrol>  - specifies whether the currently edited user
          receives notifications when comments are posted as a reply to a comment left by the user
          itself;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Page Notification</uicontrol> - specifies whether the currently edited user
          receives notifications when comments are posted on a page where the user posted a
          comment.;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Status</uicontrol> - specifies the status of an user:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>created</uicontrol> - the currently edited user is created but does not
              have any rights over the feedback-enabled WebHelp system;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>validated</uicontrol> - the currently edited user is able to use the
              feedback-enabled WebHelp system;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>suspended</uicontrol> - the currently edited user has no rights over the
              feedback-enabled WebHelp system.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The rights of the users depend on their level as follows:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>user</uicontrol> - this type of user is able to post comments and receive
          e-mails when comments are posted anywhere in the documentation, on a single page where he
          posted a comment, or when a reply to one of his comments is posted;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>moderator</uicontrol> - apart from the rights of a normal user, this type of
          user has access to the <uicontrol>Admin Panel</uicontrol>. On the administrative page a
          moderator can view, delete, export comments and set the version of the feedback-enabled
          WebHelp system;<note>Comments of version newer than the current version are not displayed.
          </note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>admin</uicontrol> - the administrator has full access to all features of the
          feedback enabled WebHelp system. </li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
