<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="marklogic-connection">
  <title>MarkLogic Database Connections</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>MarkLogic database connection</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes support for MarkLogic database connections. Once you
      configure a MarkLogic connection, you can use the <xref
        href="relational-database-explorer.dita#relational-database-explorer"><uicontrol>Data Source
          Explorer</uicontrol> view</xref> to display all the application servers that are
      configured on the MarkLogic server. You can expand each application server and view all the
      modules that it is configured to use, and the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view
      allows you to open and edit these modules.<note>To browse modules located in a database,
        directory properties must be associated with them. These directory properties are generated
        automatically if the <term>directory creation</term> property of the database is set to
        automatic. If this property is set to <term>manual</term> or <term>manual-enforced</term>,
        add the directory properties of the modules manually, using the XQuery function
          <codeph>xdmp:directory-create()</codeph>. For example, for two documents with the
          <codeph>/code/modules/main.xqy</codeph> and
          <codeph>/code/modules/imports/import.xqy</codeph> IDs, run this query:
          <codeph>(xdmp:directory-create('/code/modules/'),
          xdmp:directory-create('/code/modules/imports/'))</codeph>.<p>For more information about
          directory properties go to: <xref
            href="http://blakeley.com/blogofile/2012/03/19/directory-assistance/" format="html"
            scope="external"/>.</p></note></p>
    <p>When you execute or debug XQuery files opened from this view, the imported modules are better
      identified by the MarkLogic server. In a module, you are also able to add breakpoints (in the
      modules of the application server that executes the debugging) that the debugger takes into
        account.<note>Open XQuery modules from the application server involved in the debugging or
        execution process.</note></p>
    <p>In the <uicontrol>Requests</uicontrol> container of each application server, <ph
        keyref="product"/> displays both the queries that are stopped for debugging purposes and the
      queries that are still running. To clean up the entire <uicontrol>Requests</uicontrol>
      container at the end of your session, right-click it and use the <uicontrol>Cancel all running
        requests</uicontrol> action.</p>
    <p id="use-it-to-execute-queries">To change the XDBC application server that <ph
        keyref="product"/> uses to process XQuery expressions, select the <uicontrol>Use it to
        execute queries</uicontrol> option from its contextual menu in the <uicontrol>Data Source
        Explorer</uicontrol> view.</p>
    <p>To manage resources for a MarkLogic database through WebDAV, configure a WebDAV URL in <xref
        href="../tasks/configure-marklogic-connection.dita#configure-marklogic-connection"
        format="dita">the MarkLogic connection</xref>. </p>
    <fig>
      <title>MarkLogic Connection in Data Source Explorer</title>
      <image href="../img/marklogic_connection.png"/>
    </fig>
  </body>
</topic>
