<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="markdown-editor">
  <title>Markdown Editor</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Markdown documents<indexterm>Markdown Editor</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Markdown Editor</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Create Markdown documents</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Export Markdown documents</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides an intuitive, dynamic, and easy-to-use Markdown editor for
      writing and converting Markdown documents. It is a split-screen editor with two panels that
      are synchronized in real-time. The left side is a simple text editor that is specially
      designed for writing Markdown syntax. The right side is a WYSIWYG style preview of how changes
      will look in the output.</p>
    <section id="leftside_markdown_text_editor">
      <title>Markdown Text Editor Pane (Left Side)</title>
      <p>The left pane is a simple text editor that is refined to accept Markdown syntax. At the
        same time, you still have many of the actions, options, and features that you are used to
        when editing any other type of document in <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
      <p>The features of this special editor that are unique for Markdown documents include:<ul>
          <li><b>Unique Markdown Syntax Rules</b> - The Markdown editor in <ph keyref="product"/>
            uses <xref href="markdown-rules.dita#markdown-rules">an integration of rules</xref> that
            combine rules from common default Markdown syntax along with many of the rules used in
            the GitHub Flavored Markdown syntax.</li>
          <li><b>Syntax Highlighting</b> - The <ph keyref="product"/> syntax highlighting feature is
            integrated into the Markdown text editor to make it easier to read and write Markdown
            syntax. You can even <xref
              href="markdown-syntax-highlight.dita#markdown-syntax-highlight">customize the colors
              and styles for the syntax highlighting</xref>.</li>
          <li><b>Automatic Spell Checking</b> - The Markdown editor supports the <ph
              keyref="product"/>
            <xref href="spell-check-as-you-type.dita#spell-check-as-you-type">automatic spell
              checking feature</xref> that reports possible misspelled words as you type. You simply
            need to select the <xref
              href="preferences-editor-spell-check.dita#preferences-editor-spell-check/automatic-spell-check"
                ><uicontrol>Automatic spell check</uicontrol> option in the <uicontrol>Spell
                Check</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>, then click the <uicontrol>Select
              editors</uicontrol> button and select <uicontrol>Markdown Editor</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li><b>Helpful Toolbar and Contextual Menu Actions</b> - A <xref
              href="markdown-actions.dita#markdown-actions">variety of unique actions</xref> are
            available from the toolbar to help you insert proper Markdown syntax. The contextual
            menu also includes some common editing actions, as well as unique actions to export
            (convert) Markdown documents to HTML or DITA.</li>
          <li product="author developer editor"><b>Shortcut Keys</b> - Many of the <xref
              href="common-shortcut-keys.dita#common-shortcut-keys">shortcut keys that are most
              commonly used</xref> in <ph keyref="product"/> also work in the Markdown editor.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="rightside_wysiwyg_preview_pane">
      <title>WYSIWYG Preview Pane (Right Side)</title>
      <p>The right pane is a WYSIWYG <i>Preview</i> pane that shows a visual representation of how
        changes made in the left-side text editor will be converted to HTML or DITA output. The
        changes you make in the text editor are parsed continually and they are immediately visible
        in the <i>Preview</i> pane. There are two tabs available in the <i>Preview</i> pane, one for
        visualizing DITA output and one for visualizing HTML output. You can switch between the two
        tabs at the bottom of the pane.</p>
      <p>The <i>Preview</i> pane includes the following unique features:<ul>
          <li><b>WYSIWYG Visualization</b> - This pane presents the Markdown syntax from the
            left-side text editor in a visual WYSIWYG style interface that is automatically
            synchronized as you type.</li>
          <li>
            <b>Export Options</b> - The <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> tab includes a contextual menu
            action to <xref href="markdown-actions.dita#markdown-actions/export-dita">export
              (convert) the current Markdown document to a DITA topic</xref>. Similarly, the
              <uicontrol>HTML</uicontrol> tab includes a contextual menu action to <xref
              href="markdown-actions.dita#markdown-actions/export-html">export (convert) it to an
              XHTML document</xref>.</li>
          <li><b>Automatic Validation</b> - As you edit Markdown documents, they are <xref
              href="markdown-validation.dita#markdown-validation">validated automatically</xref>.
            The conversion engine constantly tries to parse your changes and if a change results in
            an error that prevents the parser from converting the syntax, an error message will be
            displayed in the <i>Preview</i> pane or <xref href="results-view.dita#results-view"
                ><uicontrol>Results</uicontrol> view</xref> at the bottom of the editor.</li>
          <li><b>Print Feature</b> - The Markdown editor includes a <uicontrol>Print</uicontrol>
            action that is available in the contextual menu and it allows you to configure options
            for printing the current document as you see it in the <i>Preview</i> pane.</li>
          <li product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse" id="tags-display-mode"><b>Preview
              Markup</b> - The Markdown editor includes a <xref
              href="markdown-actions.dita#markdown-actions/md-tags-display-mode"><uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/TagsDrop.png" id="image_pmr_mhm_1s"/>Tags Display Mode</uicontrol>
              drop-down menu</xref> that is available on the toolbar and it allows you to control
            the amount of markup that is displayed in the <i>Preview</i> pane.</li>
          <li><b>Specialized DITA Features</b> - The Markdown editor includes some unique, <xref
              href="markdown-dita.dita#markdown-dita">specialized features to integrate it with the
              powerful DITA support</xref> in <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <p product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">
      <fig>
        <title>Markdown Editor in <ph keyref="product"/></title>
        <image href="../img/markdown_editor.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p product="developer developerEclipse">
      <fig>
        <title>Markdown Editor in <ph keyref="product"/></title>
        <image href="../img/markdown_editor_dev.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="markdown-rules.dita#markdown-rules"/>
      <link href="markdown-actions.dita#markdown-actions"/>
      <link href="markdown-dita.dita#markdown-dita"/>
      <link href="markdown-create-new.dita#markdown-create-new"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
