<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="markdown-dita">
  <title>Working with Markdown Documents in DITA</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Markdown documents<indexterm>DITA</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA and Markdown documents</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes some unique features that allow you to easily integrate
      Markdown documents in a DITA project. This is especially helpful for teams that have
      contributors who are familiar with the Markdown syntax, but they want their output to be
      generated from DITA projects. The integration between the Markdown editor and DITA includes
      actions to export or convert Markdown documents to DITA topics and the
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> tab in the <i>Preview</i> pane provides a visualization of how
      the topic will look after conversion.</p>
    <section id="export_markdown_syntax_as_a_dita_topic">
      <title>Export Markdown as a DITA Topic</title>
      <p>The Markdown editor includes an option to quickly convert the current Markdown document
        into a DITA topic. The <uicontrol>Export as DITA Topic</uicontrol> action is available in
        the contextual menu of the left-side text editor and the right-side <i>Preview</i> pane when
        the <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol> tab selected.</p>
      <p>The conversion creates a new XML file that is defined as a DITA topic and opens it in the
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editing mode. You can then work with the document as you would
        with any other DITA topic, although you may need to manually correct some issues where the
        parser could not properly map Markdown syntax to DITA markup.</p>
    </section>
    <section product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"
      id="working_with_markdown_documents_in_the_dita_maps_">
      <title>Working with Markdown Documents in the DITA Maps Manager</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> has some specialized features that allow you to integrate Markdown
        documents directly into your DITA project using the <xref
          href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
          Manager</uicontrol></xref>. The following features are available for Markdown documents in
        the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view:<ul>
          <li><b>Insert Reference to Markdown Document</b> - You can use the
              <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Reference</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Reference
              to the currently edited file</uicontrol> actions from the <uicontrol>Append
              Child</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Insert Before</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Insert
              After</uicontrol> submenu when invoking the contextual menu in the <uicontrol>DITA
              Maps Manager</uicontrol> to insert a reference to a Markdown document at the selected
            location in the map. Markdown documents will be inserted as a topic reference
              (<codeph>topicref</codeph> element) with the <codeph>format</codeph> attribute set to
              <codeph>markdown</codeph>.</li>
          <li><b>Validate Markdown Documents in DITA Maps</b> - When you use the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/ValidateAndCheck16.png" id="image_vjz_3vv_sr"/>Validate and Check for
              Completeness</uicontrol> action from the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>
            toolbar to check the integrity of the structure of a <term>DITA map</term>, Markdown
            documents that are referenced in the <term>DITA map</term> will be converted to DITA
            topics in the background and validated the same as any other DITA topic.</li>
          <li><b>Transforming DITA Maps with Markdown Documents</b> - When transforming <term>DITA
              maps</term> that have Markdown documents referenced, the transformation will convert
            the Markdown documents to normal DITA output without you needing to manually convert the
            Markdown documents to DITA topics.</li>
          <li id="convert-md-dita"><b>Manually Convert Markdown Documents to DITA Topics</b> - If
            you need to use DITA semantics that are not possible in Markdown syntax (such as content
            references, related links, and other DITA-specific syntax), you can manually convert the
            Markdown document into a DITA topic. To do so, right-click the Markdown document in the
              <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> and select <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Convert Markdown to DITA Topic</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>. This will open a dialog box that allows you to configure options for
            converting the document to an XML file that is defined as a DITA topic.<p>
              <fig>
                <title>Convert Markdown to DITA Topic Dialog Box</title>
                <image href="../img/convert_md_dita.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p><p>This dialog box includes the following options:</p><p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Destination</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>The destination path for the new DITA topic.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>File Name</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Presents the current name and allows you to change it.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Update references</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Select this option to update all references of the file in the <term>DITA
                      map</term> and in the files referenced from the <term>DITA map</term>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Delete Markdown file</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>If selected, the Markdown version of the file is deleted when the document is
                    converted into a DITA file. If deselected (default value), when the document is
                    converted into a DITA file, the original Markdown file is also preserved in its
                    current location.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Select this button to display a preview of the changes <ph keyref="product"/>
                    is about to make.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Convert</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Select this button to perform the conversion.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <note type="tip"><ph keyref="product"/> comes with a sample ditamap project for converting
      Markdown to DITA. Go to the <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view"
          ><uicontrol product="author developer editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
          product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</uicontrol> view</xref>,
      open the <filepath>sample.xpr</filepath> project, and navigate to the
        <filepath>dita/markdown-dita</filepath> folder.</note>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="markdown-editor.dita#markdown-editor"/>
      <link href="markdown-actions.dita#markdown-actions"/>
      <link href="markdown-rules.dita#markdown-rules"/>
      <link href="markdown-validation.dita#markdown-validation"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
