<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="merging_changes">
    <title>Merging Changes</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>Merging changes</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Merging changes back into Oxygen</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Get changes</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Merge tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>As the <b>Content Author</b>, once the <b>Reviewers</b> are done with their process, you
      will have access to a <uicontrol>Get Changes</uicontrol> link when hovering over the task in
      the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Task Manager</uicontrol> view. Clicking this link opens a <b>Get
        Changes</b> merge tool that allows you to automatically merge all the changes back into
      Oxygen XML Editor or Oxygen XML Author.</p>
    <p>In most instances, you will simply click the <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol> button at the
      bottom of the merge tool to automatically merge all the changes and when the files are opened
      in Oxygen XML Editor or Oxygen XML Author, you will see the changes. As long as you kept the
        <xref
        href="content_fusion_user_interface_author.dita#content_fusion_user_interface_author/force-change-tracking"
          ><uicontrol>Force Change Tracking On</uicontrol> option</xref> selected in <ph
        keyref="product"/>, you will have the ability to accept or reject the changes. If you happen
      to encounter a conflict, you will need to select a <xref href="#merging_changes/merge-action"
        format="dita"><b>Merge Action</b> from the drop-down menu for that particular
      file</xref>.</p>
    <p>If you need to resolve conflicts or make some manual changes to the merge process, refer to
      the following section for more in depth information on using the <uicontrol>Get
        Changes</uicontrol> merge tool.</p>
    <section id="3way_directory_comparison_tool_features_and_actio">
      <title>Get Changes Merge Tool</title>
      <p>When you click the <uicontrol>Get Changes</uicontrol> link on a task, a merge tool is
        displayed that allows you to automatically integrate the changes and you also have access to
        numerous actions to manually adjust the merge.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Get Changes Merge Tool</title>
          <image href="../img/get_changes_merge_tool.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The merge tool includes the following information, features, and actions:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>Number of Changes and Conflicts</u></dt>
            <dd>The first thing you see in top-left corner of the tool is grand total of all the
              changes made by others, changes made by you, and the number of conflicts.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>Filter Buttons</u></dt>
            <dd>In the top-right corner you can use the toggle buttons to filter the list of modifications:<p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MergeAllFilesMode16.png"/> Show all
                        files</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to show all modified and unmodified files, as well as
                      conflicts.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MergeInOutMode16.png"/> Show only files
                        modified by you and others</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Filters the list to show all files that have been modified, including
                      conflicts.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MergeIncomingMode16.png"/> Show only files
                        modified by others</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Filters the list to only show the files that were modified by others.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MergeOutgoingMode16.png"/> Show only files
                        modified by you</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Filters the list to only show the files that were modified by you.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MergeConflictsMode16.png"/> Show only
                        conflicting files</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Filters the list to only show files that contain conflicts.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>List of Files Panel</u></dt>
            <dd>This panel shows the list of files in the compared file sets based upon the filter
              button that is selected. This panel includes the following sortable columns:<ul>
                <li><b>Name</b> - The file names.</li>
                <li><b>Status</b> - An icon that represents the file status. Red icons indicate some
                  sort of conflict. Gray icons indicate modifications made by you. Blue icons
                  indicate modifications made by others.</li>
                <li><b>Description</b> - A description of the file status.</li>
                <li id="merge-action"><b>Merge Action</b> - This column provides a drop-down menu
                  for each file that allows you to choose some merge actions depending upon its
                  status. A default action is always set to automatically merge the changes made by
                  others with your changes. If there is a conflict, the default is
                    <uicontrol>&lt;Select action></uicontrol> and you are required to make a
                  selection. Click this column to access the drop-down menu where you can make a
                  selection. The same actions are available in the contextual menu.</li>
              </ul><p>You can double-click any non-binary file (or select <uicontrol>Show
                  modifications</uicontrol> from the contextual menu) to open it in the file
                comparison panel (the file from your file set is shown in the left panel while the
                file from the file set with changes made by others is shown in the right
              panel).</p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>File Comparison Panels</u></dt>
            <dd>If you double-click any non-binary file in the top panel, the file is opened in this
              file comparison section. The file from your file set is shown in the left panel and
              the file from the other file set is shown in the right panel.<note>If <ph
                  keyref="product"/> does not recognize the file type, a dialog box will be
                displayed that allows you to select the type of editor you want it to be associated
                with for this comparison (if you want <ph keyref="product"/> to remember this
                association, you can select the <uicontrol>Associate file type with
                  editor</uicontrol> option at the bottom of the dialog box).</note>This panel
              includes the following information and toolbar actions:<p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>File Path</dt>
                    <dd>The first thing you see in this panel is the file path where merge actions
                      will be applied if you make changes.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/CloseQuickFind16.png"/>Close</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Closes the file comparison panel.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol>Algorithm Drop-Down Menu</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>This drop-down menu allows you to select one of the following diff
                      algorithms to be used for file comparisons:<ul>
                        <li id="auto">
                          <p>
                            <uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - Selects the most appropriate algorithm,
                            based on the compared content and its size (selected by default).</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="lines">
                          <p>
                            <uicontrol>Lines</uicontrol> - Computes the differences at line level,
                            meaning that it compares two files or fragments looking for identical
                            lines of text.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="xml-fast">
                          <p>
                            <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> - Comparison that works well on large
                            files or fragments, but it is less precise than <uicontrol>XML
                              Accurate</uicontrol>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="xml-accurate">
                          <p>
                            <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> - Comparison that is more precise
                            than <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol>, at the expense of speed. It
                            compares two XML files or fragments looking for identical XML nodes.
                          </p>
                        </li>
                      </ul></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/OptionsShortcut16.png"/>Diff
                        Options</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Opens a preferences page where you can configure various options.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-perform-files-diff">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPerform20.png"/> Perform Files
                        Differencing</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Looks for differences between the two files displayed in the left and right
                      side panels.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-ignore-whitespaces">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffIgnoreWhitespaces20.png"
                          id="image_gmn_wk3_tc" placement="inline"/> Ignore
                      Whitespaces</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Enables or disables the whitespace ignoring feature. Ignoring whitespace
                      means that before performing the comparison, the application normalizes the
                      content and trims its leading and trailing whitespaces.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-synchro-scrolling">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffSynchronizeScroll20.png"
                          id="image_ygw_yph_tc" placement="inline"/> Synchronized scrolling
                      </uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Toggles synchronized scrolling. When toggled on, a selected difference can
                      be seen in both panels.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-format-indent">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPrettyPrint20.png"/> Format and Indent
                        Both Files</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Formats and indents both files before comparing them. Use this option for
                      comparisons that contain long lines that make it difficult to spot
                        differences.<note id="format-indent-note">When comparing two JSON files, the
                          <uicontrol>Format and Indent Both Files</uicontrol> action will
                        automatically sort the keys in both files the same to make it easier to
                        compare. </note></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-copy-right-left-dlentry">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyRightToLeft20.png"/> Copy Change
                        from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Copies the selected difference from the file in the right panel to the file
                      in the left panel.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-copy-all-right-left-dlentry">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyAllRightToLeft20.png"/> Copy All
                        Changes from Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Copies all changes from the file in the right panel to the file in the left
                      panel.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-next-block-changes">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffNextBlock16.png" id="image_vrq_3k3_tc"
                        /> Next Block of Changes</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Jumps to the next block of changes. This action is not available when the
                      cursor is positioned on the last change block or when there are no
                        changes.<note>A change block groups one or more consecutive lines that
                        contain at least one change.</note></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-previous-block-changes">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPreviousBlock16.png"
                          id="image_lbz_hk3_tc"/> Previous Block of Changes</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Jumps to the previous block of changes. This action is not available when
                      the cursor is positioned on the first change block or when there are no
                      changes.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-next-change">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffNext16.png" id="image_lbp_jk3_tc"/>
                        Next Change</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Jumps to the next change from the current block of changes. When the last
                      change from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the next
                      block of changes. This action is not available when the cursor is positioned
                      on the last change or when there are no changes.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files-previous-change">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPrevious16.png" id="image_vc1_hk3_tc"
                        /> Previous Change</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Jumps to the previous change from the current block of changes. When the
                      first change from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the
                      previous block of changes. This action is not available when the cursor is
                      positioned on the first change or when there are no changes.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="files_first_change">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffFirst16.png"/> First
                      Change</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Jumps to the first change.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Left-Side File (Your changes)</dt>
                    <dd>Above the panel you can see the file path and the following two
                      buttons:</dd>
                    <dd>
                      <p>
                        <dl>
                          <dlentry>
                            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffSave16.gif"/>
                              Save</uicontrol></dt>
                            <dd>Saves changes made to the file.</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                          <dlentry>
                            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Refresh16.png"/>
                              Reload</uicontrol></dt>
                            <dd>Reloads the file.</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                      </p>
                    </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Right-Side File (Changes made by others)</dt>
                    <dd>Above the panel you can see the file path and the following two
                      buttons:</dd>
                    <dd>
                      <p>
                        <dl>
                          <dlentry>
                            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Refresh16.png"/>
                              Reload</uicontrol></dt>
                            <dd>Reloads the file.</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                      </p>
                    </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>Displaying Changes in the File Comparison Panels</u></dt>
            <dd>
              <p>Double-clicking a changed file in the top panel opened the two versions of it in
                the file comparison section. The line numbers on each side and colored marks on the
                right-side vertical stripe help you to quickly identify the locations of the
                differences. Adjacent changes are grouped into blocks of changes.</p>
              <p>
                <fig>
                  <title>File Comparison Panels</title>
                  <image href="../img/two-compare-source.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
              <p>The differences are also highlighted in several colors, depending on the type of
                change, and dynamic lines connect the compared fragments in the middle section
                between the two panes. The default colors and their shades mean the following:<ul>
                  <li><b>Pink</b> - Identifies modifications on either side.</li>
                  <li><b>Gray</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the left side (your outgoing
                    changes).</li>
                  <li><b>Blue</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the right side (incoming
                    changes).</li>
                  <li><b>Lighter Shade</b> - Identifies blocks of changes that can be merged in
                    their entirety.</li>
                  <li><b>Darker Shade</b> - Identifies specific changes within the blocks that can
                    be merged more precisely.</li>
                </ul></p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>Direct Editing Actions in the File Comparison Panels</u></dt>
            <dd>
              <p>In addition to selecting merge actions from the <xref
                  href="#merging_changes/merge-action" format="dita">drop-down menus in the
                    <uicontrol>Merge Action</uicontrol> column</xref> in the top panel, you can also
                edit the files directly in the left pane (your local changes). The two editors are
                constantly synchronized and the differences are refreshed when you save the modified
                document (<uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffSave16.gif"/>Save</uicontrol> button or
                    <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+S</shortcut></uicontrol>) or when you click the
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffPerform16.png"/>Perform File
                  Differencing</uicontrol> button.</p>
              <p>A variety of actions are available in the contextual menu in both editing panes.
                The tool also includes some inline actions to help you merge, copy, or remove
                changes. When you select a change, the following inline action widgets are
                available, depending on the type of change:<dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffAppendRightToLeft12.png"
                          placement="inline"/> Append right change to left</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Copies the content of the selected change from the right side and appends it
                      on the left side.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffCopyRightToLeft12.png" placement="inline"
                        /> Copy change from right to left</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Replaces the content of a change in the left side with the content of the
                      change in the right side.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffRemove12.png"/> Remove
                      change</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Removes the change from the left side.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl></p>
              <p>Any time you save manual changes (<uicontrol><image href="../img/DiffSave16.gif"
                  />Save</uicontrol> button or <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+S</shortcut></uicontrol>),
                the selection in the <xref href="#merging_changes/merge-action" format="dita"
                    ><uicontrol>Merge Action</uicontrol> column</xref> in the top panel
                automatically changes to <b>Use merged</b> and a copy of the original file is kept
                so that you can revert to the original file if necessary. To discard your manual
                changes and revert to your original changes, select a different action in the
                  <uicontrol>Merge Action</uicontrol> drop-down menu.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>Applying Changes</u></dt>
            <dd>When you click the <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol> button, all the merge actions you
              have selected and the changes you have made will be processed.<p>If there are
                unresolved conflicts (conflicts where no merge action is selected in the <xref
                  href="#merging_changes/merge-action" format="dita"><uicontrol>Merge
                    Action</uicontrol> drop-down menu</xref>), a dialog box will be displayed that
                allows you to choose how to solve the conflicts. You can choose between the following:<ul>
                  <li><uicontrol>Keep your changes</uicontrol> - If you select this option and then
                    click <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol>, your local changes will be preserved for the
                    unresolved conflicts.</li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Overwrite your changes</uicontrol> - If you select this option and
                    then click <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol>, your local changes will be overwritten
                    with the changes made by others, for the unresolved conflicts.</li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> - You can click the
                      <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> button to go back to the merge tool to resolve
                    the conflicts individually.</li>
                </ul></p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><u>Cancelling Changes</u></dt>
            <dd>If you click the <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> button at the bottom of the merge
              tool, all the changes you made in the tool will be lost.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
