<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="merge-dirs-with-change-tracking-highlights">
  <title>Merge Directories with Change Tracking Highlights</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Merge directories with change tracking tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_w3v_bgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Merge Directories with Change Tracking
        Highlights</uicontrol> tool can be used to merge two directories, based on a 2-way mode
      comparison.</p>
    <p id="p_wlj_f1h_nyb">All pairs of modified XML files involved in the process are merged by
      saving the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode comparison results as documents with highlighted
      tracked changes that can be later reviewed and accepted or rejected.</p>
    <p id="p_xlj_f1h_nyb">All other detected situations are treated based on several options that
      are applicable to both XML and non-XML files, or another option that is applicable only to
      non-XML files.</p>
    <p id="p_ylj_f1h_nyb">To invoke the tool, select the <uicontrol>Merge Directories with Change
        Tracking Highlights</uicontrol> action that is found in the <b>Tools</b> menu. It opens a
      dialog box where you can specify the directories to merge and the output directory to save the
      results, as well as some other options.</p>
    <p id="p_uh1_zfx_5pb">
      <fig id="fig_uwg_zfx_5pb">
        <title>Merge Directories with Change Tracking Highlights Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/merge-dirs-with-change-tracking-dialog-box.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_x5d_hgx_5pb">The <uicontrol>Merge Directories with Change Tracking
        Highlights</uicontrol> dialog box contains the following options:</p>
    <p id="p_p3d_5vj_vpb">
      <dl id="dl_q5g_5vj_vpb">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_r5g_5vj_vpb">
          <dt>Base directory</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the path of the base directory.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_jv1_bwj_vpb">
          <dt>Directory to merge with</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the path of the directory to merge with.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_owv_kwj_vpb">
          <dt>Output directory</dt>
          <dd>Specifies the path of the directory where the merge operation results are saved to.
            You can leave this field blank and the merge results will be saved in the base directory
            by overwriting it, or you can choose a separate output directory.<note
              id="note_bdz_pbh_nyb">You cannot choose the same directory specified as the directory
              to merge with as the output directory.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_nkr_lwj_vpb">
          <dt>Backup the base directory</dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, a backup copy is saved on your hard disk when the
            operation completes. This option is automatically activated and selected in the
            following cases:<ul id="ul_o33_vdh_nyb">
              <li id="li_p33_vdh_nyb">The output directory is not specified (the field is left
                blank).</li>
              <li id="li_gtk_xbh_nyb">The specified output directory is the base directory
                itself.</li>
              <li id="li_htk_xbh_nyb">In both of the above situations, a backup of the base
                directory will be performed automatically and the backup operation must succeed to
                proceed with the merge. Otherwise, the merge process being aborted. </li>
            </ul><note id="note_kbs_32h_nyb">The backup copy will have the same parent directory as
              the base directory and its name will be the name of the base directory suffixed by
              ".OXY.BAK".</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_esx_djc_kqb">
          <dt>Merge options</dt>
          <dd>The merge process has a preliminary phase where the entire structure and the content
            of the base directory is copied to the output directory. The following merge options are
              available:<p id="p_kxr_1ch_nyb">
              <dl id="dl_dbw_1ch_nyb">
                <dlentry id="dlentry_ebw_1ch_nyb">
                  <dt>Update the modified non-XML files</dt>
                  <dd>If this option is selected, all files in the output directory that are copies
                    of non-XML files in the base directory are replaced by their corresponding files
                    in the directory to merge with. Otherwise, they remain unchanged.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_bbd_cch_nyb">
                  <dt>Add the files found only in the directory to merge with</dt>
                  <dd>If this option is selected, all files that are only present in the directory
                    to merge with are also added to the output directory.<p>
                      <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                          <dt>Create change tracking markers for the XML files to be added</dt>
                          <dd>
                            <p>This option can only be used in conjunction with the <uicontrol>Add
                                the files found only in the directory to merge with</uicontrol>
                              option. Select this option if you want to create change tracking
                              markers for the XML files that are only present in the directory to
                              merge with and will be added to the output directory. Although these
                              files have no counterparts in the base directory, change tracking
                              markers of type "entire content added/inserted" will be created.</p>
                            <p>The option is not necessarily intended for the merge process itself,
                              but it is useful if you want to apply various <i>Oxygen</i>
                              transformation scenarios to the resulting output directory. For
                              example, if you merge 2 versions of a DITA project and then want a PDF
                              to highlight the changes between those versions, you can apply a
                              transformation on the resulting <filepath>ditamap</filepath> file.
                              This option results in presenting the new DITA files as "added
                              content" in the resulting PDF.</p>
                          </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                      </dl>
                    </p></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_ult_dch_nyb">
                  <dt>Delete the files found only in the base directory</dt>
                  <dd>If this option is selected, all files that are only present in the base
                    directory and initially copied to the output directory are deleted. Otherwise,
                    they are preserved.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_bmj_fch_nyb">
                  <dt>Open the operation report file in editor</dt>
                  <dd>Opens the merge operation report (XML file) in the editor.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p id="p_mzx_czj_vpb">Once the merge operation is complete, loading the report file in <ph
        keyref="product"/> provides additional functionality. Aside from the fact that the report
      provides an overview of the merge process, it also provides links to all the files in the
      resulting output directory. This is helpful for generating XML documents with tracked changes.
      For example, you can use the respective links to load these XML files in
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode to review the tracked changes and accept or reject them.
      This phase of reviewing and manually merging the XML files is typically the final phase of the
      entire merge procedure.</p>
    <p id="p_jnw_hgx_5pb">
      <fig id="fig_knw_hgx_5pb">
        <title>Example of an Operation Overview Report File</title>
        <image href="../img/merge-dirs-change-track-report.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_xgb_tls_nyb">
      <fig id="fig_df3_tls_nyb">
        <title>Example of a Merged File Opened in Author Mode</title>
        <image href="../img/merge-dirs-change-track-report-result.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
