<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="merge-directories-change-tracking">
  <title>Merge Directories with Change Tracking Highlights</title>
  <body>
    <note conkeyref="reusables-scripting/note-scripting-license" id="note_zmx_dgk_54b"/>
    <p id="p_anx_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Merge Directories with Change Tracking
        Highlights</uicontrol> script (<codeph>mergeDirsTrackChanges.sh</codeph>, found in the
        <filepath>scripts</filepath> subfolder inside <b>Oxygen's</b> installation directory) can be
      used to merge 2 directories (based on a 2-way comparison). All pairs of modified XML files
      involved in the process are merged by saving the comparison results as documents with
      highlighted tracked changes that can be later reviewed and accepted or rejected.</p>
    <section id="section_gbd_tzb_vmb">
      <title>Arguments for the Merge Directories with Change Tracking Highlights Script</title>
      <p id="p_tnx_dgk_54b">
        <codeblock outputclass="language-bourne" id="codeblock_unx_dgk_54b">sh mergeDirsTrackChanges.sh pathOfBaseDir pathOfDirToMergeWith [[pathOfOutDir] [-nb noBackupOfBaseDir] [-nu noUpdateOfModifNonXMLFiles] [-na noAddingFilesOnlyPresentInDirToMergeWith] [-nd noDeletionOfFilesOnlyPresentInBaseDir] [-cm createChangeTrackingMarkersForAddedXMLFiles]] [-help | --help | -h | --h]</codeblock>
      </p>
      <p id="p_vnx_dgk_54b">
        <dl id="dl_wnx_dgk_54b">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_xnx_dgk_54b">
            <dt>pathOfBaseDir</dt>
            <dd>Mandatory argument that specifies the path of the base directory (it can also be
              provided as a URL using <codeph>file://</codeph> protocol).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_l2b_gpl_54b">
            <dt>pathOfDirToMergeWith</dt>
            <dd>Mandatory argument that specifies the path of the directory to merge with (it can
              also be provided as a URL using <codeph>file://</codeph> protocol).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_x2j_5ck_dpb">
            <dt>pathOfOutDir</dt>
            <dd>Optional argument that specifies the path of the directory where the merge operation
              results are saved to (it can also be provided as a URL using <codeph>file://</codeph>
              protocol). If present, it must appear immediately after the first two mandatory
              arguments. If absent, the merge results are saved to the base directory, by
              overwriting it. You cannot choose the same directory specified as the directory to
              merge with as the output directory (the merge process is aborted in this case).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_zcl_bgk_dpb">
            <dt>-nb noBackupOfBaseDir</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_chc_bhf_xyb">Set to <b>true</b> if you do not want a backup copy of the base
                directory on the hard disk. There are 2 situations when a backup of the base
                directory is performed automatically and the backup operation must succeed to
                proceed with the merge. Otherwise, the merge process is aborted if the output
                directory is not specified (i.e. the <codeph>pathOfOutDir</codeph> argument is not
                present) or the specified output directory is the base directory itself.</p>
              <p id="p_vcs_1hf_xyb">The backup copy will have the same parent directory as the base
                directory and its name will be the name of the base directory suffixed by
                ".OXY.BAK". The default value is <b>false</b>, which means that for either of the 2
                previously mentioned situations, a backup copy of the base directory will be kept on
                the hard disk.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_jlx_gy3_xyb">
            <dt>-nu noUpdateOfModifNonXMLFiles</dt>
            <dd>Set to <b>true</b> if you want to keep the non-XML files at their versions from the
              base directory. The default value is <b>false</b>, which means that all files in the
              output directory that are copies of non-XML files in the base directory will be
              replaced by their corresponding files in the directory to merge with.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_fpt_4y3_xyb">
            <dt>-na noAddingFilesOnlyPresentInDirToMergeWith</dt>
            <dd>Set to <b>true</b> if you want to skip adding the files that are only present in the
              directory to merge with to the output directory as well. The default value is
                <b>false</b>, which means that all files that are only present in the directory to
              merge with are also added to the output directory.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_gbw_qy3_xyb">
            <dt>-nd noDeletionOfFilesOnlyPresentInBaseDir</dt>
            <dd>Set to <b>true</b> if you want to preserve the files that are only present in the
              base directory. The default value is <b>false</b>, which means that all files that are
              only present in the base directory and initially copied to the output directory are
              deleted.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_cyy_ry3_xyb">
            <dt>-cm createChangeTrackingMarkersForAddedXMLFiles</dt>
            <dd>Set to <b>true</b> if you want to create change tracking markers for the XML files
              only present in the directory to merge with (that will be added to the output
              directory). Although these files have no counterparts in the base directory, change
              tracking markers of the type "entire content added/inserted" will be created. The
              option is not necessarily intended for the merge process itself, but it might prove a
              useful addition when you want to apply various <term>Oxygen</term> transformation
              scenarios to the resulting output directory. For example, if you merge 2 versions of a
              DITA project and then want a PDF to highlight the changes between those versions, you
              can apply a transformation on the resulting <filepath>ditamap</filepath> file. The
                <codeph>-am</codeph> option presents the new DITA files as "added content" in the
              resulting PDF. Note that the option is only considered if the <codeph>-na</codeph>
              argument is absent or is explicitly set to <b>false</b> (default value).</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_c4x_dgk_54b">
            <dt>-help | --help | -h | --h</dt>
            <dd>Displays help text.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <note id="note_p2r_k4l_54b" othertype="Notes" type="other">
        <ul id="ul_xtb_wy3_xyb">
          <li id="li_ytb_wy3_xyb">The merge process has a preliminary phase where the entire
            structure and content of the base directory is copied to the output directory.</li>
          <li id="li_aqs_xy3_xyb">For boolean arguments, it is not necessary to provide the "true"
            value. Their presence in the argument list is equivalent to setting their value to
            "true" (and their absence from the argument list is equivalent to setting their value to
            "false"). However, constructs of the form <codeph>bool_option true|false</codeph> are
            accepted and interpreted accordingly.</li>
          <li id="li_b51_1z3_xyb">Once the merge operation is complete, a report file is created and
            saved in the output directory (in a separate subdirectory named
            ".__OXY__MERGE__REPORT"). Loading the report file in <ph keyref="product"/> provides
            additional functionality. Aside from the fact that the report provides an overview of
            the merge process, it also provides links to all the files in the resulting output
            directory. You can use the respective links to load the XML files in the editor, then
            switch to <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode to review the tracked changes and accept or
            reject them.</li>
        </ul>
      </note>
    </section>
    <section id="section_pnz_pnl_54b">
      <title>Examples of Compare Directories Script</title>
      <p id="p_idr_zxn_wqb">
        <dl id="dl_whv_zxn_wqb">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_xhv_zxn_wqb">
            <dt>Example 1: Compare Directories Without Updating non-XML Files</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_fwp_dyn_wqb">The following command results in merging <codeph>dir1</codeph>
                and <codeph>dir2</codeph> into <codeph>outdir</codeph>, but without updating the
                non-XML files in <codeph>dir1</codeph> detected with changes to their version in
                  <codeph>dir2</codeph>:<codeblock outputclass="language-bourne">sh scripts/mergeDirsTrackChanges.sh dir1 dir2 outdir -nu</codeblock></p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_vtg_3yn_wqb">
            <dt>Example 2: Compare Two Directories and Overwrite the First One</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_h42_lyn_wqb">The following command results in merging <codeph>dir1</codeph>
                and <codeph>dir2</codeph> by overwriting <codeph>dir1</codeph>. However, the
                  <codeph>dir1</codeph> is backed up
                first:<codeblock outputclass="language-bourne">sh scripts/mergeDirsTrackChanges.sh dir1 dir2</codeblock></p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_rfg_nyn_wqb">
            <dt>Example 3: Compare Directories and Create Change Tracking Markers</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_hmz_bzn_wqb">The following command results in merging <codeph>dir1</codeph>
                and <codeph>dir2</codeph> into <codeph>outdir</codeph> and creating change tracking
                markers (of the type "entire content added/inserted") for all XML files that are
                only present in <codeph>dir2</codeph> (to be added to the
                <codeph>outdir</codeph>):<codeblock outputclass="language-bourne">sh scripts/mergeDirsTrackChanges.sh dir1 dir2 outdir -cm</codeblock></p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p id="p_xgb_tls_nyb">
        <fig id="fig_df3_tls_nyb">
          <title>Example of a Merged File with Change Tracking Markers Opened in Author Mode</title>
          <image href="../img/merge-dirs-change-track-report-result.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
