<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="merge-branches">
    <title>Merging</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Branches/Tags<indexterm>Merging</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p>At some stage during the development process, you will want to merge the changes made on a
        <i>branch</i> back into the <i>trunk</i>, or vice-versa. The <i>merge</i> is accomplished by
      comparing two points (branches or revisions) in the repository and applying the obtained
      differences to your working copy. This process is closely related to the <i>diff</i>
      concept.</p>
    <note type="note">A <i>branch</i> is a line of development that exists independently of another
      line, yet still shares a common history if you look far enough back in time. A <i>branch</i>
      always begins life as <i>a copy of something</i> (such as a trunk, another branch, or tag),
      and moves on from there, generating its own history.</note>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNMerge16.png" id="image_lhq_gnq_4r"/>Merge</uicontrol>
      action is available in the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu. The working copy item selected
      when you issued the command will be the one receiving the generated changes. If there is no
      item selected, the <i>merge</i> operation will be performed on the entire working copy.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_qfn_cjl_4r">
        <title><uicontrol>Merge</uicontrol> Wizard</title>
        <image href="../img/svn_merge_wiz1.png" id="image_nmr_4jl_4r"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The four types of merging are as follows:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><xref href="../tasks/merge-revisions-range.dita#merge-revisions-range"><uicontrol>Merge
            revisions</uicontrol></xref> - Port changes from one branch to another. Note that the
          <i>trunk</i> can also be considered a branch, in this context.</li>
      <li><xref href="../tasks/synchronize-branch.dita#synchronize-branch"><uicontrol>Synchronize
            branch</uicontrol></xref> - Fetch all the changes made on a parent branch (or the
          <i>trunk</i>) to a child branch.</li>
      <li><xref href="../tasks/merge-branch.dita#merge-branch"><uicontrol>Reintegrate a
            branch</uicontrol></xref> - Merge a branch back to its parent branch (can also be the
          <i>trunk</i>).</li>
      <li><xref href="../tasks/merge-trees.dita#merge-trees"><uicontrol>Merge two different
            trees</uicontrol></xref> - Integrate the changes done on a branch to a different
        branch.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>It is recommended that you enable the following pre-merge check:<ul id="ul_gjm_rhl_4r">
        <li><xref href="pre-merge-checks.dita#pre-merge-checks"><uicontrol>Perform pre-merge best
              practices checks of the working copy target</uicontrol></xref> - When selected, the
          SVN Client checks if the working copy target item is ready for the merge operation and
          displays the <uicontrol>pre-merge checks</uicontrol> wizard page.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note type="remember">It is a good idea to perform a merge into an unmodified working copy. If
      you have made changes to your working copy, commit them first. If the <i>merge</i> does not go
      as you expect, you may want to revert the changes and revert cannot recover your uncommitted
      modifications.</note>
    <note type="important">The above recommendation becomes mandatory when <xref
        href="#merge-branches" format="dita"><i>reintegrating a branch</i></xref>.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
