<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="move-rename-resources-project-view">
  <title>Moving/Renaming Resources in the <ph product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
      >Navigator</ph><ph product="author developer editor">Project</ph> View</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view allows you to move or rename a file from the current
      project.</p>
    <p>To move a file or a directory, drag and drop it to the new location in the tree structure
      from the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view. You can also right click the file or directory
      and select the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Move resource </uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action from its contextual menu, or use the usual <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/sa_cut_menu.png"/>Cut</uicontrol> and <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/sa_paste.png"/>Paste</uicontrol> actions. <ph keyref="product"/> presents the
        <uicontrol>Move</uicontrol> dialog if you used the drag and drop or the
        <uicontrol>Cut/Paste</uicontrol> actions. The <uicontrol>Move resource</uicontrol> dialog is
      presented in case you used the refactoring actions. The following fields are available:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Destination</uicontrol> - available in the <uicontrol>Move
            resource</uicontrol> dialog only. Presents the path to the current location of the
          resource you want to move and gives you the option to introduce a new location;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>New name</uicontrol> - presents the current name of the moved resource and
          gives you the option to change it;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Update references of the moved resource(s)</uicontrol> - enable this option
          to update the references to the resource you are moving, in accordance with the new
          location and name.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To quickly rename a file or a directory, <ph product="author developer editor">use the
        in-place editing either by pressing <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/F2"/> or by selecting
          <uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol> from the contextual menu of the resource. You can also
      </ph>right click a file or a directory and select the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Rename resource </uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action from its contextual menu. <ph product="author developer editor"><ph
          keyref="product"/> presents the <uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol> dialog in case you used
        in-place editing.</ph> The <uicontrol>Rename resource</uicontrol> dialog is presented if you
      used the refactoring actions. The following fields are available:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>New name</uicontrol> - presents the current name of the edited resource and
          allows you to modify it;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Update references of the renamed resource</uicontrol> - enable this option to
          update the references to the resource you are renaming;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> - specifies the <xref
          href="search-refactor-scope.dita#search-refactor-scope">scope of the rename operation</xref>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>In case the <uicontrol>Update references of the moved resource(s)</uicontrol> option is
      enabled, a <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> option which opens the
        <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> dialog is available for both actions. The
        <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> dialog presents a list with the resources that are
      updated.</p>
    <note>The support to update references is available for XML<ph
        product="developer editor developerEclipse editorEclipse">, XML Schema, XSLT, Relax NG, and
        WSDL</ph> documents.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
