<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="multiple-locations-commit">
  <title>Committing to Multiple Locations</title>
  <body>
    <p>Although Subversion does not support committing to multiple locations at once, <ph
        keyref="svnProduct"/> offers this functionality regarding <term>external</term> items.</p>
    <p>If items to be committed belong to different <term>external</term> definitions than those
      found in the working copy, they are grouped under the corresponding item that indicates their
      repository origin. Each parent item is rendered bold and its corresponding repository location
      is presented when hovering it. Parent items are decorated with a small arrow ( <image
        href="../img/SVNStatusBarShowExternals12.png" id="image_ozc_gz5_5r"/> ) if they are
        <term>external</term> definitions. The working copy root directory is never decorated and is
      not presented if there are no <term>external</term> items listed (all items belong to the main
      working copy). Each child item is presented relative to the parent item.<note type="note">When
        an <term>external</term> directory has modifications of its own, it is presented both as a
        parent item and as an item that you can select and commit. This is always the case for
          <term>external</term> files.</note></p>
    <p>The sets of items belonging to <term>external</term> definitions from the same repository are
      committed together, resulting a single revision. So, the number of revisions can be smaller
      than the number of <term>externals</term>. External definitions are considered from the same
      repository if they have the same protocol, server address, port, and repository address within
      the server.<note><term>External</term> files are always from the same repository as the parent
        directory that defines them, so they are always committed together with the changes from
        their parent directory.</note></p>
  </body>
</topic>
