<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="nvdl-search-references-and-declarations">
  <title>Searching and Refactoring Actions</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Editing NVDL Schemas<indexterm>searching and refactoring
          actions</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The following actions can be applied on <codeph>name</codeph>, <codeph>useMode</codeph>, and
        <codeph>startMode</codeph> attributes and are available from the contextual menu of the
      current editor or from the <menucascade product="developer editor">
        <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>References</uicontrol>
      </menucascade><uicontrol product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">NVDL</uicontrol> menu:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SearchReferences16.png" id="image_or2_flq_2r"/>Search
          References</uicontrol> - searches all references of the item found at current cursor
        position in the defined scope, if any. If a scope is defined, but the current edited
        resource is not part of the range of resources determined by this scope, a warning dialog is
        shown. A search scope includes the project or a collection of files and directories. You can
        choose to automatically use the defined scope for future operations by checking the
        corresponding checkbox.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Search References in...</uicontrol> - Searches all references of the item found
        at current cursor position in the file or files that you specify when define a scope in the
        dialog above.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The following actions can be applied on named <codeph>define</codeph> parameters only.</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SearchDeclarations16.png" id="image_c3l_3lq_2r"/>Search
          Declarations</uicontrol> - Searches all declarations of the item found at current cursor
        position in the defined scope, if any. If a scope is defined, but the current edited
        resource is not part of the range of resources determined by this scope, a warning dialog is
        shown. You have the possibility to define another search scope. A search scope includes the
        project or a collection of files and folders.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Search Declarations in...</uicontrol> - Searches all declarations of the item
        found at current cursor position in the file or files specified in the search scope.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Search Occurrences in File</uicontrol> - Searches all occurrences of the item
        at the caret position in the currently edited file.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/RenameXSLResource20.png" id="image_f5n_w3v_5n"/>Rename
          Component in...</uicontrol> - Allows you to rename the current component.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>