<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-editing-site">
  <title>General Settings</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit site</indexterm>
        <indexterm>General Settings page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site logo</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Logo</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Options</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page is where you can edit the logo, name, or
      description of a site configuration and it includes some other options that can be set
      according to your needs. If you are in the <xref href="ofb-sites-page.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>, you can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-Settings17.png" id="image_gmj_s5y_fjb"/>Settings</uicontrol> button at
      the bottom-right corner of a tile to open this <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page
      for that particular site configuration. If you are already inside the interface for a
      particular site configuration, you can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-BlueSettings16.png" id="image_txz_51g_gjb"/>General</uicontrol> link in
      the left menu bar to reach this page.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_hm3_s31_hjb">
        <title>General Settings Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-general-settings.png" id="image_bfr_t31_hjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes the following options and
      features:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Edit or Add a Logo</dt>
          <dd>Click anywhere in the logo circle to select an image to use for the logo for this site
            configuration. The logo will be displayed in the tile for this site configuration in the
              <xref href="ofb-sites-page.dita"><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>. The
            supported extensions are: <i>.jpg</i>, <i>.jpeg</i>, <i>.png</i>, <i>.gif</i>. The
            maximum allowed size is 2048 KB.<note>When loading large logo images, they might be
              resized and lose some image quality. This is done to reduce network data
              traffic.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Name</dt>
          <dd>You can edit the name of the site configuration. This will be displayed as the title
            in the tile for this site configuration in the <xref href="ofb-sites-page.dita"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>.<note>The site configuration name is
              unique per user. Each user cannot have more than one site configuration with the same
              name.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Description</dt>
          <dd>You can edit the description of the site configuration. This will be displayed as the
            description in the tile for this site configuration in the <xref
              href="ofb-sites-page.dita"><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="comment-moderation">
          <dt>Comments Moderation</dt>
          <dd>
            <ul id="ul_sh4_hbg_gjb">
              <li><b>All</b> - Select this option if you want all comments to require approval by an
                  <xref href="ofb-team-management.dita"><i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
                    <i>Moderator</i></xref> before they are posted. Also, each <i>Owner</i>,
                  <i>Admin</i>, and <i>Moderator</i> for the site configuration will receive an
                email when a user adds a comment notifying them that there is a comment waiting for
                approval.</li>
              <li><b>None</b> - Select this option if you want all comments to be posted without
                requiring approval.<note>If you change this option to <uicontrol>None</uicontrol> on
                  a site configuration that was previously being moderated and had rejected
                  comments, all of those rejected comments will be purged.</note></li>
            </ul>
            <note type="tip">For more information about comment moderation, see the <xref
                href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"/> topic.</note>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt id="allow-anonymous-users">Allow Anonymous Users</dt>
          <dd>Select this option if you want to allow comments to be posted anonymously without
            requiring the user to log in.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>New comment placeholder text</dt>
          <dd>By default, <ph keyref="product"/> displays <i>Add a comment</i> for the placeholder
            text that appears in empty comment boxes. You can use this option to specify your own
            custom placeholder text. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Display installation link toggle option</dt>
          <dd>By default, <ph keyref="product"/> displays an <i>Install Oxygen Feedback on your
              website</i> link at the bottom of the commenting component in the output. You can
            deselect this option to hide that link in your output. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Disable Site</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes an option to disable a site
              configuration. You must be the <xref
                href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/owner"><i>Owner</i></xref> of the
              site configuration to access this option.</p>
            <p>To disable the site configuration, click the <uicontrol>Disable</uicontrol> button
              and you will be asked to confirm the <i>Site name</i> to process the request. The
              result is that the commenting component will no longer be displayed in the websites
              defined in all versions for this site configuration. You can reverse the action by
              clicking the <uicontrol>Enable</uicontrol> button but this will only work if enabling
              the particular site configuration is allowed by the current subscription plan.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="delete-site">
          <dt>Delete Site</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes an option to delete a site
              configuration. You must be the <xref
                href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/owner"><i>Owner</i></xref> of the
              site configuration to access this option.</p>
            <p>To delete the site configuration, click the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button and
              you will be asked to confirm the <i>Site name</i> to process the request.<note
                type="warning">Using this action will delete all versions and comments for the site
                configuration and this action cannot be reversed. You may want to
                  <uicontrol>Disable</uicontrol> the site instead, since that action is
                reversible.</note></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt id="transfer-ownership">Transfer Ownership of a Site</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes an option to transfer the
              ownership of a site configuration to another user. You must be the <xref
                href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/owner"><i>Owner</i></xref> of the
              site configuration to access this option and the user you are transferring ownership
              to must have an <xref href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/admin"
                  ><i>Admin</i> role</xref>.</p>
            <p>To transfer ownership of the site configuration, click the
                <uicontrol>Transfer</uicontrol> button, enter the new owner's email address, enter
              the name of the site, and click <uicontrol>Transfer</uicontrol>. A confirmation email
              will be sent to the specified user. They will need to access the email and accept the
              transfer within 24 hours (the pending owner can also go to the <uicontrol>General
                Settings</uicontrol> page and accept the transfer from there). You can click the
                <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> button to reverse the action anytime before the user
              accepts the transfer.<note type="warning">If the site <xref
                  href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/owner"><i>Owner</i></xref>
                deletes their account before the transfer request has been accepted, the site
                ownership transfer will be canceled.</note></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
