<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-block-level-comments">
    <title>Block-Level Comments</title>
    <body>
        <p id="p_xdx_dgk_54b"><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> includes a dynamic feature that allows your
      users to add and manage comments contextually at a specific location within the output page
      where block elements appear (e.g. section, paragraph, list, or table elements) without having
      to scroll to the comments area at bottom of the page. This means that the feedback is more
      precise and it is easier to locate the exact content referenced in the comments. The
      block-level comments are also displayed in the comments area at the bottom of the page,
      aggregated along with all the comments added in that area. The block-level comments in the
      bottom area are marked with a specific status badge (<image href="../img/ofb-block-level.png"
      />). If you click that badge, the page scrolls to the context element associated with the
      block-level comment.</p>
    <p id="p_yql_cgr_5rb">For information about how commenters can add or manage block-level
      comments, see the <xref href="ofb-commenters-guide.dita">Commenter Guide: Adding a
        Comment</xref>.</p>
    <section id="section_a4p_lw5_q4b">
      <title>How Comments are Associated with Block-Level Elements</title>
      <p id="p_ydx_dgk_54b">From a technical standpoint, <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> uses a special attribute
          (<codeph>data-ofbid="topicID/elementID"</codeph>) to associate a comment with an HTML
        element. For any element that has the <codeph>data-ofbid</codeph> set, a comment widget
          (<image href="../img/ofb-widget1.png" id="image_dwm_ql5_q4b"/>) is generated on the ride
        side of the content when a user hovers over content within the block (content inside a block
        element in the source document). The user can click the comment widget to add a comment it
        that particular location within the page. Once comments exist within a block, a widget is
        displayed with the number of comments that exist within that particular block shown in a red
        circle ( <image href="../img/ofb-widget2.png" id="image_v2d_fp5_q4b"/>). Users and admins
        can click that widget to manage existing comments.</p>
      <p id="p_zdx_dgk_54b">The <codeph>data-ofbid</codeph> attribute is automatically generated in
        the output for DITA elements that have an ID attribute set in the source content. The
        automatically generated value for the <codeph>data-ofbid</codeph> attribute is stored in the
        database and <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> uses the generated value to create a mapping between the
        element in the output and the element in the source document. Therefore, it is important to
        maintain the IDs in the source documents to ensure that this mapping persists.<note
          id="note_xbd_hcv_q4b">If you do not want to add IDs to the block elements in the DITA
          source files but you still want your users have access to the block-level comments
          feature, you can set the <codeph>webhelp.enable.block.elements.id.generation</codeph>
          transformation parameter to <b>yes</b>. This results in the <codeph>data-ofbid</codeph>
          attribute being automatically generated for block elements that do not have an ID in the
          source. A potential drawback to this is that if block-level comments are added in the
          output after the <codeph>data-ofbid</codeph> attribute is generated for elements that do
          not have an ID in the source and then the output is regenerated, the mapping between the
          block-level comment and the element will be lost and the orphaned comment will be
          displayed in the commenting component at the bottom of the page with a warning symbol in
          their status badge (<image href="../img/ofb-broken-content.png"/>) to make them easily
          identifiable.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_d32_z2v_q4b">
      <title>How to Automatically Generate IDs in Oxygen XML Editor/Author</title>
      <p id="p_a2x_dgk_54b">If your source content is maintained in <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>, there are several
        convenient methods for automatically generating IDs:<ul id="ul_c3v_bfv_q4b">
          <li id="li_b2x_dgk_54b">If you right-click a map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> and select <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Generate IDs</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>, a wizard will be presented where you can select which elements will have
            an ID automatically generated (and you can specify a value pattern).</li>
          <li id="li_c2x_dgk_54b">To have IDs automatically generated for specific elements as you edit documents going
            forward, go to <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>ID Options</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>. This opens a dialog box where you can select which elements will have an
            ID automatically generated (and you can specify a value pattern). Make sure you select
            the <uicontrol>Auto generate IDs for elements</uicontrol> option for the feature to work
            automatically going forward</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_npf_pz2_w5b">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p id="p_uqk_jtv_54b">To see a visual demonstration of the block-level comments feature, watch
        our video:</p>
      <p id="p_ewl_ltv_54b"><object width="450" height="250"
          data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V0Fc7s0SHco" outputclass="iframe">
          <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
        </object></p>
    </section>
    </body>
  <related-links>
      <link href="ofb-commenters-guide.dita">
        <linktext>Information About How Commenters Can Add or Manage Block-Level Comments</linktext>
      </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>
