<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-dashboard">
  <title>Dashboard Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Dashboard page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Welcome page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The first time you log in to the administration interface, you are directed to a Welcome page
      where you can click the <uicontrol>Add your first site</uicontrol> button to <xref
        href="ofb-creating-site.dita">create your first site configuration</xref>. After you have
      created at least one site configuration, you start with the <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol>
      page on all subsequent logins. This page is especially helpful for those who integrate the
      Feedback commenting component in multiple websites. It aggregates basic information about your
      existing site configurations.<note product="feedback-enterprise">The
          <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page is slightly different for <term
          keyref="glossentry_fb_platform_admin">Feedback Platform Admin</term>. They have access to
        their own <xref href="ofbENT-admin-area.dita">special <uicontrol>Admin
          Area</uicontrol></xref> that is reached by clicking the <image
          href="../img/ofb-Admin18.png" id="image_k5w_vjp_ymb"/> button on the right side of the top
        ribbon.</note></p>
    <p product="feedback">There is a drop-down menu at the top that you can use to filter the
        <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> by all your site configurations, or sites that you are
      assigned as the <i>Owner</i>, or sites that you are assigned as an <i>Admin</i> or
        <i>Moderator</i>.</p>
    <p product="feedback"><image href="../img/Dashboard-filter.png" id="image_m3y_sbl_slb"/></p>
    <p product="feedback">The <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> contains the following panes:</p>
    <p product="feedback">
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="sites-pane">
          <dt>Sites</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> pane displays all the existing site configurations
              along with information such as the <i>Owner</i>. The site configurations with pending
              comments are listed first, and then the rest are sorted alphabetically.</p>
            <p>The following components are available in this pane to help you filter the
              information or navigate to a certain page:<ul>
                <li>If you click the <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> title in the top-left corner of
                  the pane or if you click the <uicontrol>Manage sites</uicontrol> link in the
                  top-right corner of the pane, you will be directed to the <xref
                    href="ofb-sites-page.dita"><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref> where all
                  your site configurations are displayed in a tile format.</li>
                <li>You can click the <uicontrol>Add site</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner
                  or the pane to <xref href="ofb-creating-site.dita">create a new site
                    configuration</xref>.</li>
                <li>If you click on the name of the site configuration, it will open the <xref
                    href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
                  where comments can be moderated and managed for the particular configuration.</li>
                <li>The number of <uicontrol>Pending</uicontrol> (not shown if the <xref
                    href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                      ><uicontrol>Comments Moderation</uicontrol> option is set to
                    <i>None</i></xref>), <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>, and
                    <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol> comments are displayed for each site
                  configuration. You can click the icon or number to open the <xref
                    href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
                  with the comments automatically filtered based on the status you click.<note>The
                    number of <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol>
                    comments do not include replies (only first-level comments).</note></li>
                <li>The avatar for the site <i>Owner</i> is displayed on the right side. You can
                  hover the avatar to see the name of the <i>Owner</i>.</li>
                <li>The number of community members is displayed in a blue box on the far right for
                  each site configuration. Clicking the blue box will open the <xref
                    href="ofb-community-management.dita"><uicontrol>Community</uicontrol>
                    page</xref> where you can see all the members of the site management team and
                  any other user who has posted a comment for the particular site
                  configuration.</li>
                <li>By default, five site configurations are shown, but you can click the
                    <uicontrol>Show more</uicontrol> link at the bottom of the pane to show the rest
                  of the sites.</li>
              </ul></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Activity Stream</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The <uicontrol>Activity Stream</uicontrol> displays all the activity for the site
              configurations including information about the person who made the change and details
              about each activity.</p>
            <p>Each activity box includes the name and avatar of the commenter, a link to the actual
              topic in the published output where the comment resides, the version of the site
              configuration (clicking the version opens the <xref
                href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> with
              the comments automatically filtered based on the version), and the avatar for the site
              configuration.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>My Subscription</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays information about your current subscription, including the
            expiration date and the percentage of used and estimated <term
              keyref="glossentry_fb_page_views">Page Views</term> for the current period. You can
            click the <uicontrol>Manage subscription</uicontrol> link to open the
              <uicontrol>Subscription Plans</uicontrol> page where you can see more details and make
            changes to your subscription.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Page Views</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of page views for all site configurations that you are
            assigned as the <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>. You can click the <uicontrol>Usage
              statistics</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner to open the <uicontrol>Usage
              Statistics</uicontrol> page where they can see the number of <term
              keyref="glossentry_fb_page_views">Page Views</term> and comments added for all of your
            site configurations.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Comments</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of comments added in all site configurations that you
            are assigned as the <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>. You can click the <uicontrol>Usage
              statistics</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner to open the <uicontrol>Usage
              Statistics</uicontrol> page where they can see the number of page views and comments
            added for all of your site configurations.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p product="feedback">
      <fig id="fig_okq_ght_flb">
        <title>Dashboard Page</title>
        <image href="../img/OFB-Dashboard.png" id="image_pkq_ght_flb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>