<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-profile-management">
  <title>Profile Management</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Profile</indexterm>
        <indexterm>User profile</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Change password</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Avatars</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Delete account</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Email notifications</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Notifications</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>All users have access to a profile management page where they can manage their account,
      change their password, or configure certain email notifications. To open this page, click the
      drop-down arrow to the right of your user name and select <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p><image href="../img/ofb-profile-drop-down.png" id="image_wx5_3zz_djb"/></p>
    <p>This opens the <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> page:</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_lqv_2tr_glb">
        <title>Profile Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-profile.png" id="image_mqv_2tr_glb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>This profile management page allows you to configure various aspects of your profile
      data:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Change Your Name</dt>
          <dd>To change the name associated with your profile, click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
            button in the <uicontrol>General</uicontrol> section and enter the change in the
              <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> field.<note type="restriction">You cannot change the email
              address.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Change Your Avatar</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>To change your avatar, click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button in the
                <uicontrol>General</uicontrol> section, then click the current avatar image and
              choose <uicontrol>Select Photo</uicontrol>. You can then browse for a local image to
              use for your avatar and click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to finalize your change. The
              supported extensions are: <i>.jpg</i>, <i>.jpeg</i>, <i>.png</i>, <i>.gif</i>. The
              maximum allowed size is 2048 KB.</p>
            <p>To remove the current avatar, click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button in the
                <uicontrol>General</uicontrol> section, then click the current avatar image, choose
                <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol>, and click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to finalize
              your change.<note>When loading large avatar images, they might be resized and lose
                some image quality. This is done to reduce network data traffic.</note></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Change Your Password</dt>
          <dd>To change your password, click the <uicontrol>Change password</uicontrol> button in
            the <uicontrol>Security</uicontrol> section, enter your current password, then choose a
            new password, confirm it, and click <uicontrol>Save password</uicontrol> to finalize
            your change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Delete Your Account</dt>
          <dd>To delete your account, click the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button in the
              <uicontrol>Delete Account</uicontrol> section. A confirmation dialog box will appear.
            You will need to enter your password and click <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> to confirm
            the operation. You cannot delete your account if you have the automatic renewal option
            enabled in your subscription plan.<note>Your comments (as well as all site
              configurations for <xref href="ofb-team-management.dita"><i>Administrators</i> or the
                site <i>Owner</i></xref>) will be kept for 14 days, but will not be visible. To
              recover your account within those 14 days, log in, go to your
                <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> page, and select <uicontrol>Recover</uicontrol>.
              After recovering the account, comments (and site information for <xref
                href="ofb-team-management.dita"><i>Administrators</i> or the site
                <i>Owner</i></xref>) will be visible again. If a site <i>Owner</i> deletes their
              account and does not recover the account within 14 days, the account is purged and all
              site configurations, versions, and comments associated with that account are
              purged.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="email-notifications">
          <dt>Configure Email Notifications</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>To configure certain types of email notifications you will receive, go to the
                <uicontrol>Notifications</uicontrol> tab in the <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> page.
              You can choose to not receive any email notifications by deselecting the
                <uicontrol>Send me email notifications when</uicontrol> option. Otherwise, you can
              choose whether or not to receive an email notification when the following occurs:<ul
                id="ul_nqv_2tr_glb">
                <li><b>Someone replies to one of my comments</b></li>
                <li><b>Someone adds a comment on a topic where I added a comment</b></li>
              </ul></p>
            <p>In addition, users automatically receive an <xref href="ofb-site-notifications.dita"
                >email notification when certain events are triggered by an
              Administrator</xref>.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
