<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-what-is-feedback">
  <title>What is Oxygen Feedback?</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>What is Oxygen Feedback</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><i><b>Oxygen Feedback</b></i> is a comment management platform that can be embedded in
      WebHelp Responsive output or any HTML-based website. It provides easy interaction with
      customers, whose feedback can be used to gain a better understanding of customer needs,
      continually improve products, documentation, or websites, and to make corrections in a timely
      manner. It also provides a very efficient medium for your community to ask questions and
      receive answers from you or other community members. It has a modern, stylish appearance that
      looks great on any website, it is very easy to integrate and configure, and it includes a
      user-friendly interface and numerous useful features for both Commenters and
      Administrators.</p>
    <p>It was originally intended to be an enhanced, modernized replacement for the feedback
      component in the <b>Oxygen XML WebHelp Responsive</b> online help system. WebHelp
      administrators desired greater flexibility for configuring options and moderating comments, an
      improved user-friendly interface, and a more modern design. As its development evolved, it was
      decided to also make <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> a standalone product so that not only can it be
      embedded in WebHelp Responsive pages, but also in any HTML-based webpage.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_ygd_wtc_djb">
        <title>Oxygen Feedback Comments Section</title>
        <image href="../img/FB-image1.png" id="image_qn5_15c_djb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="section_dvp_vgb_n5">
      <title>Cookies Used by Oxygen Feedback</title>
      <p><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> uses some cookies to store browser session information with the
        intention of improving your online experience. For a list of the cookies that are used, see
        the <uicontrol>Oxygen Feedback Cookies</uicontrol> section in: <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/about_cookies.html" format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
