<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-editing-site">
  <title>Editing General Settings</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit site</indexterm>
        <indexterm>General Settings</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page is where you can edit the avatar, name, or
      description of a site configuration and it includes some other settings that can be set
      according to your needs. If you are in the <xref
        href="ofb-configuring-manageming.dita#ofb-configuring-manageming/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
          ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>, you can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-Settings17.png" id="image_gmj_s5y_fjb"/>Settings</uicontrol> button at
      the bottom-right corner of a tile to open this <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page
      for that particular site configuration. If you are already inside the interface for a
      particular site configuration, you can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-BlueSettings16.png" id="image_txz_51g_gjb"/>General</uicontrol> link in
      the left menu bar to reach this page. Only <xref href="ofb-team-management.dita">users with an
          <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> role</xref> have access to this page.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes the following options and
      features:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Edit or Add a Logo</dt>
          <dd>Click anywhere in the logo circle to select an image to use for the logo for this site
            configuration. The logo will be displayed in the tile for this site configuration in the
              <xref
              href="ofb-configuring-manageming.dita#ofb-configuring-manageming/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Name</dt>
          <dd>You can edit the name of the site configuration. This will be displayed as the title
            in the tile for this site configuration in the <xref
              href="ofb-configuring-manageming.dita#ofb-configuring-manageming/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>.<note>The site configuration name is
              unique per user. Each user cannot have more than one site configuration with the same
              name.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Description</dt>
          <dd>You can edit the description of the site configuration. This will be displayed as the
            description in the tile for this site configuration in the <xref
              href="ofb-configuring-manageming.dita#ofb-configuring-manageming/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Comments Moderation</dt>
          <dd>
            <ul id="ul_sh4_hbg_gjb">
              <li><b>All</b> - Select this option if you want all comments to require approval by an
                  <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i> before they are posted. Also, each
                  <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, and <i>Moderator</i> for the site configuration will
                receive an email when a user adds a comment notifying them that there is a comment
                waiting for approval.</li>
              <li><b>None</b> - Select this option if you want all comments to be posted without
                requiring approval. Also, email notifications are not sent if this option is
                selected.</li>
            </ul>
            <note type="tip">For more information, see <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"
              />.</note>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Allow Anonymous Users</dt>
          <dd>Select this option if you want to allow comments to be posted anonymously without
            requiring the user to log in.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
