<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-site-dashboard">
  <title>Site Dashboard</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Site Dashboard</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_wvw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Site Dashboard</uicontrol> page provides a convenient
      landing page for each particular site configuration.</p>
    <p id="p_xvw_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_hm3_s31_hjb">
        <title>Site Dashboard Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-site-dashboard.png" id="image_bfr_t31_hjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_xkn_fxy_qdc">The page includes three panes:</p>
    <p id="p_y42_nsy_qdc">
      <dl id="dl_btj_nsy_qdc">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ctj_nsy_qdc">
          <dt>Site Details Pane</dt>
          <dd>This pane includes the following features and information about the particular
              site:<ul id="ul_wtw_dgk_54b">
              <li id="li_d5w_dgk_54b"><b>Community Members</b> - The number of community members for
                the site is displayed first and there is a link to navigate to the <xref
                  href="ofb-community-management.dita"><uicontrol>Community</uicontrol> page</xref>
                where you can see all the members of the site management team and any other user who
                has posted a comment for the particular site.</li>
              <li id="li_a5w_dgk_54b"><b>Comments &amp; AI Threads</b> - The number of
                  <uicontrol>Pending</uicontrol> (not shown if the <xref
                  href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                    ><uicontrol>Comments Moderation</uicontrol> option is set to
                <i>None</i></xref>), <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol>,
                and <uicontrol>Reopened</uicontrol> comments that were posted by users are displayed
                for the site. You can click the icon or number to open the <xref
                  href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
                with the comments automatically filtered based on the status you click. Next, the
                number of AI threads that have been initiated by users are displayed for the site.
                You can click on the number to navigate to the <xref href="ofb-ai-threads.dita">AI
                  Threads page</xref> where you can view and filter messages that users have sent to
                the AI Assistant on the particular site.</li>
              <li id="li_wbh_tty_qdc"><b>Page Views</b> - The number of page views is shown for the
                site. You can click the number (or the <uicontrol>Page views</uicontrol> title) to
                open the <xref href="ofb-statistics.dita"><uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol>
                  page</xref> where you can see the number of <term
                  keyref="glossentry_fb_page_views">Page Views</term> and comments added for the
                site.</li>
              <li id="li_imj_r5y_qdc"><b>Page Ratings</b> - The number of negative and positive
                ratings that were posted by users are displayed for the site. You can click the
                numbers (or the <uicontrol>Page ratings</uicontrol> title) to open the <xref
                  href="ofb-page-ratings.dita"><uicontrol>Page Ratings</uicontrol> statistics
                  page</xref> where you can see the pages that have received an <term>up vote</term>
                or <term>down vote</term> for the particular site.</li>
              <li id="li_hhx_gvy_qdc"><b>AI Assistant</b> - The number of <xref
                  href="ofb-ai-threads.dita">AI Assistant Threads</xref> that were initiated by
                users is displayed first, followed by the number of users who initiated a session
                with the <xref href="ofb-ai-assistant.dita">AI Assistant chatbot</xref>, and then
                the number of <xref href="ofb-ai-search-summary.dita">AI Assistant Search
                  Summaries</xref> that were initiated by users. You can click any of the numbers
                (or the <uicontrol>AI Assistant</uicontrol> title) to open the <xref
                  href="ofb-statistics.dita"><uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page</xref>
                where you can view and filter statistical data regarding the AI threads, users, and
                search summaries for the site.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_mzn_bwy_qdc">
          <dt>Versions Pane</dt>
          <dd>This pane contains details about the versions configured for the site, including
            information about whether or not the particular version has content indexing, semantic
            search, AI Assistant, and AI-enhanced search summary enabled and whether or not the
            version has been installed. You can click the <uicontrol>Manage versions</uicontrol>
            link to navigate to the <xref href="ofb-version-management.dita"><uicontrol>Versions
                Settings</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can add or edit versions for the site.
            You can click <uicontrol>Add version</uicontrol> to navigate to the <xref
              href="ofb-site-initial-version.dita">initial version configuration page</xref> where
            you can add a version to the site.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ddc_swy_qdc">
          <dt>Activity Stream Pane</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the activity for the particular site, including information about
            the person who made the change and details about each activity. Topic titles are
            displayed as links that navigate to the particular output page. You can click on the
            version badge to the far right to open the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"
                ><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can manage the comments added
            by users for that version.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
