<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-semantic-search">
    <title>Semantic Search</title>
    <body>
        <p>The <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> search engine offers the possibility of using semantic search
      when searching the WebHelp Responsive output.<note id="note_a1h_5vp_dzb" type="note">The
        default search engine that comes embedded in the WebHelp Responsive output does not support
        semantic searches. </note></p>
    <p>A semantic search is an advanced search technique that aims to improve the accuracy and
      relevance of search results by understanding the context and meaning behind the search query,
      rather than relying solely on keyword matching. It goes beyond traditional keyword-based
      search, which primarily relies on matching the exact words or phrases in a query to the
      content of documents. </p>
    <p>In a semantic search, the search engine uses natural language processing (NLP) and machine
      learning techniques to analyze the intent and context of a search query.</p>
    <note type="attention">When using advanced Lucene syntax in the search text field (in the
      WebHelp Responsive output), the semantic search is disabled because the Lucene syntax shifts
      the focus to matching the search terms, while the semantic search finds text with similar
      meaning and is not appropriate for term matching.</note>
    <section id="section_cjj_wwp_dzb">
      <title>Enabling Semantic Search</title>
      <p>The semantic search functionality is not enabled by default. To enable semantic search:<ol
          id="ol_cgt_fxp_dzb">
          <li>In the administration interface of <ph keyref="product"/>, go to the <xref
              href="ofb-version-management.dita"><uicontrol>Version Settings</uicontrol> page</xref>
            for the particular version where you want semantic search enabled.</li>
          <li>Scroll to the <uicontrol>Content Indexing and Search</uicontrol> section and click
              <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> to expand the section.</li>
          <li>Select the <uicontrol>Enable content indexing</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Enable
              semantic search</uicontrol> options.<note id="note_svy_byp_dzb">The semantic search
              functionality requires that you configure <ph keyref="product"/> to <xref
                href="ofb-configuring-openai-connection.dita">connect to <tm tmtype="tm">OpenAI</tm>
                on your behalf</xref>.</note></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</li>
        </ol></p>
      <p>After editing the <uicontrol>Content Indexing and Search</uicontrol> section and enabling
        the semantic search functionality, a re-indexing operation is automatically triggered. </p>
    </section>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_f44_mhv_dzb">
        <title>Enable semantic search option</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-enable-semantic-search.png" id="image_hcm_nhv_dzb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="resources">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p id="p_agf_xh1_hzb">Video - <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/semantic_search_queries_in_webhelp.html"
          format="html" scope="external"><b>Semantic Search Queries in Oxygen WebHelp Responsive
            Output Powered by Oxygen Feedback</b></xref></p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
