<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-page-ratings">
  <title>Page Ratings Statistics</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Page ratings statistics</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Statistics</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Page ratings page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_hxw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Page Ratings</uicontrol> statistics page is where you can
      see the top 100 pages that have received an <term>up vote</term> or <term>down vote</term> for
      a site configuration, if the <xref
        href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/dlentry_wgt_vdn_btb"><uicontrol>Allow page
          ratings</uicontrol> option</xref> is enabled in the <uicontrol>General
        Settings</uicontrol> page. You can also see the messages that were submitted by your
      community if the <xref href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/dlentry_dzr_hlx_qwb"
          ><uicontrol>Display survey for negative ratings</uicontrol> option</xref> is enabled.</p>
    <p id="p_dsp_bz2_5wb">Users with a role of <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> have access to this
      statistics page. To reach this page, click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-PageRatings16.png" id="image_txz_51g_gjb"/>Page Ratings</uicontrol> link
      in the left menu bar in the interface for the site configuration.</p>
    <p id="p_ixw_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_hm3_s31_hjb">
        <title>Page Ratings Statistics Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-page-ratings-page.png" id="image_bfr_t31_hjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_jxw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Page Ratings</uicontrol> statistics page displays your
      output pages with the most up votes and down votes for the current site configuration. It
      includes a filter at the top to choose which versions to have their page ratings statistics
      displayed. Below the version filter, there are two tabs, one for the negative option and one
      for the positive option. The first tab contains a table with the top 100 pages that received
      down votes and the second tab contains a table with the top 100 pages that received up
      votes.</p>
    <p id="p_syw_jz2_5wb">The table that is displayed in this page contains information about the
      specific output page that received a rating vote, the version of the site configuration, the
      number of down and up votes the page received, and the number of messages submitted in a page
      ratings survey. You can click on any of the columns in the table to short that particular
      column. You can click the link in the <uicontrol>Page</uicontrol> column to open the output
      page. The <uicontrol>Feedback messages</uicontrol> column also includes a link to display the
      content of any messages submitted in a page ratings survey for that particular page.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
