<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-dashboard">
  <title>Dashboard Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Dashboard page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Welcome page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_ntw_dgk_54b">When you log in to the administration interface, you are directed to the
        <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page<ph product="feedback"> (if it is your first time
        logging in, a dialog box is displayed with information about your subscription)</ph>. This
      page is especially helpful for those who integrate the Feedback commenting component in
      multiple websites. It aggregates basic information about all of your existing site
        configurations.<note product="feedback-enterprise" id="note_otw_dgk_54b">The
          <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page is slightly different for the <term
          keyref="glossentry_fb_platform_admin">Feedback Platform Admin</term>. They have access to
        their own <xref href="ofbENT-admin-area.dita">special <uicontrol>Admin
          Interface</uicontrol></xref> that is reached by clicking the <image
          href="../img/ofb-Admin18.png" id="image_k5w_vjp_ymb"/> button on the right side of the top
        ribbon.</note></p>
    <p id="p_rtw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> contains the following panes
      (depending on your user role):</p>
    <p id="p_stw_dgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_ttw_dgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_dbb_4py_prb">
          <dt>Get Started</dt>
          <dd>The <uicontrol>Get Started</uicontrol> pane includes buttons that trigger actions for
            the most popular tasks, particularly for users who are getting started. Once a task is
            complete, it is marked as done (with blue outlines). The actions available are:<ul
              id="ul_g1f_yqy_prb">
              <li id="li_h1f_yqy_prb"><uicontrol>Setup organization profile</uicontrol> - This
                action opens the <xref href="ofb-organization-profile-page.dita"
                    ><uicontrol>Organization Profile</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can manage
                information about your organization.</li>
              <li id="li_f22_fry_prb"><uicontrol>Invite members</uicontrol> - This action opens the
                  <xref href="ofb-members-page.dita"><uicontrol>Members</uicontrol> page</xref>
                where you can view all the members attached to the organization, invite new members,
                and associate user roles.</li>
              <li id="li_fkd_nry_prb"><uicontrol>Create first site</uicontrol> - This action
                initiates the process of creating a new site configuration.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="sites-pane">
          <dt>Sites</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_utw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> pane displays all the existing
              site configurations along with information such as the number of pending, open, or
              resolved comments, the <i>Owner</i> of the site configuration, and the number of
              members. The site configurations with pending comments are listed first, and then the
              rest are sorted alphabetically. For users with a role of <b>organization</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>, it displays all the activity for all
              the site configurations attached to the organization. For users with a role of
              organization <i>Member</i>, it displays activity for site configurations that the user
              is assigned as <b>site</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>.</p>
            <p id="p_vtw_dgk_54b">The following components are available in this pane to help you
              filter the information or navigate to a certain page:<ul id="ul_wtw_dgk_54b">
                <li id="li_xtw_dgk_54b">If you click the <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> title in the
                  top-left corner of the pane or if you click the <uicontrol>Manage
                    sites</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner of the pane, you will be directed
                  to the <xref href="ofb-sites-page.dita"><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>
                  where all your site configurations are displayed in a tile format.</li>
                <li id="li_ytw_dgk_54b">You can click the <uicontrol>Add site</uicontrol> link in
                  the top-right corner or the pane to <xref href="ofb-creating-site.dita">create a
                    new site configuration</xref>.</li>
                <li id="li_ztw_dgk_54b">If you click on the name of the site configuration, it will
                  open the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol>
                    page</xref> where comments can be moderated and managed for the particular
                  configuration.</li>
                <li id="li_a5w_dgk_54b">The number of <uicontrol>Pending</uicontrol> (not shown if
                  the <xref href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                      ><uicontrol>Comments Moderation</uicontrol> option is set to
                    <i>None</i></xref>), <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>,
                    <uicontrol>Reopened</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol> comments
                  are displayed for each site configuration. You can click the icon or number to
                  open the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol>
                    page</xref> with the comments automatically filtered based on the status you
                    click.<note id="note_b5w_dgk_54b">The number of <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>,
                      <uicontrol>Reopened</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol> comments
                    do not include replies (only first-level comments).</note></li>
                <li id="li_d5w_dgk_54b">The number of community members is displayed in a blue box
                  on the far right for each site configuration. Clicking the blue box will open the
                    <xref href="ofb-community-management.dita"><uicontrol>Community</uicontrol>
                    page</xref> where you can see all the members of the site management team and
                  any other user who has posted a comment for the particular site
                  configuration.</li>
                <li id="li_e5w_dgk_54b">By default, five site configurations are shown, but you can
                  click the <uicontrol>Show more</uicontrol> link at the bottom of the pane to show
                  the rest of the sites.</li>
              </ul></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_f5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>Activity Stream</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_g5w_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Activity Stream</uicontrol> displays all the
              activity for site configurations, including information about the person who made the
              change and details about each activity. For users with a role of <b>organization</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>, it displays all the activity for all
              the site configurations attached to the organization. For users with a role of
              organization <i>Member</i>, it displays activity for site configurations that the user
              is assigned as <b>site</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>.</p>
            <p id="p_h5w_dgk_54b">Each activity box includes the name and avatar of the commenter, a
              link to the actual topic in the published output where the comment resides, the
              version of the site configuration (clicking the version opens the <xref
                href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> with
              the comments automatically filtered based on the version), and the avatar for the site
              configuration.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_i5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>My Subscription</dt>
          <dd>This pane is available for users with a role of organization <i>Owner</i> or
              <i>Billing Manager</i>. It displays information about your current subscription,
            including the expiration date and the percentage of used and estimated <term
              keyref="glossentry_fb_page_views">Page Views</term> for the current period. You can
            click the <uicontrol>Manage subscription</uicontrol> link to open the
              <uicontrol>Subscription Plans</uicontrol> page where you can see more details and make
            changes to your subscription.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_j5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>Page Views</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of page views for all the organization's site
            configurations that you are assigned as the organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.
            You can click the <uicontrol>Usage statistics</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner
            to open the <uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page where they can see the number
            of <term keyref="glossentry_fb_page_views">Page Views</term> and comments added for all
            of your site configurations.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_k5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>Comments</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of comments added in all the organization's site
            configurations that you are assigned as the organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.
            You can click the <uicontrol>Usage statistics</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner
            to open the <uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page where they can see the number
            of page views and comments added for all of your site configurations.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>