<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-editing-site">
  <title>General Settings</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit site</indexterm>
        <indexterm>General Settings page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site logo</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Logo</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Options</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page is where you can edit the logo, name, or
      description of a site configuration and it includes some other options that can be set
      according to your needs. If you are in the <xref
        href="ofb-configuring-managing.dita#ofb-configuring-managing/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
          ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>, you can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-Settings17.png" id="image_gmj_s5y_fjb"/>Settings</uicontrol> button at
      the bottom-right corner of a tile to open this <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page
      for that particular site configuration. If you are already inside the interface for a
      particular site configuration, you can click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-BlueSettings16.png" id="image_txz_51g_gjb"/>General</uicontrol> link in
      the left menu bar to reach this page.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_hm3_s31_hjb">
        <title>General Settings Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-general-settings.png" id="image_bfr_t31_hjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes the following options and
      features:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Edit or Add a Logo</dt>
          <dd>Click anywhere in the logo circle to select an image to use for the logo for this site
            configuration. The logo will be displayed in the tile for this site configuration in the
              <xref
              href="ofb-configuring-managing.dita#ofb-configuring-managing/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>. The supported extension are: <i>.jpg</i>,
              <i>.jpeg</i>, <i>.png</i>, <i>.gif</i>. The maximum allowed size is 2048 KB.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Name</dt>
          <dd>You can edit the name of the site configuration. This will be displayed as the title
            in the tile for this site configuration in the <xref
              href="ofb-configuring-managing.dita#ofb-configuring-managing/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>.<note>The site configuration name is
              unique per user. Each user cannot have more than one site configuration with the same
              name.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Description</dt>
          <dd>You can edit the description of the site configuration. This will be displayed as the
            description in the tile for this site configuration in the <xref
              href="ofb-configuring-managing.dita#ofb-configuring-managing/section_abb_hzp_1jb"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="comment-moderation">
          <dt>Comments Moderation</dt>
          <dd>
            <ul id="ul_sh4_hbg_gjb">
              <li><b>All</b> - Select this option if you want all comments to require approval by an
                  <xref href="ofb-team-management.dita"><i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
                    <i>Moderator</i></xref> before they are posted. Also, each <i>Owner</i>,
                  <i>Admin</i>, and <i>Moderator</i> for the site configuration will receive an
                email when a user adds a comment notifying them that there is a comment waiting for
                approval.</li>
              <li><b>None</b> - Select this option if you want all comments to be posted without
                requiring approval.</li>
            </ul>
            <note type="tip">For more information, see <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"
              />.</note>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt id="allow-anonymous-users">Allow Anonymous Users</dt>
          <dd>Select this option if you want to allow comments to be posted anonymously without
            requiring the user to log in.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="delete-site">
          <dt>Delete Site</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes an option to delete a site
              configuration. You must be the <xref
                href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/owner"><i>Owner</i></xref> of the
              site configuration to access this option.</p>
            <p>To delete the site configuration, click the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button and
              you will be asked to confirm the deletion (if you are logged in with an email and
              password rather than with social media credentials, you will also be asked to enter
              your password to proceed).<note type="warning">Using this action will delete all
                versions and comments for the site configuration and this action cannot be
                reversed.</note></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt id="transfer-ownership">Transfer Ownership of a Site</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>The <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page includes an option to transfer the
              ownership of a site configuration to another user. You must be the <xref
                href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/owner"><i>Owner</i></xref> of the
              site configuration to access this option and the user you are transferring ownership
              to must have an <xref href="ofb-team-management.dita#ofb-team-management/admin"
                  ><i>Admin</i> role</xref>.</p>
            <p>To transfer ownership of the site configuration, click the
                <uicontrol>Transfer</uicontrol> button, enter the new owner's email address, enter
              YOUR password, and click <uicontrol>Transfer</uicontrol>. A confirmation email will be
              sent to the specified user. They will need to access the email and accept the transfer
              within 24 hours (the pending owner can also go to the <uicontrol>General
                Settings</uicontrol> page and accept the transfer from there). You can click the
                <uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> button to reverse the action anytime before the user
              accepts the transfer.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
