<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-usage-statistics">
  <title>Usage Statistics Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Usage statistics</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_kdx_dgk_54b">Users with a role of organization <term>Owner</term> or <i>Admin</i> have
      access to a <uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page where they can see various statistics
      for all of the site configurations attached to the current organization.</p>
    <p id="p_glt_qkt_5rb">The top chart displays statistics in a graph form according to the
      selected metric and filtering options.</p>
    <p id="p_ndx_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_fs3_dsr_glb">
        <title>Usage Statistics Page - Graphical Chart</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-usage-statistics-page.png" id="image_gs3_dsr_glb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_odx_dgk_54b">You can click the up or down arrow to the right of the title for each
      column header to sort that particular column. If you click the name of the site configuration,
      you will be directed to that particular site configuration. By default, the table is sorted in
      the descending order of the number of page views from the last column of the table (last month
      or last day of the selected period). You can click the arrow to the left of the site
      configuration name in the first column to expand the particular site configuration to show its
      configured versions. By default, the versions are sorted chronologically in this table.</p>
    <p id="p_pdx_dgk_54b"> At the top of the usage statistics page, there are some filtering options
      for the graphs:</p>
    <p id="p_qdx_dgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_rdx_dgk_54b">
        <dlentry conkeyref="reusables-feedback/metrics" id="dlentry_nxw_dgk_54b">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="sites">
          <dt>Sites</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_sdx_dgk_54b">You can choose which site configurations to have their statistics
              displayed.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry conkeyref="reusables-feedback/date-chooser" id="dlentry_pxw_dgk_54b">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry conkeyref="reusables-feedback/aggregate-chooser" id="dlentry_qxw_dgk_54b">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry conkeyref="reusables-feedback/chart-type-chooser" id="dlentry_rxw_dgk_54b">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p id="p_k4c_khq_4bc">The second chart displays the same statistics but in numerical format.</p>
    <p id="p_nmp_5kt_5rb">
      <fig id="fig_omp_5kt_5rb">
        <title>Usage Statistics Page - Numerical Chart</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-usage-statistics-bottom.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_m1r_ngq_4bc">The <uicontrol>AI Assistant Threads</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>AI
        Assistant Search Summaries</uicontrol> metrics also include a table with additional
      statistics below the numerical chart. The additional statistics shown are as follows:<ul
        id="ul_oq5_53v_3dc">
        <li id="li_sq5_53v_3dc"><uicontrol>AI Assistant Threads</uicontrol> - The table includes
          columns that show the site name, number of AI Assistant threads, the average number of
          replies generated by the AI, the average number of user replies, the number of AI threads
          that encountered an error, the estimated number of tokens consumed across all AI threads,
          and the average number of tokens consumed by the AI Assistant per thread.</li>
        <li id="li_tq5_53v_3dc"><uicontrol>AI Assistant Search Summaries</uicontrol> - The table
          includes columns that show the site name, the total number of AI search summaries
          generated, the number of successful responses, the number of search summaries where the
          continue in chat feature was used, and the estimated number of tokens consumed by AI
          search summaries.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p id="p_q3h_v3v_3dc">
      <note id="note_rbv_jgv_3dc" type="tip">For the <uicontrol>AI Assistant Threads</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>AI Assistant Search Summaries</uicontrol> metrics, the table includes a column
        that shows the average number of tokens consumed by the AI Assistant per thread/summary. </note>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
