<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-configuring-managing">
  <title>Administration Interface</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>What is a site</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Administration interface</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sites page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site configuration</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Dashboard</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> features a user-friendly <i>administration interface</i> where you can
      moderate comments, manage users, view statistics, and configure various settings,
      notifications, and other components of the comment system. This administration interface is
      reached by logging in to your Feedback account in the <i>administration login page</i> (<xref
        href="https://feedback.oxygenxml.com/login" format="html" scope="external"/>).<note
        type="tip">You can also reach the <i>administration interface</i> from the comments area in
        any web page where it is installed by logging in and selecting <uicontrol>Home</uicontrol>
        from the drop-down menu to the right of your name.</note></p>
    <p>All the various pages within the <i>administration interface</i> have a common ribbon at the
      top with some actions to help you navigate through the interface.</p>
    <p><image href="../img/ofb-stripe.png" id="image_bqp_yst_flb"/></p>
    <p>The components in that ribbon include:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Feedback24.png" id="image_zfr_jtt_flb"/>Oxygen
              Feedback</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Feedback24.png" id="image_jkb_jtt_flb"
              />Oxygen Feedback</uicontrol> logo at the left side of the ribbon will navigate to the
              <xref href="#ofb-configuring-managing/section_mkq_ght_flb" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> action will navigate to the <xref
              href="#ofb-configuring-managing/section_mkq_ght_flb" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> drop-down menu</dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> drop-down menu displays a list of your site
            configurations, making it easy to navigate to a particular configuration from anywhere
            in the interface. It shows the 5 most recent sites, followed by 5 sites with pending
            comments, and there is a <uicontrol>View All Sites</uicontrol> action at the bottom of
            the list to see the rest of the site configurations. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Help20.png" id="image_j3h_j5t_flb"
            />Help</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> icon displays a menu where you can choose to
            open the <uicontrol>User Guide</uicontrol> or you can choose
              <uicontrol>About</uicontrol> to see information about the current version for the
            application. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>User drop-down menu</dt>
          <dd>Clicking this drop-down menu provides access to the <xref
              href="ofb-profile-management.dita">profile management page</xref>, <xref
              href="ofb-subscription.dita">subscription plans page</xref>, <xref
              href="ofb-usage-statistics.dita">usage statistics page</xref>, and <uicontrol>Log
              out</uicontrol> action.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <section id="section_mkq_ght_flb">
      <title>Dashboard </title>
      <p>When you log in to the administration interface, you start with the
          <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page. This page is especially helpful for those who want
        to integrate the Feedback commenting component in multiple websites. It aggregates basic
        information about all the existing site configurations that has the current user assigned as
          <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>.</p>
      <p>This page is divided into two panes. The left pane (<uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol>) displays
        all the existing site configurations along with information such as the <i>Owner</i>. The
        site configurations with pending comments are listed first, and then the rest are sorted
        alphabetically. The right pane (<uicontrol>Activity Stream</uicontrol>) displays all the
        activity for the site configurations including information about the person who made the
        change and details about each activity. There are also several components in each pane that
        help you to filter the information or navigate to a certain page:<ul id="ul_efz_dzt_flb">
          <li>Both panes have a filter drop-down menu at the top-right corner. If you do not want to
            see the information for all site configurations, you can choose to filter it by the site
            configurations that you are assigned as the <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
              <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
          <li>In the left pane, there is a widget to the right of the filter drop-down menu.
            Clicking this widget opens the <xref
              href="#ofb-configuring-managing/section_abb_hzp_1jb" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref> where all the site configurations are
            displayed in a tile format.</li>
          <li>In the left pane, if you click on the name of the site configuration, it will open the
              <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
            where comments can be moderated and managed for the particular configuration.</li>
          <li>In the left pane, if you hover over the colored bar to the right of the site
            configuration name, it will display the number of comments for that site by status
            type.</li>
          <li>In the left pane, you can see the number of community members for each site
            configuration to the right of the colored bar. If you click this number, it will open
            the <xref href="ofb-community-management.dita"><uicontrol>Community</uicontrol>
              management page</xref> where you can see all the management team members for the site
            configuration as well as all the user who have posted a comment on the website where the
            commenting system is installed.</li>
          <li>In the right pane, if you click on the name of the page (or the navigation widget
              <image href="../img/ofb-nav-widget.png" id="image_s4q_nc5_flb"/> to the far right
            side), it will open the particular webpage where the comment exists.</li>
          <li>In the right pane, if you click on the name of the site configuration (or the version
            number), it will open the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"
                ><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> where comments can be moderated and
            managed for the particular configuration.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_okq_ght_flb">
          <title>Dashboard Page</title>
          <?oxy_comment_start author="Steven" timestamp="20200402T120529-0400" comment="I&apos;ll need to update this once the Dashboard is complete."?>
          <image href="../img/OFB-Dashboard.png" id="image_pkq_ght_flb"/><?oxy_comment_end?>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>
        <note type="tip">No matter what page you are on within the administration interface,
          clicking on the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Feedback24.png" id="image_qkq_ght_flb"
            />Oxygen Feedback</uicontrol> logo at the top-left corner will navigate back to the main
            <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page.</note>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_abb_hzp_1jb">
      <title>Sites Page </title>
      <p>If you click the widget (<image href="../img/ofb-nav-widget.png" id="image_i2f_425_flb"/>)
        to the right of the filter drop-down menu in the left pane of the
          <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page, it opens the <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page.
        This page displays each site configurations as a tile. Each tile displays the logo, name,
        and description for the particular site configuration. The avatar for the site <i>Owner</i>
        is displayed at the top-right corner of each tile (you can hover over the avatar to see
        their name). Also, if the site configuration has the <xref
          href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"><uicontrol>Comment
            Moderation</uicontrol> option enabled</xref>, the number of pending comments are
        displayed if users have posted comments that have not yet been moderated. The tiles for site
        configurations with pending comments are listed first, and then the rest of the tiles are
        sorted alphabetically.</p>
      <p>You can click anywhere in the center box of a tile to open the <xref
          href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> for that
        particular configuration. This page is used to moderate and manage comments. You can click
        the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ofb-Settings17.png" id="image_gmj_s5y_fjb"
          />Settings</uicontrol> button at the bottom-right corner of a tile to open the
          <uicontrol>General Settings</uicontrol> page for that particular configuration. This page
        is where you can edit the logo, name, or description of a site configuration and it includes
        some other options that can be set according to your needs.</p>
      <p>This page also includes the <uicontrol>Add site</uicontrol> button at the top-right corner.
        You can click this button to <xref href="ofb-creating-site.dita">create a site
          configuration</xref>. If you have a lot of site configurations, you can use the
          <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> bar to filter the tiles. The filter component looks for the
        entered search terms in the name and description of the site configurations.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_hbx_pby_fjb">
          <title>Sites Page</title>
          <image href="../img/ofb-sites-page.png" id="image_jms_rby_fjb"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
