<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-dashboard">
  <title>Dashboard Page</title>
  <body>
    <p>When you log in to the administration interface, you start with the
        <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page. This page is especially helpful for those who want to
      integrate the Feedback commenting component in multiple websites. It aggregates basic
      information about all the existing site configurations that has the current user assigned as
        <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>.</p>
    <p>This page is divided into two panes. The left pane (<uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol>) displays
      all the existing site configurations along with information such as the <i>Owner</i>. The site
      configurations with pending comments are listed first, and then the rest are sorted
      alphabetically. The right pane (<uicontrol>Activity Stream</uicontrol>) displays all the
      activity for the site configurations including information about the person who made the
      change and details about each activity. There are also several components in each pane that
      help you to filter the information or navigate to a certain page:<ul id="ul_efz_dzt_flb">
        <li>Both panes have a filter drop-down menu at the top-right corner. If you do not want to
          see the information for all site configurations, you can choose to filter it by the site
          configurations that you are assigned as the <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
            <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
        <li>In the left pane, there is a widget to the right of the filter drop-down menu. Clicking
          this widget opens the <xref href="ofb-sites-page.dita"><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol>
            page</xref> where all the site configurations are displayed in a tile format.</li>
        <li>In the left pane, if you click on the name of the site configuration, it will open the
            <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
          where comments can be moderated and managed for the particular configuration.</li>
        <li>In the left pane, if you hover over the colored bar to the right of the site
          configuration name, it will display the number of comments for that site by status
          type.</li>
        <li>In the left pane, you can see the number of community members for each site
          configuration to the right of the colored bar. If you click this number, it will open the
            <xref href="ofb-community-management.dita"><uicontrol>Community</uicontrol> management
            page</xref> where you can see all the management team members for the site configuration
          as well as all the user who have posted a comment on the website where the commenting
          system is installed.</li>
        <li>In the right pane, if you click on the name of the page (or the navigation widget <image
            href="../img/ofb-nav-widget.png" id="image_s4q_nc5_flb"/> to the far right side), it
          will open the particular webpage where the comment exists.</li>
        <li>In the right pane, if you click on the name of the site configuration (or the version
          number), it will open the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"
              ><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> where comments can be moderated and
          managed for the particular configuration.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_okq_ght_flb">
        <title>Dashboard Page</title>
        <?oxy_comment_start author="Steven" timestamp="20200402T120529-0400" comment="I&apos;ll need to update this once the Dashboard is complete."?>
        <image href="../img/OFB-Dashboard.png" id="image_pkq_ght_flb"/><?oxy_comment_end?>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <note type="tip">No matter what page you are on within the administration interface, clicking
        on the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Feedback24.png" id="image_qkq_ght_flb"/>Oxygen
          Feedback</uicontrol> logo at the top-left corner will navigate back to the main
          <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page.</note>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>