<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-community-management">
  <title>Site Community Management</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Community users</indexterm>
        <indexterm>User roles</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Community</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Community page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>User management</indexterm>
      </keywords>
      <keywords>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Site Configuration</keyword>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Admin Interface</keyword>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_vww_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Community</uicontrol> page (accessible after selecting a
      site configuration from the <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page) is where users with a role of
        <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i> can see the members of the site management
      team (for the particular site configuration) and any other user who has posted a comment on
      the website where the Feedback system is installed for the particular site configuration. To
      reach this page, click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ofb-Community16.png"
          id="image_txz_51g_gjb"/>Community</uicontrol> link in the left menu bar in the interface
      for the site configuration.</p>
    <p id="p_www_dgk_54b">Users with a role of site <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> for the site
      configuration can change user roles from this page.</p>
    <note id="note_xxg_qjz_prb">Users cannot have a site role that is lower than their organization
      role. For example a user with an <b>organization</b> role of <i>Admin</i> cannot be assigned a
        <b>site</b> role of <i>Moderator</i>. An <b>organization</b>
      <i>Owner</i> is also indirectly considered to have a role of <b>site</b>
      <i>Owner</i> and users with a role of <b>organization</b>
      <i>Admin</i> or <i>Moderator</i> are also assigned as <b>site</b>
      <i>Admin</i>/<i>Moderator</i>.</note>
    <p id="p_u3n_4jz_prb">The possible <b>site</b> user roles are:<ul id="ul_jh2_q1m_gjb">
        <li id="li_xww_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_owner"/></b> (This role is
          automatically assigned when the site configuration is created) - This type of user has
          rights to moderate comment posts (edit, approve, reject, or delete), configure site
          settings, versions, team members, and user roles, as well as rights to delete or transfer
          the ownership of the site configuration. An <b>organization</b>
          <i>Owner</i> is also indirectly considered to have a role of <b>site</b>
          <i>Owner</i></li>
        <li id="li_yww_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_admin"/></b> - This type of user has
          rights to moderate comment posts (edit, approve, reject, or delete) and to configure site
          settings, versions, team members, and user roles. An <b>organization</b>
          <i>Admin</i> is also assigned as <b>site</b>
          <i>Admin</i>.</li>
        <li id="li_zww_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_moderator"/></b> - This type of user
          has rights to moderate comment posts (edit, approve, reject, or delete). An
            <b>organization</b>
          <i>Moderator</i> is also assigned as <b>site</b>
          <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
        <li id="li_axw_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_trusted"/></b> - Comments posted by
          this type of user are automatically approved (this includes existing and future comments).
          Users with a <i>Trusted</i> role at <b>organization</b> level are also assigned as
            <i>Trusted</i> at <b>site</b> level.</li>
        <li id="li_bxw_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_member"/></b> - This type of user has
          rights to post new comments. If the site is moderated, comments posted by this type of
          user require approval by a user with a role of <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
            <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
        <li id="li_cxw_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_banned"/></b> - This type of user
          cannot post comments and all existing pending comments added by this user are
          automatically rejected. Users with a <i>Banned</i> role at <b>organization</b> level are
          also assigned as <i>Banned</i> at <b>site</b> level.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note conkeyref="reusables-feedback/note_matrix" id="note_yrk_2px_5rb"/>
    <p id="p_gxw_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_hm3_s31_hjb">
        <title>Community Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-community-page.png" id="image_bfr_t31_hjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_dxw_dgk_54b">To filter the list or search for a particular user, start typing a name or email address in
      the text field at the top of the page. You can also filter the list by user role by using the
      drop-down menu to the right of the text field.</p>
    <p id="p_exw_dgk_54b">To change the role of any existing user, select the new role from the
      drop-down menu to the right of their user name. A confirmation email will be sent to that user
      informing them that their user role has changed. You can use the controls at the bottom to
      navigate between pages and specify how many rows are displayed per page.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
