<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE troubleshooting PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Troubleshooting//EN" "troubleshooting.dtd">
<troubleshooting id="ofb-troubleshooting-comments-gone">
  <title>Comments No Longer Appear in the Output</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Comments gone</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Comments disappeared</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <troublebody><condition id="problem">
      <title>Problem</title>
      <p id="p_a2k_dgk_54b">User comments that previously appeared in my output are now missing.</p>
    </condition><troubleSolution>
      <cause id="cause">
        <title>Possible Cause</title>
        <p id="p_b2k_dgk_54b">This could happen if you change the site/version configuration after
          the comment was posted because the association between the page and the previously posted
          comment would be lost. That association is directly dependent upon the <xref
            href="ofb-version-management.dita#ofb-version-management/dlentry_wdy_34x_5wb"><b>Base
              URL</b> configured for the associated version</xref>. When a comment is posted, the
            <b>Base URL</b> is used to obtain a relative path from the page URL and the comment is
          associated with that relative path. Therefore, if you change the <b>Base URL</b> after a
          comment is posted, the relative path of the page computed for the new <b>Base URL</b> and
          the relative path associated with the comment in the database will not match. This results
          in the comment no longer being displayed on that page.</p>
        <p id="p_jdz_wgn_2pb">For example:<ul id="ul_kxz_xgn_2pb">
            <li id="li_lxz_xgn_2pb">Suppose the original <b>Base URL</b> for a particular version of
              a site configuration
              is:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">https://example.com/docs/myProduct/</codeblock></li>
            <li id="li_kc4_2hn_2pb">A user posts a comment on a page with this
              URL:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">https://example.com/docs/myProduct/v1.0/installation/configure-db.html</codeblock></li>
            <li id="li_pbf_jhn_2pb"><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> will associate the user's comment to the
              relative path
              of:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">v1.0/installation/configure-db.html</codeblock></li>
            <li id="li_zk2_nhn_2pb">Suppose a site admin changes the <b>Base URL</b>
              to:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">https://example.com/docs/myProduct/v1.0/</codeblock></li>
            <li id="li_ksq_yhn_2pb">When a user navigates to that page, <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>
              determines that the relative path
              is:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">installation/configure-db.html</codeblock></li>
          </ul></p>
        <p id="p_tsg_f3n_2pb">When <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> queries the comments for the page using
          that relative path, the original comment will not be found.</p>
      </cause></troubleSolution></troublebody>
</troubleshooting>
