<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-version-management">
  <title>Version Settings</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Site versions</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Versions</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit versions</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site Versions page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
      <keywords>
        <keyword outputclass="label">WebHelp Output</keyword>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Site Configuration</keyword>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_uyw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Site Versions</uicontrol> page can be used to add or edit
      versions for a site configuration and you can choose to install a particular version in your
      website or WebHelp output. Each site configuration can have multiple versions. This is useful
      if you have multiple versions of the output (for example, multiple versions of published
      technical documentation or multiple article revisions). To reach this page, click the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/ofb-Versions15.png" id="image_txz_51g_gjb"
        />Versions</uicontrol> link in the left menu bar in the interface for a particular site
      configuration. Each version for a site configuration is displayed as a tile. Each tile
      displays the version, the creation date, and the URL for the particular version.</p>
    <p>Versions that do not have any page views detected in the output have a warning icon (<image
        href="../img/ofb-Warn16.png"/>) and message (<uicontrol>This version has no page
        views</uicontrol>) displayed in the tile. No page views usually means that the site/version
      has not been installed so these warnings are meant to offer troubleshooting hints.</p>
    <p id="p_vyw_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_yf3_ys2_gjb">
        <title>Site Versions Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-site-versions.png" id="image_it2_1t2_gjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_wyw_dgk_54b">This page includes the following actions:</p>
    <p id="p_xyw_dgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_yyw_dgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_zyw_dgk_54b">
          <dt>Add Version</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_azw_dgk_54b">To add a new version, click the <uicontrol>Add Version</uicontrol> button on the
              right side of the page. This initiates a two-step wizard for configuring the new
              version.</p>
            <p id="p_bzw_dgk_54b">
              <dl id="dl_czw_dgk_54b">
                <dlentry id="dlentry_dzw_dgk_54b">
                  <dt>Step 1 - Settings</dt>
                  <dd>
                    <p id="p_ezw_dgk_54b">This wizard page includes the following options:</p>
                    <p id="p_k4z_h4x_5wb">
                      <dl id="dl_vpd_34x_5wb">
                        <dlentry id="dlentry_wpd_34x_5wb">
                          <dt>Name</dt>
                          <dd>Specifies the name of the version for the site configuration. Each
                            site configuration can have multiple versions. This is useful if you
                            plan to have multiple versions of the output (for example, multiple
                            versions of published technical documentation or multiple article
                            revisions).</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry id="dlentry_wdy_34x_5wb">
                          <dt>Base URL</dt>
                          <dd>Use this option to specify the <uicontrol>Base URL</uicontrol> for
                            your website. Only <codeph>http</codeph> and <codeph>https</codeph>
                            protocols are allowed and it must NOT point to a file (e.g.
                              <filepath>http://example.com/index.html</filepath> is not
                              allowed).<note conkeyref="reusables-feedback/site-base-url-note"
                              id="note_s4r_j4x_5wb"/></dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry id="dlentry_j1l_k4x_5wb">
                          <dt>Creation Date</dt>
                          <dd>Use this option to specify a creation date. This date is displayed in
                            the tile for the particular version in the <uicontrol>Site
                              Versions</uicontrol> page.</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry id="dlentry_xrh_l4x_5wb">
                          <dt>Show Comments from Older Versions</dt>
                          <dd>By default, comments are only displayed for the current version.
                            However, you can select this option to choose to also show comments from
                            either <uicontrol>All Versions</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>All Versions
                              Starting with</uicontrol> a particular version number.<note type="tip"
                              id="note_sdb_m4x_5wb">The version number is displayed on the
                              right-hand side of the comment box in both the output and in the <xref
                                href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol>
                                page</xref>.</note></dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                          <dt>Display in-place error message for comments component</dt>
                          <dd>Select this option if you want an error message to be displayed
                            directly in the location where the comments component should appear if
                            any issues arise during the integration process. A hyperlink is also
                            displayed that directs you to a user guide topic to help you
                            troubleshoot the issue.<note type="tip">It is recommended to keep this
                              feature enabled during the initial setup or when making changes to
                              your site configuration. This can help identify and resolve
                              integration issues.</note></dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry id="dlentry_hfg_m4x_5wb">
                          <dt>Enable Content Indexing</dt>
                          <dd>Select this option to enable content indexing for this version and you
                            can specify the language that will be used while indexing and searching
                            the output. For more details, see <xref
                              href="#ofb-version-management/dlentry_hfg_m4x_5wb"/>.</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                      </dl>
                    </p>
                    <p id="p_lzw_dgk_54b">Click the <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol> button to proceed to the next
                      wizard page.</p>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_mzw_dgk_54b">
                  <dt>Step 2 - Installation</dt>
                  <dd>
                    <p id="p_nzw_dgk_54b">The second wizard page includes options for choosing how to install the
                      particular version of the Feedback system. There are three options:</p>
                    <p conkeyref="reusables-feedback/installation-options" id="p_ozw_dgk_54b"/>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_pzw_dgk_54b">
          <dt>Settings</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_qzw_dgk_54b">To edit an existing version, click the
                <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> button at the bottom-right corner of the tile for a
              particular version. This opens an <uicontrol>Version settings</uicontrol> page.</p>
            <p id="p_uyq_chg_pwb">
              <fig id="fig_j5j_dhg_pwb">
                <title>Version Settings Page</title>
                <image href="../img/ofb-site-versions-settings.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
            <p id="p_j12_mhg_pwb"> This settings page includes the following options:</p>
            <p id="p_yvb_snx_5wb">
              <dl id="dl_yw3_snx_5wb">
                <dlentry id="dlentry_zw3_snx_5wb">
                  <dt>Name</dt>
                  <dd>Specifies the name of the version for the new site configuration version.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_zgl_tnx_5wb">
                  <dt>Base URL</dt>
                  <dd>Use this option to specify the <uicontrol>Base URL</uicontrol> for your
                    website.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_qng_5nx_5wb">
                  <dt>Creation Date</dt>
                  <dd>Use this option to specify a creation date. This date is displayed in the tile
                    for the particular version in the <uicontrol>Site Versions</uicontrol>
                    page.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_j1f_vnx_5wb">
                  <dt>Show Comments from Older Versions</dt>
                  <dd>By default, comments are only displayed for the current version. However, you
                    can click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button to the right of this option to
                    choose to also show comments from either <uicontrol>All Versions</uicontrol> or
                      <uicontrol>All Versions Starting with</uicontrol> a particular version number.
                    Make sure you click the <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> button (that replaces the
                      <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button) after making a change.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Display in-place error message for comments component</dt>
                  <dd>Select this option if you want an error message to be displayed directly in
                    the location where the comments component should appear if any issues arise
                    during the integration process. A hyperlink is also displayed that directs you
                    to a user guide topic to help you troubleshoot the issue.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="content-indexing-search">
                  <dt>WebHelp Responsive Content Indexing and AI Features</dt>
                  <dd><p id="p_zly_ynx_5wb">
                      <note id="note_w2d_znx_5wb" type="other" othertype="Prerequisites">
                        <ul>
                          <li>The output must be generated using <b>Oxygen WebHelp</b> version 25 or
                            later.</li>
                          <li product="feedback">The website that will be indexed but be
                            public.</li>
                          <li product="feedback-enterprise">The website that will be indexed but be
                            accessible to the <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> server.</li>
                          <li>The root directory of the published output must include the
                              <filepath>sitemap.xml</filepath> file that is generated by the
                              <b>Oxygen XML WebHelp Responsive</b> transformation (it contains all
                            the files that should be indexed).</li>
                        </ul>
                      </note>
                    </p><p id="p_cbz_b4x_5wb">Use this option to enable/disable content indexing and
                      to configure search functions. When content indexing is enabled for a site's
                      version, the corresponding WebHelp Responsive output will use <b>Oxygen
                        Feedback</b> as the search engine when users search the published content.
                      If content indexing is disabled, the search will be performed using the JS
                      Search Engine bundled in the WebHelp Responsive output.</p><p>The
                        <i>Configuration Overview</i> shows which features in this section are
                      enabled. Click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button to the right of the
                      section to expand it and expose the configurable options (<uicontrol>Enable
                        content indexing</uicontrol> must be selected to access the additional
                      options in this section).</p><p id="p_lv3_f4x_5wb">Once the content indexing
                      is enabled, you can choose the language that the search engine will use for
                      the indexing and which AI features are enabled.</p><p id="p_jss_5gq_ncc"
                          ><u><b>AI Features</b></u><note id="note_pgs_jgq_ncc" type="notice">To use
                        the AI features, you must have an AI-ready subscription. See <xref
                          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen_feedback/buy_feedback.html"
                          format="html" scope="external"/> for information about the available
                        subscription plans.</note></p>The <uicontrol>AI Features</uicontrol> section
                    contains options for configuring AI-enhanced search functionality. These
                    AI-related options are available if you have configured <ph keyref="product"/>
                    to <xref href="ofb-configuring-openai-connection.dita">connect to <tm
                        tmtype="tm">OpenAI</tm> on your behalf</xref> in the <xref
                      href="ofb-organization-profile-page.dita"><i>Organization Profile</i>
                      page</xref>.<ul id="ul_df2_f15_m1c">
                      <li id="li_ef2_f15_m1c"><uicontrol>Enable semantic search</uicontrol> -
                        Activates <xref href="ofb-semantic-search.dita">functionality to enable
                          semantic searches</xref>, an advanced search technique that aims to
                        improve the accuracy and relevance of search results by understanding the
                        context and meaning behind the search query, rather than relying solely on
                        keyword matching.</li>
                      <li id="li_hfs_m15_m1c"><uicontrol>Enable AI Assistant</uicontrol> - If
                        selected, WebHelp sites that have <ph keyref="product"/> installed will have
                        an <xref href="ofb-ai-assistant.dita"><uicontrol>AI Assistant</uicontrol>
                          button</xref> displayed in the lower-right corner of each page that will
                        allow users to interact with the <xref href="ofb-ai-assistant.dita">AI
                          Assistant</xref> to help find answers to questions and find information
                        quickly and accurately.</li>
                      <li id="li_wxn_w5t_pbc"><uicontrol>Enable Assistant debug mode</uicontrol> -
                        Selecting this option enables the debug mode for the <xref
                          href="ofb-ai-assistant.dita">AI Assistant</xref>. When enabled, a
                          <uicontrol>Debug</uicontrol> button appears at the bottom of the chat
                        window for users with a <xref href="ofb-user-roles-matrix.dita">role of
                            <i>Admin</i> or <i>Owner</i></xref>. Clicking the button displays the
                        complete set of interactions between <ph keyref="product"/> and the AI. </li>
                      <li id="li_qsb_4sm_5bc"><uicontrol>Enable AI-enhanced search
                          summary</uicontrol> - If selected, when a user enters a search query in
                        the WebHelp search results page, an AI-generated response to the search
                        query is displayed before the usual search results. The response is
                        generated using the <xref href="ofb-ai-assistant.dita">AI Assistant</xref>
                        based upon information found in the current publication. </li>
                    </ul><note id="note_m5k_r5f_mcc" type="notice">The <uicontrol>AI
                        Assistant</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>AI-enhanced Search Summary</uicontrol>
                      features can generate costs. It is recommended to use support from OpenAI to
                      configure a budget limit on the <xref
                        href="https://platform.openai.com/account/api-keys" format="html"
                        scope="external">API key</xref> configured for the organization.</note><p
                      id="p_lv3_f4x_5wbss">Make sure you click the <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>
                      button (that replaces the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button) after making a
                      change.</p><p id="p_mv3_f4x_5wb"><uicontrol>Status</uicontrol> shows you the
                      current status of the indexing. To the right of that is a <uicontrol><image
                          href="../img/ofb-check-index.png"/>Check Index Status</uicontrol> button
                      that can be used to query the OTSS server for the status of the current
                      content indexing.</p><p id="p_nv3_f4x_5wb">Click the
                        <uicontrol>Index</uicontrol> button to manually trigger an indexing. It then
                      shows how often the indexing will automatically be triggered when there is a
                      change in the content. After clicking the <uicontrol>Index</uicontrol> button,
                      the following buttons are available under the status:<ul id="ul_eqd_5ym_dfc">
                        <li id="li_fqd_5ym_dfc"><uicontrol>Reindex</uicontrol> - Triggers a new
                          indexing operation.</li>
                        <li id="li_xhg_vym_dfc"><uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> - Deletes the
                          associated index.</li>
                        <li id="li_pmc_wym_dfc"><uicontrol>Log File</uicontrol> - Download the log
                          file for the latest indexing operation.</li>
                      </ul></p><p id="p_jnb_swz_2xb">
                      <note id="note_s3h_swz_2xb" type="tip">For more details about the content
                        indexing functionality, watch our webinar: <xref
                          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/events/2023/webinar_how_to_enable_content_indexing_and_search_in_Oxygen_feedback_3_0.html"
                          format="html" scope="external">How to Enable Content Indexing and Search
                          in <b>Oxygen Feedback 3.0</b></xref>.</note>
                    </p></dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="install-version">
          <dt>Installation</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_xzw_dgk_54b">To install an existing version, click the <uicontrol>Installation</uicontrol> button
              at the bottom-left corner of the tile for a particular version. This opens an <xref
                href="ofb-site-installation.dita"><uicontrol>Installation Instructions</uicontrol>
                page</xref> where you can choose how to install the particular version of the
              Feedback system. There are three options:</p>
            <p conkeyref="reusables-feedback/installation-options" id="p_yzw_dgk_54b"/>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_l4q_3m4_s2c">
          <dt>Duplicate (available from the vertical ellipsis <image
              href="../img/ofb-ellipse-gray.png"/> menu)</dt>
          <dd>To duplicate a version, click the vertical ellipsis (<image
              href="../img/ofb-ellipse-gray.png"/>) in the bottom-right corner of the version tile
            and select <uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol>. This makes a copy of the duplicated version
            and re-opens the settings page where you can configure the version settings for the new
            version.  </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_tkb_ftm_dfc">
          <dt>Delete (available from the vertical ellipsis <image href="../img/ofb-ellipse-gray.png"
            /> menu)</dt>
          <dd>To delete a version, click the vertical ellipsis (<image
              href="../img/ofb-ellipse-gray.png"/>) in the bottom-right corner of the version tile
            and select <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>. You will be asked to confirm the operation and
            if you proceed, all comments for this particular version will be lost. The associated
            text search index is also deleted.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
