<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-version-management">
  <title>Versions</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Site versions</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Versions</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit versions</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site Versions page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Site Versions</uicontrol> page can be used to add or edit versions for a site
      configuration and you can choose to install a particular version in your website or WebHelp
      output. Each site configuration can have multiple versions. This is useful if you have
      multiple versions of the output (for example, multiple versions of published technical
      documentation or multiple article revisions). To reach this page, click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-Versions15.png" id="image_txz_51g_gjb"/>Versions</uicontrol> link in the
      left menu bar in the interface for a particular site configuration. Each version for a site
      configuration is displayed as a tile. Each tile displays the version, the publishing date, and
      the URL for the particular version.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_yf3_ys2_gjb">
        <title>Site Versions Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-site-versions.png" id="image_it2_1t2_gjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>This page includes the following actions:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Add Version</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>To add a new version, click the <uicontrol>Add Version</uicontrol> button on the
              right side of the page. This initiates a two-step wizard for configuring the new
              version.</p>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Step 1 - Settings</dt>
                  <dd>
                    <p>This wizard page includes the following options:<ul id="ul_rrf_xgg_gjb">
                        <li><b>Version</b> - Specifies the version number for the site
                          configuration. Each site configuration can have multiple versions. This is
                          useful if you plan to have multiple versions of the output (for example,
                          multiple versions of published technical documentation or multiple article
                          revisions). </li>
                        <li><b>Site Base URL</b> - Use this option to specify the <uicontrol>Base
                            URL</uicontrol> for your website. Only <codeph>http</codeph> and
                            <codeph>https</codeph> protocols are allowed and it must NOT point to a
                          file (e.g. <filepath>http://example.com/index.html</filepath> is not
                            allowed).<note conkeyref="reusables-feedback/site-base-url-note"/></li>
                        <li><b>Publishing Date</b> - Use this option to specify a publishing date.
                          This date is displayed in the tile for the particular version in the
                            <uicontrol>Site Versions</uicontrol> page.</li>
                        <li><b>Show Comments from Older Versions</b> - By default, comments are only
                          displayed for the current version. However, you can select this option to
                          choose to also show comments from either <uicontrol>All
                            Versions</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>All Versions Starting
                            with</uicontrol> a particular version number.<note type="tip">The
                            version number is displayed on the right-hand side of the comment box in
                            both the output and in the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"
                                ><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>.</note></li>
                      </ul></p>
                    <p>Click the <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol> button to proceed to the next
                      wizard page.</p>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Step 2 - Installation</dt>
                  <dd>
                    <p>The second wizard page includes options for choosing how to install the
                      particular version of the Feedback system. There are three options:</p>
                    <p conkeyref="reusables-feedback/installation-options"/>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Edit Version</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>To edit an existing version, click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button at the
              bottom-right corner of the tile for a particular version. This opens an
                <uicontrol>Edit Version</uicontrol> page that includes the following options:<ul
                id="ul_njn_xjg_gjb">
                <li><b>Version</b> - Specifies the version number for the new site configuration
                  version.</li>
                <li><b>Site Base URL</b> - Use this option to specify the <uicontrol>Base
                    URL</uicontrol> for your website.</li>
                <li><b>Publishing Date</b> - Use this option to specify a publishing date. This date
                  is displayed in the tile for the particular version in the <uicontrol>Site
                    Versions</uicontrol> page.</li>
                <li><b>Show Comments from Older Versions</b> - By default, comments are only
                  displayed for the current version. However, you can select this option to choose
                  to also show comments from either <uicontrol>All Versions</uicontrol> or
                    <uicontrol>All Versions Starting with</uicontrol> a particular version
                  number.</li>
              </ul></p>
            <p>Make sure you click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to confirm any changes made on this
              page.</p>
            <p>You can delete a particular version by clicking the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>
              button. You will be asked to confirm the operation and if you proceed, all comments
              for this particular version will be lost.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="install-version">
          <dt>Install Version</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>To install an existing version, click the <uicontrol>Installation</uicontrol> button
              at the bottom-left corner of the tile for a particular version. This opens an <xref
                href="ofb-site-installation.dita"><uicontrol>Installation Instructions</uicontrol>
                page</xref> where you can choose how to install the particular version of the
              Feedback system. There are three options:</p>
            <p conkeyref="reusables-feedback/installation-options"/>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
