<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-members-page">
  <title>Members Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Members page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
      <keywords>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Admin Interface</keyword>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Email Notifications</keyword>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_vww_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Members</uicontrol> page is where users with a role of
      organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> can see all the member attached to the organization.
      Users with a role of organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> can also invite new members and
      change user roles.</p>
    <p id="p_wgr_qmz_prb">To invite a new member:<ol id="ol_mtd_sks_5rb">
        <li id="li_ntd_sks_5rb">Enter their email address in the <uicontrol>Email</uicontrol> field
          at the top (you can enter multiple email addresses to invite multiple members at
          once).</li>
        <li id="li_smd_5ks_5rb">Choose a role for them. This role will be assigned to each of the
          invited users when they register their accounts.</li>
        <li id="li_rvp_xks_5rb">Click the <uicontrol>Invite</uicontrol> button. An email is sent to
          the new member and they will be listed in the <uicontrol>Pending Invitations</uicontrol>
          tab until they accept the invitation. Also in the <uicontrol>Pending
            Invitations</uicontrol> tab, you can click the vertical ellipsis to the far right of the
          user's name to access actions to <uicontrol>Resend invition</uicontrol> or
            <uicontrol>Delete invition</uicontrol> (this will delete the current invitation even if
          the user has received the link).</li>
      </ol></p>
    <p id="p_exw_dgk_54b">To change the role of any existing user, select the new role from the
      drop-down menu to the right of their user name. A notification email will be sent to that user
      informing them that their user role has changed.</p>
    <p id="p_www_dgk_54b">The possible organization user roles are:<ul id="ul_jh2_q1m_gjb">
        <li id="li_xww_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_owner"/></b> (This role is
          automatically assigned when the organization is created) - This type of user has rights to
          moderate comment posts (edit, approve, reject, or delete), configure site settings, the
          organization profile, versions, team members, and user roles, change the organization ID,
          delete the organization, or to delete or transfer the ownership of site
          configurations.</li>
        <li id="li_cxf_5lr_5rb" product="feedback"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_billing-manager"
            /></b> - This type of user has rights to purchase and manage the subscription for an
          organization.</li>
        <li id="li_yww_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_admin"/></b> - This type of user has
          rights to moderate comment posts (edit, approve, reject, or delete) and to configure site
          settings, the organization profile, versions, team members, and user roles.</li>
        <li id="li_zww_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_moderator"/></b> - This type of user
          has rights to moderate comment posts (edit, approve, reject, or delete).</li>
        <li id="li_axw_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_trusted"/></b> - Comments posted by
          this type of user are automatically approved (this includes existing and future
          comments).</li>
        <li id="li_bxw_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_member"/></b> - This type of user has
          rights to post new comments. If the site is moderated, comments posted by this type of
          user require approval by a user with a role of <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
            <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
        <li id="li_cxw_dgk_54b"><b><term keyref="glossentry_fb_banned"/></b> - This type of user
          cannot post comments and all existing pending comments added by this user are
          automatically rejected. A user banned at organization level is also banned from all sites
          attached to the organization.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note conkeyref="reusables-feedback/note_vch_px2_vrb" id="note_av2_nz2_vrb"/>
    <note conkeyref="reusables-feedback/note_matrix" id="note_o4d_dpx_5rb"/>
    <p id="p_dxw_dgk_54b">You can use the search field in either the <uicontrol>Members</uicontrol>
      or <uicontrol>Pending Invitations</uicontrol> tab to search for a particular user (by name or
      email) in the particular tab. When you change tabs, the search filter is saved for that
      particular tab.</p>
    <p id="p_gxw_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_hm3_s31_hjb">
        <title>Members Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-members-page.png" id="image_bfr_t31_hjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_cyz_znt_5rb">
      <fig id="fig_dyz_znt_5rb">
        <title>Members Page - Pending Invitations Tab</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-members-page-pending.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
