<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-site-notifications">
  <title>Site Notifications</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Site notifications</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site owner notifications</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site admin notifications</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site management team notifications</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Any type of user can <xref
        href="ofb-profile-management.dita#ofb-profile-management/email-notifications">configure the
        types of email notifications</xref> they receive when other users reply to their comment or
      add a comment in a thread where they have commented. To access the user notification options,
      click the account drop-down menu at the top-right corner of the interface, select
        <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol>, and go to the <uicontrol>Notifications</uicontrol> tab.</p>
    <p>In addition, certain notifications are automatically sent when certain events are
        triggered:<ul id="ul_v4p_54l_gjb">
        <li><b>User Role is Changed</b> - All users will receive an email notification if their user
          role is changed by an <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.</li>
        <li><b>Site Edited</b> - If a site configuration is edited, any other user with a role of
            <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> for that site configuration will receive an email
          notification.</li>
        <li><b>Site Deleted</b> - If a site configuration is deleted, any other user with a role of
            <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> for that site configuration will receive an email
          notification.</li>
        <li><b>Site Version Edited</b> - If a site configuration's version is edited, any other user
          with a role of <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> for that site configuration will receive an
          email notification.</li>
        <li><b>Site Version Added</b> - If a version is added to a site configuration, any other
          user with a role of <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> for that site configuration will receive
          an email notification.</li>
        <li><b>Site Version Deleted</b> - If a site configuration's version is deleted, any other
          user with a role of <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> for that site configuration will receive
          an email notification.</li>
        <li><b>Comment Rejected</b> - If the site configuration has the <xref
            href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"><uicontrol>Comment
              Moderation</uicontrol> option enabled</xref> and a <i>Moderator</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
            <i>Owner</i> rejects a comment, the user who posted the comment and any user with a role
          of <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i> for that site configuration will
          receive an email notification.</li>
        <li><b>Comment Deleted</b> - If the site configuration has the <xref
            href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"><uicontrol>Comment
              Moderation</uicontrol> option enabled</xref> and a <i>Moderator</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or
            <i>Owner</i> deletes a comment, the user who posted the comment and any user with a role
          of <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i> for that site configuration will
          receive an email notification.</li>
        <li><b>Comment Needs to be Approved or Rejected</b> - If the site configuration has the
            <xref href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
              ><uicontrol>Comment Moderation</uicontrol> option enabled</xref> and a user adds or
          edits a comment, any user with a role of <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>
          for that site configuration will receive an email notification.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
