<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-semantic-search">
    <title>Semantic Search</title>
    <body>
        <p>The search engine provided by <ph keyref="product"/> offers the possibility of using
      semantic search when searching the WebHelp Responsive output.<note id="note_a1h_5vp_dzb"
        type="note">The default search engine that comes embedded in the WebHelp Responsive output
        does not support semantic searches. </note></p>
    <p>Semantic search is an advanced search technique that aims to improve the accuracy and
      relevance of search results by understanding the context and meaning behind the search query,
      rather than relying solely on keyword matching. It goes beyond traditional keyword-based
      search, which primarily relies on matching the exact words or phrases in a query to the
      content of documents. </p>
    <p>In semantic search, the search engine uses natural language processing (NLP) and machine
      learning techniques to analyze the intent and context of a search query.</p>
    <section id="section_cjj_wwp_dzb">
      <title>Enabling Semantic Search</title>
      <p>The semantic search functionality is not enabled by default. To enable semantic search:<ol
          id="ol_cgt_fxp_dzb">
          <li>In the administration interface of <ph keyref="product"/> go to the <uicontrol>Version
              Settings</uicontrol> page</li>
          <li>Scroll to the <uicontrol>Content Indexing and Search</uicontrol> section</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol></li>
          <li>Check the <uicontrol>Enable semantic search</uicontrol> option<note
              id="note_vxc_pxp_dzb">Content indexing functionality must be activated in order to be
              able to enable and use semantic search.</note><note id="note_svy_byp_dzb">The semantic
              search functionality requires an <tm tmtype="tm">OpenAI</tm> API key to be provided in
              the Organization Page.</note></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol></li>
        </ol></p>
      <p>After editing the <uicontrol>Content Indexing and Search</uicontrol> section and enabling
        the Semantic Search functionality a re-indexing operation is triggered. </p>
    </section>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_f44_mhv_dzb">
        <title>Enable semantic search option</title>
        <image href="ofb-enable-semantic-search.png" id="image_hcm_nhv_dzb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section id="resources">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p id="p_agf_xh1_hzb">Video - <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/semantic_search_queries_in_webhelp.html"
          format="html" scope="external"><b>Semantic Search in Oxygen WebHelp Responsive Output
            Powered by Oxygen Feedback</b></xref>:<div><object width="450" height="250"
              data="https://youtu.be/driFQ7G6gOU" outputclass="iframe"/></div></p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
