<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-team-management">
  <title>Management Team</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Site management team</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Moderator role</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Admin role</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Management Team page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Management Team</uicontrol> page can be used to define the site management
      team (users with the <term keyref="glossentry_fb_owner">Owner</term>, <term
        keyref="glossentry_fb_admin">Admin</term>, or <term keyref="glossentry_fb_moderator"
        >Moderator</term> role). To reach this page, click the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/ofb-ManagementTeam16.png" id="image_txz_51g_gjb"/>Management Team</uicontrol>
      link in the left menu bar in the interface for a particular site configuration. The current
      team is listed with their avatar, name, and email address. The possible roles are:<ul
        id="ul_x2s_rng_gjb">
        <li><b>Moderator</b> - This type of user has rights to moderate comment posts (edit,
          approve, reject, or delete).</li>
        <li id="admin"><b>Admin</b> - This type of user has rights to moderate comment posts and to
          configure site settings, versions, team members, and user roles. The site <i>Owner</i>
          also has all of these rights.</li>
        <li id="owner"><b>Owner</b> (This role is automatically assigned when the site configuration
          is created) - This type of user has rights to moderate comment posts (edit, approve,
          reject, or delete), configure site settings, versions, team members, and user roles, as
          well as rights to <xref href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/delete-site"
            >delete</xref> or <xref href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/transfer-ownership"
            >transfer the ownership</xref> of the site configuration.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To add a new user to the management team, enter their email address in the
        <uicontrol>Email</uicontrol> field at the top of the page, assign a role with the drop-down
      menu, and click the <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> button. A confirmation email will be sent to
      that email address informing them that their user role has been changed and that person will
      have approximately one day to accept it before it expires. In the meantime, their new role
      will be in a pending status until they accept the change request or it expires.<note
        type="note">The owner of the email address must be registered on the platform. If they have
        not already done so, they will need to <xref href="ofb-signing-up.dita">sign up</xref>
        before you can add them.</note></p>
    <p>To change the role of any <b>Moderator</b> or <b>Admin</b>, select the new role from the
      drop-down menu to the right of their user name. A confirmation email will be sent to that user
      and that person will have approximately one day to accept the change request before it
      expires. In the meantime, their current role will remain the same and the new role will be in
      a pending status until they accept the change request or it expires.</p>
    <p>To remove a user, click the <image href="../img/Remove16.png" id="image_zzn_2pg_gjb"/> button
      to the right of the drop-down menu. When a user is removed from the management team, they are
      assigned a role of <i>Member</i>.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_ucv_jx1_hjb">
        <title>Management Team Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-management-team.png" id="image_vcv_jx1_hjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
