<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-dashboard">
  <title>Dashboard Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Dashboard page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Welcome page</indexterm>
      </keywords>
      <keywords>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Dashboard Page</keyword>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Statistics</keyword>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_ntw_dgk_54b">When you log in to the administration interface, you are directed to the
        <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page<ph product="feedback"> (if it is your first time
        logging in, a dialog box is displayed with information about your subscription)</ph>. This
      page is especially helpful for those who integrate the Feedback commenting component in
      multiple websites. It aggregates basic information about all of your existing sites.<note
        product="feedback-enterprise" id="note_otw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol>
        page is slightly different for the <term keyref="glossentry_fb_platform_admin">Feedback
          Platform Admin</term>. They have access to their own <xref href="ofbENT-admin-area.dita"
          >special <uicontrol>Admin Interface</uicontrol></xref> that is reached by clicking the
          <image href="../img/ofb-Admin18.png" id="image_k5w_vjp_ymb"/> button on the right side of
        the top ribbon.</note></p>
    <p id="p_rtw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> contains the following panes
      (depending on your user role):</p>
    <p id="p_stw_dgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_ttw_dgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_dbb_4py_prb">
          <dt>Get Started</dt>
          <dd>The <uicontrol>Get Started</uicontrol> pane includes buttons that trigger actions for
            the most popular tasks, particularly for users who are getting started. Once a task is
            complete, it is marked as done (with blue outlines). The actions available are:<ul
              id="ul_g1f_yqy_prb">
              <li id="li_h1f_yqy_prb"><uicontrol>Setup organization profile</uicontrol> - This
                action opens the <xref href="ofb-organization-profile-page.dita"
                    ><uicontrol>Organization Profile</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can manage
                information about your organization.</li>
              <li id="li_f22_fry_prb"><uicontrol>Invite members</uicontrol> - This action opens the
                  <xref href="ofb-members-page.dita"><uicontrol>Members</uicontrol> page</xref>
                where you can view all the members attached to the organization, invite new members,
                and associate user roles.</li>
              <li id="li_fkd_nry_prb"><uicontrol>Create first site</uicontrol> - This action
                initiates the process of creating a new site configuration.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="sites-pane">
          <dt>Sites</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_utw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> pane displays all the existing
              sites along with information about user comments, AI threads, site ownership, and
              members. The sites with pending comments are listed first, and then the rest are
              sorted alphabetically. For users with a role of <b>organization</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>, it displays all the activity for all
              the sites attached to the organization. For users with a role of organization
                <i>Member</i>, it displays activity for sites that the user is assigned as
                <b>site</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>.</p>
            <p id="p_vtw_dgk_54b">The following features are available in this pane to help you
              filter the information or navigate to a certain page:<ul id="ul_wtw_dgk_54b">
                <li id="li_xtw_dgk_54b"><b>Manage Sites</b> - If you click the
                    <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> title in the top-left corner of the pane or if you
                  click the <uicontrol>Manage sites</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner of the
                  pane, you will be directed to the <xref href="ofb-sites-page.dita"
                      ><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> page</xref> where all your sites are displayed
                  in a tile format.</li>
                <li id="li_ytw_dgk_54b"><b>Add Site</b> - You can click the <uicontrol>Add
                    site</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner or the pane to <xref
                    href="ofb-creating-site.dita">create a new site configuration</xref>.</li>
                <li id="li_btc_d2y_g1c"><b>Go To Site</b> - If you click the name of a site, it will
                  open the <xref href="ofb-site-dashboard.dita"><uicontrol>Site
                      Dashboard</uicontrol></xref> for that particular site.</li>
                <li id="li_a5w_dgk_54b"><b>Moderate Comments</b> - The number of
                    <uicontrol>Pending</uicontrol> (not shown if the <xref
                    href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                      ><uicontrol>Comments Moderation</uicontrol> option is set to
                    <i>None</i></xref>), <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>,
                    <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Reopened</uicontrol> comments
                  that were posted by users are displayed for each site. You can click the icon or
                  number to open the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"
                      ><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> with the comments automatically
                  filtered based on the status you click.<note id="note_b5w_dgk_54b">The number of
                      <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Reopened</uicontrol>, and
                      <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol> comments do not include replies (only
                    first-level comments).</note></li>
                <li id="li_ezn_jqy_qdc"><b>AI Threads</b> - The number of AI threads that have been
                  initiated by users are displayed for each site. You can click on the number to
                  navigate to the <xref href="ofb-ai-threads.dita">AI Threads page</xref> where you
                  can view and filter messages that users have sent to the AI Assistant on the
                  particular site.</li>
                <li id="li_uch_yqy_qdc"><b>Site Owner</b> - The avatar of the <i>Owner</i> of each
                  site is displayed. You can hover over the circular avatar to see the name of the
                  owner.</li>
                <li id="li_d5w_dgk_54b"><b>Community Members</b> - The number of community members
                  is displayed in a blue box on the far right for each site. Clicking the blue box
                  will open the <xref href="ofb-community-management.dita"
                      ><uicontrol>Community</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can see all the
                  members of the site management team and any other user who has posted a comment
                  for the particular site.</li>
                <li id="li_e5w_dgk_54b"><b>Show More</b> - By default, five sites are shown, but you
                  can click the <uicontrol>Show more</uicontrol> link at the bottom of the pane to
                  show the rest of the sites.</li>
              </ul></p>
          </dd>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_dm4_tpy_qdc">
              <note id="note_hgk_5py_qdc" type="notice">Sites that do not have any page views
                detected in the output have a warning icon (<image href="../img/ofb-Warn16.png"/>)
                displayed under the site avatar/name. No page views usually means that the
                site/version has not been installed so these warnings are meant to offer
                troubleshooting hints.</note>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_f5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>Activity Stream</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_g5w_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Activity Stream</uicontrol> displays the activity
              for all sites, including information about the person who made the change and details
              about each activity. For users with a role of <b>organization</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>, it displays all the activity for all
              the sites attached to the organization. For users with a role of organization
                <i>Member</i>, it displays activity for sites that the user is assigned as
                <b>site</b>
              <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i>.</p>
            <p id="p_h5w_dgk_54b">Each activity box includes the name and avatar of the commenter, a
              link to the actual topic in the published output where the comment resides, the
              version of the site (clicking the version opens the <xref
                href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref> with
              the comments automatically filtered based on the version), and the avatar for the
              site.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_i5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>My Subscription</dt>
          <dd>This pane is available for users with a role of organization <i>Owner</i> or
              <i>Billing Manager</i>. It displays information about your current subscription,
            including the expiration date and the percentage of used and estimated <term
              keyref="glossentry_fb_page_views">Page Views</term> for the current period. You can
            click the <uicontrol>Manage subscription</uicontrol> link to open the <xref
              href="ofb-subscription.dita"><uicontrol>Subscription Plans</uicontrol> page</xref>
            where you can see more details and make changes to your subscription.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_j5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>Page Views</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of page views for all the organization's sites that you
            are assigned as the organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>. You can click the
              <uicontrol>Page views</uicontrol> title or the <uicontrol>Usage statistics</uicontrol>
            link in the top-right corner to open the <xref href="ofb-statistics.dita"
                ><uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can see the number of
              <term keyref="glossentry_fb_page_views">Page Views</term> and comments added for all
            of your sites.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_k5w_dgk_54b" product="feedback">
          <dt>Comments</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of comments added in all the organization's sites that
            you are assigned as the organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>. You can click the
              <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> title or <uicontrol>Usage statistics</uicontrol> link
            in the top-right corner to open the <xref href="ofb-statistics.dita"><uicontrol>Usage
                Statistics</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can see the number of page views and
            comments added for all of your sites.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_k5w_dgk_54c" product="feedback">
          <dt>AI Assistant Threads</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of <xref href="ofb-ai-threads.dita">AI Assistant
              Threads</xref> that were initiated by users in all the organization's sites that you
            are assigned as the organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>. You can click the
              <uicontrol>AI Assistant Threads</uicontrol> title or the <uicontrol>Usage
              statistics</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner to open the <xref
              href="ofb-statistics.dita"><uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page</xref> where
            you can view and filter statistical data regarding the AI threads for all of your
            sites.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_k5w_dgk_54d" product="feedback">
          <dt>AI Assistant Users</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of users who initiated a session with the <xref
              href="ofb-ai-assistant.dita">AI Assistant Chatbot</xref> in all the organization's
            sites that you are assigned as the organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>. You can
            click the <uicontrol>AI Assistant Users</uicontrol> title or the <uicontrol>Usage
              statistics</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner to open the <xref
              href="ofb-statistics.dita"><uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page</xref> where
            you can view and filter statistical data regarding the AI sessions for all of your
            sites.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_k5w_dgk_54e" product="feedback">
          <dt>AI Assistant Summaries</dt>
          <dd>This pane displays the number of <xref href="ofb-ai-search-summary.dita">AI Assistant
              Search Summaries</xref> that were initiated by users in all the organization's sites
            that you are assigned as the organization <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>. You can click
            the <uicontrol>AI Assistant Summaries</uicontrol> title or the <uicontrol>Usage
              statistics</uicontrol> link in the top-right corner to open the <xref
              href="ofb-statistics.dita"><uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page</xref> where
            you can view and filter statistical data regarding the AI search summaries for all of
            your sites.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
