<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-profile-management">
  <title>Profile Management</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Profile</indexterm>
        <indexterm>User profile</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Change password</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Avatars</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Delete account</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Email notifications</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Notifications</indexterm>
      </keywords>
      <keywords>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Email Notifications</keyword>
        <keyword outputclass="label">Site Configuration</keyword>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_phx_dgk_54b">All users have access to a profile management page where they can manage their account,
      change their password, or configure certain email notifications. To open this page, click the
      drop-down arrow to the right of your user name and select <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> (this
      can be done either from the commenting component at the bottom of the output page or from the
        <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> administration interface).</p>
    <p id="p_rhx_dgk_54b">This opens the <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> page:</p>
    <p id="p_shx_dgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_lqv_2tr_glb">
        <title>Profile Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-profile.png" id="image_mqv_2tr_glb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_thx_dgk_54b">This profile management page allows you to configure various aspects of your profile data. It
      includes two tabs (<uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> and
      <uicontrol>Notifications</uicontrol>).</p>
    <section id="section_cxm_bjs_s4b">
      <title>Profile Tab</title>
      <p id="p_l45_djs_s4b">The <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> tab includes the following
          options:<dl id="dl_vhg_cjs_s4b">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_whg_cjs_s4b">
            <dt>Change Your Name</dt>
            <dd>To change the name associated with your profile, click the
                <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button in the <uicontrol>General</uicontrol> section and
              enter the change in the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> field.<note type="restriction"
                id="note_xhg_cjs_s4b">You cannot change the email address.</note></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_yhg_cjs_s4b">
            <dt>Change Your Avatar</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="p_zhg_cjs_s4b">To change your avatar, click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
                button in the <uicontrol>General</uicontrol> section, then click the current avatar
                image and choose <uicontrol>Select Photo</uicontrol>. You can then browse for a
                local image to use for your avatar and click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to finalize
                your change. The supported extensions are: <i>.jpg</i>, <i>.jpeg</i>, <i>.png</i>,
                  <i>.gif</i>. The maximum allowed size is 2048 KB.</p>
              <p id="p_a3g_cjs_s4b">To remove the current avatar, click the
                  <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button in the <uicontrol>General</uicontrol> section,
                then click the current avatar image, choose <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol>, and click
                  <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to finalize your change.<note id="note_b3g_cjs_s4b"
                  >When loading large avatar images, they might be resized and lose some image
                  quality. This is done to reduce network data traffic.</note></p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_c3g_cjs_s4b">
            <dt>Change Your Password</dt>
            <dd>To change your password, click the <uicontrol>Change password</uicontrol> button in
              the <uicontrol>Security</uicontrol> section, enter your current password, then choose
              a new password, confirm it, and click <uicontrol>Save password</uicontrol> to finalize
              your change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_d3g_cjs_s4b">
            <dt>Delete Your Account</dt>
            <dd>To delete your account, click the <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> button in the
                <uicontrol>Delete Account</uicontrol> section. A confirmation dialog box appears.
              You need to enter your password and click <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> to confirm the
                operation.<ph product="feedback"> You cannot delete your account if you have the
                automatic renewal option enabled in your subscription plan.</ph><note
                id="note_e3g_cjs_s4b">Your comments (as well as all site configurations for <xref
                  href="ofb-team-management.dita"><i>Admins</i> or the site <i>Owner</i></xref>) are
                kept for 14 days, but will not be visible. To recover your account within those 14
                days, log in, go to your <uicontrol>Profile</uicontrol> page, and select
                  <uicontrol>Recover</uicontrol>. After recovering the account, comments (and site
                information for <xref href="ofb-team-management.dita"><i>Admins</i> or the site
                    <i>Owner</i></xref>) will be visible again. If a site <i>Owner</i> deletes their
                account and does not recover the account within 14 days, the account is purged and
                all site configurations, versions, and comments associated with that account are
                purged.</note><note id="note_fwj_szz_prb" type="restriction">An organization
                  <i>Owner</i> cannot delete their own account. </note></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_f5w_cjs_s4b">
      <title>Notifications Tab</title>
      <p id="p_g5w_cjs_s4b">The <uicontrol>Notifications</uicontrol> tab includes various options
        for configuring the notifications that you will receive when certain events are
        triggered.</p>
      <p id="p_yjd_5js_s4b">At the top of this tab, you can select between:<ul id="ul_cxw_qks_s4b">
          <li id="li_dxw_qks_s4b"><uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> - Use this subtab to configure
            notification settings for all site configurations.</li>
          <li id="li_ktl_rks_s4b"><uicontrol>By Site</uicontrol> - Use this subtab to create a
            custom notification scheme for a particular site configuration. You simply choose your
            site configuration from the drop-down menu, click the <uicontrol>Add scheme</uicontrol>
            button, and configure the notification options that appear (details can be found
            below).</li>
        </ul><note id="note_ckq_fsd_qrb">Users with a role of organization <i>Owner</i>,
            <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i> can configure notifications for all site
          configurations attached to an organization.</note></p>
      <p id="p_ynr_pks_s4b">There are three possible sections of notification settings that can be
        configured, depending on your user rights:</p>
      <p id="p_eq4_nls_s4b">
        <dl id="dl_w5r_nls_s4b">
          <dlentry id="dlentry_x5r_nls_s4b">
            <dt>Member Notifications</dt>
            <dd>All users have access to these options. You can choose to not receive any email
              notifications of this type by deselecting the <uicontrol>Send me email notifications
                when</uicontrol> option. Otherwise, you can choose whether or not to receive an
              email notification when the following occurs:<ul id="ul_vgw_rls_s4b">
                <li id="li_wgw_rls_s4b"><b>Someone replies to one of my comments</b> - You will
                  receive an email notification when someone replies to a comment that you
                  added.</li>
                <li id="li_xgw_rls_s4b"><b>Someone adds a comment on a topic where I added a
                    comment</b> - You will receive an email notification when someone adds a comment
                  on any page where you have added a comment.</li>
                <li id="li_ppj_4tj_1tb"><b>Someone resolves one of my comments</b> - You will
                  receive an email notification when someone marks a comment you added as
                  resolved.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_ojj_4ls_s4b">
            <dt>Moderator Notifications</dt>
            <dd>Users with an <i>Owner</i>, <i>Admin</i>, or <i>Moderator</i> role have access to
              these options. You can choose to not receive any email notifications of this type by
              deselecting the <uicontrol>Send me email notifications when</uicontrol> option.
              Otherwise, you can choose whether or not to receive an email notification when the
              following occurs:<ul id="ul_ql3_5ls_s4b">
                <li id="li_xlq_dms_s4b"><b>Someone adds a comment that needs to be approved</b> -
                  You will receive an email notification when a user adds or edits a comment and the
                  site configuration has the <xref
                    href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                      ><uicontrol>Comment Moderation</uicontrol> option enabled</xref>.</li>
                <li id="li_sl3_5ls_s4b"><b>A moderator approves a comment</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when a moderator approves a comment and the site configuration
                  has the <xref href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                      ><uicontrol>Comment Moderation</uicontrol> option enabled</xref>.</li>
                <li id="li_slk_qms_s4b"><b>Someone adds a comment</b> - You will receive an email
                  notification when a user adds a comment for any site configuration that you are
                  assigned as a <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_bjc_sms_s4b"><b>Someone edits a comment</b> - You will receive an email
                  notification when a user edits a comment for any site configuration that you are
                  assigned as a <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_rjd_sms_s4b"><b>Someone deletes a comment</b> - You will receive an email
                  notification when a user deletes a comment for any site configuration that you are
                  assigned as a <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_y22_sms_s4b"><b>A moderator rejects a comment</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when a moderator rejects a comment for any site configuration
                  that you are assigned as a <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_dbf_sms_s4b"><b>A moderator restores a comment</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when a moderator restores a rejected/deleted comment for any
                  site configuration that you are assigned as a <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_exf_sms_s4b"><b>A moderator resolves a comment</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when a moderator resolves a comment for any site configuration
                  that you are assigned as a <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_ctg_sms_s4b"><b>A moderator reopens a comment</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when a moderator reopens a resolved comment for any site
                  configuration that you are assigned as a <i>Moderator</i>.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="dlentry_bry_4ls_s4b">
            <dt>Admin Notifications</dt>
            <dd>Users with an <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> role have access to these options. You
              can choose to not receive any email notifications of this type by deselecting the
                <uicontrol>Send me email notifications when</uicontrol> option. Otherwise, you can
              choose whether or not to receive an email notification when the following occurs:<ul
                id="ul_wrg_sns_s4b">
                <li id="li_zrg_sns_s4b"><b>An administrator edits a site</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when an administrator edits any site configuration that you are
                  assigned as <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_zdy_xns_s4b"><b>An administrator deletes a site</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when an administrator deletes any site configuration that you
                  are assigned as <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_uqz_yns_s4b"><b>An administrator adds a version</b> - You will receive an
                  email notification when an administrator adds a version to any site configuration
                  that you are assigned as <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_wgb_c4s_s4b"><b>An administrator edits a version</b> - You will receive
                  an email notification when an administrator edits a version for any site
                  configuration that you are assigned as <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_kjn_f4s_s4b"><b>An administrator deletes a version</b> - You will receive
                  an email notification when an administrator deletes a version for any site
                  configuration that you are assigned as <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i>.</li>
                <li id="li_xqc_gsm_btb"><uicontrol>Send me a daily email with a page ratings
                    report</uicontrol> - If selected (default), users who are assigned as
                    <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> will receive a daily email that contains a report
                  of the pages that were rated within the past 24 hours.</li>
                <li id="li_f1c_nxm_dfc"><uicontrol>Send me a daily email with an AI Threads
                    report</uicontrol> - If selected (default), users who are assigned as
                    <i>Owner</i> or <i>Admin</i> will receive a daily email that contains a report
                  that summarizes the new AI threads that were created in the past 24 hours.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p id="p_trm_dks_s4b">In addition, users automatically receive an <xref
          href="ofb-site-notifications.dita">email notification when certain events are triggered by
          an Administrator</xref>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
