<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-usage-statistics">
  <title>Usage Statistics</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Usage statistics</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Users with a role of <i>Owner</i> for any site configurations have access to a
        <uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page where they can see the number of page views and
      comments added for all of their site configurations. You cannot see statistics for site
      configurations that you are not assigned the role of <i>Owner</i>. To open this page, click
      the drop-down arrow to the right of your user name and select <uicontrol>Usage
        Statistics</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p><image href="../img/ofb-profile-drop-down-statistics.png" id="image_yvz_2sr_glb"/></p>
    <p>This opens the <uicontrol>Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page: </p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_fs3_dsr_glb">
        <title>Usage Statistics Page</title>
        <image href="../img/ofb-usage-statistics-page.png" id="image_gs3_dsr_glb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The top half of the page displays statistics for page views and/or comments in a graph form
      according to the selected filtering options. The bottom half of the page displays the
      statistics for each selected site configuration in a table with numeric values. You can click
      the up or down arrow to the right of the title for each column header to sort that particular
      column. If you click the name of the site configuration, you will be directed to that
      particular site configuration. By default, the table is sorted in the descending order of the
      number of page views from the last column of the table (last month or last day of the selected
      period). You can click the arrow to the left of the site configuration name in the first
      column to expand the particular site configuration to show its configured versions. By
      default, the versions are sorted chronologically in this table.</p>
    <p> At the very top of the usage statistics page, you can use the drop-down to filter the
      statistics by: <uicontrol>All sites</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Sites owned by me</uicontrol>, or
        <uicontrol>Sites administered by me</uicontrol>. Then, there are more filtering options for
      the graphs:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="metrics">
          <dt>Metrics</dt>
          <dd>You can select the type of metric to be displayed. You can choose between
              <uicontrol>Page views</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol>, or both.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="sites">
          <dt>Sites</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>You can choose which site configurations to have their statistics displayed.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="date-chooser">
          <dt>Date Chooser</dt>
          <dd>You can select the time period to be displayed. You can choose a relative period
            (current month, last week, last month, last 3 months, last 6 months, and last year) or
            you can select a custom period. The default time period is automatically selected based
            upon the amount of data that is found in each month.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="aggregate-chooser">
          <dt>Aggregate Chooser</dt>
          <dd>You can choose between <uicontrol>Daily</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Monthly</uicontrol>
            for the type of aggregation to be displayed.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="chart-type-chooser">
          <dt>Chart Type Chooser</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>You can select the type of the chart to be displayed. You can choose between
                <uicontrol>Line</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Bar</uicontrol>, and
                <uicontrol>Stack</uicontrol>.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
