<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofbENT-admin-area">
  <title>Platform Admin Interface</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Admin area</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Platform admin area</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <term keyref="glossentry_fb_platform_admin">Feedback Platform Admin</term> has access to
      their own special <uicontrol>Admin Area</uicontrol> that is reached by clicking the <image
        href="../img/ofb-Admin18.png" id="image_dnm_3rp_ymb"/> button on the right side of the top
      ribbon.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Admin Area</uicontrol> provides access to the following pages:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ofb-Sites18.png" id="image_zsk_srp_ymb"
            /></uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays a list of the existing site configurations for your organization, along with
            information such as the number of pending, open, or resolved comments, the <i>Owner</i>,
            and community members. <p>The following components are available to help you filter the
              information or navigate to a certain page:<ul id="ul_ydh_lsp_ymb">
                <li>You can use the search field at the top of the page to filter the results by
                  site or owner.</li>
                <li>If you click on the name of the site configuration, it will open the <xref
                    href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
                  where comments can be moderated and managed for the particular configuration.</li>
                <li>The number of <uicontrol>Pending</uicontrol> (not shown if the <xref
                    href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                      ><uicontrol>Comments Moderation</uicontrol> option is set to
                    <i>None</i></xref>), <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>, and
                    <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol> comments are displayed for each site
                  configuration. You can click the icon or number to open the <xref
                    href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
                  with the comments automatically filtered based on the status you click.<note>The
                    number of <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol>
                    comments do not include replies (only first-level comments).</note></li>
                <li>The avatar for the site <i>Owner</i> is displayed on the right side. You can
                  hover the avatar to see the name of the <i>Owner</i>.</li>
                <li>The number of community members is displayed in a blue box on the far right for
                  each site configuration. Clicking the blue box will open the <xref
                    href="ofb-community-management.dita"><uicontrol>Community</uicontrol>
                    page</xref> where you can see all the members of the site management team and
                  any other user who has posted a comment for the particular site configuration.
                </li>
              </ul></p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ofb-License18.png" id="image_jqs_trp_ymb"
            /></uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays information about the current subscription plan and license, and provides
            components to manage them. For more details, see <xref href="ofb-subscription-ENT.dita"
            />.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
