<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofbENT-admin-area">
  <title>Platform Admin Interface</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Admin interface</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Platform admin area</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_atw_dgk_54b">The <term keyref="glossentry_fb_platform_admin">Feedback Platform
        Admin</term> has access to their own special <uicontrol>Admin Interface</uicontrol> that is
      reached by clicking the <image href="../img/ofb-Admin18.png" id="image_dnm_3rp_ymb"/> button
      on the right side of the top ribbon.</p>
    <p id="p_btw_dgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Admin Interface</uicontrol> provides access to the
      following panes that are unique for the <term keyref="glossentry_fb_platform_admin">Feedback
        Platform Admin</term>:</p>
    <p id="p_ctw_dgk_54b">
      <dl id="dl_dtw_dgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_etw_dgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays a list of the existing site configurations for your organization, along with
            information such as the number of pending, open, or resolved comments, the name of the
            organization, and community members. <p id="p_ftw_dgk_54b">The following components are
              available to help you filter the information or navigate to a certain page:<ul
                id="ul_ydh_lsp_ymb">
                <li id="li_gtw_dgk_54b">You can use the search field at the top of the page to
                  filter the results by site or owner.</li>
                <li id="li_htw_dgk_54b">If you click on the name of the site configuration, it will
                  open the <xref href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol>
                    page</xref> where comments can be moderated and managed for the particular
                  configuration.</li>
                <li id="li_itw_dgk_54b">The number of <uicontrol>Pending</uicontrol> (not shown if
                  the <xref href="ofb-editing-site.dita#ofb-editing-site/comment-moderation"
                      ><uicontrol>Comments Moderation</uicontrol> option is set to
                    <i>None</i></xref>), <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol>, and
                    <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol> comments are displayed for each site
                  configuration. You can click the icon or number to open the <xref
                    href="ofb-moderating-comments.dita"><uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> page</xref>
                  with the comments automatically filtered based on the status you click.<note
                    id="note_jtw_dgk_54b">The number of <uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> and
                      <uicontrol>Resolved</uicontrol> comments do not include replies (only
                    first-level comments).</note></li>
                <li id="li_jtv_lny_prb">The name of the organization that the site configuration
                  belongs to is displayed in the sortable <uicontrol>Organization</uicontrol>
                  column.</li>
                <li id="li_ltw_dgk_54b">The number of community members is displayed in a blue box
                  in the <uicontrol>Members</uicontrol> column for each site configuration. Clicking
                  the blue box will open the <xref href="ofb-community-management.dita"
                      ><uicontrol>Members</uicontrol> page</xref> where you can see all the members
                  of the site management team and any other user who has posted a comment for the
                  particular site configuration. </li>
              </ul></p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_mtw_dgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>License</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays information about the current subscription plan and license, and provides
            components to manage them.<ph product="feedback-enterprise"> For more details, see <xref
                href="ofb-subscription-ENT.dita"/>.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
