<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ope-introduction">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Introduction</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section id="section_uyj_xzv_ykb">
      <title>What is the Oxygen Publishing Engine?</title>
      <p id="p_yjx_dgk_54b">The <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/publishing_engine.html" format="html"
          scope="external"><b>Oxygen Publishing Engine</b></xref> is a cost-effective bundle that
        offers automation support for transforming DITA content into WebHelp, PDF, EPUB, and plain
        HTML output from your integration scripts. It bundles the DITA Open Toolkit with integrated
          <i>Oxygen</i> publishing plugins, including the responsive <b>Oxygen WebHelp</b> and the
        CSS-based <b>PDF Chemistry</b> engine.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_aym_dzh_j3b">
      <title>Oxygen Publishing Engine License</title>
      <p id="p_zjx_dgk_54b">If you have purchased a license for the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/publishing_engine.html" format="html" scope="external"
            ><b>Oxygen Publishing Engine</b></xref>, you will be able to produce both PDF and
        WebHelp output without any restrictions.</p>
      <p id="p_akx_dgk_54b">To install your <b>Oxygen Publishing Engine</b> license key, save the license key text in a
        file with the name <filepath>licensekey.txt</filepath> and place it in the <term
          keyref="glossentry_dita_ot_dir"/> folder.</p>
    </section>
    <note type="tip" id="note_bkx_dgk_54b">For more information about the <b>Oxygen Publishing Engine</b> and how to
      transform your DITA content into PDF and WebHelp output, watch our Webinar: <xref
        href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p4YE9MRJj54" format="html" scope="external"
          ><b>Introducing the Oxygen Publishing Engine for DITA</b></xref>.</note>
    <section id="section_x5d_hwt_v4b">
      <title>Oxygen Styles Basket</title>
      <p id="p_y5d_hwt_v4b">The <xref href="https://styles.oxygenxml.com/" format="html"
          scope="external"><b>Oxygen Styles Basket</b></xref> is a handy free-to-use web-based
        visual tool that helps you to fine-tune the CSS file that is used to customize your PDF or
        WebHelp output. You simply pick and mix aspects from galleries to add and adjust the rules
        in your custom CSS file. </p>
      <p id="p_bjq_cgk_54b">It is based on galleries that you can use to pick and mix styling
        aspects to create a custom look and feel. Various different types of aspects can be selected
        to be integrated in the CSS stylesheet (such as fonts, tables, lists, spacing, code). It is
        also possible to re-upload a previously generated CSS for further customization.</p>
      <p id="p_pdb_qxt_v4b">You can see the results of your changes in the
          <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> pane or you can click the <uicontrol>See
          Results</uicontrol> toolbar button to see the results in a generated preview version of
        either PDF or WebHelp output. When you are finished with your customization, you can
          <uicontrol>Download</uicontrol> the results as a CSS file or a <i>Publishing Template
          Package</i> that you can use in your transformation process.</p>
      <p id="p_cbt_kxt_v4b">
        <fig id="fig_lmc_kxt_v4b">
          <title>Oxygen Styles Basket Interface</title>
          <image href="../img/ope_styles_basket.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_x2n_vhh_vrb">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p id="p_orm_dgk_54b">For more information about the <b>Oxygen Styles Basket</b>, see the
        following resources:<ul id="ul_i3k_2zf_msb">
          <li id="li_j3k_2zf_msb"><xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/osb_video.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Video: Introducing the New Oxygen Styles
              Basket</b></xref></li>
          <li id="li_m1s_kzf_msb"><xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/events/2022/webinar_using_oxygen_styles_basket_to_create_css_customization_from_scratch.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Webinar: Using Oxygen Styles Basket to Create CSS
                Customization from Scratch</b></xref></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
