<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="open-save-Unicode-documents">
  <title>Opening and Saving Documents with Unsupported Characters</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Special characters<indexterm>Unsupported characters</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Special characters<indexterm>Unrecognized characters</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>When loading documents, <ph product="editor author developer"><ph keyref="product"/> reads
        the document prolog to determine the specified encoding type.</ph>
      <ph product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse"><ph keyref="product"/> receives the
        encoding of the document from the Eclipse platform.</ph> This encoding is then used to
      instruct the Java Encoder to load support for and to save the document using the specified
      code chart. <ph product="editor author developer">When the encoding type cannot be determined,
          <ph keyref="product"/> displays the <uicontrol>Available Java Encodings</uicontrol> dialog
        box that provides a list of all encodings supported by the Java platform.</ph></p>
    <section id="opening_documents_with_unsupported_characters_fbr"
      product="author developer editor">
      <title>Opening Documents with Unsupported Characters</title>
      <p>When opening a document in <ph keyref="product"/>, if it contains characters that are not
        supported by the specified encoding standard (these unrecognized characters are rendered as
        an empty box <image href="../img/Unrecognized_Char.png"/>), the application determines how
        to handle them based upon the setting specified in the <xref
          href="preferences-encoding.dita#preferences-encoding/encoding-errors-handling"
            ><uicontrol>Encoding Errors Handling</uicontrol> option in the
            <uicontrol>Encoding</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>. The default setting is
          <uicontrol>REPORT</uicontrol>, which means an error message is displayed for characters
        that cannot be represented in the specified encoding. If the option is set to
          <uicontrol>REPLACE</uicontrol>, the character is replaced with a standard replacement
        character for the particular encoding. If the option is set to
        <uicontrol>IGNORE</uicontrol>, the error is ignored and the character is not rendered.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="saving_documents_with_unsupported_characters">
      <title>Saving Documents with Unsupported Characters</title>
      <p product="editor author developer">When saving a document edited in the
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol>
        modes, if it contains characters that are not supported by the encoding declared in the
        document prolog, <ph keyref="product"/> displays a notification that you need to resolve the
        conflict before saving the document.</p>
      <p product="author editor">When saving a document edited in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        mode, all characters that fall outside the detected encoding will be automatically converted
        to hexadecimal character entities.</p>
      <p>When saving a document with UTF-16 encoding, the saved document has a Byte Order Mark (BOM)
        that specifies the byte order of the document content. The default byte order is
        platform-dependent. That means that a UTF-16 document created on a Windows platform (where
        the default byte order mark is <i>UnicodeLittle</i>) has a different BOM than one created on
        a Mac OS platform (where the byte order mark is <i>UnicodeBig</i>). The byte order and the
        BOM of an existing document are preserved when the document is edited and saved. <ph
          product="author developer editor"> This behavior can be changed in <ph keyref="product"/>
          from the <xref href="preferences-encoding.dita"><uicontrol>Encoding</uicontrol>
            preferences page</xref>.</ph></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
