<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="open-local-file-from-cmd">
  <title>Opening Local Files at Start-up from Command Line</title>
  <body>
    <p>To open a local file at start-up when you open <ph keyref="product"/> from the command line,
      add the paths for one or more local files as parameters in the command line:<ul>
        <li><synph>scriptName <parmname>[pathToXMLFile1]</parmname>
            <parmname>[pathToXMLFile2]</parmname> ...</synph> where <parmname>scriptName</parmname>
          is the name of the startup script for your platform (<ph product="editor">oxygen.bat</ph>
          <ph product="author">
            <filepath>oxygenAuthor.bat</filepath>
          </ph><ph product="developer">
            <filepath>oxygenDeveloper.bat</filepath>
          </ph> on Windows, <ph product="editor">
            <filepath>oxygen.sh</filepath>
          </ph>
          <ph product="author">
            <filepath>oxygenAuthor.sh</filepath>
          </ph><ph product="developer">
            <filepath>oxygenDeveloper.sh</filepath>
          </ph> on Unix/Linux, <ph product="editor">
            <filepath>oxygenMac.sh</filepath>
          </ph><ph product="author">
            <filepath>oxygenAuthorMac.sh</filepath>
          </ph><ph product="developer">
            <filepath>oxygenDeveloperMac.sh</filepath>
          </ph> on Mac OS) and <i>
            <filepath>pathToXMLFileN</filepath>
          </i> is the name of a local XML file.</li>
        <li product="editor developer">
          <p>an XML file and a schema file to be associated automatically to the file and used for
            validation and content completion:
            <screen>scriptName -instance pathToXMLFile -schema pathToSchemaFile -schemaType XML_SCHEMA|DTD_SCHEMA|RNG_SCHEMA|RNC_SCHEMA -dtName documentTypeName</screen>where
              <cmdname>scriptName</cmdname> is the name of the startup script for your platform
            (oxygen.bat on Windows, oxygen.sh on Unix/Linux, oxygenMac.sh on Mac OS),
              <parmname>pathToXMLFile</parmname> is the name of a local XML file,
              <parmname>pathToSchemaFile</parmname> is the name of the schema which you want to
            associate to the XML file, the four constants (XML_SCHEMA, DTD_SCHEMA, RNG_SCHEMA,
            RNC_SCHEMA) are the possible schema types (W3C XML Schema, DTD, Relax NG schema in full
            syntax, Relax NG schema in compact syntax). The next parameter,
              <parmname>documentTypeName</parmname>, specifies the name of the <i>Document Type</i>
            for which the schema is defined. If the Document Type is already set in preferences, its
            schema and type are updated.</p>
        </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The two possibilities of opening files at startup by specifying them in the command line are
      explained also if the startup script receives one of the <i>-h</i> or <i>--help</i>
      parameters. </p>
  </body>
</topic>
