<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="open-save-Unicode-documents">
  <title>Opening and Saving Unicode Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit<indexterm>Unicode documents</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>When loading documents, <ph product="editor author developer"><ph
          keyref="product"/> reads the document prolog
        to determine the specified encoding type.</ph>
      <ph product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse"><ph
          keyref="product"/> receives the encoding of
        the document from the Eclipse platform.</ph> This encoding is then used to instruct the Java
      Encoder to load support for and to save the document using the specified code chart. <ph
        product="editor author developer">When the encoding type cannot be determined, <ph
          keyref="product"/> prompts and display the
          <uicontrol>Available Java Encodings</uicontrol> dialog which provides a list of all
        encodings supported by the Java platform.</ph></p>
    <p product="editor author developer">If the opened document contains an unsupported character,
        <ph keyref="product"/> applies <xref
        href="preferences-encoding.dita">the policy specified for handling such errors.</xref> If
      the policy is set to REPORT, <ph keyref="product"
      /> displays an error dialog about the character not allowed by the encoding. If the policy is
      set to IGNORE, the character is removed from the document displayed in the editor panel. If
      the policy is set to REPLACE, the character is replaced with a standard replacement character
      for that encoding.</p>
    <p>While in most cases you are using UTF-8, simply changing the encoding name causes the
      application to save the file using the new encoding.</p>
    <p product="editor author developer">On saving the edited document, if it contains characters
      not included in the encoding declared in the document prolog <ph
        keyref="product"/> detects the problem and
      signals it to the user. The user is responsible to resolve the conflict before saving the
      document.</p>
    <p>To edit documents written in Japanese or Chinese, change the font to one that supports the
      specific characters (a Unicode font). For the Windows platform, <i>Arial Unicode MS</i> or
        <i>MS Gothic</i> is recommended. Do not expect <i>Wordpad</i> or <i>Notepad</i> to handle
      these encodings. Use <i>Internet Explorer</i> or <i>Word</i> to examine XML documents.</p>
    <p>When a document with a UTF-16 encoding is edited and saved in <ph
        keyref="product"/>, the saved document has a
      byte order mark (BOM) which specifies the byte order of the document content. The default byte
      order is platform-dependent. That means that a UTF-16 document created on a Windows platform
      (where the default byte order mark is <i>UnicodeLittle</i>) has a different BOM than a UTF-16
      document created on a Mac OS platform (where the byte order mark is <i>UnicodeBig</i>). The
      byte order and the BOM of an existing document are preserved when the document is edited and
      saved. <ph product="editor author svnClient">This behavior can be changed in <ph
          keyref="product"/> from the <xref
          href="preferences-encoding.dita">Encoding preferences panel</xref>.</ph>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
