<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="openapi-framework">
  <title>OpenAPI (Swagger) Document Type (Framework)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Supported frameworks<indexterm>OpenAPI</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>OpenAPI document type</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Swagger</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_mtk_cgk_54b"><b>OpenAPI</b> specification, previously known as Swagger specification,
      is a specification that defines a standard, programming language-agnostic interface
      description for HTTP APIs, which allows both humans and computers to discover and understand
      the capabilities of a service without requiring access to source code, additional
      documentation, or inspection of network traffic. Use cases for machine-readable API definition
      documents include interactive documentation, code generation for documentation, automation of
      test cases, and more. OpenAPI documents describe an APIs services and are represented in
      either YAML or JSON formats.</p>
    <p id="p_kmh_nyf_ktb"><ph keyref="product"/> includes three OpenAPI frameworks:<ul
        id="ul_r3c_qyf_ktb">
        <li id="li_s3c_qyf_ktb">OpenAPI 2.0</li>
        <li id="li_r2l_qyf_ktb">OpenAPI 3.0</li>
        <li id="li_czt_qyf_ktb">OpenAPI 3.1</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="section_xj4_pxf_ktb">
      <title>Editing OpenAPI Documents</title>
      <p id="p_ntk_cgk_54b">In <ph keyref="product"/>, you can, of course, edit OpenAPI documents in
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, but <ph keyref="product"/> also includes a built-in
        framework that renders OpenAPI (Swagger) documents in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        visual editing mode. When opening a detected OpenAPI document in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, you will have access to some form controls,
        collapsible sections, and other features to help you visualize and edit these
          documents.<note type="tip" id="note_otk_cgk_54b">There is an OpenAPI sample document named
            <filepath>petsore.json</filepath> located in
            <filepath>[OXYGEN-INSTALL-DIR]/samples/json/openapi</filepath> that you can use to see
          how these documents are rendered in <ph keyref="product"/>.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_rm1_txf_ktb">
      <title>Validation and Content Completion</title>
      <p id="p_sm1_txf_ktb">Validation and content completion is supported in <ph keyref="product"/>
        for OpenAPI documents (version 2.0, 3.0, 3.1). The validation and content completion in
        OpenAPI documents are driven by schemas according to the OpenAPI version in the document.
        Each of the three frameworks (OpenAPI 2.0, OpenAPI 3.0, and OpenAPI 3.1) have a unique
        schema specified for content completion and validation. When opening an OpenAPI document (in
        JSON or YAML format), <ph keyref="product"/> automatically associates the corresponding
        schema based on the OpenAPI version of the document.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_vvs_vvd_1rb">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <ul id="ul_rll_xfn_dtb">
        <li>​ <ph keyref="product"/> ​includes a tool for generating documentation for ​ ​OpenAPI​
          components in HTML format: <xref href="openapi-documentation-generator.dita"/></li>
        <li><ph keyref="product"/> includes a testing tool for <term>OpenAPI</term> files: <xref
            href="openapi-tester.dita"/></li>
        <li id="li_us3_yfn_dtb">For more details about the <i>OpenAPI Specification</i>, along with
          example documents, go to <xref href="https://spec.openapis.org/oas/latest.html"
            format="html" scope="external"/>.</li>
        <li id="li_fzt_xfn_dtb">
          <p id="p_nll_dgk_54bc">For more information about OpenAPI editing, testing, and
            documenting, watch our webinar:</p>
          <p id="p_oll_dgk_54bd"><object width="450" height="250"
              data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gKdabeh49Qk" outputclass="iframe">
              <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
            </object></p>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
