<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="openapi-framework">
  <title>OpenAPI (Swagger) Document Type (Framework)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Supported frameworks<indexterm>OpenAPI</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>OpenAPI document type</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Swagger</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <b>OpenAPI</b> specification is a community-driven open specification that defines a
      standard, programming language-agnostic interface description for HTTP APIs, which allows both
      humans and computers to discover and understand the capabilities of a service without
      requiring access to source code, additional documentation, or inspection of network traffic.
      Use cases for machine-readable API definition documents include interactive documentation,
      code generation for documentation, automation of test cases, and more. OpenAPI documents
      describe an APIs services and are represented in either YAML or JSON formats.</p>
    <p>In <ph keyref="product"/>, you can, of course, edit OpenAPI documents in
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, but <ph keyref="product"/> also includes a built-in
      framework that renders OpenAPI (Swagger) documents in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> visual
      editing mode. The framework is an extension of the JSON framework. When opening a detected
      OpenAPI document in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, you will have access to some form
      controls, collapsible sections, and other features to help you visualize and edit these
        documents.<note type="tip">There is an OpenAPI sample document named
          <filepath>petsore.json</filepath> located in
          <filepath>[OXYGEN-INSTALL-DIR]/samples/json/openapi</filepath> that you can use to see how
        these documents are rendered in <ph keyref="product"/>.</note></p>
    <p>For more details about the <i>OpenAPI Specification</i>, along with example documents, go to
        <xref href="https://github.com/OAI/OpenAPI-Specification" format="html" scope="external"
      />.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
