<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="operations-repos">
  <title>Copy / Move / Delete Resources From a Repository</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>working with repositories<indexterm>copy/move/delete
            resources</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Once you have a location defined in the <xref href="repository-view.dita"
          ><uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view</xref>, you can execute commands like copy, move
      and delete directly on the repository. The commands correspond to the following actions in the
      contextual menu:</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Copy to</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Move to</uicontrol> action allows you to
      copy and move individual or multiple resources to a specific directory from the
        <term>HEAD</term> revision of the repository.<fig>
        <title>Copy/Move Items in Repository</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_svn_copy_move_repos.png"/>
      </fig></p>
    <p>The dialog box used to copy or move items allows you to browse the <term>HEAD</term> revision
      of the repository and select the destination of the items, presenting its repository URL below
      the tree view.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> section presents relevant options regarding the item(s)
      that you move or copy:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> - this field is displayed only if you copy/move a single
          item;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Revision</uicontrol> - presents the revision from which you copy one or more
          items, allowing you to also choose another revision;<note>Since only items from the HEAD
            revision can be moved, the <uicontrol>Revision</uicontrol> options are not presented for
            the <uicontrol>Move to</uicontrol> action.</note><note>When you copy a single item while
            browsing a revision other than <term>HEAD</term>, the <uicontrol>Revision</uicontrol>
            options present this revision but does not allow you to change it. The same applies if
            copying multiple items.</note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>New name</uicontrol> - This option is presented when you copy or move a
          single item, allowing you to also rename it.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>Another useful action is <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>, allowing you to erase resources
      directly from the repository.</p>
    <p>All three actions are commit operations and you will be prompted with the <uicontrol>Commit
        message</uicontrol> dialog.</p>
  </body>
</topic>