<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_x4m_2x1_12">
  <title>Configuring Options</title>
  <body>
    <p>A set of options controls <ph
        keyref="product"/>, allowing you to
      configure most of the features. To offer you the highest degree of flexibility in customizing
      the application to fit the end-user's role in your organization, <ph
        keyref="product"/> comes with several
      distinct layers of option values, arranged here according to their priority, from low to
      high:</p>
    <p>
      <ul id="ul_ddg_vcb_12">
        <li><term>Default Options</term> - should be regarded as factory defaults or built-in
            values.<p>This predefined set of values are tuned so <ph
              keyref="product"/> behaves
            optimally in most working environments.</p></li>
        <li><xref href="default-options.dita#default-options" format="dita"><term>Customized Default
              Options</term></xref> - designed to customize the initial option values for a group of
          users. <p>This layer allows an administrator to deploy the application preconfigured with
            a standardized set of option values.<note>Once this layer is set, it represents the
              initial state of <ph
                keyref="product"/> when an
              end-user presses the <uicontrol>Restore defaults</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Reset
                Global Options</uicontrol> buttons.</note></p></li>
        <li><xref href="preferences.dita#preferences" format="dita"><term>Global
            Options</term></xref> - allows individual users to personalize <ph
            keyref="product"/> according to
          their specific needs.</li>
        <li product="author developer editor"><xref
            href="preferences-sharing.dita#preferences-sharing" format="dita"><term>Project
              Options</term></xref> - allow project managers to establish a set of rules for a
          specific project. These rules standardize the information exchanged by the team members
          (for example, if the project is stored in a repository, a common set of formatting rules
          avoid conflicts that may appear when documents modified by different team members are
          committed to the repository).</li>
      </ul>
      <fig product="author developer editor">
        <title>Option lookup priority</title>
        <image id="image_5kd_jch_12" href="../img/Option-Lookup-Priority.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <note>If you set a specific option in one of the layers, but it is not applied in the
      application, make sure that one of the higher priority layers is not overwriting it.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
