<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="options-tab-sample-xml-files">
  <title>Options Tab (Generate Sample XML Files Tool)</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/XMLGenerator16.png"/>Generate Sample XML Files</uicontrol>
      tool includes a dialog box that allows you to configure a variety of options for generating
      the XML files. The <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> tab allows you to set specific options for
      namespaces and elements.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Generate Sample XML Files Dialog Box (Options Tab)</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_generate_xml_dialog_options.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>This tab includes the following options:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Namespace / Element</uicontrol> table</dt>
          <dd>Allows you to set a namespace for each element name that appears in an XML document
            instance. The following prefix-to-namespace associations are available:<ul>
              <li>All elements from all namespaces (<codeph>&lt;ANY></codeph> -
                  <codeph>&lt;ANY></codeph>). This is the default setting.</li>
              <li>All elements from a specific namespace.</li>
              <li>A specific element from a specific namespace.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> subtab</dt>
          <dd>
            <dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Displays the namespace specified in the table at the top of the dialog box.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Element</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Displays the element specified in the table at the top of the dialog box.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Generate optional elements</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>When checked, all elements are generated, including the optional ones (having
                  the <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> attribute set to 0 in the schema).</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Generate optional attributes</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>When checked, all attributes are generated, including the optional ones (having
                  the <codeph>use</codeph> attribute set to <codeph>optional</codeph> in the
                  schema).</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Values of elements and attributes</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Controls the content of generated attribute and element values. The following
                  choices are available: <ul>
                    <li><uicontrol>None</uicontrol> - No content is inserted.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Default</uicontrol> - Inserts a default value depending of data
                      type descriptor of the particular element or attribute. The default value can
                      be either the data type name or an incremental name of the attribute or
                      element (according to the global option from the <uicontrol>XML Instances
                        Generator</uicontrol> preferences page). Note that type restrictions are
                      ignored when this option is enabled. For example, if an element is of a type
                      that restricts an <uicontrol>xs:string</uicontrol> with the
                        <uicontrol>xs:maxLength</uicontrol> facet to allow strings with a maximum
                      length of 3, the XML instance generator tool may generate string element
                      values longer than 3 characters.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - Inserts a random value depending of data
                      type descriptor of the particular element or attribute.<note type="important"
                        >If all of the following are true, the <uicontrol>XML Instances
                          Generator</uicontrol> outputs invalid values:<ul>
                          <li>At least one of the restrictions is a <codeph>regexp</codeph>.</li>
                          <li>The value generated after applying the regexp does not match the
                            restrictions imposed by one of the facets.</li>
                        </ul></note></li>
                  </ul></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Preferred number of repetitions</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Allows you to set the preferred number of repeating elements related to
                    <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> and <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph> facets defined in the
                  XML Schema. <ul>
                    <li>If the value set here is between <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> and
                        <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph>, then that value is used.</li>
                    <li>If the value set here is less than <codeph>minOccurs</codeph>, then the
                        <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> value is used.</li>
                    <li>If the value set here is greater than <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph>, then
                        <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph> is used.</li>
                  </ul></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Maximum recursion level</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>If a recursion is found, this option controls the maximum allowed depth of the
                  same element.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Type alternative strategy</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Used for the <codeph>xs:alternative</codeph> element from XML Schema 1.1. The
                  possible strategies are:<ul>
                    <li><uicontrol>First</uicontrol> - The first valid alternative type is always
                      used.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - A random alternative type is used.</li>
                  </ul></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Choice strategy</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Used for <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> or <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph>
                  elements. The possible strategies are:<ul>
                    <li><uicontrol>First</uicontrol> - The first branch of
                        <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> or the head element of
                        <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph> is always used.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - A random branch of
                        <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> or a substitute element or the head element of a
                        <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph> is used.</li>
                  </ul></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Generate the other options as comments</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>If enabled, generates the other possible choices or substitutions (for
                    <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> and <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph>). These
                  alternatives are generated inside comments groups so you can uncomment and use
                  them later. Use this option with care (for example, on a restricted namespace and
                  element) as it may generate large result files.</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Element values</uicontrol> subtab</dt>
          <dd>Allows you to add values that are used to generate the content of elements. If there
            is more than one value, then the values are used in a random order.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Attribute values</uicontrol> subtab</dt>
          <dd>Allows you to add values that are used to generate the content of attributes. If there
            is more than one value, then the values are used in a random order.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Load settings</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this button to load previously exported settings.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Export settings</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this button to save the current settings for future use.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>You can click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> at any point to generate the sample XML files.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
