<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="options-tab-sample-xml-files">
  <title>The Options Tab</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> tab allows you to set specific options for different
      namespaces and elements.</p>
    <fig product="editor developer">
      <title>The Generate Sample XML Files Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_generate_xml_dialog_options.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Generate Sample XML Files Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_generate_xml_dialog_options.png"/>
    </fig>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Namespace / Element table</uicontrol> - Allows you to set a namespace for each
        element name that appears in an XML document instance. The following prefix-to-namespace
        associations are available:<ul>
          <li>All elements from all namespaces (&lt;ANY> - &lt;ANY>). This is the default setting
            and can be customized from the <xref
              href="preferences-xml-instances-generator.dita#preferences-xml-instances-generator"
              format="dita">XML Instances Generator</xref> preferences page.</li>
          <li>All elements from a specific namespace.</li>
          <li>A specific element from a specific namespace.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Generate optional elements</uicontrol> - When checked, all elements are
            generated, including the optional ones (having the <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> attribute
            set to 0 in the schema).</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Generate optional attributes</uicontrol> - When checked, all attributes are
            generated, including the optional ones (having the <codeph>use</codeph> attribute set to
              <codeph>optional</codeph> in the schema.)</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Values of elements and attributes</uicontrol> - Controls the content of
            generated attribute and element values. Several choices are available: <ul>
              <li><uicontrol>None</uicontrol> - No content is inserted;</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Default</uicontrol> - Inserts a default value depending of data type
                descriptor of the particular element or attribute. The default value can be either
                the data type name or an incremental name of the attribute or element (according to
                the global option from the <uicontrol>XML Instances Generator</uicontrol>
                preferences page). Note that type restrictions are ignored when this option is
                enabled. For example, if an element is of a type that restricts an
                  <uicontrol>xs:string</uicontrol> with the <uicontrol>xs:maxLength</uicontrol>
                facet in order to allow strings with a maximum length of 3, the XML instance
                generator tool may generate string element values longer than 3 characters.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - Inserts a random value depending of data type
                descriptor of the particular element or attribute.<note type="important">
                  <p>If all of the following are true, the <uicontrol>XML Instances
                      Generator</uicontrol> outputs invalid values:<ul>
                      <li>at least one of the restrictions is a regexp;</li>
                      <li>the value generated after applying the regexp does not match the
                        restrictions imposed by one of the facets.</li>
                    </ul>This limitation leads to attributes or elements with values set to
                      <i>Invalid</i>.</p>
                </note></li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Preferred number of repetitions</uicontrol> - Allows the user to set the
            preferred number of repeating elements related with <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> and
              <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph> facets defined in XML Schema. <ul>
              <li>If the value set here is between <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> and
                  <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph>, then that value is used;</li>
              <li>If the value set here is less than <codeph>minOccurs</codeph>, then the
                  <codeph>minOccurs</codeph> value is used;</li>
              <li>If the value set here is greater than <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph>, then
                  <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph> is used.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Maximum recursion level</uicontrol> - If a recursion is found, this option
            controls the maximum allowed depth of the same element.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Choice strategy</uicontrol> - Option used in case of
              <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> or <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph> elements. The
            possible strategies are:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>First</uicontrol> - the first branch of <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> or
                the head element of <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph> is always used;</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - a random branch of <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> or a
                substitute element or the head element of a <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph> is
                used.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Generate the other options as comments</uicontrol> - Option to generate the
            other possible choices or substitutions (for <codeph>xs:choice</codeph> and
              <codeph>substitutionGroup</codeph>). These alternatives are generated inside comments
            groups so you can uncomment and use them later. Use this option with care (for example
            on a restricted namespace and element) as it may generate large result files.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Load settings / Export settings</uicontrol> - The current settings can be
            saved for further usage with the <uicontrol>Export settings</uicontrol> button, and
            reloaded when necessary with the <uicontrol>Load settings</uicontrol> button.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Element values</uicontrol> - The <uicontrol>Element values</uicontrol> tab
        allows you to add values that are used to generate the elements content. If there are more
        than one value, then the values are used in a random order.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Attribute values</uicontrol> - The <uicontrol>Attribute values</uicontrol> tab
        allows you to add values that are used to generate the attributes content. If there are more
        than one value, then the values are used in a random order.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
