<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="oracle-xml-schema-repository-level">
  <title>Oracle's XML Schema Repository Level</title>
  <body>
    <p>The Oracle database supports XML schema repository (XSR) in the database catalogs. The
      contextual menu of a <uicontrol>
        <image href="../img/bt_db_xml_schemas_repo.png"/> XML Schema Repository </uicontrol> node of
      the tree from the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view contains the following
      actions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_refresh.png"/> Refresh </uicontrol> - Performs a refresh
        of the selected node's subtree.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Register</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog for adding a new schema file in the XML
        repository. To add an XML Schema, enter the schema URI and location on your file system.
        Local scope means that the schema will be visible only to the user who registers it. Global
        scope means that the schema is public.<note>Registering a schema may involve
          dropping/creating types. Hence you need type-related privileges such as DROP TYPE, CREATE
          TYPE, and ALTER TYPE.  You need privileges to delete and register the XML schemas involved
          in the registering process. You need all privileges on XMLType tables that conform to the
          registered schemas. For XMLType columns, the ALTER TABLE privilege is needed on
          corresponding tables. If there are schema-based XMLType tables or columns in other
          database schemas, you need privileges such as the following:<ul>
            <li>CREATE ANY TABLE</li>
            <li>
              <p>CREATE ANY INDEX</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>SELECT ANY TABLE</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>UPDATE ANY TABLE</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>INSERT ANY TABLE</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>DELETE ANY TABLE</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>DROP ANY TABLE</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>ALTER ANY TABLE</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>DROP ANY INDEX</p>
            </li>
          </ul> To avoid having to grant all these privileges to the schema owner, Oracle recommends
          that the registration be performed by a DBA if there are XML schema-based XMLType table or
          columns in other users' database schemas.</note></li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
