<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="outliner-view">
  <title>Outline View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing XML Documents<indexterm>document navigation<indexterm>outline
              view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Outline View</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view displays a general tag overview of the currently
      edited XML Document. It also shows the correct hierarchical dependencies between elements.
      This makes it easier for you to be aware of the document structure and the way element tags
      are nested. It allows for fast navigation of the document by displaying the start of the
      content of the child elements in the node of the parent element, thus allowing you to quickly
      see the content of an element without expanding it in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> tree.
      It also allows you to insert or delete nodes using contextual menu actions.</p>
    <p>The outline view has the following functions: XML document overview, outline filters,
      modification follow-up, document structure change, document tag selection.</p>
    <p>The upper part of the view contains a filter box that allows you to focus on the relevant
      components. If you type a text fragment in the filter box, the components that match it are
      presented. For advanced usage you can use wildcards (*, ?) and separate multiple patterns with
      commas.</p>
    <p>The Outline view offers the following functionality:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><xref href="overview-outliner.dita"/></li>
      <li><xref href="followup-outliner.dita"/></li>
      <li><xref href="structure-change-outliner.dita"/></li>
      <li><xref href="filters-outliner.dita"/></li>
      <li><xref href="outliner-popup-menu.dita#outliner-popup-menu"/></li>
      <li><xref href="selection-outliner.dita"/></li>
    </ul>
    <fig id="figure-outliner-view-oxygen" product="editor author developer">
      <title>The Outline View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_outliner_panel.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="figure-outliner-view-oxygenEclipse"
      product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Outline View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_outliner_panel.png"/>
    </fig>
  </body>
</topic>
