<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="overview">
    <title>Overview</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>What is Content Fusion</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Introduction</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p><ph keyref="product"/> is a flexible, intuitive collaboration platform designed to adapt
      to virtually any type of workflow that a collaborative team may use for their documentation
      life cycle. It allows a <b>Content Author</b> to upload documents that need to be reviewed by
      subject matter experts or other team members. The <b>Reviewers</b> simply follow a link to
      open <ph keyref="product"/> in a browser where they can access the uploaded documents to
      review, add comments, or contribute changes. They can share the files with other
        <b>Reviewers</b> and all of them can communicate with each other and the <b>Content
        Author</b> directly from the <ph keyref="product"/> interface. Ultimately, the <b>Content
        Author</b> has access to a <i>Merge</i> tool that allows them to automatically integrate all
      of the changes back into Oxygen XML Editor or Oxygen XML Author.</p>
    <p>Since every team has their own specific methods of collaborating, <ph keyref="product"/> was
      designed to be as flexible as possible so that it can be used and integrated into any
      documentation workflow. Thus, you can use whatever type of workflow you want, but the most
      common and basic use-case is something like this:<ol>
        <li>The <b>Content Author</b> has written some content that needs to be reviewed by
          others.</li>
        <li>The <b>Content Author</b> creates a task, attaches the files, and uploaded them to the
            <ph keyref="product"/> server.</li>
        <li>The <b>Content Author</b> shares a link to the task with a <b>Reviewer</b>.</li>
        <li>The <b>Reviewer</b> follows the link to open the <ph keyref="product"/> interface in a
          browser where they can access the task.</li>
        <li>The <b>Reviewer</b> clicks on the files to open them in an online visual editor where
          they can proofread, add comments, and make changes.</li>
        <li>Once they are finished, the <b>Reviewer</b> simply clicks the <uicontrol>Finalize
            Review</uicontrol> button or adds a message in the <ph keyref="product"/> interface to
          let the <b>Content Author</b> know they are finished.</li>
        <li>The <b>Content Author</b> pulls the changes and automatically merges them back into the
          original documentation. </li>
      </ol></p>
    </body>
</topic>
