<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="overview">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Introduction to Content Fusion</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_dht_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> is a collaboration solution that is flexible and
      intuitive, making it suitable for any type of workflow used by a collaborative team during the
      documentation review process. It provides a platform where a writer can upload documents that
      need to be reviewed in the form of a review task, the reviewers can access the documents in a
      browser where they can review the content, add comments, or contribute changes. They can
      communicate with each other directly from the <ph keyref="product"/> interface and ultimately,
      the task owner has access to a <xref href="cf-projects-workspace-conflict-resolution.dita"
        >built-in <i>Merge</i> tool</xref> to automatically integrate all the changes back into
        <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.</p>
    <p id="p_qn5_z5m_42c">The <xref href="cf-projects.dita">Content Fusion projects support</xref>
      allows you to connect to an existing Git repository that has a DITA project as its source.
      Users with a <i>Content Fusion Author</i> role can create review tasks inside a project and
      reviewers' suggestions are tracked on a dedicated branch in the Git repository. You can also
      build and configure deliverables for creating PDF or WebHelp output. Additionally, Content
      Fusion projects allow authors to make changes across multiple files and then commit them to
      the project.</p>
    <section id="resources">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p>For in-depth visual looks at <ph keyref="product"/>, see the following resources:<ul
          id="ul_bzc_455_ypb">
          <li id="li_if5_gv5_ypb">Webinar: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/events/2025/webinar_introducing_oxygen_content_fusion_cloud.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Introducing Oxygen Content Fusion
            Cloud</b></xref></li>
          <li id="li_if5_gv5_ypb2">Webinar: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/events/2021/webinar_engage_everyone_in_the_technical_documentationprocess.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Oxygen Content Fusion: Engage everyone in the
                technical documentation process</b></xref></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
