<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="overview">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>What is Content Fusion</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Introduction</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_dht_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> is a collaboration solution that is flexible and
      intuitive, making it suitable for any type of workflow used by a collaborative team during the
      documentation review process. It provides a platform for a <b>Content Author</b> to upload
      documents that need to be reviewed, the <b>Reviewers</b> simply follow a link to access the
      documents in a browser where they can review the content, add comments, or contribute changes.
      They can communicate with the <b>Content Author</b> or other <b>Reviewers</b> directly from
      the <ph keyref="product"/> interface and ultimately, the <b>Content Author</b> has access to a
      built-in <i>Merge</i> tool to automatically integrate all of the changes back into
        <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>.</p>
    <p id="p_eht_dgk_54b">Since every team has their own specific methods of collaborating, <ph
        keyref="product"/> was designed to be as flexible as possible so that it can be used and
      integrated in any documentation workflow. Therefore, you can use whatever type of workflow you
      want, but the most common and basic use-case is something like this:<ol id="ol_fht_dgk_54b">
        <li id="li_ght_dgk_54b">The <b>Content Author</b> has written some content that needs to be
          reviewed by others.</li>
        <li id="li_hht_dgk_54b">The <b>Content Author</b> creates a task, attaches the files, and
          uploaded a snapshot of them to the <ph keyref="product"/> server.</li>
        <li id="li_iht_dgk_54b">The <b>Content Author</b> shares a link to the task with a
            <b>Reviewer</b>.</li>
        <li id="li_jht_dgk_54b">The <b>Reviewer</b> follows the link to open the <ph
            keyref="product"/> interface in a browser where they can access the task.</li>
        <li id="li_kht_dgk_54b">The <b>Reviewer</b> clicks on the files to open them in an online
          visual editor where they can proofread, add comments, and make changes.</li>
        <li id="li_lht_dgk_54b">Once they are finished, the <b>Reviewer</b> simply clicks the
            <uicontrol>Finalize Review</uicontrol> button or adds a message in the <ph
            keyref="product"/> interface to let the <b>Content Author</b> know they are
          finished.</li>
        <li id="li_mht_dgk_54b">The <b>Content Author</b> can compare changes made by the
            <b>Reviewer</b> by using a <i>diff</i> link that is available in the left-side activity
          stream for every file change.</li>
        <li id="li_nht_dgk_54b">The <b>Content Author</b> pulls the changes and automatically merges
          the snapshot back into the original documentation.</li>
        <li id="li_oht_dgk_54b">The <b>Content Author</b> accepts or rejects the suggested changes
          and commits to their repository.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <section id="resources">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p>For in-depth visual looks at <ph keyref="product"/>, see the following resources:<ul
          id="ul_bzc_455_ypb">
          <li id="li_if5_gv5_ypb">Webinar: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/events/2021/webinar_engage_everyone_in_the_technical_documentationprocess.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Oxygen Content Fusion: Engage everyone in the
                technical documentation process</b></xref>.</li>
          <li id="li_if5_gv5_ypb2">Video: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/content_fusion/6_beta.html" format="html"
              scope="external"><b>Exploring the New Features Added in Content Fusion 6.0 (Beta
                version)</b></xref></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
