<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="oxy-editor-properties">
  <title>oxy_editor() Properties and Common Content</title>
  <shortdesc>List of properties of the supported form controls</shortdesc>
  <body>
    <p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <p id="edit_property"><codeph>edit</codeph> - lets you edit the value of an attribute, the
            text content of an element or Processing Instructions (PIs). This property can have the
            following values:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>@attribute_name</uicontrol> - The name of the attribute who's value is
                being edited. If the attribute is in a namespace the value of the property must be a
                QName and the CSS must have a namespace declaration for the
                prefix:<pre>@namespace fc "http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/samples/form-controls";
myElement {
    content: oxy_editor(
        type, combo,
        edit,  "@fc:my_attr"
    )
}</pre></li>
              <li><uicontrol>#text</uicontrol> - specifies that the presented/edited value is the
                simple text value of an element.<note>You can set the value of the
                    <codeph>visibility</codeph> property to <codeph>-oxy-collapse-text</codeph> to
                  render the text only in the form control that the oxy_editor function
                  specifies</note></li>
            </ul></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p id="contentType_property"><codeph>contentType</codeph> - specifies the type of content
            for which the form control offers syntax highlight. The following values are supported:
              <codeph>text/css; text/shell; text/cc; text/xquery; text/xml; text/python; text/xsd;
              text/c; text/xpath; text/javascript; text/xsl; text/wsdl; text/html; text/xproc;
              text/properties; text/sql; text/rng; text/sch; text/json; text/perl; text/php;
              text/java; text/batch; text/rnc; text/dtd; text/nvdl; text/plain</codeph>;</p>
        </li>
        <li><ph id="indentOnTab_property"><codeph>indentOnTab</codeph> - specifies the behaviour of
            the <uicontrol>Tab</uicontrol> key. If the value of this property is set to
              <uicontrol>true</uicontrol>, the <uicontrol>Tab</uicontrol> key inserts characters. If
            it is set to <uicontrol>false</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Tab</uicontrol> is used for
            navigation, jumping to the next editable position in the document</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="text-property"><codeph>text</codeph> - this property specifies the built-in form
            control you are using</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="actionContext-property"><codeph>actionContext</codeph> - specifies the context
            in which the action associated with the form control is executed. Its possible values
            are <codeph>element</codeph> and <codeph>caret</codeph>. If you select the
              <codeph>element</codeph> value, the context is the element that holds the form
            control. If you select the <codeph>caret</codeph> value, the action is invoked at the
            caret location. In case the caret is not inside the element that holds the form control,
            the <codeph>element</codeph> value is selected automatically</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="columns-property"><codeph>columns</codeph> - controls the width of the form
            control. The unit size is the width of the <uicontrol>w</uicontrol> character</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="fontInherit-property"><codeph>fontInherit</codeph> - this value specifies
            whether the form control inherits its font from its parent element. The values of this
            property can be <codeph>true</codeph>, or <codeph>false</codeph></ph></li>
        <li><ph id="values-property"><codeph>values</codeph> - specifies the values that populate
            the content completion list of proposals. In case these values are not specified, they
            are collected from the associated schema</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="tooltips-property"><codeph>tooltips</codeph> - associates tooltips to each value
            in the <codeph>values</codeph> property. The value of this property are a list of
            tooltips separated by commas. In case you want the tooltip to display a comma, use the
              <codeph>${comma}</codeph> variable</ph>. The property will be ignored if the number of
          tooltips and the number of values don't match.</li>
        <li><ph id="tooltip-property"><codeph>tooltip</codeph> - specifies a tooltip for the form
            control itself. This tooltip is displayed when you hover the form control using your
            cursor</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="color-property"><codeph>color</codeph> - specifies the foreground color of the
            form control. In case the value of the <codeph>color</codeph> property is
              <codeph>inherit</codeph>, the form control has the same color as the element in which
            it is inserted</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="type-property"><codeph>type</codeph> - this property specifies the built-in form
            control you are using.  Only needed if you use <codeph>oxy_editor</codeph> generic
            function to add the form control</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="labels-property"><codeph>labels</codeph> - this property must have the same
            number of items as the <codeph>values</codeph> property. Each item provides a literal
            description of the items listed in the <codeph>values</codeph> property</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="resultSeparator-property"><codeph>resultSeparator</codeph> - in case multiple
            check-boxes are used, the separator is used to compose the final result</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="uncheckedValues-property"><codeph>uncheckedValues</codeph> - specifies the
            values that are committed when the check-boxes are not selected</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="property-rows"><codeph>rows</codeph> - this property specifies the number of
            rows that the form control presents</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="selectionMode-property"><codeph>selectionMode</codeph> - specifies whether the
            form control allows the selection of a single value or of multiple values. The
            predefined values of this property are <codeph>single</codeph> and
              <codeph>multiple</codeph></ph></li>
        <li><ph id="editorSort"><codeph>editorSort</codeph> - allows you to sort the values rendered
            on the pop-up window. The possible values of this property are
              <codeph>ascending</codeph> and <codeph>descending</codeph></ph></li>
        <li><ph id="rendererSort"><codeph>rendererSort</codeph> - allows you to sort the values
            rendered on the pop-up form control label. The possible values of this property are
              <codeph>ascending</codeph> and <codeph>descending</codeph></ph></li>
        <li><ph id="rendererSeparator-property"><codeph>rendererSeparator</codeph> - defines a
            separator used when multiple values are rendered</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="actionID-property"><codeph>actionID</codeph> - the ID of the action specified in
              <xref
              href="../tasks/dg-configuring-actions-menus-toolbar.dita#dg-configuring-actions-menus-toolbar"
              >Author actions</xref>, that is invoked when you click the button</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="visible-property"><codeph>visible</codeph> - specifies whether the form control
            is visible. The possible values of this property are <uicontrol>true</uicontrol> (the
            form control is visible) and <uicontrol>false</uicontrol> (the form control is not
            visible)</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="transparent-property"><codeph>transparent</codeph> - flattens the aspect of the
            button form control, removing its border and background</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="actionDisplayStyle-property"><codeph>actionStyle</codeph> - specifies what to
            display for an action in the pop-up menu. The values of this property can be text, and
            icon, or both</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="width-property"><codeph>width</codeph> - specifies the horizontal space reserved
            for the content. The value of this property has the same format as the value of the CSS
              <codeph>width</codeph> property. In case this value is not specified, the text is
            wrapped</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="background-color-property"><codeph>background-color</codeph> - specifies the
            background color of the form control. In case the value of the
              <codeph>background-color</codeph> property is <codeph>inherit</codeph>, the form
            control has the same color as the element in which it is inserted</ph></li>
        <li>
          <p id="style-property"><codeph>styles</codeph> - specifies styles for the form control.
            The values of this property are a set of CSS properties:<ul>
              <li><codeph>font-weight</codeph>, <codeph>font-size</codeph>,
                  <codeph>font-style</codeph>, <codeph>font</codeph>;</li>
              <li><codeph>text-align</codeph>, <codeph>text-decoration</codeph>;</li>
              <li><codeph>width</codeph>;</li>
              <li><codeph>color</codeph>, <codeph>background-color</codeph>.</li>
            </ul><codeblock outputclass="language-css">element{
    content: oxy_label(text, "Label Text", styles,
      "font-size:2em;color:red;");
}</codeblock></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><codeph>text-align</codeph> - specifies the alignment of the generated content in its
            reserved space. This property has three possible values:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>left</uicontrol>;</li>
              <li><uicontrol>right</uicontrol>;</li>
              <li><uicontrol>center</uicontrol>.</li>
            </ul><codeblock outputclass="language-css">element {
  content: 
    oxy_label(text, "Label1:", width, 20em, text-align, center)
    oxy_label(text, "Label2:", width, 100px, text-align, right)
}</codeblock></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p id="show_text"><codeph>showText</codeph> - specifies if the action text should be
            displayed on the button form control. If this property is missing then the button
            displays only the icon if it is available, or the text if the icon is not available. The
            values of this property can be <codeph>true</codeph> or
            <codeph>false</codeph>.<codeblock outputclass="language-css">element {
  content: oxy_button(actionID, 'remove.attribute', showText, true);
}</codeblock></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p id="show_icon"><codeph>showIcon</codeph> - specifies if the action icon should be
            displayed on the button form control. If this property is missing then the button
            displays only the icon if it is available, or the text if the icon is not available. The
            values of this property can be <codeph>true</codeph> or
            <codeph>false</codeph>.<codeblock outputclass="language-css">element {
  content: oxy_button(actionID, 'remove.attribute', showIcon, true);
}</codeblock></p>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <section>
      <title>Common Content</title>
      <ul id="ul_zdq_243_vm">
        <li><ph id="adding_form_controls">It can be added using the generic function
              <codeph>oxy_editor</codeph>. Alternatively, you can use the dedicated
          function:</ph></li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
