<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="oxy-allows-child-element">
  <title>The <codeph>oxy:allows-child-element()</codeph> Function</title>
  <shortdesc>This extension function allows author actions to be available in a context only if the
    associated schema permits it.</shortdesc>
  <body>
    <p>The oxy:allows-child-element() is evaluated at the caret position and has the following
      signature: <codeph>oxy:allows-child-element($childName, ($attributeName,
        $defaultAttributeValue, $contains?)?)</codeph>.</p>
    <p>The following parameters are supported:<parml>
        <plentry>
          <pt><codeph>childName</codeph></pt>
          <pd>the name of the element that you want to check whether it is valid in the current
            context. Its value is a string that supports the following forms:<ul>
              <li>the child element with the specified local name that belongs to the default
                namespace.<codeblock>oxy:allows-child-element("para")</codeblock>The above example
                verifies if the <keyword>para</keyword> element (of the default namespace) is
                allowed in the current context.</li>
              <li>the child element with the local name specified by any
                namespace.<codeblock>oxy:allows-child-element("*:para")</codeblock>The above example
                verifies if the <keyword>para</keyword> element (of any namespace) is allowed in the
                current context.</li>
              <li>a qualified name of an element.
                <codeblock>oxy:allows-child-element("prefix:para")</codeblock>The prefix is resolved
                in the context of the element where the caret is located. The function matches on
                the element with the <keyword>para</keyword> local name from the previous resolved
                namespace. In case the prefix is not resolved to a namespace, the function returns
                  <codeph>false</codeph>.</li>
              <li>any element.<codeblock>oxy:allows-child-element("*")</codeblock>The above function
                verifies if any element is allowed in the current context.<note>A common use case of
                    <codeph>oxy:allows-child-element("*")</codeph> is in combination with the
                    <codeph>attributeName</codeph> parameter.</note></li>
            </ul></pd>
        </plentry>
      </parml><parml>
        <plentry>
          <pt><codeph>attributeName</codeph></pt>
          <pd>the attribute of an element that you want to check whether it is valid in the current
            context. Its value is a string that supports the following forms:<ul>
              <li>the attribute with the specified name from no
                namespace.<codeblock>oxy:allows-child-element("*", "class", " topic/topic ")</codeblock>The
                above example verifies if an element with the <codeph>class</codeph> attribute and
                the default value of this attribute (that contains the <codeph>topic/topic</codeph>
                string) is allowed in the current context.</li>
              <li>the attribute with the local name specified by any
                namespace.<codeblock>oxy:allows-child-element("*", "*:localname", " topic/topic ")</codeblock></li>
              <li>a qualified name of an
                attribute.<codeblock>oxy:allows-child-element("*", "prefix:localname", " topic/topic ")</codeblock>The
                prefix is resolved in the context of the element where the caret is located. In case
                the prefix is not resolved to a namespace, the function returns
                  <codeph>false</codeph>.</li>
            </ul></pd>
        </plentry>
        <plentry>
          <pt><codeph>defaultAttributeValue</codeph></pt>
          <pd>a string that represents the default value of the attribute. Depending on the value of
            the next parameter the default value of the attribute must either contain this value or
            be equal with it.</pd>
        </plentry>
        <plentry>
          <pt><codeph>contains</codeph></pt>
          <pd>an optional boolean. The default value is <codeph>true</codeph>. For the
              <codeph>true</codeph> value, the default value of the attribute must contain the
              <codeph>defaultAttributeValue</codeph> parameter. In case the value is
              <codeph>false</codeph>, the two values must be the same.</pd>
        </plentry>
      </parml></p>
  </body>
</topic>
