<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="pdf-css-css-tab">
  <title>CSS Tab (XML to PDF Transformation with CSS)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XML to PDF with CSS transformation scenario<indexterm>CSS
          tab</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/intro-for-transformation-tabs"/></p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>CSS</uicontrol> tab contains the following options:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/xml-url" id="xml-url">
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="css-url">
          <dt>CSS URL</dt>
          <dd>Optionally, you can use this option to specify the location of a custom CSS file to be
            applied to the transformation. If this option is left blank, only the CSS referenced
            directly from the document will be applied. <ph
              conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path-ph"/><ph
              product="author developer editor"> You can also use the <uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/Edit16.gif"/>Open in editor</uicontrol> button to open the specified
              file in the editor panel.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Apply CSS stylesheets set in the current framework</dt>
          <dd>If selected, CSS stylesheets that are specified in the framework (in the <xref
              href="the-css-sub-tab.dita">Document Type configuration CSS subtab</xref>) are applied
            to the transformation in addition to any CSS referenced directly in the document or
            specified in the <xref href="#pdf-css-css-tab/css-url" format="dita">CSS URL
              field</xref>.<note>If CSS files are specified in multiple ways, the transformation
              applies the CSS in the following order (from lowest priority to highest):<ul>
                <li>CSS files that are specified in the framework (in the <xref
                    href="the-css-sub-tab.dita">Document Type configuration CSS subtab</xref>).</li>
                <li>CSS files referenced directly in the document.</li>
                <li>CSS files specified in the <xref href="#pdf-css-css-tab/css-url" format="dita"
                    >CSS URL field</xref>.</li>
              </ul></note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Processor options link</dt>
          <dd>Opens the <xref href="preferences-css-processors.dita"><uicontrol>CSS-based
                Processors</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> where you can configure some options
            for generating PDF output.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
