<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="pdf_publishing_template_contents">
  <title>Publishing Template Package Contents for PDF Customizations</title>
  <titlealts>
    <navtitle>Template Package Contents for PDF</navtitle>
  </titlealts>
  <body>
    <p>An <term>Oxygen Publishing Template</term> package must contain a template descriptor file
      and some other resources (such as CSS files). All the template resources can be stored in
      either a ZIP archive or in a folder. It is recommended to use a ZIP archive when you need it
      to share with others.</p>
  </body>
  <topic id="template_descritpor_file_pdf">
    <title>Template Descriptor File</title>
    <body>
      <p>Each publishing template includes a descriptor file that defines the meta-data associated
        with template. It is an XML file that defines all the resources included in a template (such
        as CSS files and transformation parameters).</p>
      <p>The template descriptor file must have the <filepath>.opt</filepath> file extension and
        must be located in the templates' root folder.</p>
      <p>A PDF template descriptor might look like this:</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    &lt;name>Flowers&lt;/name>

    &lt;pdf>
        &lt;tags>
            &lt;tag>purple&lt;/tag>
            &lt;tag>light&lt;/tag>
        &lt;/tags>
        &lt;preview-image file="flowers-preview.png"/>
        
        &lt;resources>
            &lt;css file="flowers.css"/>
        &lt;/resources>
        
        &lt;parameters>
            &lt;parameter name="figure.title.placement" value="top"/>
        &lt;/parameters>
    &lt;/pdf>
&lt;/publishing-template></codeblock>
      <note type="tip">It is recommended to edit the template descriptor in <b>Oxygen XML
          Editor/Author</b> because it provides content completion and validation support.</note>
      <section id="template_name_and_description">
        <title>Template Name and Description</title>
        <p>Each template descriptor file requires a <b>name</b> element. This information is
          displayed as the name of the template in the transformation scenario dialog box. </p>
        <p>Optionally, you can include a <b>description</b> and it displayed when the user hovers
          over the template in the transformation scenario dialog box.</p>
        <p>
          <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    &lt;name>Flowers&lt;/name>
    &lt;description>Flowers themed light colored template&lt;/description>
    ...</codeblock>
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="template_author">
        <title>Template Author</title>
        <p>Optionally, you can include author information in the descriptor file and it displayed
          when the user hovers over the template in the transformation scenario dialog box. This
          information might be useful if users run into an issue or have questions about a certain
          template.</p>
        <p>If you include the <b>author</b> element, a <b>name</b> is required and optionally you
          can include <b>email</b>, <b>organization</b>, and <b>organizationUrl</b> information.</p>
        <p>
          <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    ...
    &lt;author>
      &lt;name>John Doe&lt;/name>
      &lt;email>jdoe@example.com&lt;/email>
      &lt;organization>ACME&lt;/organization>
      &lt;organizationUrl>http://www.example.com/jdoe&lt;/organizationUrl>
    &lt;/author>
    ...</codeblock>
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="webhelp_element">
        <title>PDF Element</title>
        <p>The <b>pdf</b> element contains various details about the template and its resources that
          define the output. The elements that are allowed in this <b>pdf</b> section specify the
            <xref href="#template_descritpor_file_pdf/template_tags" format="dita">template
            tags</xref>, <xref href="#template_descritpor_file_pdf/template_preview_image"
            format="dita">template preview image</xref>, <xref href="#template_resources_pdf"
            format="dita">resources</xref> (such as CSS files), <xref
            href="#transformation_parameters_pdf" format="dita">transformation parameters</xref>, or
            <xref href="#xslt_extension_points_pdf" format="dita">XSLT extensions</xref>.</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">    &lt;pdf>
        &lt;tags>
          ...
        &lt;/tags>
        &lt;preview-image file="MyPreview.png"/>

        &lt;resources>
          ...
        &lt;/resources>

        &lt;parameters>
          ...
        &lt;/parameters>
    &lt;/pdf></codeblock>
      </section>
      <section id="template_tags">
        <title>Template Tags</title>
        <p>The <b>tags</b> section provides meta information about the template (such as color
          theme). Each <b>tag</b> is displayed at the top of the <uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol>
          tab window in the transformation scenario dialog box and they help the user filter and
          find particular templates.</p>
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    ...
    &lt;pdf>
      &lt;tags>
        &lt;tag>purple&lt;/tag>
        &lt;tag>light&lt;/tag>
      &lt;/tags></codeblock>
      </section>
      <section id="template_preview_image">
        <title>Template Preview Image</title>
        <p>The <b>preview-image</b> element is used to specify an image that will be displayed in
          the transformation scenario dialog box. It provides a visual representation of the
          template to help the user select the right template. The image dimensions should be
            <codeph>200 x 115</codeph> pixels and the supported image formats are:
            <codeph>JPEG</codeph>, <codeph>PNG</codeph>, or <codeph>GIF</codeph>.</p>
        <p>You can also include an <b>online-preview-url</b> element to specify the URL of a
          published sample of your template. This will display an <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/OnlinePreview16.png"/>Online preview</uicontrol> icon in the bottom-right
          corner of the image in the transformation scenario dialog box and if the user clicks that
          icon, it will open the specified URL in their default
          browser.<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    ...
    &lt;pdf>
      ...
      &lt;preview-image file="ashes/ashes-tree.png"/>
      &lt;online-preview-url=https://www.example.com/samples/tiles/ashes&lt;/online-preview-url></codeblock></p>
      </section>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="template_resources_pdf">
    <title>Template Resources</title>
    <body>
      <p>The <b>resources</b> section of the descriptor file specifies a set of resources (CSS
        files) that are used to customize various components in generated output. These resources
        will be copied to the output folder during the transformation process. At least one CSS file
        must be included, while the other types of resources are
          optional.<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    ...
    &lt;pdf>
      ...                
      &lt;resources>            
          &lt;css file="css/custom_styles.css"/>
          &lt;css file="css/custom_fonts.css"/>
      &lt;/resources></codeblock><note>All
          relative paths specified in the descriptor file are relative to the template root
          folder.</note></p>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="xslt_extension_points_pdf">
    <title>XSLT Extension Points</title>
    <body>
      <p>The publishing template allows supports one or more XSLT extension points. They can be
        specified in the descriptor file using the following
        structure:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    ...
    &lt;pdf>
        ...        
        &lt;xslt>
            &lt;extension 
              id="com.oxygenxml.pdf.css.xsl.merged2html5"
              file="xslt/merged2html5Extension.xsl"/>
            &lt;extension
              id="com.oxygenxml.pdf.css.xsl.merged2merged"
              file="xslt/merged2mergedExtension.xsl"/>
        &lt;/xslt></codeblock></p>
      <p>For more information about the available extension points, see: <xref
          href="pdf-xslt-extensions.dita"/>.</p>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="transformation_parameters_pdf">
    <title>Transformation Parameters</title>
    <body>
      <p>You can also set one or more transformation parameters in the descriptor
        file.<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;publishing-template>
    ...    
    &lt;pdf>
      ...
      &lt;parameters>
        &lt;parameter name="show.changes.and.comments" value="yes"/>      
      &lt;/parameters>
    &lt;/pdf></codeblock></p>
      <p>The following information can be specified in the <codeph>parameter</codeph> element:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Parameter name</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>The name of the parameter. It may be one of the transformation parameters listed in
                the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab of the <b>DITA Map to PDF - based on HTML5
                  &amp; CSS</b> transformation scenario or a <xref
                  href="http://www.dita-ot.org/2.5/parameters/parameters-pdf.html" format="html"
                  scope="external">DITA-OT PDF-based output parameter</xref>.</p>
              <note type="note">It is not recommended to specify an input/output parameter in the
                descriptor file (such as the input Map, DITAVAL file, or temporary
                directory).</note>
              <note type="attention">JVM arguments like <term>-Xmx</term> cannot be specified as a
                transformation parameter.</note>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Parameter Value</dt>
            <dd>The value of the parameter. It should be a relative path to the template root folder
              for file paths parameters.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Parameter Type</dt>
            <dd>The type of the parameter: <codeph>string</codeph> or <codeph>filepath</codeph>. The
                <codeph>string</codeph> value is default.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p>After <xref href="whr-create-publishing-template.dita#whr-create-publishing-template"
          >creating a publishing template</xref> and <xref
          href="whr-publishing-template-apply-transformation.dita#whr-publishing-template-apply-transformation"
          >adding it to the templates gallery</xref>, when you select the template in the
        transformation scenario dialog box, the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab will
        automatically be updated to include the parameters defined in the descriptor file. These
        parameters are displayed in italics.</p>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="combining-pdf-webhelp_pdf">
    <title>Combining PDF and WebHelp Responsive Customizations in a Template Package</title>
    <body>
      <p>An <term>Oxygen Publishing Template</term> package can contain both a PDF and WebHelp
        Responsive customization in the same template package and you can use that same template in
        both types of transformations. The template descriptor file can define the customization for
        both types by including both a <codeph>webhelp</codeph> and <codeph>pdf</codeph> element and
        some of the resources can be
        reused.<codeblock conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/publishing-templates-codeblock" outputclass="language-xml"/></p>
    </body>
  </topic>
</topic>
