<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="performance-problems-large-documents">
  <title>Large Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Performance Problems<indexterm>large documents</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>
      <ph product="editor author developer svnClient diff">When started from the icon created on the
        Start menu or the Desktop on Windows or from the shortcut created on the Linux desktop the
        maximum memory available to <ph keyref="product"/> is set by default to <ph
          product="author developer editor">40% of the amount of physical RAM but not more than 700
          MB.</ph>
        <ph product="diff">256 MB.</ph>
        <ph product="svnClient">256 MB.</ph> When started from the command line scripts the maximum
        memory is 256 MB.</ph> If large documents are edited in <ph keyref="product"/> and you see
      that performance slows down considerably after some time then a possible cause is that the
      application needs more memory in order to run properly. <ph
        product="editor author developer svnClient diff">You can increase the maximum amount of
        memory available to <ph keyref="product"/> by <xref
          href="set-parameter-in-startup-script.dita">setting the -Xmx parameter in a configuration
          file</xref> specific to the platform that runs the application. </ph>
      <ph product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">You can increase the maximum amount
        of memory available to <ph keyref="product"/> by specifying the parameters <cmdname>-vmargs
          -Xmx</cmdname> in the command used to launch the Eclipse platform. You might also consider
        modifying the minimum file size that enables the <xref
          href="editing-large-documents.dita#editing-large-documents">large file editing
          support</xref>.</ph>
    </p>
    <note type="attention">
      <p>The maximum amount of memory should not be equal to the physical amount of memory available
        on the machine because in that case the operating system and other applications will have no
        memory available.</p>
    </note>
    <p product="editor author developer svnClient diff">When installed on a multi-user environment
      such as Windows Terminal Server or Unix/Linux, to each instance of <ph keyref="product"/> will
      be allocated the amount stipulated in the memory value. To avoid degrading the general
      performance of the host system, please ensure that the amount of memory available is optimally
      apportioned for each of the expected instances.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
