<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="performance-problems-large-documents">
  <title>Performance Issues with Large Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Out Of Memory error</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section id="problem">
      <title>Problem</title>
      <p>The performance of the application slows down considerably over time when working with
        large documents.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="solution">
      <title>Solution</title>
      <p>A possible cause is that the application needs more memory to run properly. <ph
          product="author developer editor svnClient">You can increase the maximum amount of memory
          available to <ph keyref="product"/> by <xref href="set-parameter-in-startup-script.dita"
            >setting the <parmname>-Xmx</parmname> parameter in a configuration file</xref> that is
          specific to the platform that runs the application. </ph>
        <ph product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">You can increase the maximum
          amount of memory available to <ph keyref="product"/> by setting the
            <userinput>-vmargs</userinput> and <userinput>-Xmx</userinput> parameters in the command
          used to launch the Eclipse platform.</ph>
      </p>
      <note type="attention">The maximum amount of memory should not be equal to the physical amount
        of memory available on the machine because in that case the operating system and other
        applications will have no memory available.</note>
      <p product="author developer editor svnClient">When installed on a multiple user environment,
        each instance of <ph keyref="product"/> will be allocated the amount stipulated in the
        memory value. To avoid degrading the general performance of the host system, ensure that the
        amount of memory available is optimally apportioned for each of the expected instances.</p>
      <note><ph product="author developer editor svnClient">When starting <ph keyref="product"/>
          from the icon created on the Start menu or Desktop in Windows (or from the shortcut
          created on the Linux desktop), the default maximum memory available to the application is
          set to <ph product="author developer editor">40% of the amount of physical RAM, but not
            more than 700 MB.</ph>
          <ph product="svnClient">512 MB.</ph></ph><p><ph
            product="author developer editor svnClient">When starting <ph keyref="product"/> from a
            command-line script, the default maximum memory is 512 MB.</ph></p></note>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
