<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="pre-merge-checks">
  <title>Pre-Merge Checks</title>
  <body>
    <p>Before performing a merge, it is recommended to make sure that the working copy target item
      is ready for the merge operation. The SVN Client includes a best practices step that checks
      various conditions of the working copy target item to ensure that the merge operation will
      succeed. By selecting the <uicontrol>Perform pre-merge best practices checks of the working
        copy target</uicontrol> option in the first page of the <uicontrol>Merge</uicontrol> wizard,
      the <uicontrol>Pre-merge checks</uicontrol> wizard page is displayed to give you a summary of
      the verified conditions. </p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_qrm_sll_4r">
        <title>Pre-Merge Checks Wizard Page</title>
        <image href="../img/svn_pre_merge_checks.png" id="image_psv_5ll_4r"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The following conditions are checked in this operation:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>No local modifications</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The working copy item (or any of its children) receiving the merge should not contain
            uncommitted changes, to make it easier to revert merge-generated changes if you
            encounter unexpected results.<note type="tip">If this condition fails, you should
                <i>commit</i> or <i>revert</i> the local modifications before merging. </note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>No switched children</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>None of the children of the working copy item receiving the merge should be switched,
            to avoid incomplete merges and <i>subtree mergeinfo</i>.<note type="tip">If this
              condition fails, you should switch back all the children before merging. </note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Complete working copy tree</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The working copy item receiving the merge should be a complete directory tree
            structure with an infinite depth, to avoid incomplete merges and <i>subtree
              mergeinfo</i>.<note type="tip">If this condition fails, you should change the
                <i>sticky</i> depth of the working copy item receiving the merge to <i>infinity</i>
              value. </note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>No mixed revisions</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>To avoid unexpected merge conflicts, the working copy item that is receiving the merge
            should not contain items that were updated to other revisions. <note type="tip">If this
              condition fails, you should <i>update</i> the working copy before merging.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p>Each condition is marked with an icon that represents the state of the condition. The
      possible states are as follows:<ul id="ul_k33_pql_4r">
        <li><image href="../img/SVNMarkResolved16.png" id="image_hrl_14q_4r"/> (<b>Successful</b>) -
          The condition is fulfilled successfully.</li>
        <li><image href="../img/Hotspot16.png" id="image_njy_sdn_wr"/> (<b>Warning</b>) - The
          condition is not fulfilled, but it is not mandatory. </li>
        <li><image href="../img/SVNError.png" id="image_tjz_jpq_4r"/> (<b>Error</b>) - The condition
          is not fulfilled and is mandatory (therefore, the operation cannot proceed until you solve
          the error).</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note type="tip">For each condition state, a message is displayed that gives you additional
      information about the results and, for warning or errors, a hint that explains how you can
      solve them.</note>
    <note type="important">After solving any of the warnings or errors, it is recommended that you
      perform the <i>pre-merge checks</i> again to make sure your new changes are valid.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
