<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="predefined-refactoring-operations">
  <title>Predefined Refactoring Operations</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Predefined XML refactoring operations</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The XML Refactoring tool includes a variety of predefined operations that can be used for
      common refactoring tasks. They are grouped by category in the <uicontrol>Refactoring
        operations</uicontrol> wizard page. You can also access the operations from the
        <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu in the contextual menu of <ph
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> or
        </ph><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode. The operations are also grouped by category in this
      submenu (<uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Elements</uicontrol>, and
        <uicontrol>Fragments</uicontrol>). When selecting the operations from the contextual menu,
        <ph keyref="product"/> considers the editing context to get the names and namespaces of the
      current element or attribute, and uses this information to preconfigure some of the parameter
      values for the selected refactoring operation.</p>
    <p>The following predefined operations are available:</p>
    <section>
      <title>Refactoring Operations for <i>Attributes</i></title>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Add/Change attribute</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to change the value of an attribute or insert a new one. To perform
            this operation, specify the following parameters:<ul id="ul_hxk_gpb_jr">
              <li>The parent <uicontrol>Element</uicontrol> of the attribute to be changed, in the
                form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix, or an
                XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Local name</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol>, and
                  <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> of the affected attribute.</li>
              <li>One of the following choices for the <uicontrol>Operation mode</uicontrol> in the
                  <i>Options</i> section:<ul id="ul_uvc_hqb_jr">
                  <li><uicontrol>Add the attribute in the parent elements where it is
                      missing</uicontrol></li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Change the value in the parent elements where the atrribute already
                      exists</uicontrol></li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Both</uicontrol></li>
                </ul></li>
            </ul><note type="tip" id="xpath-options-note">Use the link provided in the lower part of
              the wizard to open the <uicontrol>XML / XSLT-FO-XQuery / XPath</uicontrol> preferences
              page where you can configure XPath options and declare namespace prefixes.
            </note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Delete attribute</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to remove one or more attributes. To perform this operation,
            specify the following parameters:<ul id="ul_bxx_pqb_jr">
              <li>The parent <uicontrol>Element</uicontrol> of the attribute to be deleted, in the
                form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix, or an
                XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The name of the <uicontrol>Attribute</uicontrol> to be deleted.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Rename attribute</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to rename an attribute. Specify the following parameters in the
              <uicontrol>Rename attribute</uicontrol> dialog box:<ul id="ul_egw_4rb_jr">
              <li>The parent <uicontrol>Element</uicontrol> of the attribute to be renamed, in the
                form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix, or an
                XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The name of the <uicontrol>Attribute</uicontrol> to be renamed.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>New local name</uicontrol> of the attribute.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Replace in attribute value</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to search for a text fragment inside an attribute value and change
            the fragment to a new value. To perform this operation, specify the following
              parameters:<ul id="ul_yx4_dfc_jr">
              <li>The parent <uicontrol>Element</uicontrol> of the attribute to be modified, in the
                form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix, or an
                XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The name of the <uicontrol>Attribute</uicontrol> to be modified.</li>
              <li>The text fragments to <uicontrol>Find</uicontrol>. You can use Perl-like regular
                expressions when specifying the text to find.</li>
              <li>The text fragment to <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol>. This parameter can bind
                regular expression capturing groups (<systemoutput>$1, $2</systemoutput>, etc.) from
                the find pattern.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Refactoring Operations for <i>Elements</i></title>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Delete element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to delete elements. To perform this operation, specify the
            following parameter:<ul id="ul_jdc_dgc_jr">
              <li>The target <uicontrol>Element</uicontrol> to be deleted, in the form of a local
                name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix, or an XPath
                expression.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Delete element content</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to delete the content of elements. To perform this operation,
            specify the following parameter:<ul id="ul_zly_m3c_jr">
              <li>The target <uicontrol>Element</uicontrol> in which its content is to be deleted,
                in the form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace
                prefix, or an XPath expression.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to insert new elements. To perform this operation, specify the
            following parameters:<ul id="ul_kht_v3c_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>Local name</uicontrol> of the element to be inserted.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol> of the element to be inserted.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>XPath</uicontrol> location of an existing element where the new
                element will be inserted, in the form of a local name from any namespace, a local
                name with a namespace prefix, or an XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Position</uicontrol>, in relation to the specified existing
                element, where the new element will be inserted. The possible selections in the
                drop-down menu are: <uicontrol>After</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Before</uicontrol>,
                  <uicontrol>First child</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Last child</uicontrol>.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Rename element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to rename elements. To perform this operation, specify the
            following parameters:<ul id="ul_vsk_3kc_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>Target elements (XPath)</uicontrol> to be renamed, in the form of a
                local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix, or an XPath
                expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>New local name</uicontrol> of the element.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Unwrap element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to remove the surrounding tags of elements, while keeping the
            content unchanged. To perform this operation, specify the following parameters:<ul
              id="ul_env_nkc_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>Target elements (XPath)</uicontrol> for which its surrounding tags
                will be removed, in the form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a
                namespace prefix, or an XPath expression.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Wrap element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to surround elements with element tags. To perform this operation,
            specify the following parameters:<ul id="ul_dx2_zkc_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>Target elements (XPath)</uicontrol> to be surrounded with tags, in
                the form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix,
                or an XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Local name</uicontrol> of the <i>Wrapper element</i>.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol> of the <i>Wrapper element</i>.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Wrap element content</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to surround the content of elements with element tags. To perform
            this operation, specify the following parameters:<ul id="ul_pvy_klc_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>Target elements (XPath)</uicontrol> to surround its content with
                tags, in the form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace
                prefix, or an XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Local name</uicontrol> of the <i>Wrapper element</i> in which its
                content will be wrapped.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol> of the <i>Wrapper element</i> in which its
                content will be wrapped.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Refactoring Operations for <i>Fragments</i></title>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Insert XML fragment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to insert an XML fragment. To perform this operation, specify the
            following parameters:<ul id="ul_wft_5lc_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>XML Fragment</uicontrol> to be inserted.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>XPath</uicontrol> location of an existing element where the
                fragment will be inserted, in the form of a local name from any namespace, a local
                name with a namespace prefix, or an XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>Position</uicontrol>, in relation to the specified existing
                element, where the fragment will be inserted. The possible selections in the
                drop-down menu are: <uicontrol>After</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Before</uicontrol>,
                  <uicontrol>First child</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Last child</uicontrol>.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Replace element content with XML fragment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to replace the content of elements with an XML fragment. To perform
            this operation, specify the following parameters:<ul id="ul_syw_dmc_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>Target elements (XPath)</uicontrol> for which its content will be
                replaced, in the form of a local name from any namespace, a local name with a
                namespace prefix, or an XPath expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>XML Fragment</uicontrol> with which to replace the content of the
                target element.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Replace element with XML fragment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this operation to replace elements with an XML fragment. To perform this
            operation, specify the following parameters:<ul id="ul_lqk_4mc_jr">
              <li>The <uicontrol>Target elements (XPath)</uicontrol> to be replaced, in the form of
                a local name from any namespace, a local name with a namespace prefix, or an XPath
                expression.</li>
              <li>The <uicontrol>XML Fragment</uicontrol> with which to replace the target
                element.</li>
            </ul><note conref="#predefined-refactoring-operations/xpath-options-note"/></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Additional Notes</title>
    </section>
    <note>There are some operations that allows <codeph>&lt;ANY></codeph> for the <b>local name</b>
      and <b>namespace</b> parameters. This value can be used to select an element or attribute
      regardless of its local name or namespace. Also, the <codeph>&lt;NO_NAMESPACE></codeph> value
      can be used to select nodes that do not belong to a namespace. </note>
    <note>Some operations have parameters that accept XPath expressions to match elements or
      attributes. In these XPath expressions you can only use the prefixes declared in the <xref
        href="preferences-xpath.dita"><menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XSLT-FO-XQUERY</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XPath</uicontrol>
        </menucascade></xref> page. This preferences page can be easily opened by clicking the link
      in the note (<uicontrol>Each prefix used in an XPath expression must be declared in the
        Default prefix-namespace mappings section</uicontrol>) at the bottom of the <b>Configure
        Operation Parameters</b> wizard page.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
