<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-track-changes" >
    <title>Review Preferences</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Editor
                        preferences<indexterm>author track
                changes</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>To open the Author <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> preferences page, go to<menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Edit modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
        <p>The available preferences are:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> - The name of the user who performs the changes when
          <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> is active for a given editor. This information is
        associated with each performed change;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Track Changes (applies for all authors)</uicontrol>:</li>
            <li><uicontrol id="initial_state">Initial State</uicontrol> - Controls the initial
          <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> state;<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Stored in document</uicontrol> - Recommended when multiple editors work on
            the same set of documents because the state of <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol>
            (enabled/disabled) is kept in the edited document. When you open such a document and the
              <uicontrol>Store in document</uicontrol> option is active, if the
              <codeph>&lt;?oxy_options track_changes="on"?></codeph> processing instruction was
            saved in the document, the <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> is enabled. When this
            option is enabled and you open a document in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the
              <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> state is restored from the previous use of the
            document. This means that if another user edited the document with <uicontrol>Track
              Changes</uicontrol> turned on before sending it to you, you will also have
              <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> switched on when you open it in the
              <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Always On</uicontrol> - The <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> feature is
            active when you open a document; </li>
          <li><uicontrol>Always Off</uicontrol> - The <uicontrol>Track Changes</uicontrol> feature
            is inactive when you open a document;</li>
        </ul><note><uicontrol>Initial Track Changes State</uicontrol> options do not affect
          documents already open in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Changed lines marker</uicontrol> - enable this option to display a vertical
        stripe in the left of the content that is commented, or modified when <uicontrol>Track
          Changes</uicontrol> is enabled;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Inserted content color</uicontrol> - Sets the color used for marking the
        inserted content. This includes the font foreground and background, and the underline that
        decorates all inserted text:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - Automatically assigns colors for the insert changes for
            each author name. Enabled by default;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Custom</uicontrol> - Uses a custom color for all insert changes, regardless
            of the author name;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Use same color for text foreground</uicontrol> - Uses the same color to
            paint the inserted text foreground;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Use same color for background</uicontrol> - Uses the same color for the
            insert text background. Use the slider to adjust the transparency level;</li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Deleted content color</uicontrol> - Sets the color used for marking the
        deleted content. This includes the font foreground and background, and the strike-through
        that decorates all deleted text:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - Automatically assigns colors for the delete changes for
            each author name. Enabled by default;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Custom</uicontrol> - Uses a custom color for all delete changes, regardless
            of the author name;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Use same color for text foreground</uicontrol> - Uses the same color to
            paint the deleted text foreground;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Use same color for background</uicontrol> - Uses the same color for the
            deleted text background. Use the slider to adjust the transparency level;</li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Commented color (applies for all authors)</uicontrol> - Sets the
        background color of the annotated text:<ul id="ul_ab333fe6-748e-4ddd-9efc-8ad89410160e">
          <li><uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - Automatically assigns colors for the annotated content
            for each author name. Enabled by default;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Custom</uicontrol> - Use a custom color for all annotated content,
            regardless of the author name. Use the slider to control the transparency level.</li>
        </ul></li>
        </ul>
    </body>
    <related-links>
        <link href="author-change-tracking.dita#author-change-tracking">
            <desc>Tracking Document Changes</desc>
        </link>
    </related-links>
</topic>