<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-scenarios-management">
  <title>Scenarios Management Preferences</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>scenarios management</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_ntr_bgk_54b">To configure Scenarios Management options, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to
        <uicontrol>Scenarios Management</uicontrol>. This allows you to share the global
      transformation scenarios with other users by exporting them to an external file that can also
      be imported in this preferences panel.</p>
    <p id="p_otr_bgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_ptr_bgk_54b">
        <title>Scenarios Management Preferences Panel</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_scenario_manag_options.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_qtr_bgk_54b">The actions available in this panel are as follows:</p>
    <ul id="ul_rtr_bgk_54b">
      <li id="li_str_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Import Global Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to import all
        transformation scenarios from a file created with the export scenario action. The names of
        the imported scenarios will appear in the <uicontrol>Configure Transformation
          Scenario</uicontrol> dialog box followed by <i>(import)</i>. This way there are no
        scenario name conflicts.</li>
      <li id="li_ttr_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Export Global Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to export all
        global transformation scenarios available in the <uicontrol>Configure Transformation
          Scenario</uicontrol> dialog box.</li>
      <li id="li_utr_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Import Global Validation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to import all
        validation scenarios from a file created with the export scenario action. The names of the
        imported scenarios will appear in the <uicontrol>Configure Validation Scenario</uicontrol>
        dialog box followed by <i>(import)</i>. This way there are no scenario name conflicts.</li>
      <li id="li_vtr_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Export Global Validation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to export all
        global validation scenarios available in the <uicontrol>Configure Validation
          Scenario</uicontrol> dialog box.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>