<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-editor-spell-check">
  <title>Spell Check Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Editor preferences<indexterm>spell
              check</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Spell Check</uicontrol> preferences page , go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Spell Check</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Spell checking engine</uicontrol> - the application ships with two spell check
        engines, <term>Hunspell</term> and <term>Java spell checker</term>. Each engine has a
        specific format of spelling dictionaries. The languages of the built-in dictionaries of the
        selected engine are listed in the <uicontrol>Default language</uicontrol> options
          list.<note>In case you configured an additional location for the dictionaries that <ph
            keyref="product"/> uses, the
            <uicontrol>Default language</uicontrol> option collects the languages both from the
          default and additional locations.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Automatic Spell Check</uicontrol> - enable this option to make the spellchecker
        highlight errors as you edit a document;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Select editors</uicontrol> - allows you to select the file types for which the
        automatic spell check takes effect. File types in which automatic spell check is generally
        not useful, like CSS and DTD, are excluded by default.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Spell check highlight color</uicontrol> - use
        this option to set the color used by the spell check engine to highlight spelling
        errors.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Default language</uicontrol> - the default language list allows you to choose
        the language used by the spell check engine;<note>You can <xref
            href="../tasks/add-Hunspell-dictionary.dita">add more spelling dictionaries</xref> to
          the spell check engines.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Use "lang" and "xml:lang" attributes</uicontrol> - if enabled, the contents of
        any element with one of the <codeph>lang</codeph> or <codeph>xml:lang</codeph> attributes is
        checked using a dictionary suitable for the language specified in the attribute value, if
        this dictionary is available. When these attributes are missing, the language used is
        controlled by the two radio buttons: <uicontrol>Use the default language</uicontrol> or
          <uicontrol>Do not check</uicontrol>;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>XML spell checking in</uicontrol> - these options allow you to specify if the
        spell checker will be enabled inside XML comments, attribute values, text, and CDATA
        sections;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Case sensitive</uicontrol> - when enabled, spell checking reports
        capitalization errors, for example a word that starts with lowercase after <i>etc.</i> or
          <i>i.e.</i>;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore mixed case words</uicontrol> - when enabled, operations do not check
        words containing mixed case characters (e.g. <i>SpellChecker</i>);</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore words with digits</uicontrol> - when enabled, the spell checker does not
        check words containing digits (e.g. <i>b2b</i>);</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore Duplicates</uicontrol> - when enabled, the spell checker does not signal
        two successive identical words as an error;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore URL</uicontrol> - when enabled, ignores words looking like URL or file
        names (e.g. <i>www.oxygenxml.com</i> or <i>c:\boot.ini</i>);</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Check punctuation</uicontrol> - when enabled, punctuation checking is enabled:
        misplaced white space and wrong sequences, like a dot following a comma, are highlighted as
        errors;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Allow compounds words</uicontrol> - when enabled, all words formed by
        concatenating two legal words with a hyphen (hyphenated compounds) are accepted. If the
        language allows it, two words concatenated without hyphen (closed compounds) are also
        accepted.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Allow general prefixes</uicontrol> - when enabled, a word formed by
        concatenating a registered prefix and a legal word is accepted. For example if <i>mini-</i>
        is a registered prefix, the spell check engine accepts the word <i>mini-computer</i>.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Allow file extensions</uicontrol> - when enabled, accepts any word ending with
        registered file extensions (e.g. <i>myfile.txt</i>, <i>index.html</i>, etc.).</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore acronyms</uicontrol> - when enabled, the acronyms are not reported as
        errors.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore elements</uicontrol> - a list of XPath expressions for the elements that
        the spell check engine ignores. The following restricted set of XPath expressions are supported:<ul>
          <li>'/' and '//' separators;</li>
          <li>'*' wildcard.</li>
        </ul>An example of allowed XPath expression: <i>/a/*/b</i>.</li>
    </ul>
    <p product="authorEclipse editorEclipse developerEclipse">To change the color used by the spell
      check engine to highlight spelling errors, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> General</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Editors</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Text Editors</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Annotations</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Spell Check Annotation</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
