<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-diff-files">
    <title>Files Comparison Preferences</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Diff</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p product="editor author diff developer">To open the <uicontrol>Files
        Comparison</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author diff developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Files Comparison</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. This preferences page allows you to configure the following options:</p>
        <fig id="figure-diff-options" product="editor author diff developer">
            <title>The Files Comparison Preferences Panel</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_diff_options.png"/>
        </fig>
        <ul product="editor author diff developer">
            <li id="diff-algorithm"><uicontrol>Default algorithm</uicontrol> - the default algorithm
        used for comparing files. The following options are available:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - automatic selection of the diff algorithm, based on the
            file content and its size;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Characters</uicontrol> - computes the differences at character level;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Words</uicontrol> - computes the differences at word level;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Lines</uicontrol> - computes the differences at line level;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Syntax aware</uicontrol> - for the file types known by <ph keyref="product"
            />, this algorithm computes the differences taking into consideration the syntax (the
            specific types of tokens) of the documents;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> - a diff algorithm well-suited for large XML documents
            (tens of MB). Sacrifices accuracy in favor of speed;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> - XML-tuned diff algorithm. It favors accuracy
            over speed.</li>
        </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Algorithm strength</uicontrol> - controls the amount of resources
        allocated to the application to perform the comparison. The algorithm stops searching more
        differences when reaches the maximum allowed resources. A dialog is shown when this limit is
        reached and partial results are displayed. Four settings are available:
          <uicontrol>Low</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Medium</uicontrol> (default),
          <uicontrol>High</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Very High</uicontrol>;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Ignore Whitespaces</uicontrol> - ignoring whitespaces means that before
        performing the comparison, the application normalizes the content (collapses any sequence of
        whitespace characters (space, newline or tab characters) into a single space) and trims its
        leading and trailing whitespaces;<note>If the <uicontrol>Ignore Whitespaces</uicontrol>
          check box is selected, comparing the <codeph>a b</codeph> sequence with <codeph>a
            b</codeph>, <ph keyref="product"/> finds no differences, because after normalization,
          all whitespaces from the first sequence are collapsed into a single space character.
          However, when comparing <codeph>a b</codeph> with <codeph>ab</codeph> (no whitespace
          between <codeph>a</codeph> and <codeph>b</codeph>), <ph keyref="product"/> signals a
          difference.</note></li>
            <li id="diff-options"><uicontrol>XML Diff Options</uicontrol> - this set of options
        allows you to specify the types of XML nodes for which the differences will be ignored (will
        not be reported) by the <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>XML
          Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Merge adjacent differences</uicontrol> - considers two adjacent
        differences as one when the differences are painted in the side-by-side editors. If
        unchecked, every difference is represented separately;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Mark end tags as different for modified elements</uicontrol> - end tags
        of modified elements are presented as differences too, otherwise only the start tags are
        presented as differences;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Ignore expansion state for empty elements</uicontrol> - empty elements in
        both expansion states are considered matched, that is <codeph>&lt;element/&gt;</codeph> and
          <codeph>&lt;element&gt;&lt;/element&gt;</codeph> are considered equal.</li>
        </ul>
    </body>
</topic>