<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-xquery">
  <title>XQuery Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>XSLT/FO/XQuery
              preferences<indexterm>XQuery</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>XQuery</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XSLT/FO/XQuery</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XQuery</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The generic XQuery preferences are the following:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>XQuery validate with</uicontrol> - allows you to select the processor that
        validates XQuery documents. In case you are validating an XQuery file that has an associated
        validation scenario, <ph keyref="product"/> uses the processor specified in the scenario. If
        no validation scenario is associated, but the file has an associated transformation
        scenario, the processor specified in the scenario is used. If the processor does not support
        validation or if no scenario is associated, then the value from this combo box will be used
        as validation processor;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Size limit of Sequence view (MB)</uicontrol> - when the result of an XQuery
        transformation is <xref href="transform-xquery-sequence-view.dita">set in the transformation
          scenario as sequence</xref> the size of one chunk of the result that is fetched from the
        database in lazy mode in one step is set in this option. If this limit is exceed, go to the
          <uicontrol>Sequence</uicontrol> view and click <uicontrol>More results
          available</uicontrol> to extract more data from the database;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Format transformer output</uicontrol> - specifies whether the output of the
        transformer is formatted and indented (pretty printed).<note>This option is ignored if you
          choose <uicontrol>Sequence</uicontrol> (lazy extract data from a database) from the
          associated transformation scenario;</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Create structure indicating the type nodes</uicontrol> - if checked, <ph
          keyref="product"/> takes the results of a query and creates an XML document containing
        copies of all items in the sequence, suitably wrapped.<note>This option is ignored if you
          choose <uicontrol>Sequence</uicontrol> (lazy extract data from a database) from the
          associated transformation scenario;</note></li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
