<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-editor-open-save">
  <title>Open / Save Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Editor
              preferences<indexterm>open/save</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>OutOfMemory</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Out Of Memory</indexterm>
        <indexterm>OutOfMemoryError</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Open / Save</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author svnClient diff developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Open / Save</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li product="author developer editor svnClient"><uicontrol>When bidirectional (BIDI) text is
          detected</uicontrol> - allows you to choose the application behavior when you try to open
        a file that contains BIDI Unicode characters. You can choose between <uicontrol>Enable
          bidirectional editing mode</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Disable bidirectional editing
          mode</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Prompt for each document</uicontrol>.</li>
      <li product="author developer editor svnClient" id="disable-bidi-support"><uicontrol>Disable
          bidirectional text support for documents larger than (Characters)</uicontrol> - when you
        try to open a document that exceeds the specified limit, the bidirectional editing mode is
        turned off, even if the <uicontrol>When bidirectional (BIDI) text is detected</uicontrol>
        option is set to <uicontrol>Enable bidirectional editing mode</uicontrol>.</li>
      <li product="svnClient diff"><uicontrol>Show BIDI limit warning</uicontrol> - if enabled, a
        warning dialog is shown when the ope file which contains bidirectional characters is too
        large and bidirectional support is disabled to improve application performance.</li>
      <li
        product="author authorEclipse authorSDK developer developerEclipse diff editor editorEclipse"
          ><uicontrol>Safe save (only for local files)</uicontrol> - option that provides an
        increased degree of protection in the unlikely event of a failure of the
          <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> action. This mechanism creates a temporary file that holds the
        edited content until it is safely saved in the original file. If the
          <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> action fails, the temporary file is kept in the system
        temporary folder, <uicontrol>OxygenXMLTemp</uicontrol> subfolder. </li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Make backup copy on save (only for local
          files)</uicontrol> - If enabled, a backup copy is made when saving the edited document.
        This option is available only for local files (files that are stored on the local file
        system). The default backup file extension is <filepath>.bak</filepath>, but you can change
        it as you prefer.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Enable automatic save</uicontrol> - When
        enabled, your document are saved automatically after a preset time interval.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Automatic save interval (minutes)</uicontrol>
        - Selects the interval in minutes between two automatic save actions.</li>
      <li product="editor author editorEclipse authorEclipse developer developerEclipse"
          ><uicontrol>Save all files before transformation or validation</uicontrol> - Saves all
        open files before validating or transforming an XML document. This way the dependencies are
        resolved, for example when modifying both the XML document and its XML Schema.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Check errors on save</uicontrol> - If
        enabled, <ph keyref="product"/> checks your
        document for errors before saving it.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Save all files before calling external
          tools</uicontrol> - If enabled, all files are saved before executing an <xref
          href="integrating-external-tools.dita#integrating-external-tools" format="dita">external
          tool</xref>.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Optimize loading in the Text edit mode for
          files over (MB)</uicontrol> - File loading is optimized for reduced memory usage for any
        file with a size larger than this value. This optimization is useful for being able to load
        and edit very large files, but it comes with <xref
          href="editing-large-documents.dita#editing-large-documents">several restrictions</xref>
        for memory-intensive operations.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Show warning when loading large
          documents</uicontrol> - A warning dialog is displayed when you try to load a very large
        file.</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Optimize loading for documents with lines
          longer than (Characters)</uicontrol> - Line wrap is turned on for a document containing
        lines that exceed the length specified with this option. For a list of the restrictions
        applied to a document with long lines, see <xref
          href="long-lines-document.dita#long-lines-document" format="dita">the <uicontrol>Editing
            Documents with Long Lines</uicontrol> section.</xref></li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>Show warning when loading documents with long
          lines</uicontrol> - If enabled, a warning dialog is displayed when you try to open a file
        that contains at least one line that exceeds the maximum line length specified in the
        previous option. The warning dialog informs you that line wrapping is turned on and some of
        the editing features are disabled. Another option is to <xref
          href="formatting-and-indenting-xml-documents.dita#formatting-and-indenting-xml-documents"
          format="dita">format and indent the document</xref> after it is opened in the editor
        panel. For a list of the restrictions applied to a document with long lines, see the section
        about <xref href="long-lines-document.dita#long-lines-document" format="dita">formatting
          documents with long lines</xref>.</li>
      <li product="editor author editorEclipse authorEclipse developer developerEclipse"
          ><uicontrol>Clear undo buffer on save</uicontrol> - If enabled, <ph
          keyref="product"/> erases its undo stack
        when you save a document. Only modifications made after you have saved the document can be
        undone. Check this option if you encounter frequent <term>out of memory</term> problems
          (<uicontrol>OutOfMemoryError</uicontrol>) when editing very large documents.</li>
      <li product="author developer diff editor"><uicontrol>Consider application bundles to be
          directories when browsing</uicontrol> - This option is available only on the Mac OS X
        platform. When checked, the file browser dialog allows browsing inside an application bundle
        as in a regular folder. When unchecked, the file browser dialog does not allow browsing
        inside an application bundle, as the Finder application does on Mac OS X. The same effect
        can be obtained by setting the property
          <i><term>apple.awt.use-file-dialog-packages</term></i> to <term>true</term> or
          <term>false</term> in the <filepath>Info.plist</filepath> descriptor file of the <ph
          keyref="product"/> application:
        <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">
&lt;key&gt;apple.awt.use-file-dialog-packages&lt;/key&gt;
&lt;string&gt;false&lt;/string&gt;</codeblock>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
