<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-project-level-settings">
  <title>Project Level Settings Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>Project Level Settings</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Project Level Settings preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Project Level Settings</uicontrol> preference page allows you to decide
      whether various settings should be saved in the project configuration file or in the global
      settings. Settings that are saved at project level can easily be shared with others. To
      configure these options, <ph conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"
      /> and go to <uicontrol>Project Level Settings</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The following options can be toggled on or off to determine which settings will be saved at
      project level:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Allow validation scenario associations to be saved at project
              level</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, you are allowed to save associations to <xref
              href="create-validation-scenario.dita">custom validation scenarios</xref> at project
            level (in the project configuration file). If deselected, all associations will be saved
            globally.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Allow transformation scenario associations to be saved at project
              level</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, you are allowed to save associations to <xref
              href="defining-new-transformation-scenario.dita">custom transformation
              scenarios</xref> at project level (in the project configuration file). If deselected,
            all associations will be saved globally.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Save current DITA root map at project level</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, when you change the <xref
              href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager/root-map">currently selected DITA
              context root map</xref>, it will be saved in the project configuration file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Save DITA media working sets at project level</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, all <xref
              href="dita-reusable-components-view.dita#dita-reusable-components-view/media_tab"
              >configured working sets for DITA media resources</xref> will be saved in the project
            configuration file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Save DITA map validate and check for completeness settings at project
              level</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this is selected, the options chosen in the <xref href="dita-map-validate.dita"
              >DITA Map Validate and Check for Completeness dialog box</xref> will be saved in the
            project configuration file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
