<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/reference.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-dita">
  <title>DITA Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p>To access the DITA Preferences page, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>. This preferences page includes the following sections and
      options: </p>
    <section id="DITA-OT-section"><title><uicontrol>DITA Open Toolkit</uicontrol>
      Section</title>This section allows you to specify the default directory of the DITA Open
      Toolkit distribution (bundled with the <ph keyref="product"/> installation) to be used for
      validating and publishing DITA content. You can select from the following:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Built-in DITA-OT 1.8</uicontrol> - This is the default setting and the
          default DITA OT directory is:
          <filepath>[OXYGEN_DIR]/frameworks/dita/DITA-OT</filepath>.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Built-in DITA-OT 2.x (with experimental DITA 1.3 support)</uicontrol> - All
          defined DITA transformation scenarios will run with DITA-OT 2.x. This also gives you
          access to new DITA 1.3 file templates when you <xref
            href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa" product="author developer editor"
            >create new documents from templates</xref><xref
            href="../tasks/creating-from-templates.dita"
            product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">create new documents from
            templates</xref>. The default DITA OT directory is:
            <filepath>[OXYGEN_DIR]/frameworks/dita/DITA-OT2.x</filepath>.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Custom</uicontrol> - In the <uicontrol>Location</uicontrol> field, you can
          either provide a new file path for the specific DITA OT that you want to use or you can
          select a previously used one from the drop-down list.</li>
      </ul></section>
    <p><ph product="author editor"> The <uicontrol>DITA Maps file patterns</uicontrol> option allows
        you to set the extension of the files that will be handled as DITA maps when opened in <ph
          keyref="product"/>. <ph keyref="product"/> can open a DITA map in the regular editor view
        or in the <xref keyref="dita_edit-maps">DITA Maps Manager</xref>.</ph></p>
    <p product="author editor"> The following options are available <uicontrol>When opening a
        map</uicontrol>:<ul id="ul_g5k_kdq_jq">
        <li><uicontrol>Always open in the DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> - A DITA map file is always
          opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Always open as XML</uicontrol> - A DITA map file is always opened in the XML
          editor.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol> - When opening a DITA map, you are prompted to choose
          between opening it in the XML editor panel or in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
            Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p conkeyref="reusables-configuring-oxygen/p-show-console-output" id="show_console_output"/>
    <p id="insert-topic-ref-p">The following options are available for the <uicontrol>Insert
        Reference</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol> operations:<ul
        id="ul_i5l_r55_bs">
        <li><uicontrol>Always fill values for attributes</uicontrol> - Allows you to specify that in
          the <uicontrol>Insert Reference\Edit Properties</uicontrol> dialog box, the values for
          these attributes will be automatically populated with a detected value (based on the
          specifications), even if it is the same as the default value.<ul id="ul_yhk_s55_bs">
            <li><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> - If enabled, the <i>Format</i> attribute will always
              be populated automatically .</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> - If enabled, the <i>Scope</i> attribute will always be
              populated automatically.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - If enabled, the <i>Type</i> attribute will always be
              populated automatically.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>
      <ph product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">At the bottom of the page there is a
        link to the <xref href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
          >Profiling Attributes preferences</xref>, where you can configure how profiling and
        conditional text is displayed in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></p>
  </body>
</topic>
