<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-encoding">
  <title>Encoding Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the
            Application<indexterm>encoding</indexterm><indexterm>UTF-8</indexterm><indexterm>BOM</indexterm><indexterm>byte
            order mark</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Encoding</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Encoding</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The following encoding preferences are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li product="editor author svnClient diff developer"><uicontrol>Encoding for non XML
          files</uicontrol> - specifies the default encoding the <ph keyref="product"/> uses to open
        non XML documents. This is necessary because non XML files have a large variety of formats
        and there is no standard mechanism for declaring the encoding that should be used for
        opening and saving the file. In case of XML files, the encoding is declared at the beginning
        of the file in a special declaration element or it is assumed to be the default value, which
        is UTF-8;</li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>UTF-8 BOM handling</uicontrol> - specifies
        how to handle the <term>Byte Order Mark</term> (BOM) when <ph keyref="product"/> saves an
        UTF-8 XML document: <ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Don't Write</uicontrol> - do not save the BOM bytes. Loaded BOM bytes are
            ignored;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Write</uicontrol> - save the BOM bytes;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Keep</uicontrol> - do not alter the BOM declaration of the currently open
            file. This is the default option.</li>
        </ul><note>The UTF-16 BOM is always preserved. UTF-32 documents have a
            <term>big-endian</term> byte order.</note></li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient diff developer"><uicontrol>Encoding errors
          handling</uicontrol> - defines how to handle characters that cannot be represented in the
        specified encoding of the document when the document is opened. The available options are:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>REPORT</uicontrol> - displays an error dialog box with the character that
            cannot be represented in the specified encoding. Unrecognized characters are rendered as
            an empty box. This is the default option;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>IGNORE</uicontrol> - the character is ignored and it is not included in the
            document displayed in the editor panel;<note type="attention">If you edit and save the
              document, the characters that cannot be represented in the specified encoding are
              dropped.</note></li>
          <li><uicontrol>REPLACE</uicontrol> - replace the character with a standard replacement
            character. For example, if the encoding is UTF-8, the replacement character has the
            Unicode code <codeph>FFFD</codeph>, and if the encoding is ASCII, the replacement
            character code is 63.</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
    <note product="author developer editor">The default encoding for RNC files is considered
      UTF-8.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
