<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-scenarios-management">
  <title>Scenarios Management Preferences</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>scenarios management</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Scenarios Management</uicontrol> preferences panel is opened from menu <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Scenarios Management</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> and allows sharing the global transformation scenarios with other users by
      exporting them to an external file that can be also imported in this preferences panel.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Scenarios Management Preferences Panel</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_scenario_manag_options.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The actions available in this panel are the following:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Import Global Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to import at
        global level all transformation scenarios from a properties file created with the export
        scenario action. The names of the imported scenarios will appear in the <uicontrol>Configure
          Transformation Scenario</uicontrol> dialog followed by <uicontrol>(import)</uicontrol>.
        This way there are no scenario name conflicts.<p>If you want to work with project level
          scenarios you have to first switch to project level in the <uicontrol>Configure
            Transformation Scenario</uicontrol> dialog.</p></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Export Global Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to export all
        global transformation scenarios available in the <uicontrol>Configure Transformation
          Scenario</uicontrol> dialog.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Import Global Validation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to import at global
        level all scenarios from a properties file created with the export scenario action. The
        names of the imported scenarios will appear in the <uicontrol>Configure Validation
          Scenario</uicontrol> dialog followed by <uicontrol>(import)</uicontrol>. This way there
        are no scenario name conflicts.<p>If you want to work with project level scenarios you have
          to first switch to project level in the <uicontrol>Configure Validation
            Scenario</uicontrol> dialog.</p></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Export Global Validation Scenarios</uicontrol> - Allows you to export all
        global validation scenarios available in the <uicontrol>Configure Validation
          Scenario</uicontrol> dialog.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>