<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-sharing">
  <title>Project Level User Options</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>sharing preferences<indexterm>global
              options<indexterm>project
    options</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You are able to set the <ph keyref="product"/> options either globally, or to bound them to a
      specific project by choosing the appropriate setting in the preferences pages:</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Controlling the Storage of the Preferences</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_preferences_control_global_project.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>By default, <uicontrol>Global Options</uicontrol> is selected, meaning that the options are
      stored on your computer, in your user home folder. </p>
    <p>When you choose <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol>, the preferences are stored in the
      project file and can be shared with other users. For instance, if your project file and other
      files and folders are saved on a version control system (like SVN, CVS or Source Safe) or a
      shared folder, your team can use the same options/scenarios you have chosen to store in the
      project file.</p>
    <example>
      <p>You may decide that the default schema associations and catalogs must be shared with other
        team members. To do this, go to <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XML Catalog</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and select <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol>. Now all the options set in
        the <uicontrol>XML Catalog</uicontrol> page are saved in your current project. At a later
        time, you can drop a preferences panel from being stored into the project by selecting
          <uicontrol>Global Options</uicontrol>.</p>
    </example>
    <p>The same mechanism is applied for saving transformation and validation scenarios.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="validation-scenarios-sharing.dita#validation-scenarios-sharing"/>
    <link href="../tasks/create-transformation-scenario.dita#create-transformation-scenario"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>