<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-editor-format">
  <title>Format Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Editor
              preferences<indexterm>format</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>OutOfMemory</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Out Of Memory</indexterm>
        <indexterm>OutOfMemoryError</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Format</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Detect indent on open</uicontrol> - the editor detects the indent settings of
        the open XML document. This way you can correctly format (pretty-print) files that were
        created with different settings, without changing your options every time you edit such a
        file. Besides, you can activate the option for detecting the maximum line width used by the
        formatting and hard wrap mechanism. These features were designed to minimize the differences
        created by the <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> operation when working with a
        versioning system, like CVS for example;<note>If the document contains different-size
          indents, the application computes a weighted average value.</note><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Use zero-indent, if detected</uicontrol> - the formatting operation takes
            into account an indent level of zero in case this is detected.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><ph id="indent-with-tabs"><uicontrol>Indent with tabs</uicontrol> - when enabled, sets the
          indent size to a <term>tab</term> unit. When unchecked, the application uses space
          characters to form an indent. The number of space characters that form a <term>tab</term>
          is defined by the <uicontrol>Indent size</uicontrol> option;</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Indent size</uicontrol> - sets the number of space characters or the tab size
        that equals a single indent. An <i>indent</i> can be a number of spaces or a tab, selectable
        using the <uicontrol>Indent With Tabs</uicontrol> option. For example, if set to 4, one tab equals:<ul>
          <li>either 4 space characters, if the <uicontrol>Indent With Tabs</uicontrol> option is
            unchecked;</li>
          <li>or one tab that spans 4 characters, if the <uicontrol>Indent With Tabs</uicontrol>
            option is checked.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Hard line wrap</uicontrol> - when enabled, <ph keyref="product"/> breaks the
        edited line automatically when its length exceeds the maximum set line width. This feature
        allows you to neatly edit a document;</li>

      <li><uicontrol>Indent on Enter</uicontrol> - if enabled, <ph keyref="product"/> indents the
        new line introduced when pressing the Enter key;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Enable Smart Enter</uicontrol> - if you press the Enter key between a start and
        an end tag, <ph keyref="product"/> places the cursor in an indented position on the empty
        line formed between the start and end tag;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Detect line width on open</uicontrol> - detects the line width automatically
        when the document is opened;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Format and indent the document on open</uicontrol> - when enabled, an XML
        document is formatted and indented before opening it in the editor panel. This option
        applies only to documents associated with the XML editor. <ph
          product="editor author developer">This option does not apply to <term>read-only</term>
          documents when the <xref
            href="preferences-editor.dita#preferences-editor/preferences_can_edit_read_only">Can
            edit read only files</xref> option is disabled;</ph>
      </li>
      <li><uicontrol>Line width - Format and Indent</uicontrol> - defines the point at which the
          <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> (pretty-print) function performs hard line
        wrapping. For example, if set to 100, after a <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol>
        action, the longest line will have at most 100 characters;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Clear undo buffer before Format and Indent</uicontrol> - if checked, you cannot
        undo anymore editing actions that preceded the <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol>
        operation. Only modifications performed after you have performed the operation can be
        undone. Check this option if you encounter out of memory problems
          (<uicontrol>OutOfMemoryError</uicontrol>) when performing the <uicontrol>Format and
          Indent</uicontrol> operation.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the formatting options offered by <ph keyref="product"
      />, go to <xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Autodetect_Formating.html" format="html"
        scope="external">http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Autodetect_Formating.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
