<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-author">
  <title>Author Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Editor
              preferences<indexterm>author</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> preferences page, go to<menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Edit modes</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Author default background color</uicontrol> - default background color of the
        Author editing mode. The <codeph>background-color</codeph> CSS property set in the CSS file
        associated with the current edited document overwrites this option;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Author default foreground color</uicontrol> - default foreground color of the
        Author editing mode. The <codeph>color</codeph> CSS property set in the CSS file associated
        with the current edited document overwrites this option;</li>
      <li id="show-placeholders"><uicontrol>Show placeholders for empty elements</uicontrol> - when
        enabled, placeholders are displayed for empty elements to make them clearly visible. A
        placeholder is rendered as a light grey box displaying the element name;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show Author layout messages</uicontrol> - if enabled, all errors reported
        during layout creation are presented in the <uicontrol>Errors</uicontrol> view;</li>
      <li product="editor author"><uicontrol>Show block range</uicontrol> - if enabled, a
          <term>block range indicator</term> is shown in a stripe located in the left side of the
        editor. The block range indicator is displayed as a heavy line that spans from the first
        line to the last line of the block; </li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show XML comments</uicontrol> - shows comments of the documents you edit in
          <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show processing instructions</uicontrol> - shows processing instructions of the
        documents you edit in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show doctype</uicontrol> - shows <term>doctype</term> sections of the documents
        you edit in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Display referred content (e.g.: entities, XInclude, DITA conref,
          etc.)</uicontrol> - when enabled, the references (like entities, XInclude, DITA conref)
        also display the content of the resources they refer. If you toggle this option while
        editing, reload the file for the modification to take effect;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Auto-scale images wider than (pixels)</uicontrol> - sets the maximum width of
        an image beyond which <ph keyref="product"/> scales the image;<ul>
          <li id="show-very-large-images"><uicontrol>Show very large images</uicontrol> - enables
            the very large images support (larger than 6 megapixels) in the
              <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode;<note type="important">If you enable this option
              and your document contains many such images, <ph keyref="product"/> may consume all
              available memory, throwing an <term>OutOfMemory error</term>. This means that you need
              to restart the application after you increase the <xref
                href="set-parameter-in-startup-script.dita#set-parameter-in-startup-script"
                format="dita" product="author editor">available memory limit.</xref>
              <ph product="authorEclipse authorSDK editorEclipse">available memory limit.</ph>
            </note></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Format and indent</uicontrol> - here you can set the format and indent method
        that is applied when a document is saved in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, or when
        switching the editing mode (from Text to Author or vice versa):<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Only the modified content</uicontrol> - the <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>
            operation only formats the nodes that were modified in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
            mode. The rest of the document preserves its original formatting.<note>This option
              applies also to the DITA Maps open in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
              Manager</uicontrol>.</note></li>
          <li><uicontrol>The entire document</uicontrol> - the <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> operation
            applies formatting to the entire document regardless of the nodes that were modified in
              <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. <p>If the <uicontrol>Apply also 'Format and
                Indent' action as in 'Text' edit mode</uicontrol> option is enabled, the content of
              the document is formatted by applying the <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol>
              rules from the <xref
                href="preferences-editor-format-xml.dita#preferences-editor-format-xml"
                product="author authorEclipse editor editorEclipse" format="dita"
                >Editor/Format/XML</xref>
              <ph product="authorSDK">Editor/Format/XML</ph> option page. In this case, the result
              of the <uicontrol>Format and indent</uicontrol> operation will be the same as when it
              is applied in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editing mode.</p></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Tags display mode</uicontrol> - default display mode for element tags presented
        in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. You can choose between:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Full Tags with Attributes</uicontrol> - this mode reveals the entire XML
            markup, easing the transition from a Text based editing to an
              <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode editing. Tags contain element names, attribute
            names, and attribute values;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Full Tags</uicontrol> - displays name tags that enclose block and inline
            elements;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Block Tags</uicontrol> - displays a mix of element name tags that enclose
            block elements and compact tags that enclose the inline elements;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Inline Tags</uicontrol> - displays only name tags that enclose the inline
            elements;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Partial Tags</uicontrol> - displays compact tags that enclose the inline
            elements;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>No Tags</uicontrol> - no tags are displayed. This representation is as
            close as possible to the document published content;</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Tags background color</uicontrol> - allows you to configure the Author tags
        background color;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Tags foreground color</uicontrol> - allows you to configure the Author tags
        foreground color;</li>
      <li product="authorEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Whitespaces</uicontrol><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Foreground color</uicontrol> - specifies the foreground color of the
            whitespaces rendered in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. To enable this option,
            also select the <uicontrol>Show whitespaces characters</uicontrol> option from <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol> Text Editors</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
