<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-file-types">
    <title>File Types Preferences</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>File Types</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>File type preferences</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p><ph keyref="product"/> offers built-in editing support for a wide variety of file types,
      but you can also add new file extensions and associate them with whatever editor type fits
      your needs. The associations set here between a file extension and the type of editor will
      determine which editor will be opened for editing purposes when that type of file is created
      or opened.</p>
        <p>To configure the <uicontrol>File Types</uicontrol> options, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to
        <uicontrol>File Types</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>
      <fig product="developer editor">
        <title>File Types Preferences Page</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_dev_ed_file_types.png" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <fig product="author">
        <title>File Types Preferences Page</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_file_types.png" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
        <p>The table contains the following columns:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Extension</uicontrol> - The extensions of the files that will be
                associated with an editor type.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol> - The type of editor which the extensions will be
        associated with. Some editors provide easy access to frequent operations via toolbars (XML
        editor, XSL editor, DTD editor) while others provide just a syntax highlight scheme (Java
        editor, SQL editor, Shell editor, etc.).<p>If the editor set here is not one of the XML
          editors (XML editor, XSL editor, XSD editor, RNG editor, WSDL editor) then the encoding
          set in the <xref href="preferences-encoding.dita"><uicontrol>Encoding for non XML
              files</uicontrol> option</xref> is used for opening and saving a file of this type.
        </p></li>
        </ul>
    <p product="developer editor">The files that match the <uicontrol>Ant build patterns</uicontrol>
      will be associated with the Ant editor.</p>
        <p>The files that match the <uicontrol>Binary file patterns</uicontrol> patterns are handled
      as binary and opened in the associated system application. Also, they are excluded from the
      following actions available in the <xref
        href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
          ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref>: <uicontrol>File/Replace in Files</uicontrol>,
        <uicontrol>Check Spelling in Files</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol>.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
