<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-xml-instances-generator">
  <title>XML Instances Generator Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>XML instances
          generator</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>XML Instances Generator</uicontrol> preferences panel is opened from menu <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML Instances Generator</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. It sets the default parameters of the <uicontrol>Generate Sample XML
        Files</uicontrol> tool that is available on the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu.</p>
    <p>The options of the tool that generates XML instance documents based on a W3C XML Schema are
      the following:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Generate optional elements</uicontrol> - If checked, the elements declared
        optional in the schema will be generated in the XML instance.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Generate optional attributes</uicontrol> - If checked, the attributes declared
        optional in the schema will be generated in the XML instance.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Values of elements and attributes</uicontrol> - Specifies what values are
        generated in elements and attributes of the XML instance. It can have one of the values:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>None</uicontrol> - no values for the generated elements and attributes</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Default</uicontrol> - the value is the element name or attribute name</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - a random value</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Preferred number of repetitions</uicontrol> - If the values set here is greater
        than <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph>, then the <codeph>maxOccurs</codeph> is used.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Maximum recursivity level</uicontrol> - For recursive type definitions this
        parameter specifies the number of levels of recursive elements inserted in the parent
        element with the same name.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Type alternative strategy</uicontrol> - specifies how the element type
        alternatives are generated in the XML instance:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>First</uicontrol> - the first element type alternative whose XPath
            condition is true is used;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - a random element type alternative whose XPath
            condition is true is used;<note>In case no XPath condition is true, the default element
              type alternative is used.</note></li>
          <li>
            <note>To evaluate an XPath expression, either the values of the attributes defined in
              the <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> tab of the <uicontrol>XML Instance
                Generator</uicontrol> dialog, or the attributes values defined in the XML Schema are
              used.  </note>
          </li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Choice strategy</uicontrol> - For <keyword>choice</keyword> element models
        specifies what choice will be generated in the XML instance:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>First</uicontrol> - the first choice is selected from the
              <keyword>choice</keyword> definition and an instance of that choice is generated in
            the XML instance document.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Random</uicontrol> - a random choice is selected from the
              <keyword>choice</keyword> definition and an instance of that will be generated.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Generate the other options as comments</uicontrol> - If checked, the other
        options of the <keyword>choice</keyword> element model (the options which are not selected)
        will be generated inside an XML comment in the XML instance.</li>
      <li id="use-incremental-names"><uicontrol>Use incremental attribute / element names as
          default</uicontrol> - If checked, the value of an element or attribute starts with the
        name of that element or attribute. For example, for an <codeph>a</codeph> element the
        generated values are: <codeph>a1</codeph>, <codeph>a2</codeph>, <codeph>a3</codeph>, etc. If
        not checked, the value is the name of the type of that element / attribute, for example:
          <codeph>string</codeph>, <codeph>decimal</codeph>, etc.</li>
      <li id="maximim-length"><uicontrol>Maximum length</uicontrol> - The maximum length of string
        values generated for elements and attributes.</li>
      <li id="discard-optional-elements"><uicontrol>Discard optional elements after nested
          level</uicontrol> - The optional elements that exceed the specified nested level are
        discarded. This option is useful for limiting deeply nested element definitions that can
        quickly result in very large XML documents.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
