<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-encoding">
  <title>Encoding Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>character
            encoding</indexterm><indexterm>encoding</indexterm><indexterm>UTF-8</indexterm><indexterm>BOM</indexterm><indexterm>byte
            order mark</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To configure character encoding options, <ph
        conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Encoding</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. The following encoding options are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li product="author developer editor svnClient"
          ><uicontrol><?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140826T142325-0400" comment="This will probably change to &quot;Fallback character encoding&quot; per issue #34."?>Encoding
          for non XML files<?oxy_comment_end?></uicontrol> - This setting specifies the default
        character encoding used to open documents whose character encoding cannot be determined. <ph
          keyref="product"/> detects character encoding for different file types as follows: <ul
          id="ul_f55_tfn_dp">
          <li>For XML, DTD and CSS the encoding specified in the document is used. If an encoding is
            not specified, the default encoding of UTF-8 is used.</li>
          <li>For JAVASCRIPT, JSON, SQL, XQUERY, and RNC, the default encoding of UTF-8 is
            used.</li>
          <li>For all other file types, the encoding specified here is used. </li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author developer"><uicontrol>UTF-8 BOM handling</uicontrol> - This setting
        specifies how to handle the <term>Byte Order Mark</term> (BOM) when <ph keyref="product"/>
        saves a UTF-8 XML document: <ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Don't Write</uicontrol> - do not save the BOM bytes. Loaded BOM bytes are
            ignored.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Write</uicontrol> - save the BOM bytes.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Keep</uicontrol> - do not alter the BOM declaration of the currently open
            file. This is the default option.</li>
        </ul><note>The UTF-16 BOM is always preserved. UTF-32 documents have a
            <term>big-endian</term> byte order.</note></li>
      <li product="author developer editor svnClient"><uicontrol>Encoding errors
          handling</uicontrol> - This setting specifies how to handle characters that cannot be
        represented in the character encoding that is used when the document is opened. The
        available options are:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>REPORT</uicontrol> - displays an error identifying the character that
            cannot be represented in the specified encoding. Unrecognized characters are rendered as
            an empty box. This is the default option.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>IGNORE</uicontrol> - the error is ignored and the character is not included
            in the document displayed in the editor.<note type="attention">If you edit and save the
              document, the characters that cannot be represented in the specified encoding are
              dropped.</note></li>
          <li><uicontrol>REPLACE</uicontrol> - the character is replaced with a standard replacement
            character. For example, if the encoding is UTF-8, the replacement character has the
            Unicode code <codeph>FFFD</codeph>, and if the encoding is ASCII, the replacement
            character code is 63.</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
