<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-colors">
  <title>Colors Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the application <indexterm>Appearance
              Preferences<indexterm>Colors</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you configure the colors for frames, dialog boxes, controls,
      and commands.  To configure the <uicontrol>Colors</uicontrol>, <ph
        conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Appearance</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Colors</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>Clicking the color button for any of the options opens a <uicontrol>Choose color</uicontrol>
      dialog box. It includes several tabs that allow you to configure the color in numerous ways.
      This page allows you to select and configure the color for the following:<ul
        id="ul_gbr_1n1_3s">
        <li><uicontrol>Background</uicontrol> - Background color for various general user interface
          items.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Text components background</uicontrol> - Background color for various
          components (such as text fields, views, and dialog boxes).</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Menus and toolbars backround</uicontrol> - Background color for specific
          components such as menus, toolbars, and tabs.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Selection background</uicontrol> - Background color for the current
          selections in certain components, such as some views and panes.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Inactive selection background</uicontrol> - Background color for a selection
          in a view that is not the current focus.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Menus and toolbars selection background</uicontrol> - (This option is not
          available for Mac OS) Background color for menu selections and toolbar buttons.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>View titles background</uicontrol> - Background color for the titles of view
          and tabs.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Foreground</uicontrol> - Foreground color for various general user interface
          items.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Disabled foreground</uicontrol> - Foreground color for various components
          that are not the current focus (such as views other than the currently selected one).</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Selection foreground</uicontrol> - Foreground color for the current
          selection.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Link foreground</uicontrol> - Foreground color for links in views and dialog
          boxes.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Borders and table grids</uicontrol> - Color for certain borders and table
          grid lines.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Separator</uicontrol> - Color for the separators in toolbars, menus, and
          dialog boxes.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <note>You must restart the application for your changes to be applied.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
