<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-xslt-saxon8">
  <title>Saxon-HE/PE/EE Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>XSLT/FO/XQuery preferences<indexterm>Saxon
              HE/PE/EE</indexterm><indexterm>Saxon-HE/PE/EE</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Saxon HE/PE/EE</uicontrol> preferences panel go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author svnClient developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XSLT/FO/XQuery</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Saxon</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Saxon HE/PE/EE</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to configure
      the following XSLT options for the Saxon <ph
        conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/saxon9FullVersion"/> transformer
      (editions: Home Edition, Professional, and Enterprise):</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Use a configuration file ("-config")</uicontrol> - sets a Saxon <ph
          conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/saxon9FullVersion"/> configuration
        file that is executed for XSLT transformation and validation processes;</li>
      <li><ph id="saxon-option-versmsg"><uicontrol>Version warnings ("-versmsg")</uicontrol> - warns
          you when the transformation is applied to an XSLT 1.0 stylesheet</ph>;</li>
      <li><ph id="saxon-option-l"><uicontrol>Line numbering ("-l")</uicontrol> - error line number
          is included in the output messages</ph>;</li>
      <li><ph id="saxon-option-debug-trace"><uicontrol>Debugger trace into XPath expressions
            (applies to debugging sessions)</uicontrol> - instructs the <xref
            product="editor editorEclipse developer developerEclipse"
            href="../tasks/steps-in-typical-debug-process.dita" format="dita">XSLT Debugger</xref>
          <ph product="author authorEclipse">XSLT Debugger</ph> to step into XPath
        expressions</ph>;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Expand attributes defaults ("-expand")</uicontrol> - specifies whether the
        attributes defined in the associated DTD or XML Schema that have default values are expanded
        in output of the transformation you are executing;</li>
      <li id="saxon-option-dtd"><uicontrol>DTD validation of the source ("-dtd")</uicontrol> - the
        following options are available:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>On</uicontrol> - requests <term>DTD-based</term> validation of the source
            file and of any files read using the document() function;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Off</uicontrol> - (default setting) suppresses DTD validation;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Recover</uicontrol> - performs DTD validation but treats the errors as
            non-fatal.</li>
        </ul><note>Any external DTD is likely to be read even if not used for validation, because
          DTDs can contain definitions of entities.</note></li>
      <li id="saxon-option-warnings"><uicontrol>Recoverable errors ("-warnings")</uicontrol> -
        policy for handling recoverable errors in the stylesheet: Allows you to choose how dynamic
        errors are handled. One of the following options can be selected:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Recover silently ("silent")</uicontrol>;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Recover with warnings ("recover")</uicontrol> - default setting;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Signal the error and do not attempt recovery ("fatal")</uicontrol>.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li id="saxon-option-strip"><uicontrol>Strip whitespaces ("-strip")</uicontrol> - strip
        whitespaces feature can be one of the following three options:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>All ("all")</uicontrol> - strips all whitespace text nodes from source
            documents before any further processing, regardless of any
              <codeph>xsl:strip-space</codeph> declarations in the stylesheet, or any
              <codeph>xml:space</codeph> attributes in the source document;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Ignorable ("ignorable")</uicontrol> - strips all ignorable whitespace text
            nodes from source documents before any further processing, regardless of any
              <codeph>xsl:strip-space</codeph> declarations in the stylesheet, or any
              <codeph>xml:space</codeph> attributes in the source document. Whitespace text nodes
            are ignorable if they appear in elements defined in the DTD or schema as having
            element-only content;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>None ("none")</uicontrol> - default setting. No whitespaces are stripped
            before further processing. However, whitespace are stripped if this is specified in the
            stylesheet using <codeph>xsl:strip-space</codeph>.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li id="saxon-option-opt"><uicontrol>Optimization level ("-opt")</uicontrol> - set
        optimization level. The value is an integer in the range 0 (no optimization) to 10 (full
        optimization); currently all values other than 0 result in full optimization but this is
        likely to change in the future. The default is full optimization; this feature allows
        optimization to be suppressed in cases where reducing compile time is important, or where
        optimization gets in the way of debugging, or causes extension functions with side-effects
        to behave unpredictably. (Note however, that even with no optimization, the lazy evaluation
        may still cause the evaluation order to be not as expected).</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The advanced options available only in Saxon PE / EE are:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><ph id="saxon-option-ext"><uicontrol>Allow calls on extension functions
            ("-ext")</uicontrol> - if checked, the stylesheet is allowed to call external Java
          functions. This does not affect calls on integrated extension functions, including Saxon
          and EXSLT extension functions. This option is useful when loading an untrusted stylesheet,
          perhaps from a remote site using an http:// URL; it ensures that the stylesheet cannot
          call arbitrary Java methods and thus gain privileged access to resources on your
          machine;</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Register Saxon-CE extension functions and instructions</uicontrol> - registers
        the Saxon-CE extension functions and instructions when compiling a stylesheet using the
        Saxon <ph conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/saxon9FullVersion"/>
          processors;<note
          conref="supported-XSLT-processors.dita#supported-XSLT-processors/saxon-ce-execution-limitation"
          product="developer editor developerEclipse editorEclipse"/></li>
    </ul>
    <p>The advanced options available only in Saxon EE are:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>XML Schema version</uicontrol> - use this option to change the default XML
          Schema version set in <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> XML</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> XML Parser</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> XML Schema</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.<note>This option is available when you configure the Saxon EE advanced
            options from a transformation scenario.</note></li>
        <li id="saxon-option-val"><uicontrol>Validation of the source file ("-val")</uicontrol> -
          requests schema-based validation of the source file and of any files read using the
            <codeph>document()</codeph> or similar functions. Validation is available only with
          Saxon-EE, and this flag automatically switches on the <codeph>-sa</codeph> option.
          Available options:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Schema validation ("strict")</uicontrol> - this mode requires an XML
              Schema and specifies that the source documents should be parsed with schema-validation
              enabled;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Lax schema validation ("lax")</uicontrol> - this mode specifies if the
              source documents should be parsed with schema-validation enabled if an XML Schema is
              provided;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Disable schema validation</uicontrol> - this specifies that the source
              documents should be parsed with schema-validation disabled.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><ph id="saxon-option-outval"><uicontrol>Validation errors in the results tree treated as
              warnings ("-outval")</uicontrol> - normally, if validation of result documents is
            requested, a validation error is fatal. Enabling this option causes such validation
            failures to be treated as warnings.</ph>
        </li>
        <li><ph id="saxon-option-outval-comments"><uicontrol>Write comments for non-fatal validation
              errors of the result document</uicontrol> - the validation messages are written (where
            possible) as a comment in the result document itself;</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="generate_bytecode_option"><ph><uicontrol>Generate bytecode
                ("--generateByteCode:(on|off)")</uicontrol></ph> - when you enable this option,
            Saxon-EE attempts to generate Java bytecode for evaluation of parts of a query or
            stylesheet that are amenable to such treatment. For further details regarding this
            option, go to<xref href="http://www.saxonica.com/documentation/javadoc/"
              format="html#GENERATE_BYTE_CODE" scope="external"
              >http://www.saxonica.com/documentation/javadoc/</xref></ph>;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Initializer class</uicontrol> - equivalent with the <term>-init</term> Saxon
          command-line argument. The value is the name of a user-supplied class that implements the
            <apiname>net.sf.saxon.lib.Initializer</apiname> interface; this initializer is called
          during the initialization process, and may be used to set any options required on the
          configuration programmatically. It is particularly useful for tasks such as registering
          extension functions, collations, or external object models, especially in Saxon-HE where
          the option cannot be set via a configuration file. Saxon only calls the initializer when
          running from the command line, but the same code may be invoked to perform initialization
          when running user application code.<note type="important">The <xref
              href="xslt-tab.dita#xslt-tab/advanced-options">advanced Saxon-HE/PE/EE options
              configured in a transformation scenario</xref> override the Saxon-HE/PE/EE options
            defined globally.</note></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>