<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-data-sources">
  <title>Data Sources Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>data sources</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Data Sources</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Data Sources</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. In this preferences page you can configure data sources and connections to
      relational databases as well as native XML databases. You can check the list of drivers (<xref
        href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/database_drivers.html" scope="external" format="html"
        >http://www.oxygenxml.com/database_drivers.html</xref>) available for the major database
      servers.</p>
    <fig product="editor author developer">
      <title>The Data Sources Preferences Panel</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_datasources.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Data Sources Preferences Panel</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_datasources.png"/>
    </fig>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> - opens the <uicontrol>Data Sources Drivers</uicontrol> dialog
        that allows you to configure a new database driver.<fig product="editor author developer">
          <title>The Data Sources Drivers Dialog</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_datasource_oracle.png"/>
        </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
          <title>The Data Sources Drivers Dialog</title>
          <image href="../img/ec_datasource_oracle.png"/>
        </fig><p>The following options are available:</p><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - the name of the new data source driver that will be used
            for creating connections to the database;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - selects the data source type from the supported driver
            types;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> - opens the User Manual at <xref
              href="download-database-drivers.dita">the list of the sections</xref> where the
            configuration of supported data sources is explained and the URLs for downloading the
            database drivers are specified;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Driver Class</uicontrol> - specifies the driver class for the data source
            driver;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> - adds the driver class library;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> - removes the selected driver class library from the
            list;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Detect</uicontrol> - detects driver class candidates;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Stop</uicontrol> - stops the detection of the driver candidates;</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> - opens the <uicontrol>Data Sources Drivers</uicontrol> dialog
        for editing the selected driver. See above the specifications for the <uicontrol>Data
          Sources Drivers</uicontrol> dialog. In order to edit a data source, there must be no
        connections using that data source driver;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> - deletes the selected driver. In order to delete a data
        source, there must be no connections using that data source driver;</li>
    </ul>
    <fig product="editor author developer">
      <title>The Connections Preferences Panel</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_connections.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Connections Preferences Panel</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_connections.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>For performance issues, you can set the maximum number of cells that will be displayed in the
        <uicontrol>Table Explorer</uicontrol> view for a database table. Leave the field
        <uicontrol>Limit the number of cells</uicontrol> empty if you want the entire content of the
      table to be displayed. By default this field is set to 2,000. If a table having more cells
      than the value set here is displayed in the <uicontrol>Table Explorer</uicontrol> view, a
      warning dialog will inform you that the table is only partially shown.</p>
    <p>In Oracle XML a container can hold millions of resources. If the node corresponding to such a
      container in the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view would display all the
      contained resources at the same time the performance of the view would be very slow. To
      prevent such a situation only a limited number of the contained resources is displayed as
      child nodes of the container node. Navigation to other contained resources from the same
      container is enabled by the <i>Up</i> and <i>Down</i> buttons in the <uicontrol>Data Source
        Explorer</uicontrol> view. This limited number is set in the option <uicontrol>Maximum
        number of children for container nodes</uicontrol>. The default value is 200 nodes.</p>
    <p product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">The <uicontrol>Show warning when
        expanding other database schema</uicontrol> option controls if a warning message will be
      displayed when expanding another database schema and there are tables selected in the current
      expanded one. This applies for the dialog <uicontrol>Select database table</uicontrol> when
      invoking the <uicontrol>Convert DB Structure to XML Schema</uicontrol> action.</p>
    <p>The actions of the buttons from the <uicontrol>Connections</uicontrol> panel are the
      following:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> - opens the <uicontrol>Connection</uicontrol> dialog which has
        the following fields:<fig product="editor author developer">
          <title>The Connection Dialog</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_connections_new.png"/>
        </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
          <title>The Connection Dialog</title>
          <image href="../img/ec_connections_new.png"/>
        </fig><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - the name of the new connection that will be used in
            transformation scenarios and validation scenarios;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Data Source</uicontrol> - allows selecting a data source defined in the
              <uicontrol>Data Source Drivers</uicontrol> dialog.</li>
        </ul><p>Depending upon the selected data source, you can set some of the following
          parameters in the <uicontrol>Connection details</uicontrol> area:</p><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>URL</uicontrol> - the URL for connecting to the database server;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>User</uicontrol> - the user name for connecting to the database
            server;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Password</uicontrol> - the password of the specified user name;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Host</uicontrol> - the host address of the server;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Port</uicontrol> - the port where the server accepts the connection;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>XML DB URI</uicontrol> - the database URI;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Database</uicontrol> - the initial database name;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Collection</uicontrol> - one of the available collections for the specified
            data source;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Environment home directory</uicontrol> - specifies the home directory (only
            for a Berkeley database);</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Verbosity</uicontrol> - sets the verbosity level for output messages (only
            for a Berkeley database);</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Use a secure HTTPS connection (SSL)</uicontrol> - allows you to establish a
            secure connection to an eXist database through the SSL protocol. </li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> - opens the <uicontrol>Connection</uicontrol> dialog, allowing
        you to edit the selected connection. See above the specifications for the
          <uicontrol>Connection</uicontrol> dialog;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> - creates a duplicate of the currently selected
        connection;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> - deletes the selected connection.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
