<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-colors-sh">
  <title>Syntax Highlight Preferences</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>Syntax Highlight</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Syntax highlight preferences</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> supports syntax highlighting in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode
      editors for numerous types of documents, including XML, XHTML, JavaScript, XQuery, XPath, PHP,
      CSS, LESS, Markdown, Text, <ph product="editor editorEclipse developer developerEclipse">DTD,
        RNC, Java, JSON</ph><ph product="developer editor">, Ant</ph>, and more. </p>
    <p>To configure syntax highlighting, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Syntax Highlight</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>To set syntax colors for a language, expand the listing for that language in the top panel to
      show the list of syntax items for that type of document. Use the color and style selectors to
      change how each syntax item is displayed. The results of your changes are displayed in the
        <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> panel. If you do not know the name of the syntax token that
      you want to configure, click that token in the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> area to select
        it.<note>All default color sets come with a high-contrast variant that is automatically used
        when you switch to a black-background or white-background high-contrast theme in your
        Windows operating system settings. The high-contrast theme will not overwrite any default
        color you set in <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Syntax Highlight</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> preferences page.</note></p>

    <p>The settings for XML documents are also used in XSD, XSL, RNG documents and the
        <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> area has a separate tab for each of them when
        <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol> is selected in the top pane.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Enable nested syntax highlight</uicontrol> option controls whether or not
      content types that are nested in the same file (such as PHP, JS, or CSS scripts inside an HTML
      file) are highlighted according to the color schemes defined for each content type.</p>
  </body>
</topic>