<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-document-type-association">
  <title>Document Type Association Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>document type
          association</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p conref="../concepts/doc-type.dita#doc-type/document-type-definition"/>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author developer authorSDK">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p><ph
        conref="dg-complex-customization-tutorial.dita#dg-complex-customization-tutorial/dta_definition"
      /></p>
    <p>The following actions are available in this preferences panel:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Change framework directory location</uicontrol> - specifies a custom frameworks
        folder from where <ph keyref="product"/> loads the document types;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Document types table</uicontrol> - presents the currently defined document type
        associations, ordered by priority and alphabetically. Each edited document type has a set of
        association rules (rules used by the application to detect the proper document type
        association to use for an opened XML document). A rule is described by:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol> - specifies the namespace of the root element from
            the association rules set (<i>* (any)</i> by default). If you want to apply the rule
            only when the root element is in no namespace, leave this field empty (remove the
              <uicontrol>ANY_VALUE</uicontrol> string);</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Root local name</uicontrol> - specifies the local name of the root element
              (<i>* (any)</i> by default);</li>
          <li><uicontrol>File name</uicontrol> - specifies the name of the file (<i>* (any)</i> by
            default);</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Public ID</uicontrol> - represents the Public ID of the matched
            document;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Java class</uicontrol> - presents the name of the Java class which is used
            to determine if a document matches the rule;</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> - opens a dialog box that allows you to add a new
        association;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> - opens a new dialog allowing you to edit an existing
          association;<note>If you try to edit an existing association type when you have no write
          permissions to its store location, a dialog box will be shown, asking if you want to
          extend the document type.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> - opens a new dialog allowing you to duplicate the
        configuration of an existing document type association;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Extend</uicontrol> - extend an existing document type, allowing you to add or
        remove functionality, starting from a base document type. All these changes will be saved as
        a patch. When the base document type is modified and evolves (from one application version
        to another, for example) the extension will evolve along with the base document type,
        allowing it to use the new features/actions added in the base document type.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> - deletes the selected associations;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Enable DTD/XML Schema processing in document type detection</uicontrol> - when
        this option is enabled, the matching process also examines the DTD/XML Schema associated
        with the document. For example, the fixed attributes declared in the DTD for the root
        element are also analyzed, if this is specified in the association rules.<p>This is
          especially useful if you are writing DITA customizations. DITA topics and maps are also
          matched by looking for the <codeph>DITAArchVersion</codeph> attribute of the root element.
          This attribute is specified as <codeph>default</codeph> in the DTD and it is detected in
          the root element, helping <ph keyref="product"/> to correctly match the DITA
          customization.</p><p>This option is enabled by default;</p></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Only for local DTD's / XML Schemas</uicontrol> - when the previous feature is
        enabled, you can choose with this option to process only the local DTD's / XML
          Schemas.<p>This option is enabled by default.</p></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Enable DTD/XML Schema caching</uicontrol> - when this option is enabled the
        associated DTDs or XML Schema are cached when parsed for the first time, improving
        performance when opening new documents with similar schema associations.<p>This option is
          enabled by default.</p></li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
