<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-xml-catalog">
  <title>XML Catalog Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>XML<indexterm>XML
          Catalog</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML catalog preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To configure options that pertain to <xref keyref="glossentry_xml-catalog"><term>XML
          Catalogs</term></xref>, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML Catalog</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available:<dl>
        <dlentry id="xml_catalog_prefer">
          <dt><uicontrol>Prefer</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Determines whether public identifiers specified in the catalog are used in favor of
            system identifiers supplied in the document. Suppose you have an entity in your document
            for which both a public identifier and a system identifier has been specified, and the
            catalog only contains a mapping for the public identifier (for example, a matching
            public catalog entry). You can choose between the following:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>system</uicontrol> - If selected, the system identifier in the document
                is used.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>public</uicontrol> - If selected, the URI supplied in the matching
                public catalog entry is used. Generally, the purpose of catalogs is to override the
                system identifiers in XML documents, so <uicontrol>public</uicontrol> should usually
                be used for your catalogs.</li>
            </ul><note>If the catalog contains a matching system catalog entry giving a mapping for
              the system identifier, that mapping would have been used, the public identifier would
              never have been considered, and this setting would be irrelevant.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Verbosity</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When using catalogs it is sometimes useful to see what catalog files are parsed, if
            they are valid or not, and what identifiers are resolved by the catalogs. This option
            selects the detail level of such logging messages of the <term>XML catalog</term>
            resolver that will be displayed in the <uicontrol>Catalogs</uicontrol> table at the
            bottom of the window. You can choose between the following:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>None</uicontrol> - No message is displayed by the catalog resolver when
                it tries to resolve a URI reference, a SYSTEM one or a PUBLIC one with the <term>XML
                  catalogs</term> specified in this panel.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Unresolved entities</uicontrol> - Only the logging messages that track
                the failed attempts to resolve references are displayed.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>All messages</uicontrol> - The messages of both failed attempts and
                successful ones are displayed.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="xml_catalog_resolve_schema">
          <dt><uicontrol>Resolve schema locations also through system mappings</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>
            <p>If selected, <ph keyref="product"/> analyzes both <i>uri</i> and <i>system</i>
              mappings to resolve the location of schema.<note>This option is not applicable for DTD
                schemas since the public and system catalog mappings are always
              considered.</note></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="xml_catalog_process_ns">
          <dt><uicontrol>Process "schemaLocation" namespaces through URI mappings for XML
              Schema</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If selected, the target namespace of the imported XML Schema is resolved through the
              <i>uri</i> mappings. The namespace is taken into account only when the schema
            specified in the <i>schemaLocation</i> attribute was not resolved successfully. If not
            selected, the system IDs are used to resolve the schema location.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Use default catalog</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected and <ph keyref="product"/> cannot resolve the catalog
            mapping with any other means, the default global catalog (listed below this checkbox) is
            used. For more information, see <xref
              href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita#using-XML-Catalogs/catalog-order"/>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Catalogs</uicontrol> table</dt>
          <dd>You can use this table to add or manage global user-defined catalogs. The following
            actions are available at the bottom of the table:<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Add16.png" placement="inline"
                        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"/>Add</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to add a catalog to the list. <ph
                      conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path-ph"/></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Wrench16.png" id="image_l2t_4ns_tr"
                        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
                    />Edit</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to edit an existing catalog. <ph
                      conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path-ph"/></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif" placement="inline"
                        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
                    />Delete</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Deletes the currently selected catalog from the list.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MoveUpEntry16.gif" id="image_fpb_rr1_5r"
                        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"/>Up</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Moves the selection to the previous resource.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MoveDownEntry16.gif" id="image_xht_qr1_5r"
                        product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
                    />Down</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Moves the selection to the following resource.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p><p>
              <note>When you add, delete, or edit a catalog in this table, you need to reopen the
                currently edited files that use the modified catalog or run <xref
                  href="validation-actions-in-user-interface.dita#validation-actions-in-user-interface"
                  format="dita">a manual <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol> action </xref> so that the
                changes take full effect.</note>
            </p><p>You can also add or configure catalogs at <term>framework</term> level from the
                <xref href="document-type-catalogs-tab.dita#document-type-catalogs-tab"
                  ><uicontrol>Catalogs</uicontrol> tab</xref> in the <xref
                href="the-document-type-dialog.dita#the-document-type-dialog"><uicontrol>Document
                  Type</uicontrol> configuration dialog box</xref>.</p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link format="html"
        href="http://xerces.apache.org/xml-commons/components/resolver/resolver-article.html#ctrlresolver"
        scope="external">
        <linktext>Controlling the Catalog Resolver</linktext>
      </link>
      <link href="using-XML-Catalogs.dita#using-XML-Catalogs"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
