<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-global">
  <title>Global Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>global</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To set the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> options of <ph keyref="product"/>, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> preferences
      page:</p>
    <ul>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Automatic Version Checking</uicontrol> - Sets whether <ph keyref="product"/> will
        check for a new version on startup. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Language</uicontrol> - Sets the language used in the user interface to English,
        French, German, Dutch, Japanese, or
        <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140806T172801-0400" comment="I do not see Italian as a choice in 16.0. Is it scheduled for 16.1?"?>Italian<?oxy_comment_end?>.
        You must restart <ph keyref="product"/> for the change to take effect. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Other language</uicontrol> - Sets the language used in the user interface to
        another language using an interface localization file
        (<?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140806T173240-0400" comment="Localization topic has no mention of using a properties file."?>either
          <term>properties</term> or XML<?oxy_comment_end?>). <ph product="editor author developer"
          >For details about creating this file, see <xref
            href="changing-user-interface-language.dita"/>.</ph>
        <note>If some interface labels are not rendered correctly after restarting the application,
          (for example Chinese or Korean characters are not displayed correctly), make sure that
          your operating system had the appropriate language pack installed (for example the
          East-Asian language pack).</note>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Look and Feel</uicontrol> - Allows you to change graphic style (look and feel) of
        the user interface. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> - Allows you to set the style of the interface. On Windows
        there are available the following styles:<ul>
          <li>Office 2003</li>
          <li>Vsnet</li>
          <li>Eclipse</li>
          <li>Xerto</li>
          <li>Default</li>
        </ul><note>After changing the style, restart the application in order for the modification
          to take effect.</note><p>On Linux there are available the following styles:</p><ul>
          <li>Eclipse</li>
          <li>Default</li>
        </ul><note>After changing the style, you have to restart the application in order for the
          modification to take effect.</note><p>On Mac OS X this option is not available.</p>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Themes</uicontrol> - Allows you to set the theme of the interfaced. On Windows
        this option is enabled only if you have selected the<uicontrol>Office 2003</uicontrol> or
          <uicontrol>Default</uicontrol> styles. The following themes are available:<ul>
          <li>Normal Color</li>
          <li>Home Stead</li>
          <li>Metallic</li>
          <li>Default</li>
          <li>Gray</li>
        </ul><p>On Linux and Mac OS X this option is not available.</p>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Line separator</uicontrol> - Allows you to specify the line separator use when
        saving files. Use <uicontrol>System Default</uicontrol> to select the normal line separator
        for your OS. If you want the existing file separator of a file to be maintained, regardless
        of your current OS, check <uicontrol>Detect the line separator on file open</uicontrol>. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Detect the line separator on file open</uicontrol> - When this option is checked,
        the editor detects the line separator when a file is loaded and it uses it when the file is
        saved. New files are saved using the line separator defined by the<uicontrol>Line
          separator</uicontrol> option. </li>
      <li product="editor author developer" id="default_internet_browser">
        <uicontrol>Default Internet browser</uicontrol> - The path to a web browser to be used for:<ul>
          <li>opening (X)HTML or PDF transformation results;</li>
          <li>opening a web page (for example, pointing to specific paragraphs in the W3C
            recommendation of XML Schema in case of XML Schema validation errors).</li>
        </ul> If you leave this setting blank, you system default browser will be used. </li>
      <li product="editor author developer">
        <uicontrol>Open last edited files from project</uicontrol> - When enabled,<ph
          keyref="product"/> opens the files you had open the last time you used a project whenever
        you open the application or switch to that project. </li>
      <li product="author developer editor">
        <uicontrol>Beep on operation finished</uicontrol> - When selected, <ph keyref="product"/>
        beeps when a validation or transform action ends. Different tones are used for success and
        failure. The tones used may depend on your operating system's sound settings. </li>
      <li product="author authorSDK developer editor svnClient">
        <uicontrol>Show memory status</uicontrol> - When selected, the memory<ph keyref="product"/>
        uses is displayed in the status bar. To free memory, click the <uicontrol><image
            id="image_hy1_j32_gg" href="../img/run_garbage_collector.png" placement="inline"/>Run
          Garbage Collector</uicontrol> button located at the right side of the status bar. The
        memory status bar turns yellow or red when <ph keyref="product"/> uses too much memory. You
        can change the amount of memory available to Oxygen by <xref
          keyref="set-parameters-for-application-launchers">changing the parameters of the
          application launcher</xref>.  </li>
      <li product="author developer editor">
        <uicontrol>Check opened files for file system changes</uicontrol> - If selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> checks the content of the all opened editors to see if they have been
        updated by another application. If the file has changed, it will ask you if you want to
        reload the file. <ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Auto update unmodified editors on file system changes</uicontrol> - If
            selected, <ph keyref="product"/> automatically updates unmodified editors if the edited
            file changes externally.
            <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140811T112228-0400" comment="This is one of the few times that the default is mentioned. We could decide to state the default for all settings, but it is not clear that people really need to know this. "?>By
            default this option is disabled<?oxy_comment_end?>, meaning that you are prompted to
            decide if you want <ph keyref="product"/> to update the file content.</li>
        </ul><note><uicontrol><?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140811T112557-0400" comment="Really? oXygen reloads other types of files when they are changed externally, so what part of the behavior is specific to DITA?

In any case, if this behavior is specific to DITA, this needs to be stated in the interface, not just in the help. In fact, it should be in a DITA specific settings page, not a global page, which suggests that any setting entered there are global in nature -- that is, that they apply to everything."?>Check
            opened files for file system changes</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Auto update unmodified
            editors on file system changes</uicontrol> influence only DITA documents.
          <?oxy_comment_end?></note>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Show Java vendor warning at startup</uicontrol> - If selected, displays a warning
        on startup if a non-recommended version of the Java virtual machine is being used. </li>
      <li product="editor author developer">
        <p><uicontrol>File Chooser Dialog</uicontrol> - Set the directory that will be shown when
          the <xref href="opening-existing-documents.dita">Open file dialog</xref> is displayed.</p><ul><li>
            <uicontrol>Last visited directory</uicontrol> - The last visited folder. </li>
      <li>
            <uicontrol>Directory of the edited file</uicontrol> - The folder where the currently
            edited file is stored. </li></ul></li>
      <li>
        <uicontrol>Show hidden files and directories</uicontrol> - Shows system hidden files and folders in the file browser dialog and the folder browser
          dialog. This setting is not available on OS X.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
