<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-global">
  <title>Global Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>global</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To set the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> options of <ph keyref="product"/>, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> preferences
      page:</p>
    <ul>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Automatic Version Checking</uicontrol> - This option sets whether <ph
          keyref="product"/> will check for a new version on startup. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Language</uicontrol> - This option sets the language used in the user interface
        to English, French, German, Dutch, Japanese, or
        <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140806T172801-0400" comment="I do not see Italian as a choice in 16.0. Is it scheduled for 16.1?"?>Italian<?oxy_comment_end?>.
        You must restart <ph keyref="product"/> for the change to take effect. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Other language</uicontrol> - This option sets the language used in the user
        interface using an interface localization file
        (<?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140806T173240-0400" comment="Localization topic has no mention of using a properties file."?>either
          <term>properties</term> or XML<?oxy_comment_end?>). <ph product="editor author developer"
          >For details about creating this file, see <xref
            href="changing-user-interface-language.dita"/>.</ph> You can use this option to set the
        language of the user interface to a language that is not shipped with <ph keyref="product"
          />.<note>If some interface labels are not rendered correctly after restarting the
          application, (for example Chinese or Korean characters are not displayed correctly), make
          sure that your operating system has the appropriate language pack installed (for example
          the East-Asian language pack).</note>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Look and Feel</uicontrol> - This option lets you change the graphic style (look
        and feel) of the user interface. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> - This option sets the style of the interface. On Windows the
        following styles are available:<ul>
          <li>Office 2003</li>
          <li>Vsnet</li>
          <li>Eclipse</li>
          <li>Xerto</li>
          <li>Default</li>
        </ul><p>On Linux the following styles are available:</p><ul>
          <li>Eclipse</li>
          <li>Default</li>
        </ul>On Mac OS X this option is not available.<note>After changing the style, you must
          restart the application  for the modification to take effect.</note>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Themes</uicontrol> - This option sets the theme of the interface. This option is
        available only on Windows, and only if you have selected the<uicontrol>Office
          2003</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Default</uicontrol> styles. The following themes are available:<ul>
          <li>Normal Color</li>
          <li>Home Stead</li>
          <li>Metallic</li>
          <li>Default</li>
          <li>Gray</li>
        </ul><p>This option is not available on Linux and Mac OS X .</p>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Line separator</uicontrol> - This option sets the line separator used when saving
        files. Use <uicontrol>System Default</uicontrol> to select the normal line separator for
        your OS. If you want the existing file separator of a file to be maintained, regardless of
        your current OS, check <uicontrol>Detect the line separator on file open</uicontrol>. </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Detect the line separator on file open</uicontrol> - When this option is
        selected, the editor detects the line separator when a file is loaded and it uses it when
        the file is saved. New files are saved using the line separator defined by
          the<uicontrol>Line separator</uicontrol> option. </li>
      <li product="editor author developer" id="default_internet_browser">
        <uicontrol>Default Internet browser</uicontrol> - This option sets the Web browser that <ph
          keyref="product"/> will use to:<ul>
          <li>open (X)HTML or PDF transformation results</li>
          <li>open a web page (for example, pointing to specific paragraphs in the W3C
            recommendation of XML Schema in case of XML Schema validation errors)</li>
        </ul> If you leave this setting blank, the system default browser will be used. </li>
      <li product="editor author developer">
        <uicontrol>Open last edited files from project</uicontrol> - When this option is enabled,<ph
          keyref="product"/> opens the files you had open the last time you used a project whenever
        you open the application or switch to that project. </li>
      <li product="author developer editor">
        <uicontrol>Beep on operation finished</uicontrol> - When this option is selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> beeps when a validation or transform action ends. Different tones are
        used for success and failure. The tones used may depend on your operating system's sound
        settings. </li>
      <li product="author developer editor svnClient">
        <uicontrol>Show memory status</uicontrol> - When this option is selected, the memory<ph
          keyref="product"/> uses is displayed in the status bar. To free memory, click the
            <uicontrol><image id="image_hy1_j32_gg" href="../img/run_garbage_collector.png"
            placement="inline"/>Free unused memory</uicontrol> button located at the right side of
        the status bar. The memory status bar turns yellow or red when <ph keyref="product"/> uses
        too much memory. You can change the amount of memory available to Oxygen by <xref
          keyref="set-parameters-for-application-launchers">changing the parameters of the
          application launcher</xref>. </li>
      <li product="author developer editor">
        <uicontrol>Check opened files for file system changes</uicontrol> - When this option is
        selected, <ph keyref="product"/> checks the content of the all opened editors to see if they
        have been updated by another application. If the file has changed, <ph keyref="product"/>
        will ask you if you want to reload the file. <ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Auto update unmodified editors on file system changes</uicontrol> - If this
            option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> automatically updates unmodified editors if
            the edited file changes externally. </li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li product="editor author svnClient developer">
        <uicontrol>Show Java vendor warning at startup</uicontrol> - If this option is selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> displays a warning on startup if a non-recommended version of the Java
        virtual machine is being used. </li>
      <li product="editor author developer">
        <p><uicontrol>File Chooser Dialog</uicontrol> - This options sets the directory that will be
          shown when the <xref href="opening-existing-documents.dita">Open file dialog</xref> is
          displayed.</p><ul><li>
            <uicontrol>Last visited directory</uicontrol> - The last visited folder will be
            displayed. </li>
      <li>
            <uicontrol>Directory of the edited file</uicontrol> - The folder where the currently
            edited file is stored will be displayed. </li></ul></li>
      <li>
        <uicontrol>Show hidden files and directories</uicontrol> - If this option is selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> shows system hidden files and folders in the file browser dialog and
        the folder browser dialog. This setting is not available on OS X. </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
