<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-svn-working-copy">
    <title>Working Copy Preferences</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>working copy</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>To configure the <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> preferences, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to  <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>SVN</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol>
        </menucascade>. The option that you can configure in this preferences page are
      specific to SVN working copies:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <uicontrol>Working copies location</uicontrol> - Allows you to define a location where you keep your working copies. This location is
          automatically suggested when you checkout a new working copy.
      </li>
      <li>
        <uicontrol>Working copy administrative directory</uicontrol> - Allows you to customize the directory name where the svn entries are kept for each
          directory in the working copy.
      </li>
      <li id="svn-load-old-wc-format">
        <uicontrol>When loading an old format working copy</uicontrol> - You can instruct Syncro SVN
        Client to do one of the following:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol> - You are notified when such a working copy is used
            and you are allowed to choose what action to be taken - to upgrade or not the format of
            the current working copy.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Never upgrade</uicontrol> - Older format working copies are left untouched.
            No attempt to upgrade the format is made.<note>SVN 1.6 and older working copies still
              need to be upgraded before loading them.</note></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li>
        <uicontrol>Enable working copy caching</uicontrol> - If checked, the content of the working copies is cached for refresh operations.
      </li>
      <li>
        <uicontrol>Automatically refresh the working copy</uicontrol> - If checked, the working copy
        is refreshed from cache. Only the new changes (modifications with a date/time that follows
        the last refresh operation) are refreshed from disk. <ph product="editor author developer"
          >Disabled by default.</ph><ph product="svnClient">Enabled by default.</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Allow moving/renaming mixed revision directories</uicontrol> - If enabled, the
        Syncro SVN Client will allow you to move or rename a directory even if its child items have
        a different revision. Otherwise, an error message is displayed when there are multiple
        revisions to avoid unnecessary conflicts. It is recommended to leave this option disabled
        and to <uicontrol>Update</uicontrol> the subtree to a single revision before moving or
        renaming it.</li>
      <li>
        <uicontrol>When synchronizing with repository</uicontrol> - The action that will be executed automatically after the
            <uicontrol>Synchronize</uicontrol> action. The possible actions are:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Always switch to 'Modified' mode</uicontrol> - The
                <uicontrol>Synchronize</uicontrol> action is followed automatically by a switch to
                <uicontrol>Modified</uicontrol> mode of <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view, if
                <uicontrol>All Files</uicontrol> mode is currently selected.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Never switch to 'Modified' mode</uicontrol> - Keeps the currently
              selected view mode unchanged.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol> - The user is always asked if he wants to switch
              to <uicontrol>Modified</uicontrol> mode.</li>
          </ul>
      </li>
      <li id="svn-options-app-global-ignores">
        <uicontrol>Application global ignores</uicontrol> - Allows setting file patterns that may include the <codeph>*</codeph> and
            <codeph>?</codeph> wildcards for unversioned files and folders that must be ignored when
          displaying the working copy resources in <xref href="working-copy-view.dita">the
              <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref>. These patterns are case-sensitive.
          For example,<codeph>*.txt</codeph> matches <codeph>file.txt</codeph>, but does not match
            <codeph>file.TXT</codeph>.
      </li>
    </ul>
    </body>
</topic>
