<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-xsltproc">
  <title>XSLTProc Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>XSLTProc</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XSLTProc preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To configure <uicontrol>XSLTProc</uicontrol> options, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XSLT-XQuery</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XSLTProc</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in this preferences page:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Enable XInclude processing</uicontrol> - If selected, XInclude references will
        be resolved when XSLTProc is used as transformer in <xref
          href="transformation-scenario.dita">XSLT transformation scenarios</xref>.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Skip loading the document's DTD</uicontrol> - If selected, the DTD specified in
        the DOCTYPE declaration will not be loaded.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Do not apply default attributes from document's DTD</uicontrol> - If selected,
        the default attributes declared in the DTD and not specified in the document are not
        included in the transformed document.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Do not use Internet to fetch DTD's, entities or docs</uicontrol> - If selected,
        the remote references to DTD's and entities are not followed.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Maximum depth in templates stack</uicontrol> - If this limit of maximum
        templates depth is reached the transformation ends with an error.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Verbosity</uicontrol> - If selected, the transformation will output detailed
        status messages about the transformation process in the <uicontrol>Warnings</uicontrol>
        view.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show version of libxml and libxslt used</uicontrol> - If selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> will display in the <uicontrol>Warnings</uicontrol> view the version of
        the <b>libxml</b> and <b>libxslt</b> libraries invoked by XSLTProc.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show time information</uicontrol> - If selected, the
          <uicontrol>Warnings</uicontrol> view will display the time necessary for running the
        transformation.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show debug information</uicontrol> - If selected, the
          <uicontrol>Warnings</uicontrol> view will display debug information about what templates
        are matched, parameter values, and so on.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show all documents loaded during processing</uicontrol> - If selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> will display in the <uicontrol>Warnings</uicontrol> view the URL of all
        the files loaded during transformation.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show profile information</uicontrol> - If selected, <ph keyref="product"/> will
        display in the <uicontrol>Warnings</uicontrol> view a table with all the matched templates,
        and for each template will display: the match XPath expression, the template name, the
        number of template modes, the number of calls, the execution time.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show the list of registered extensions</uicontrol> - If selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> will display in the <uicontrol>Warnings</uicontrol> view a list with
        all the registered extension functions, extension elements and extension modules.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Refuses to write to any file or resource</uicontrol> - If selected, the
        XSLTProc processor will not write any part of the transformation result to an external file
        on disk. If such an operation is requested by the processed XSLT stylesheet the
        transformation ends with a runtime error.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Refuses to create directories</uicontrol> - If selected, the XSLTProc processor
        will not create any directory during the transformation process. If such an operation is
        requested by the processed XSLT stylesheet the transformation ends with a runtime
        error.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
