<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-dita-new-topics">
  <title>DITA New Topics Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>DITA New topics</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA new topics preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To access the DITA New Topics preferences page, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>New Topics</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. This preferences page includes the following options:</p>
    <section id="section_ud1_nwz_gmb">
      <title>New Topics section</title>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry id="file-name-rules">
            <dt>Use the title to generate the file name</dt>
            <dd>This option (and its sub-options) pertain to the rules that will be used to generate
              file names in the <xref href="create-topic-in-map.dita#create-topic-in-map"
                product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"><i>New DITA File dialog
                box</i></xref><xref href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa" product="developer"
                  ><i>New Document Wizard</i></xref>. Select this option to use the text entered in
              the <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> field to automatically generate a file name (the
              generated name can be seen in the <uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> field). By default,
              the generated name will replace spaces with underscores (<codeph>_</codeph>), all
              illegal characters will be removed, and all upper case characters changed to lower
              case, but you can use the sub-options to change this.</dd>
            <dd>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Replace non-alphanumeric characters with</dt>
                    <dd>
                      <p>If selected, the file name generation mechanism will replace all
                        non-alphanumeric characters in the title with the character entered in this
                        option.</p>
                      <p>
                        <dl>
                          <dlentry>
                            <dt>Lower case only</dt>
                            <dd>If selected, the file name generation mechanism will only use lower
                              case letters.</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                      </p>
                    </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt>Use camel case</dt>
                    <dd>
                      <p>If selected, the file name generation mechanism will convert the title to a
                        file name using the <term>camel case</term> convention where the first word
                        starts with a lower case letter and all subsequent words begin with upper
                        case (for example, <codeph>myFileName</codeph>).</p>
                      <p>
                        <dl>
                          <dlentry>
                            <dt>Upper case first letter</dt>
                            <dd>Select this option if you want the file name generation mechanism to
                              convert the title to a file name using the <term>camel case</term>
                              convention but with an upper case letter for the first word (for
                              example, <codeph>MyFileName</codeph>).</dd>
                          </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                      </p>
                    </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Use the file name as the value of the root ID attribute</dt>
            <dd>If selected, when creating a new topic, the file name (as seen in the
                <uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> field but without the file extension) will be used as
              the value of the root <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute for the new topic.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="insert-link-section">
      <title>Inserting Links section</title>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Always set values for the following attributes</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>Allows you to specify that when a link reference is inserted (using actions in the
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/LinkDrop.png" id="image_nbp_mkx_sr"
                  />Link</uicontrol> drop-down menu), the values for certain attributes will always
                be automatically populated with a detected value (based on the specifications), even
                if it is the same as the default value. You can choose to always populate the values
                for the following attributes:<ul id="ul_sqm_h2r_y3b">
                  <li><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> - If selected, the <xmlatt>format</xmlatt>
                    attribute will always be automatically populated with a detected value.</li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> - If selected, the <xmlatt>scope</xmlatt>
                    attribute will always be automatically populated with a detected value.</li>
                  <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - If selected, the <xmlatt>type</xmlatt> attribute
                    will always be automatically populated with a detected value.</li>
                </ul></p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Use '.' instead of the ID of the parent topic (DITA 1.3)</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>When addressing a non-topic element within the topic that contains the URI
                reference, the URI reference can use an abbreviated fragment-identifier syntax that
                replaces the topic ID with <codeph>"."</codeph> (<codeph>#./elementId</codeph>). For
                more information, see <xref
                  href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/dita/1.3/specs/index.html#archSpec/base/uri-based-addressing.html"
                  format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
