<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-svn">
  <title>SVN Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>SVN</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>SVN</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>SVN</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. In this preferences page the user preferences for the embedded SVN client tool
      are configured. Some other preferences for the embedded SVN client tool can be set in the
      global files called <filepath>config</filepath> and <filepath>servers</filepath>, that is the
      files with parameters that act as defaults applied to all the SVN client tools that are used
      by the same user on his login account on the computer. These files can be opened for editing
      with the two edit actions available in the SVN client tool on the <uicontrol>Global Runtime
        Configuration</uicontrol> submenu of the <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> menu.</p>
    <fig id="figure-svn-preferences">
      <title>The SVN Preferences Panel</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_svn_options.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The SVN preferences are the following:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Enable symbolic link support</uicontrol> (<i>available only on Mac OS X and
          Linux</i>) - <ph conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/apacheSubversion"/>
        has the ability to put a symbolic link under version control, via the usual SVN
          <cmdname>add</cmdname> command. The Subversion repository has no internal concept of a
        symbolic link, it stores a versioned symbolic link as an ordinary file with a
          <codeph>svn:special</codeph> property attached. The SVN client (on Unix) sees the property
        and translates the file into a symbolic link in the working copy.<note>Windows file systems
          have no symbolic links, so a Windows client won't do any such translation: the object
          appears as a normal file.</note><p> If the symbolic link support is disabled then the
          versioned symbolic links, on Linux and OS X, are supported in the same way as on Windows,
          that is a text file instead of symbolic link is created.</p><note type="important">It is
          recommended to disable symbolic links support if you do not have versioned symbolic links
          in your repository, because the SVN operations will work faster. However, you should not
          disable this option when you do have versioned symbolic links in repository. In that case
          a workaround would be to refer to working copy by its real path, not a path that includes
          a symbolic link.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Allow unversioned obstructions</uicontrol> - controls how should be handled
        working copy resources being ignored / unversioned when performing an update operation and
        from the repository are incoming files with the same name, in the same location, that
        intersect with those being ignored / unversioned. If the option is enabled, then the
        incoming items will become BASE revisions of the ones already present in the working copy,
        and those present will be made versioned resources and will be marked as modified. Exactly
        as if the user first made the update operation and after that he / she modified the files.
        If the option is disabled, the update operation will fail when encountering files in this
        situation, possibly leaving other files not updated. By default, this option is
        enabled.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Use unsafe copy operations</uicontrol> - sometimes when the working copy is
        accessed through Samba and SVN client cannot make a safe copy of the committed file due to a
        delay in getting write permission the result is that the committed file will be saved with
        zero length (the content is removed) and an error will be reported. In this case this option
        should be selected so that SVN client does not try to make the safe copy.</li>
      <li id="svn_https_encryption_protocol"><uicontrol>HTTPS encryption protocols</uicontrol> -
        sets a specific encryption protocol to be used when the <xref
          href="repository-access-https.dita#repository-access-https" format="dita">application
          accesses a repository through HTTPS protocol</xref>. You can choose one of the following
          values:<ul id="ul_4qd_ycm_lf">
          <li><uicontrol>SSLv3, TLSv1</uicontrol> (default value)</li>
          <li><uicontrol>SSLv3 only</uicontrol></li>
          <li><uicontrol>TLSv1 only</uicontrol></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>SSH</uicontrol> - specifies the command line for an external SSH client which
        will be used when connecting to a SVN+SSH repository. Absolute paths are recommended for the
        SSH client executable and the file paths given as arguments (if any). Depending on the SSH
        client used and your SSH server configuration you may need to specify in the command line
        the user name and / or private key / passphrase. Here you can also choose if the default
        user name (the same user name as the SSH client user) will be used for SVN repository
        operations or you should be prompted for a SVN user name whenever SVN authentication is
        required. For example on Windows the following command line uses the
          <filepath>plink.exe</filepath> tool as external SSH client for connecting to the SVN
        repository with
        SVN+SSH:<screen xml:space="preserve">C:\plink-install-folder\plink.exe -l username -pw password -ssh -batch host_name_or_IP_address_of_SVN_server</screen></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Results Console</uicontrol> - specifies the maximum number of lines displayed
        in the <uicontrol>Console</uicontrol> view. The default value is 1,000.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Annotations View</uicontrol> - sets the color used for highlighting in the
        editor panel all the changes contributed to a resource by the revision selected in <xref
          href="annotations-view.dita">the <uicontrol>Annotations</uicontrol> view</xref>.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Revision Graph</uicontrol> - enables caching for the action of computing a
        revision graph. When a new revision graph is requested one of the caches from the previous
        actions may be used which will avoid running the whole query again on the SVN server. If a
        cache is used it will finish the action much faster.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>