<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-file-types">
    <title>File Types Preferences</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>file
            types</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p><ph keyref="product"/>
            offers editing support for a wide variety of file types, but users are free to add new
            file extensions and associate them with the editor type which fits better. <ph
                product="editor author developer">The associations set here between a file extension and the
                type of editor which opens the file for editing have precedence over the default
                associations available in <xref href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita">the <menucascade>
                        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
                        <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
                    </menucascade> dialog</xref>.</ph></p>
        <p>To open the <uicontrol>File Types</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author diff developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>File Types</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
        <fig id="figure-file-types-options-oxygen">
      <title>The File Types Preferences Panel</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_dev_ed_file_types.png" product="developer editor"/>
      <image href="../img/sa_file_types.png" product="author"/>    
    </fig>
        <fig id="figure-file-types-options-diff" product="diff">
            <title>The File Types preferences panel</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_diff_file_types.png"/>
        </fig>
        <p>The table columns contain the following data:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Extension</uicontrol> - The extensions of the files that will be
                associated with an editor type.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol> - The type of editor which the extensions will be
                associated with. Some editors provide easy access to frequent operations via
                toolbars (e.g. XML editor, XSL editor, DTD editor) while others provide just a
                syntax highlight scheme (e.g. Java editor, SQL editor, Shell editor, etc.).<p>If the
                    editor set here is not one of the XML editors (XML editor, XSL editor, XSD
                    editor, RNG editor, WSDL editor) then the encoding set in <xref
                        href="preferences-encoding.dita">the preference <uicontrol>Encoding for non
                            XML files</uicontrol>
                    </xref> is used for opening and saving a file of this type. This is necessary
                    because in case of XML files the encoding is usually declared at the beginning
                    of the XML file in a special declaration or it assumes the default value UTF-8
                    but in case of non XML files there is no standard mechanism for declaring the
                    encoding of the file.</p></li>
        </ul>
        <p product="editor author">You can also decide the files which will be handled as DITA maps
            when opened in <ph keyref="product"/>. If
            the files match the pattern that is specified in <uicontrol>DITA Maps file
                patterns</uicontrol> you will be prompted to open them in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                Manager</uicontrol> view.</p>
    <p product="developer editor">The files that match the <uicontrol>Ant build patterns</uicontrol>
      will be associated with the Ant editor.</p>
        <p product="editor author developer">The files that match the <uicontrol>Binary file
                patterns</uicontrol> patterns are handled as binary and opened in the associated
            system application. Also, they are excluded from the following actions available in the
                <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
                    ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref>: <uicontrol>File/Replace in
                Files</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Check Spelling in Files</uicontrol>,
                <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol>.</p>
    </body>
</topic>