<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-open-find-resources">
  <title>Open/Find Resource Preferences Page</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>Open/Find Resource</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Open/Find resource preferences</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Search preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can configure various options that pertain to the <xref
        href="open-find-resource-dialog.dita#open-find-resource-dialog"><uicontrol>Open/Find
          Resource</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> and <xref
        href="open-find-resource-view.dita#open-find-resource-view"><uicontrol>Open/Find
          Resource</uicontrol> view</xref>. To access these options, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to
        <uicontrol>Open/Find Resource</uicontrol>. </p>
    <p>The following options are available in this <uicontrol>Open/Find Resource</uicontrol>
      preferences page:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Limit search results to</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Specifies the maximum number of results that are displayed in the <xref
              href="open-find-resource-dialog.dita#open-find-resource-dialog"><uicontrol>Open/Find
                Resource</uicontrol> dialog box/view</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Enable searching in content</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This option is selected by default and it allows you to use the <xref
              href="open-find-resource-dialog.dita#open-find-resource-dialog"><uicontrol>Open/Find
                Resource</uicontrol> dialog box/view</xref> to search in content or reviews, as well
            as in file paths. If this option is not selected, you can only use the
              <uicontrol>Open/Find Resource</uicontrol> feature to search in file paths.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Content search scope</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Ignore content of these files</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Allows you to select specific directories, files, or file types that are
                    ignored when you perform a search. For example, <filepath>*.txt</filepath>
                    ignores all the <filepath>.txt</filepath> files, <filepath>*/topics/*</filepath>
                    ignores all the files from the <filepath>topics</filepath> directory, regardless
                    of their depth, and <filepath>file:/C:/tmp/*</filepath> ignores everything from
                    the <filepath>tmp</filepath> directory.<note>The specified pattern must begin
                      with the desired protocol (in our case <i>file</i>) and also contain
                      forward slash (<filepath>/</filepath>).</note></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Index the content of remote resources</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Controls the indexing of resources that are not local. For example, the
                    resources referenced in a <xref keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA
                        map</term></xref> opened from a remote server (from a CMS or from a WebDAV
                    location) are not indexed by default. To index the content of these resources,
                    select this option.<note>Selecting this option may lead to delays when the
                      indexing is computed.</note></dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Content search options</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Content language</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Use this option to specify a language for the search engine to use for the
                    current document. This is helpful if you have multiple languages within the
                    content of a document. The search engine will use a set of <term>stop
                      words</term> and analyzers tuned specifically for that specific language. By
                    default, it is mapped to the <xref
                      href="preferences-global.dita#preferences-global/language">UI language
                      specified in the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>.
                    Therefore, you need to change this option only if the language of the text you
                    want to perform the search in differs from the UI language.<note type="tip">If
                      you select <uicontrol>&lt;Generic language (no stemming)></uicontrol> from the
                      drop-down list, no word stemming is performed when creating the index. This
                      might be useful if your content has many technical terms that should be
                      indexed as they are.</note></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Stop words</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>A list of <term>stop words</term> that will be filtered out of the search
                    processing. The list is automatically populated based upon the specified
                      <uicontrol>Content language</uicontrol>, but you can add or remove words from
                    the list. </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>When searching in content, return</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>This option specifies how matches are returned when doing searches in content.
                    You can choose between two options:<ul>
                      <li><uicontrol>Exact matches</uicontrol> - The search results match the exact
                        whole words that you enter in the search field of the <uicontrol>Open/Find
                          Resource</uicontrol> dialog box/view.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>Prefix matches</uicontrol> (default) - The search results match
                        documents that contain words starting with the search terms. For instance,
                        searching for "pref page" will also find documents containing "preference
                        page".</li>
                    </ul></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Automatically join search terms using:</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Allows you to select the default boolean operator that <ph keyref="product"/>
                    applies when you perform a search. For example, if the AND operator is selected
                    and you search for "car assembly", the matches must contain both of the words.
                    If you choose OR, the matches must contain one of the selected search terms and
                    results that contain both words are promoted to the top of the list.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt id="enable-xml-aware"><uicontrol>Enable XML-aware searching</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>When selected, you can perform <xref href="using-open-find-resources.dita"
                      >XML-specific searches</xref> for XML elements and attributes.<note>Selecting
                      this option may slow down the indexing of your documents and increase the
                      index size on the disk.</note><p>
                      <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                          <dt><uicontrol>Index files with size less than (KB)</uicontrol></dt>
                          <dd>Since indexing can be slowed down when the <xref
                              href="#preferences-open-find-resources/enable-xml-aware" format="dita"
                                ><uicontrol>Enable XML-aware searching</uicontrol> option</xref> is
                            active, you can use this option to set a maximum file size to be
                            indexed.</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                      </dl>
                    </p></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Stop Words</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>A list of comma separated <term>stop words</term>, meaning that the words
                    added in this list are filtered out prior to processing a search query.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="open-find-resource-view.dita#open-find-resource-view"/>
      <link href="open-find-resource-dialog.dita#open-find-resource-dialog"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
