<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/reference.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-dita">
  <title>DITA Preferences</title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <body>
    <p>To access the DITA Preferences page, <ph conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"
      /> and click on <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>DITA-OT directory</uicontrol> option specifies the directory of the DITA Open
      Toolkit distribution to be used, by default, for validating and publishing DITA content. You
      can either provide a new file path for the specific DITA OT that you want to use or you can
      select a previously used one from the drop-down menu.<note>The DITA Open Toolkit is bundled
        with the <ph keyref="product"/> installation.</note><ph product="author editor"> The
          <uicontrol>DITA Maps file patterns</uicontrol> option allows you to set the extension of
        the files that will be handled as DITA maps when opened in <ph keyref="product"/>. <ph
          keyref="product"/> can open a DITA map in the regular editor view or in the <xref
          keyref="dita.edit-maps">DITA Maps Manager</xref>.</ph></p>
    <p product="author editor"> The following options are available <uicontrol>When opening a
        map</uicontrol>:<ul id="ul_g5k_kdq_jq">
        <li><uicontrol>Always open in the DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> - A DITA Map file is always
          opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Always open as XML</uicontrol> - A DITA Map file is always opened in the XML
          editor.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol> - When opening a DITA Map, you are prompted to choose
          between opening it in the XML editor panel or in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
            Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p id="p-show-console-output"><ph id="show_console_output">The <uicontrol>Show console
          output</uicontrol> option allows you to specify when to display the console output log.
        The following options are available:</ph><ul id="ul_ccp_yyv_sq">
        <li><uicontrol>When build fails</uicontrol> - displays the console output log if the build
          fails.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Always</uicontrol> - displays the console output log, regardless of whether
          or not the build fails.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>
      <ph product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">At the bottom of the page there is a
        link to the <xref href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#profiling.conditions"
          >Profiling Attributes preferences</xref>, where you can configure how profiling and
        conditional text is displayed in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></p>
  </body>
</topic>
