<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-archive">
  <title>Archive Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>archive</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Archive</uicontrol> preferences panel is opened from menu <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author diff developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Archive</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in the <uicontrol>Archive</uicontrol> preferences
      panel:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Archive backup options</uicontrol> - Controls if the application makes backup
        copies of the modified archives. The following options are available:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Always create backup copies of modified archives</uicontrol> - When you
            modify an archive, its content is backed up.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Never create backup copies of modified archives</uicontrol> - No backup
            copy is created.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Ask for each archive once per session</uicontrol> - Once per application
            session for each modified archive, user confirmation is required to create the backup.
            This is the default setting.<note>Backup files have the name
                <filepath>originalArchiveFileName.bak</filepath> and are located in the same folder
              as the original archive.</note></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse"><uicontrol>Show archive backup
          dialog</uicontrol> - Select this option if you want to be notified for backup when
        modifying in archives. The last backup option you chose will always be used as the default
        one.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Archive types</uicontrol> - This table contains all known archive extensions
        mapped to known archive formats. Each row maps a list of extensions to an archive type
        supported in <ph keyref="product"/>. You can
        edit an existing mapping or create a new one by associating your own list of extensions to
        an archive format.<fig id="edit-archive-extension-dlg-oxygen" product="editor author diff">
          <title>Edit Archive Extension Mappings</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_archive_extensions.png"/>
        </fig><fig id="edit-archive-extension-dlg-oxygenEclipse"
          product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
          <title>Edit Archive Extension Mappings</title>
          <image href="../img/ec_archive_extensions.png"/>
        </fig><note type="important">You have to restart <ph
            keyref="product"/> after removing an
          extension from the table in order for that extension to not be recognised anymore as an
          archive extension.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Store Unicode file names in Zip archives</uicontrol> - Use this option when you
        archive files that contain international (that is, non-English) characters in file names or
        file comments. If an archive is modified in any way with this option turned on, UTF-8
        characters are used in the names of all files in the archive. </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
