<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-colors-sh">
  <title> Syntax Highlight Preferences</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm><indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>Editor<indexterm>Syntax
              Highlight</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Syntax highlight preferences</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> supports syntax highlighting of XML in the <xref
        href="text-mode-editor.dita#text-mode-editor"><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode
      editor</xref>, <ph product="editor editorEclipse developer developerEclipse">DTD, Relax NG
        (XML and Compact Syntax), Java, </ph>JavaScript / JSON<ph product="developer editor">,
        Ant</ph>, PHP, CSS<ph product="editor editorEclipse developer developerEclipse">, XQuery,
        C++, C, Perl, Properties, SQL, Shell and Batch</ph> documents. </p>
    <p>To configure syntax highlighting, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Syntax Highlight</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>To set syntax colors for a language, expand the listing for that language in the top panel to
      show the list of syntax items for that language. Use the color and style selectors to change
      how each syntax item is displayed. The results of your changes are displayed in the preview
      panel. If you do not know the name of the syntax token that you want to configure, click that
      token in the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> area to select it.<note>All default color sets
        come with a high-contrast variant that is automatically used when you switch to a
        black-background or white-background high-contrast theme in your Windows operating system
        settings. The high-contrast theme will not overwrite any default color you set in <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Syntax Highlight</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> preferences page.</note></p>

    <p>The settings for XML documents are used also in XSD, XSL, RNG documents. The
				<uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> area has separate tabs for XML, XSD, XSL, RNG.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Enable nested syntax highlight</uicontrol> option controls whether or not
      content types that are nested in the same file (such as PHP, JS, or CSS scripts inside an HTML
      file) are highlighted according to the color schemes defined for each content type.</p>
  </body>
</topic>