<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-editor-format">
  <title>Format Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Editor
              preferences<indexterm>format</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">This preferences page contains various
      formatting options which influence editing and formatting both in the
        <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> modes. To control additional
      options specifically for the <xref keyref="mode_author">Author mode</xref> editor, see <xref
        keyref="author_whitespace-handling"/>.</p>
    <p product="developer developerEclipse">This preferences page contains various formatting
      options which influence editing and formatting in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode.</p>
    <p>
      <note>These settings apply to the formatting of source documents. The formatting of output
        documents is determined by the <xref keyref="transform_documents">transformation scenarios
          that create them</xref>. </note>
    </p>
    <p>The following options are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Detect indent on open</uicontrol> - <ph keyref="product"/> detects how a
        document is indented when it is opened. <ph keyref="product"/> uses a heuristic method of
        detection by computing a weighted average indent value from the initial document content.
        You can disable this setting if the detected value does not work for your particular case
        and you want to use a fixed-size indent for all the edited documents.<note type="tip">If you
          want to minimize the formatting differences created by the <uicontrol>Format and
            Indent</uicontrol> operation in a document edited in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
          edited mode, make sure that both the <uicontrol>Detect indent on open</uicontrol> and
            <uicontrol>Detect line width on open</uicontrol> options are enabled.</note><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Use zero-indent, if detected</uicontrol> - By default, if no indent was
            detected in the document, the fixed-size indent is used. Enable this option if all your
            document have no indentation and you want to keep them that way.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><ph id="indent-with-tabs"><uicontrol>Indent with tabs</uicontrol> - If selected, indents
          are created using tab characters. If unchecked, lines are indented using space
          characters.</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Indent size</uicontrol> - A fixed number of spaces used for indenting a
        line.</li>
      <li id="hard-line-wrap-li"><uicontrol>Hard line wrap (Limit to "Line width - Format and
          Indent")</uicontrol> - If selected, when typing content in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
        editing mode when the maximum line width is reached, a line break is automatically inserted. </li>

      <li id="indent-on-enter-li"><uicontrol>Indent on enter</uicontrol> - If disabled, when you
        press the <userinput>Enter</userinput> key to insert a line break in the
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>editing mode, no indentation will be added to the new line. </li>
      <li id="smart-enter-li"><uicontrol>Enable smart enter</uicontrol> - If selected, when you
        press the <userinput>Enter</userinput> key between a start and an end XML tag in the
          <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editing mode, the cursor is placed in an indented position on
        the empty line formed between the start and end tag.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Detect line width on open</uicontrol> - When selected, <ph keyref="product"/>
        detects the line width automatically when the document is opened.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Format and indent the document on open</uicontrol> - When selected, an XML
        document is formatted and indented before opening it in <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
      <li><ph id="line-width-ph"><uicontrol>Line width - Format and Indent</uicontrol> - Defines the
          number of characters after which the <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol>
          (pretty-print) action performs hard line wrapping. For example, if set to 100, after a
            <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> action, the longest line will have at most 100
          characters.</ph>
        <ph product="author editor authorEclipse developerEclipse">This setting is also used when
          saving the XML content edited in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing
          mode.</ph><note>To avoid having an indent that is longer than the line width setting and
          without having sufficient space available for the text content, the indent limit is
          actually set at half the value of the <uicontrol>Line width - Format and
            Indent</uicontrol> setting. The remaining space is reserved for text.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Clear undo buffer before Format and Indent</uicontrol> - The <uicontrol>Format
          and Indent</uicontrol> operation can be undone, but if used intensively, a considerable
        amount of the memory allocated for <ph keyref="product"/> will be used for storing the undo
        states. If this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> empties the undo buffer before
        doing a <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> operation. This means you will not be able
        to undo any changes you made before the format and indent operation. Select this option if
        you encounter out of memory problems (<uicontrol>OutOfMemoryError</uicontrol>) when
        performing the <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> operation.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The indent size and line width limit settings are used in various places in the
        application:<ul id="ul_sz1_ttz_mr">
        <li>When the <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> action is used in the
            <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editing mode.</li>
        <li>When you press <userinput>ENTER</userinput> in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> editing
          mode to break a line.</li>
        <li>When editing in the <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode with <uicontrol>Hard line
            wrap</uicontrol> enabled.</li>
        <li product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">When the XML is serialized by saving
          content in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing mode.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the formatting options offered by <ph keyref="product"
      />, go to <xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Autodetect_Formating.html" format="html"
        scope="external"/>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
