<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-editor-format">
  <title>Format Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Configure the Application<indexterm>Editor
              preferences<indexterm>format</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>OutOfMemory</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Out Of Memory</indexterm>
        <indexterm>OutOfMemoryError</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> lets you control how the text of an XML document is formatted when you
      use the Format and Indent
      <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140904T154115-0400" comment="I&apos;m pretty sure everything here applies to the format and indent option in the text mode editor. Controlling how the Author mode editor formats the underlying XML is elsewhere."?>option<?oxy_comment_end?>
      in the <xref keyref="mode.text">Text mode</xref> editor. To configure the
        <uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> options, <ph
        conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Format</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p><note>These settings apply to the Text mode editor. To control how the <xref
          keyref="mode.author">Author mode</xref> editor formats the underlying XML document, see
          <xref keyref="author.whitespace-handling"/>.</note><note>These settings apply to the
        formatting of XML source documents, not the formatting of output documents. The formatting
        of output documents is determined by the <xref keyref="transform.documents">transformations
          that create them</xref>. </note>The following options are available:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Detect indent on open</uicontrol> -
        <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140904T164234-0400" comment="Why is Indent with Tabs the only setting that is greyed out when this option is selected. Do all the other setting override the indenting found in the source file even if this is checked? (Actually, Indent Size is disabled too, but its label is not, so it is not really apparent that it is disabled.)"?>The
        editor detects how a document is indented when it is opened<?oxy_comment_end?>. Choose this
        setting if you edit XML documents that are indented in different ways and want the
        formatting of each to be preserved as closely as
        possible.<?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140904T163504-0400" comment="Which setting is this? I can&apos;t tell what this refers to."?>
        Additionally, you can activate the option for detecting the maximum line width used by the
        formatting and hard wrap mechanism.<?oxy_comment_end?> These features were designed to
        minimize the differences created by the <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> operation
        when your files are stored in a version control system.<note>If the document contains
          different-size indents, the application computes a weighted average value to used for new
          indents.</note><ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Use
              <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140904T163713-0400" comment="What does zero-indent mean? None of the lines are indented?"?>zero-indent<?oxy_comment_end?>,
              if detected</uicontrol> - the formatting operation
            <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140904T163803-0400" comment="What does &quot;takes into account&quot; mean? What, specifically, does it do if the file has zero indent?"?>takes
            into account<?oxy_comment_end?> an indent level of zero in case this is detected.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><ph id="indent-with-tabs"><uicontrol>Indent with tabs</uicontrol> - If selected, indents
          are created using tab characters. If unchecked, indents are formed with spaces. The number
          of space used is set by the <uicontrol>Indent size</uicontrol> option.</ph></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Indent size</uicontrol> - The number of spaces used to create an indent.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Hard line wrap</uicontrol> - When selected, <ph keyref="product"/> breaks the
        edited line automatically when its length exceeds the limit specified by the <uicontrol>Line
          width - Format and Indent</uicontrol>, or the length that was detected on open (if
          <uicontrol>Detect line width on open</uicontrol> is selected).</li>

      <li><uicontrol>Indent on Enter</uicontrol> - When selected, <ph keyref="product"/> indents the
        new line when you press the Enter key.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Enable Smart Enter</uicontrol> - When selected, if you press the Enter key
        between a start and an end tag, <ph keyref="product"/> places the cursor in an indented
        position on the empty line formed between the start and end tag.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Detect line width on open</uicontrol> - When selected, detects the line width
        automatically when the document is opened.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Format and indent the document on open</uicontrol> - When selected, an XML
        document is formatted and indented before opening it in the editor panel.
        <?oxy_comment_start author="Mark" timestamp="20140904T165404-0400" comment="I&apos;m not sure what this means. Does it mean it only applies to XML documents (and not, for instance, CSS documents? If so, isn&apos;t that also true of Enable Smart Enter, for instance? Or is the word &quot;tag&quot; to specific in the description of that setting. (That is, Smart enter would work between braces in CSS)?"?>This
        option applies only to documents associated with the XML editor.<?oxy_comment_end?>
        <ph product="editor author developer">This option does not apply to <term>read-only</term>
          documents when the <xref
            href="preferences-editor.dita#preferences-editor/preferences_can_edit_read_only">Can
            edit read only files</xref> option is disabled.</ph>
      </li>
      <li><uicontrol>Line width - Format and Indent</uicontrol> - Defines the point at which the
          <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol> (pretty-print) function performs hard line
        wrapping. For example, if set to 100, after a <uicontrol>Format and Indent</uicontrol>
        action, the longest line will have at most 100 characters.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Clear undo buffer before Format and Indent</uicontrol> - If selected, <ph
          keyref="product"/> empties the undo buffer before doing a  <uicontrol>Format and
          Indent</uicontrol> operation. This means you will not be able to undo any changes you made
        before the format and indent operation. Select this option if you encounter out of memory
        problems (<uicontrol>OutOfMemoryError</uicontrol>) when performing the <uicontrol>Format and
          Indent</uicontrol> operation.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the formatting options offered by <ph keyref="product"
      />, go to <xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Autodetect_Formating.html" format="html"
        scope="external">http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Autodetect_Formating.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
