<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-dita-maps">
  <title>DITA Maps Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>DITA Maps</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA maps preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To access the <i>DITA Maps</i> preferences page, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Maps</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. This preferences page includes the following options:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry product="author editor">
          <dt>DITA Maps file patterns</dt>
          <dd><ph>Allows you to specify the extension types that will be handled as <term>DITA
                maps</term> when opened in <ph keyref="product"/>.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="when-opening-dlentry" product="author editor">
          <dt>When opening a map</dt>
          <dd><ph keyref="product"/> can open a <term>DITA map</term> in the regular editor view or
            in the <xref keyref="dita_edit-maps"><uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol></xref>.
            This option allows you to specify how a map will be opened. You can choose one of the
            following options:<ul id="ul_mkd_yzz_gmb">
              <li><uicontrol>Always open in the DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> - A <term>DITA
                  map</term> file is always opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>
                view.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Always open as XML</uicontrol> - A <term>DITA map</term> file is always
                opened in the XML editor.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol> - When opening a <term>DITA map</term>, you are
                prompted to choose between opening it in the XML editor panel or in the
                  <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Expand references to other maps when opening a map in Author mode</dt>
          <dd>Enabling this option will improve performance (decrease the loading time) when opening
            maps in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode (particularly maps that contain a large
            amount of submaps). This option is disabled by default.<note>You must close and reopen
              the map to see the effects of enabling/disabling this option.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <section id="section_xk5_lyz_gmb">
      <title>DITA Maps Manager section</title>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry id="prefer-navtitle-dlentry">
            <dt>Prefer using the navigation title for rendering topic references</dt>
            <dd>If selected and there is a <xmlatt>navtitle</xmlatt> attribute set on a
                <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement>, then the <xmlatt>navtitle</xmlatt> is used to
              render the title of the topic in the <xref
                href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
                  Manager</uicontrol></xref>.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="allow-submaps-editing">
            <dt>Allow referenced submaps to be edited</dt>
            <dd>If selected, all DITA maps referenced directly or indirectly in a DITA map that is
              open in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view will be fully editable. You
              will be able to add new topic references, modify properties, and move topic references
              from one submap to another. Saving the main DITA map will also save the contents of
              the modified submaps.<note type="attention">The documents must be reopened to apply a
                change to this option.</note></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Local files only</dt>
            <dd>If selected, only submaps that are located on local disk drives will be editable. As for maps located in remote locations (e.g. content management systems), the save operation might not work on all submaps. This checkbox is selected by default.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_wrf_lyz_gmb">
      <title>Inserting Topic References section</title>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry id="always-fill-values-dlentry">
            <dt>Always set values for the following attributes</dt>
            <dd>Allows you to specify that when inserting a topic reference <ph>(using the <xref
                  href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref"><uicontrol>Insert
                    Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> and <xref
                  href="dita-edit-properties.dita#dita-edit-properties"><uicontrol>Edit
                    Properties</uicontrol> dialog box</xref>)</ph>, the values for certain
              attributes will always be automatically populated with a detected value (based on the
              specifications), even if it is the same as the default value. You can choose to always
              populate the values for the following attributes:<ul id="ul_otf_2zz_gmb">
                <li><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> - If selected, the <xmlatt>format</xmlatt>
                  attribute will always be automatically populated with a detected value.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> - If selected, the <xmlatt>scope</xmlatt> attribute
                  will always be automatically populated with a detected value.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - If selected, the <xmlatt>type</xmlatt> attribute
                  will always be automatically populated with a detected value.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Navigation title</uicontrol> - If selected, the
                    <xmlatt>navtitle</xmlatt> attribute will always be automatically populated with
                  a detected value.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Use the file name as the value of the "keys" attribute</dt>
            <dd>If selected, when inserting a topic reference into a map, the file name will be used
              as the value of the <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt> attribute for the new
                <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement>. This option has a slightly different effect
              depending on the method used for inserting the topic reference:<ul id="ul_w4f_qcq_klb">
                <li><b>Drag/Drop or Copy/Paste in the DITA Maps Manager</b> - If you drag or copy a
                  resource from another view (or outside <ph keyref="product"/>) and drop or paste
                  it into the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> and a key is already defined
                  for that resource, a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute will be inserted instead.
                  This even works for two consecutive drag/drop or copy/paste operations without
                  saving the file and it works for multiple selections of topic references.</li>
                <li><b>Drag/Drop or Copy/Paste in a Map opened in Author Mode</b> - If you drag or
                  copy a resource from another view (or outside <ph keyref="product"/>) and drop or
                  paste it into a map that is open in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, and a key
                  is already defined for that resource, a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute will be
                  inserted instead.<note type="restriction">In this particular scenario, if you
                    perform two identical, consecutive drag/drop or copy/paste operations without
                    saving the file between operations, the value of the <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt>
                    attribute will be the same for both inserted topic references. The workaround
                    for this limitation is to simply save the map after each drag/drop or copy/paste
                    operation.</note></li>
                <li><b>Using the Fast Create Topics or Duplicate Actions</b> - If you use the <xref
                    href="fast-create-topics.dita"><uicontrol>Fast Create Topics</uicontrol>
                    feature</xref> or <xref href="create-topic-in-map.dita"
                      ><uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> action</xref> to insert topic references,
                  the newly created <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement> elements will contain the
                    <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt> attribute with its value set depending on the file
                  name.</li>
                <li><b>Using the <uicontrol>Insert Topic Reference</uicontrol> Dialog Box from the
                    DITA Maps Manager</b> - If you use an action in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                    Manager</uicontrol> to insert topic references (e.g. <menucascade>
                    <uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/Topicref16.png" id="image_zcs_fgv_4lb"
                      />Reference</uicontrol>
                  </menucascade>), a <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt> attribute will be set for each inserted
                  topic reference and the value depends on the file name. <ph
                    product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">You can see the value in the
                      <uicontrol>Define keys</uicontrol> field from the <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol>
                    tab of <xref href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref">the
                        <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> and you can change
                    it</ph><ph product="author editor"> If a single target was selected, you can see
                    the value in the <uicontrol>Define keys</uicontrol> field from the
                      <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> tab of <xref
                      href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref">the <uicontrol>Insert
                        Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> and you can change it, while if
                    multiple targets were selected, the values are automatically generated based on
                    each file name when the insertion is performed, and you cannot see or change the
                    values in that dialog box</ph>.</li>
              </ul><note>This option also has an effect on image references. When inserting a
                reference to an image in a DITA map and this option is selected, a
                  <xmlelement>keydef</xmlelement> element is created if it is allowed by the schema.
                If it is not allowed (or this option is deselected), a specific topic reference
                element is created with the value of the <xmlatt>processing-role</xmlatt> attribute
                set to <b>resource-only</b>.</note></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_aln_kyz_gmb" product="author editor">
      <title>Review section</title>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry id="navigating-review-items">
            <dt>When the last/first item is reached while navigating review items</dt>
            <dd>This option allows you to specify what should happen when you are navigating review
              items in the <xref href="review-view.dita"><uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view</xref>
              and you reach the last or first review item. You can choose one of the following
                options:<ul id="ul_emz_r11_hmb">
                <li><uicontrol>Open the next/previous document (in the current DITA map hierarchy)
                    that contains review items</uicontrol> - If you reach the last/first review item
                  in the document, clicking the <uicontrol><image href="../img/NextReference16.png"
                      id="image_fmz_r11_hmb"/>Next</uicontrol> or <uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/PreviousReference16.png" id="image_gmz_r11_hmb"
                    />Previous</uicontrol> navigation buttons will open the next/previous document
                  (from the current DITA map hierarchy) that contains review items.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Do nothing</uicontrol> - If you reach the last/first review item in
                  the document, clicking the <uicontrol><image href="../img/NextReference16.png"
                      id="image_hmz_r11_hmb"/>Next</uicontrol> or <uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/PreviousReference16.png" id="image_imz_r11_hmb"
                    />Previous</uicontrol> navigation buttons will do nothing.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol> - If you reach the last/first review item in
                  the document, clicking the <uicontrol><image href="../img/NextReference16.png"
                      id="image_jmz_r11_hmb"/>Next</uicontrol> or <uicontrol><image
                      href="../img/PreviousReference16.png" id="image_kmz_r11_hmb"
                    />Previous</uicontrol> navigation buttons will open a dialog box asking if you
                  want to open the next/previous document (from the current DITA map hierarchy) that
                  contains review items.</li>
              </ul></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
