<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-editor-open-save">
  <title>Open/Save Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>Editor<indexterm>Open/Save</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Open preferences</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Save preferences</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Performance preferences</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Special character preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> lets you control how files are opened and saved. To configure the
      options for opening and saving documents, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Open/Save</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available:<dl>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">
          <dt><uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Lock local resources</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>When this option is selected and you open a file from the local file system or
                    a shared network drive, <ph keyref="product"/> locks the file for the current
                    user and the file becomes read-only for other users while the lock exists.
                    Locked and read-only files have a lock icon (<image
                      href="../img/SVNLockInternal10.png"/>) displayed on their editor tabs. Newly
                    created files are <i>locked</i> when you first save them. If you select
                    this option with files already opened in <ph keyref="product"/>, it will
                      <i>lock</i> all the currently opened files. If you deselect this option
                    with files already opened, it will unlock them by deleting the corresponding
                      <filepath>.lock</filepath> files. When you try to save locked (read-only)
                    files, a <uicontrol>Save As</uicontrol> dialog box will be displayed to avoid
                    overwriting the initial resource.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Restore cursor position</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Selected by default, it ensures that the last position of the cursor will be
                    remembered when a document is re-opened. If this option is not selected, the
                    cursor will always be positioned at the beginning of the document.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Open each document in a tab next to the current
                    one</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>When selected (default), each new document is opened in a tab next to the
                    currently opened tab. If not selected, each new document is opened in a tab at
                    the end of the current tab stack.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Format document when longest line exceeds</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd><ph keyref="product"/> will create line breaks if the characters in a line
                    exceed the specified value. You can choose one of the following:<ul
                      id="ul_fdg_hj4_sq">
                      <li><uicontrol>Always format</uicontrol></li>
                      <li><uicontrol>Never format</uicontrol></li>
                      <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol></li>
                    </ul></dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="support-for-special-characters" product="author developer editor svnClient">
          <dt product="author developer editor"><uicontrol>Support for Special
              Characters</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>When bidirectional text, Asian languages, or other special
                      characters are detected</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>You can choose how you want <ph keyref="product"/> to handle bidirectional
                    text, Asian languages, or other special characters when they are detected. You
                    can choose one of the following:<ul id="ul_fgm_2w4_sq">
                      <li id="enable-support-special-chars"><uicontrol>Enable support for special
                          characters</uicontrol> - The support for special characters will always be
                        enabled.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>Disable support for special characters</uicontrol> - The
                        support for special characters will always be disabled.</li>
                      <li><uicontrol>Prompt for each document</uicontrol> - You will be prompted to
                        choose whether or not to enable the support for special characters whenever
                        they are detected in a newly opened document.</li>
                    </ul></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Disable special characters support for documents larger than
                      (characters)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Enabling bidirectional text editing support can affect performance on large
                    files. When this option is selected, bidirectional editing is disabled for files
                    exceeding the specified size, even if the <xref
                      href="#preferences-editor-open-save/enable-support-special-chars"
                      format="dita"><uicontrol>Enable support for special characters</uicontrol>
                      option</xref> is selected.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="svnClient">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Show BIDI limit warning</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>It this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> will warn you if
                    bidirectional editing support is disabled and a file exceeds the specified
                    limit.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">
          <dt><uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor" id="show-save-as-option">
                  <dt>Show "Save as" option to save newly created documents in the "New" document
                    wizard</dt>
                  <dd>It is selected by default, but if you deselect this option, the <xref
                      href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa/save-as-step"><uicontrol>Save
                        as</uicontrol> option</xref> will not be available in the <xref
                      href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa"><uicontrol>New Document</uicontrol>
                      wizard</xref>, so you will not have the ability to change the default name and
                    path of the new file.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Safe save (only for local files)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>In the unlikely event of a failure when attempting a
                      <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> action, this option provides increased protection
                    from corruption of the original file. When this option is selected, it saves the
                    content to a temporary file and if the save is unsuccessful, the editor
                    preserves its unsaved state status.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor">
                  <dt><uicontrol>On Save, make backup copy with extension (only for local
                      files)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>If selected, a backup copy is made when saving the edited document. This
                    option is available only for local files (files that are stored on the local
                    file system). The default backup file extension is <filepath>.bak</filepath>,
                    but that can be changed in the text field.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor" id="enable-automatic-save">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Automatically save the document every</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>If selected, your documents are automatically saved after a preset time
                    interval that is specified in the drop-down list.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Save all files before transformation or validation</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Saves all opened files before validating or transforming an XML document. This
                    ensures that any dependencies are resolved when modifying the XML document and
                    its XML Schema.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Check errors on save</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>If selected, <ph keyref="product"/> runs a validation that checks your
                    document for errors before saving it.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor" id="save-all-files-before-tool">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Save all files before calling external tools</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>If selected, all files are saved before executing an <xref
                      href="integrating-external-tools.dita#integrating-external-tools"
                      format="dita">external tool</xref>.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">
          <dt><uicontrol>Performance</uicontrol> section</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor" id="optimize-loading-text-mode">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Optimize loading in the Text edit mode for files over
                      (MB)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>File loading is optimized for reduced memory usage for any file whose size is
                    larger than the value specified in this drop-down list. This is useful for
                    editing large files, but there are <xref
                      href="editing-large-documents.dita#editing-large-documents">several
                      restrictions</xref> for memory-intensive operations.<p>
                      <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                          <dt><uicontrol>Show warning when loading large documents</uicontrol></dt>
                          <dd><ph keyref="product"/> will warn you if you open a file that is bigger
                            than the specified size.</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                      </dl>
                    </p></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor" id="optimize-loading-long-lines">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Optimize loading for documents with lines longer than
                      (Characters)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd><i>Line wrap</i> is automatically performed for documents that contain
                    lines that exceed the length specified in this text field. For a list of the
                    restrictions applied to a document with long lines, see <xref
                      href="long-lines-document.dita#long-lines-document" format="dita">Editing
                      Documents with Long Lines</xref>.<p>
                      <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                          <dt><uicontrol>Show warning when loading documents with long
                              lines</uicontrol></dt>
                          <dd>When selected, <ph keyref="product"/>will warn you when you open a
                            file with lines longer than the specified length. To reduce the length
                            of lines in a file, <xref keyref="edit_format-and-indent-XML">format and
                              indent the document</xref> after it is opened in the editor panel. For
                            a list of the restrictions applied to a document with long lines, see
                              <xref href="long-lines-document.dita#long-lines-document"
                              format="dita"/>.</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                      </dl>
                    </p></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Clear undo buffer on save</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>If selected, <ph keyref="product"/> clears its undo buffer when you save a
                    document. Thus, modifications made prior to saving the document cannot be
                    undone. Select this option if you frequently encounter <b>out of
                      memory</b> errors when editing large documents.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry product="author developer editor">
                  <dt><uicontrol>Consider application bundles to be directories when
                      browsing</uicontrol> (OS X only)</dt>
                  <dd>This option is available only on the Mac OS X platform. When selected, the
                    file browser dialog box allows you to browse inside an application bundle, as in
                    a regular folder. Otherwise, it is not allowed (the same as the Finder
                    application on Mac OS X). <note>The same effect can be obtained by setting the
                          <codeph>apple.awt.use-file-dialog-packages</codeph> property to
                        <b>true</b> or <b>false</b> in the
                        <filepath>Info.plist</filepath> descriptor file of the <ph keyref="product"
                      /> application:
                      <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;key>apple.awt.use-file-dialog-packages&lt;/key>
&lt;string>false&lt;/string></codeblock></note></dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
