<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-global">
  <title>Global Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>Global</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Global preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The global options cover a number of aspects of the overall operation of <ph keyref="product"
      />. To configure the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> options, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to
        <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> preferences page:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Automatic Version Checking</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> will check for a new version on
            startup.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="check-for-notifications" product="author developer editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Check for notifications</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If selected (default value), the application will check for various types of messages
            from the <ph keyref="product"/> website and they will be displayed in the status bar.
            The types of messages include the addition of new videos on the website, the
            announcement of upcoming webinars and conferences where the <ph keyref="product"/> team
            will participate, and more.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="language">
          <dt><uicontrol>Language</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This option specifies the language used in the user interface. You can choose between
            English, French, German, Dutch, or Japanese. You must restart <ph keyref="product"/> for
            the change to take effect.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="other-language">
          <dt><uicontrol>Other language</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This option sets the language used in the user interface using an interface
            localization file. <ph product="editor author developer">For details about creating this
              file, see <xref href="changing-user-interface-language.dita"/>.</ph> You can use this
            option to set the language of the user interface to a language that is not shipped with
              <ph keyref="product"/>.<note>If some interface labels are not rendered correctly after
              restarting the application, (for example, Chinese or Korean characters are not
              displayed correctly), make sure that your operating system has the appropriate
              language pack installed (for example, the East-Asian language pack).</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="line-separator">
          <dt><uicontrol>Line separator</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This option sets the line separator used when saving files. Use <uicontrol>System
              Default</uicontrol> to select the normal line separator for your OS. If you want the
            existing file separator of a file to be maintained, regardless of your current OS,
            select <uicontrol>Detect the line separator on file open</uicontrol>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Detect the line separator on file open</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, the editor detects the line separator when a file is
            loaded and it uses it when the file is saved. New files are saved using the line
            separator defined by the <xref href="#preferences-global/line-separator" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Line separator</uicontrol> option</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Default Internet browser</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This option sets the Web browser that <ph keyref="product"/> will use to do the following:<ul>
              <li>Open (X)HTML or PDF transformation results.</li>
              <li>Open a web page (for example, pointing to specific paragraphs in the W3C
                recommendation of XML Schema if there are XML Schema validation errors).</li>
            </ul> If you leave this setting blank, the system default browser will be used.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Open last edited files from project</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> opens the files you had open the
            last time you used a project whenever you open the application or switch to that
            project.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>Beep on operation finished</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> beeps when a validation or
            transform action ends. Different tones are used for success and failure. The tones used
            may depend on the sound settings in your operating system.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="show-memory-status">
          <dt><uicontrol>Show memory status</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, the memory<ph keyref="product"/> uses is displayed in
            the status bar. To free memory, click the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/TrashIcon16.gif" id="image_rts_4w2_wr"/> Free unused memory</uicontrol>
            button located at the right side of the status bar. The memory status bar turns yellow
            or red when <ph keyref="product"/> uses too much memory. You can change the amount of
            memory available to <ph keyref="product"/> by <xref
              keyref="set-parameters-for-application-launchers">changing the parameters of the
              application launcher</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Check opened files for file system changes</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> checks the content of the all
            opened editors to see if they have been updated by another application. If the file has
            changed, <ph keyref="product"/> will ask you if you want to reload the file.<p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Auto update unmodified editors on file system
                    changes</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>If this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> automatically updates
                    unmodified editors if the edited file changes externally.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Show Java vendor warning at startup</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> displays a warning on startup if a
            non-recommended version of the Java virtual machine is being used.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry product="author developer editor">
          <dt><uicontrol>File Chooser Dialog</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>
            <p>This options specifies the directory that will be shown when the <xref
                href="opening-existing-documents.dita">Open file dialog box</xref> is displayed. You
              can choose between:</p>
            <ul>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>Last visited directory</uicontrol> - The last visited folder will be
                displayed. </li>
              <li>
                <uicontrol>Directory of the edited file</uicontrol> - The folder where the currently
                edited file is stored will be displayed.</li>
            </ul>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Show hidden files and directories</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, <ph keyref="product"/> shows system hidden files and
            folders in the file browser dialog box and the folder browser dialog box. This setting
            is not available on OS X.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
