<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/reference.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-dita">
  <title>DITA Preferences</title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <body>
    <p>To access the DITA Preferences page, <ph conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"
      /> and go to <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>DITA-OT directory</uicontrol> option specifies the directory of the DITA Open
      Toolkit distribution (bundled with the <ph keyref="product"/> installation) to be used, by
      default, for validating and publishing DITA content. You can either provide a new file path
      for the specific DITA OT that you want to use or you can select a previously used one from the
      drop-down menu.<note>You can select <userinput>${frameworksDir}/dita/DITA-OT2.x</userinput> to
        make all defined DITA transformation scenarios run with DITA-OT 2.0. This also gives you
        access to new DITA 1.3 file templates when you <xref
          href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa" product="author developer editor">create
          new document from templates</xref><xref href="../tasks/creating-from-templates.dita"
          product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">create new documents from
          templates</xref>.</note><ph product="author editor"> The <uicontrol>DITA Maps file
          patterns</uicontrol> option allows you to set the extension of the files that will be
        handled as DITA maps when opened in <ph keyref="product"/>. <ph keyref="product"/> can open
        a DITA map in the regular editor view or in the <xref keyref="dita_edit-maps">DITA Maps
          Manager</xref>.</ph></p>
    <p product="author editor"> The following options are available <uicontrol>When opening a
        map</uicontrol>:<ul id="ul_g5k_kdq_jq">
        <li><uicontrol>Always open in the DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> - A DITA map file is always
          opened in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Always open as XML</uicontrol> - A DITA map file is always opened in the XML
          editor.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Always ask</uicontrol> - When opening a DITA map, you are prompted to choose
          between opening it in the XML editor panel or in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
            Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p conkeyref="reusables-configuring-oxygen/p-show-console-output" id="show_console_output"/>
    <p id="insert-topic-ref-p">The following options are available for the <uicontrol>Insert\Edit
        Reference</uicontrol> operations:<ul id="ul_i5l_r55_bs">
        <li><uicontrol>Always fill values for attributes</uicontrol> - Allows you to specify that in
          the <uicontrol>Insert\Edit Reference</uicontrol> dialog box, the values for these
          attributes will be automatically populated with a detected value (based on the
          specifications), even if it is the same as the default value.<ul id="ul_yhk_s55_bs">
            <li><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol> - If enabled, the <i>Format</i> attribute will always
              be populated automatically .</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> - If enabled, the <i>Scope</i> attribute will always be
              populated automatically.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> - If enabled, the <i>Type</i> attribute will always be
              populated automatically.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>
      <ph product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">At the bottom of the page there is a
        link to the <xref href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#preferences-profiling-conditions"
          >Profiling Attributes preferences</xref>, where you can configure how profiling and
        conditional text is displayed in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></p>
  </body>
</topic>
