<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="preferences-dita-new-topics">
  <title>DITA New Topics Preferences</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Preferences<indexterm>DITA New topics</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>DITA new topics preferences</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To access the DITA New Topics preferences page, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>New Topics</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. This preferences page includes the following options:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="file-name-rules">
          <dt><uicontrol>Use the title to generate the file name</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This option (and its sub-options) pertain to the rules that will be used to generate
            file names in the <xref href="create-topic-in-map.dita#create-topic-in-map"
              product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"><i>New DITA File dialog
              box</i></xref><xref href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa" product="developer"><i>New
                Document Wizard</i></xref>. Select this option to use the text entered in the
              <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> field to automatically generate a file name (the
            generated name can be seen in the <uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> field). By default, the
            generated name will replace spaces with underscores (<codeph>_</codeph>), all illegal
            characters will be removed, and all upper case characters changed to lower case, but you
            can use the sub-options to change this.</dd>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Replace spaces with</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>
                    <p>If selected, the file name generation mechanism will replace spaces in the
                      title with the character entered in this option.</p>
                    <p>
                      <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                          <dt><uicontrol>Lower case only</uicontrol></dt>
                          <dd>If selected, the file name generation mechanism will only use lower
                            case letters.</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                      </dl>
                    </p>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Use camel case</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>
                    <p>If selected, the file name generation mechanism will convert the title to a
                      file name using the <term>camel case</term> convention where the first word
                      starts with a lower case letter and all subsequent words begin with upper case
                      (for example, <codeph>myFileName</codeph>).</p>
                    <p>
                      <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                          <dt><uicontrol>Upper case first letter</uicontrol></dt>
                          <dd>Select this option if you want the file name generation mechanism to
                            convert the title to a file name using the <term>camel case</term>
                            convention but with an upper case letter for the first word (for
                            example, <codeph>MyFileName</codeph>).</dd>
                        </dlentry>
                      </dl>
                    </p>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Use the file name as the value of the root ID attribute</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If selected, when creating a new topic, the file name (as seen in the <uicontrol>Save
              as</uicontrol> field but without the file extension) will be used as the value of the
            root <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute for the new topic.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Use the file name as the value of the "keys" attribute for topic
              references</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If selected, when inserting a topic reference into a map, the file name will be used
            as the value of the <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt> attribute for the new
              <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement>.<ph
              product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> This option has a slightly
              different effect depending on the method used for inserting the topic
              reference:</ph><ul id="ul_w4f_qcq_klb"
              product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">
              <li><b>Drag/Drop or Copy/Paste in the DITA Maps Manager</b> - If you drag or copy a
                resource from another view (or outside <ph keyref="product"/>) and drop or paste it
                into the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> and a key is already defined for
                that resource, a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute will be inserted instead. This
                even works for two consecutive drag/drop or copy/paste operations without saving the
                file and it works for multiple selections of topic references.</li>
              <li><b>Drag/Drop or Copy/Paste in a Map opened in Author Mode</b> - If you drag or
                copy a resource from another view (or outside <ph keyref="product"/>) and drop or
                paste it into a map that is open in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, and a key is
                already defined for that resource, a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute will be
                inserted instead.<note type="restriction">In this particular scenario, if you
                  perform two identical, consecutive drag/drop or copy/paste operations without
                  saving the file between operations, the value of the <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt>
                  attribute will be the same for both inserted topic references. The workaround for
                  this limitation is to simply save the map after each drag/drop or copy/paste
                  operation.</note></li>
              <li><b>Using the Fast Create Topics or Duplicate Actions</b> - If you use the <xref
                  href="fast-create-topics.dita"><uicontrol>Fast Create Topics</uicontrol>
                  feature</xref> or <xref href="create-topic-in-map.dita"
                    ><uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> action</xref> to insert topic references, the
                newly created <xmlelement>topicref</xmlelement> elements will contain the
                  <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt> attribute with its value set depending on the file
                name.</li>
              <li><b>Using the <uicontrol>Insert Topic Reference</uicontrol> Dialog Box from the
                  DITA Maps Manager</b> - If you use an action in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
                  Manager</uicontrol> to insert topic references (e.g. <menucascade>
                  <uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol>
                  <uicontrol><image href="../img/Topicref16.png" id="image_zcs_fgv_4lb"
                    />Reference</uicontrol>
                </menucascade>), a <xmlatt>keys</xmlatt> attribute will be set for each inserted
                topic reference and the value depends on the file name. <ph
                  product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">You can see the value in the
                    <uicontrol>Define keys</uicontrol> field from the <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol>
                  tab of <xref href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref">the
                      <uicontrol>Insert Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> and you can change
                  it</ph><ph product="author editor"> If a single target was selected,  you can see
                  the value in the <uicontrol>Define keys</uicontrol> field from the
                    <uicontrol>Keys</uicontrol> tab of <xref
                    href="dita-insert-topic-ref.dita#dita-insert-topic-ref">the <uicontrol>Insert
                      Reference</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> and you can change it, while if
                  multiple targets were selected, the values are automatically generated based on
                  each file name when the insertion is performed, and you cannot see or change the
                  values in that dialog box</ph>.</li>
            </ul><note>This option also has an effect on image references. When inserting a
              reference to an image in a DITA map and this option is selected, a
                <xmlelement>keydef</xmlelement> element is created if it is allowed by the schema.
              If it is not allowed (or this option is deselected), a specific topic reference
              element is created with the value of the <xmlatt>processing-role</xmlatt> attribute
              set to <b>resource-only</b>.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
