<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="printing-a-file">
  <title>Printing a Document</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Printing</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Print documents</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Print Preview dialog box</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Printing is supported in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol><ph product="author editor">,
          <uicontrol>Author,</uicontrol></ph> and <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> modes.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Print</uicontrol>(<uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_p"
        >))</uicontrol>) action that is available from <uicontrol>File</uicontrol> menu displays a
      series of dialog boxes that allow you to configure print settings. After defining the settings
      in each dialog box, click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to continue to the next one.</p>
    <p>A <uicontrol>Print Preview</uicontrol> action is also available in the
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol> menu. It first opens a <uicontrol>Page Setup</uicontrol> dialog
      box where you can define some paper, orientation, and margin settings. After you click
        <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>, it displays the <uicontrol>Print Preview</uicontrol> dialog box
      where you can see a preview of how the document will look when it is printed..</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Print Preview Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_print_preview.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The main window is split in three sections:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Preview area</uicontrol> - Displays the formatted document page as it will
        appear on printed paper.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Left stripe</uicontrol> - The left-side stripe that displays a list of
        thumbnail pages. Clicking any of them displays the page content in the main preview
        area.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Toolbar</uicontrol> - The toolbar area at the top that contains controls for
        printing, page settings, page navigation, print scaling, and zoom.</li>
    </ul>
    <section id="other_printing_features">
      <title>Other Printing Features</title>
      <ul>
        <li product="author editor">If you are printing a document that is opened in the
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> visual editing mode, you can use the <xref
            href="dg-media-at-rule.dita#dg-media-at-rule">CSS print media type</xref> to change the
          styling in the printed output.</li>
        <li product="author editor">If you are printing a document that is opened in
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and it contains <xref keyref="author_change-tracking"
            format="dita"><term>Tracked Changes</term></xref>, you can print (or print preview) a
          copy of the document as if all changes have been accepted by switching the <xref
            href="author-managing-changes.dita#author-managing-changes/track_changes_view_modes"
            format="dita"><uicontrol>Track Changes Visualization Mode</uicontrol></xref> to
            <uicontrol>View Final</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li>If you are printing a document that is opened in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode and
          line numbers are displayed (the <xref
            href="preferences-editor-text.dita#preferences-editor-text/show-line-numbers"
              ><uicontrol>Show line numbers</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected), the printed
          output will include the line numbers.</li>
        <li>If you are printing an XML document that is opened in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode
          and the <xref href="folding-of-the-xml-elements.dita#folding-of-the-xml-elements"
              ><term>folding</term> support</xref> is activated (the <xref
            href="preferences-editor-text.dita#preferences-editor-text/enable-folding"
              ><uicontrol>Enable folding</uicontrol> option</xref> is selected), the printed output
          will include the current <term>folded</term> state. Note that this applies to printing an
          entire document and not selections within the document.</li>
        <li>If you are printing an XML document that is opened in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode
          and a block of content is selected, you have the ability to print only the selection of
          text rather than the entire document. When you invoke the print action with a block of
          content selected in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode, a dialog box will be presented that
          offers you the choice to print the selection or the entire document.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
