<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="privacy_options">
    <title>Privacy Options</title>
    <body>
    <p>As an on-premise desktop application, <ph keyref="product"/> does not store sensitive user
      data or user-specific files on remote servers. The full <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/privacy_policy.html" format="html" scope="external">Privacy
        Policy</xref> is available on the official <ph keyref="product"/> web site.</p>
    <p>Whenever it is started, the application may connect to its official web site
        (<b>https://www.oxygenxml.com</b>) to provide notifications about new releases or new
      events. In the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> preferences page, there are some checkboxes that
      can be disabled if you do not want this type of information retrieved:<dl id="dl_qzt_5h2_jvb">
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Automatic Version Checking</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, the application obtains information about new available
            versions from the official <ph keyref="product"/> web site. No specific information
            about the current installation is passed to the <ph keyref="product"/> web site during
            this process.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Check for Oxygen-related events at startup</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, the application obtains information about events that get
            displayed in the <uicontrol>Welcome</uicontrol> screen. The types of downloaded events
            include information about the addition of new videos on the website, announcements of
            upcoming webinars and conferences where the <ph keyref="product"/> team will
            participate, and more. No specific information about the current installation is passed
            to the <ph keyref="product"/> web site during this process.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Check for Oxygen-related notifications</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is selected, the application obtains information about other various
            notifications that get displayed <xref
              href="getting-familiar.dita#getting-familiar/dlentry_lml_bgk_54b">on the right side of
              the status bar</xref>. No specific information about the current installation is
            passed to the <ph keyref="product"/> web site during this process.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>Providing installation-specific details to the <ph keyref="product"/> technical support team
      is also possible by using the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Report problem</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action from the main menu. Also, if an <term>unhandled/fatal</term> error
      occurs in the application, the user is presented with a <uicontrol>Report problem</uicontrol>
      dialog box and can choose to submit the error and its context for analysis. The
        <uicontrol>Report problem</uicontrol> dialog box shows the exact specific details that are
      sent to the <ph keyref="product"/> technical support team and can be examined by the end user
      before being sent. No files or confidential information are sent.</p>
    <p>When the application is installed on Windows or Linux using the provided installation kit,
      the last installation step allows you to click a <b>Privacy Options</b> link to choose which
      privacy-related settings should be disabled before the application starts for the first time.
      The <b>Privacy Options</b> can also be disabled when performing an unattended install. See
      instructions here: <xref
        href="eppo-installation-windows.dita#eppo-installation-windows/unattended_installation"
      />.</p>
    <p>Besides the settings already present in the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol> preferences page,
      the <uicontrol>Privacy Options</uicontrol> dialog box contains two extra settings:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Allow installing add-ons</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is not selected, the end user is not allowed to install add-ons in the
            application.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Allow installing "AI Positron" add-on</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>If this option is not selected, the end user is not allowed to install the
              <uicontrol>AI Positron</uicontrol> add-on in the application.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Allow connections to the AI Positron service</dt>
          <dd>If this option is not selected, the end user is not allowed to use the AI Positron
            service in the application.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p product="author developer editor">
      <fig id="fig_cnx_mh2_jvb">
        <title>Installation - Privacy Policy Link</title>
        <image href="../img/privacy-options-install.png" id="image_j52_jh2_jvb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p product="author developer editor">
      <fig id="fig_zms_qh2_jvb">
        <title>Installation -Privacy Options</title>
        <image href="../img/privacy-options-installation-settings.png" id="image_n21_qh2_jvb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
