<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="profiling-conditional-text-menu" >
  <title>Profiling / Conditional Text Menu</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingToolbar20.png"/> Profiling / Conditional
        Text</uicontrol> toolbar menu groups the following actions:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Show Profiling Colors and Styles</uicontrol> - Enable this option to turn on
          conditional styling.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> - Enable this option to turn on
          conditional text markers. They are displayed at the end of conditional text blocks, as a
          list of attribute name and their currently set values.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show Excluded Content</uicontrol> - Controls if the content filtered out by a
          particular condition set is hidden or greyed-out in the editor area and in the
            <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> views. When
          this option is turned on, the content filtered by the currently applied condition set is
          greyed-out. To show only the content that matches the currently applied condition set,
          turn off this option.<note>To remind you that document content is hidden, <ph
              keyref="product"/> displays labels showing the currently applied condition set. These
            labels are displayed in the Author editing area, the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view
            and <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view. Right click any of the labels to
            quickly access the <uicontrol>Show Excluded Content</uicontrol> action.</note></li>
        <li>The list of all profiling condition sets that match the current document type. Click on
          a condition set entry to activate it.</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_options_shortcut.png"/>Profiling
            Settings...</uicontrol> - Link to the <xref
            href="preferences-profiling-conditions.dita#profiling.conditions" format="dita"
            >profiling options</xref> preference pages, where you can manage profiling attributes,
          profiling conditions sets, as well as profiling styles and colors options.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>All these settings are associated with the current project, being restored the next time you
      open it. For a new project all Profiling/Conditional Text menu actions states are reset to
      their default values.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
