<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="profiling-conditional-text">
  <title>Profiling and Conditional Text</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Profiling and Conditional Text</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="cond-text-intro">Profiling text is a way to mark blocks of text meant to appear in some
      renditions of the document but not in others. Conditional text differs from one variant of the
      document to another, while unconditional text appear in all document versions. For example,
      you can mark a section of a document that is to be included in a manual to be designated for
        <i>expert</i> users and another section for <i>novice</i> users, while unmarked sections are
      included in all renditions.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to define values for the profiling attributes and they can
      be easily managed to filter content in the published output. You can switch between profile
      sets to see how the edited content looks like before publishing. You can also conditionally
      profile parts of a document so that certain parts are displayed when certain profiling
      conditions are set. You can even customize the colors and styling of how the profiling is
      displayed in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</p>
    <p>You can use profiling and conditional text to help you create documentation for multiple
      output scenarios, including:<ul>
        <li>Multiple outputs for a series of similar products.</li>
        <li>Multiple outputs for various releases of a product.</li>
        <li>Multiple outputs for various audiences.</li>
      </ul>This feature helps to reduce the effort for updating and translating your content and
      provides an easy way to customize the output for various audiences.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Example: Profiling Content</title>
        <image href="../img/profiling_example.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a preconfigured set of profiling attribute values for some of
      the most popular document types. These attributes can be redefined to match your specific
      needs. You can also define your own profiling attributes for each document type (framework)<ph
        product="author editor"> and your profiling configuration can be shared amongst content
        authors through the project file</ph>.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="customize-profiling-conditions.dita#customize-profiling-conditions"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>