<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="profiling-conditional-text">
  <title>Profiling and Conditional Text</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Profiling</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode
            editing<indexterm>Profiling</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Profiling content in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="cond-text-intro">Profiling text is a way to mark blocks of text meant to appear in some
      renditions of the document but not in others. Conditional text differs from one variant of the
      document to another, while unconditional text appear in all document versions. For example,
      you can mark a section of a document that is to be included in a manual to be designated for
        <i>expert</i> users and another section for <i>novice</i> users, while unmarked sections are
      included in all renditions.</p>
    <section id="profiling_attributes_and_condition_sets">
      <title>Profiling Attributes and Condition Sets</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to define values for the profiling attributes and they
        can be easily managed to filter content in the published output. You can switch between
        profile sets to see how the edited content looks like before publishing. You can also
        conditionally profile parts of a document so that certain parts are displayed when certain
        profiling conditions are set. You can even customize the colors and styling of how the
        profiling is displayed in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</p>
      <p>You can use profiling and conditional text to help you create documentation for multiple
        output scenarios, including:<ul>
          <li>Multiple outputs for a series of similar products.</li>
          <li>Multiple outputs for various releases of a product.</li>
          <li>Multiple outputs for various audiences.</li>
        </ul>This feature helps to reduce the effort for updating and translating your content and
        provides an easy way to customize the output for various audiences.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Example: Profiling Content</title>
          <image href="../img/profiling_example.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a preconfigured set of profiling attribute values for some
        of the most popular document types. These attributes can be redefined to match your specific
        needs. You can also define your own profiling attributes for each document type (<xref
          keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>framework</term></xref>)<ph product="author editor">
          and your profiling configuration can be shared amongst content authors through the project
          file</ph>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="profiling-content-section">
      <title>Apply Profiling to DITA Content</title>
      <p>To apply a profiling attribute to DITA content, highlight the content and select
          <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> from the contextual menu. To profile
        specific elements in a topic or map, right-click inside the element and select
          <uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol>. The <wintitle>Edit Profiling
          Attributes</wintitle> dialog box is displayed, allowing you to select each of the
        profiling tokens that apply for each attribute.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="edit-profiling-image">
          <title>Edit Profiling Attributes Dialog Box</title>
          <image href="../img/edit-profiling-attributes-dialog.png" id="image_dkz_hsd_bq"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The profiling attributes and their potential values that appear in this dialog box depend
        on what has been configured in <ph keyref="product"/>. If you have a large list of profiling
        attributes, you can use the text filter field to search for attributes or values, and you
        can expand or collapse attributes by using the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/ExpandAll16.png"/>Expand All/<image href="../img/CollapseAll16.png"
          />Collapse All</uicontrol> buttons to the right of the text filter or the arrow button to
        the left of the profiling attribute name.</p>
      <p>The attributes and values that appear in the dialog box are determined as follows:</p>
      <ul id="ul_bsp_5sd_bq">
        <li>If your <xref keyref="glossentry_root-map"><term>root map</term></xref> references a
          DITA <xref keyref="glossentry_subject-scheme-map"><term>subject scheme map</term></xref>
          that <xref href="subject-scheme-map.dita#subject-scheme-map">defines values for the
            profiling attributes</xref>, those values are used. <ph keyref="product"/> collects all
          the profiling values from the <term>subject scheme map</term> that is referenced in the
          map that is currently opened in the <xref href="dita-maps-manager.dita">DITA Maps
            Manager</xref> (or <xref href="root-map.dita#root-map">set as the root map</xref>). In
          the <xref href="#profiling-conditional-text/edit-profiling-image" format="dita">image
            above</xref> (taken from the <ph keyref="product"/> documentation project), you see
          values for eight products. They are the only values that are defined in the subject scheme
          map and thus, are the only ones that appear in the dialog box.</li>
        <li product="author editor">If your project defines <xref
            keyref="glossentry_project-options">project-level</xref> configuration values for the
            <xref keyref="options_editor_profiling">profiling attributes</xref>, those values are
          used.</li>
        <li product="author editor">If <ph keyref="product"/> defines <xref
            keyref="glossentry_global-options">global-level</xref> configuration values for the
            <xref keyref="options_editor_profiling">profiling attributes</xref>, those values are
          used.</li>
        <li>Otherwise, a generic default set of profiling attributes and values are available.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="visualizing_profiled_content">
      <title>Visualizing Profiled Content</title>
      <p>You can visualize the effect of profiling content by using the profiling tools in the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/ProfilingDrop.png" id="image_pm5_bzf_yr"
            placement="inline"/>Profiling/Conditional Text</uicontrol> drop-down menu that is
        located on the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> toolbar. You can select which
        profiles to show, or apply colors to text that is profiled in various ways, as shown in the
        following image:</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Example: Profiled Content</title>
          <image href="../img/profiling-styles-sample.png" id="image_s2j_vvd_bq" placement="inline"
          />
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="customize-profiling-conditions.dita#customize-profiling-conditions"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>