<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="randomize-xml-content">
  <title>Randomize XML Text Content</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Help <indexterm>Randomize XML text content</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes an action that randomizes the text content of an XML
      document. This action is available in the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Support Tools</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu. It is helpful if you need to send XML samples to the Oxygen support team
      and you want to keep the text content confidential. It opens a dialog box that allows you to
      select the resources for which the text content will be randomized. You can then save the
      resources and send them to the Oxygen support team without fear of compromising sensitive or
      private data.<note type="warning">Before using this action, it is highly recommended that you
        copy the XML resources to be processed, save them in a separate folder, and then perform
        this operation on the copies instead of the original files. Otherwise, you may lose your
        original content.</note></p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Randomize XML Text Content Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/randomize_text_content.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Randomize XML Text Content</uicontrol> dialog box includes the following
      options:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to select the set of files whose text content will be randomized by the
            operation. You can select from predefined resource sets (such as the current file, your
            whole project, the current <xref keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA
              map</term></xref> hierarchy for DITA projects, etc.) or you can define your own set of
            resources by creating a working set.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Filters</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This section includes the following options:<ul id="ul_t3v_nzv_3r">
              <li><uicontrol>Include files</uicontrol> - Allows you to filter the selected resources
                by using a file pattern. For example, to restrict the operation to only analyze
                build files you could use <userinput>build*.xml</userinput> for the file
                pattern.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Restrict only to known XML file types</uicontrol> - When selected, only
                resources with a known XML file type will be affected by the operation.</li>
              <li product="author developer editor"><uicontrol>Look inside archives</uicontrol> -
                When selected, the resources inside archives will also be affected.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
