<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="real-pseudo-conflicts">
  <title>Real Conflicts vs Mergeable Conflicts</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Synchronize with the SVN Repository<indexterm>resolve conflicts<indexterm>real conflicts
              vs mergeable conflicts</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>There are two types of conflicts:<ul>
        <li><i>real conflict</i> (<image href="../img/SynchronizeRealConflict.png"/> decorator in
            <i>Name</i> column)  - Syncro SVN Client considers the following resource states to be
          real conflicts:<ul>
            <li><i>conflicted</i> state - a file reported by SVN as being in this state is obtained
              after it was updated/merged while having incoming and outgoing content or property
              changes at the same time, changes which could not be merged. A content conflict
                (<image href="../img/SVNWCConflicted10.png"/> symbol in <i>Local file status</i>
              column) is reported when the modified file has binary content or it is a text file and
              both local and remote changes were found on the same line. A properties conflict
                (<image href="../img/SVNWCPropConflicted10.png"/> symbol in <i>Local properties
                status</i> column) is reported when a property's value was modified both locally and
              remotely;</li>
            <li><i>tree conflicted</i> state (<image href="../img/SVNWCTreeConflicted10.png"/>
              symbol in <i>Local file status</i> column)  - obtained after an update or merge
              operation, while having changes at the directory structure level (for example, file is
              locally modified and remotely deleted or locally scheduled for deletion and remotely
              modified);</li>
            <li><i>obstructed</i> state (<image href="../img/SVNWCObstructed10.png"/> symbol in
                <i>Local file status</i> column) - obtained after a resource was versioned as one
              kind of object (file, directory, symbolic link), but has been replaced outside Syncro
              SVN Client by a different kind of object.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><i>pseudo-conflict</i> (<image href="../img/SVNSynchronizePseudoConflict9.png"/>
          decorator in <i>Name</i> column) - a file is considered to be in <i>pseudo-conflict</i>
          when it contains both incoming and outgoing changes. When incoming and outgoing changes do
          not intersect, an update operation may automatically merge the incoming file content into
          the existing locally one. In this case, the <i>pseudo-conflict</i> marker is removed. This
          marker is used only as a warning which should prevent you to run into a real
          conflict.</li>
      </ul><note>
        <ul>
          <li>A conflicting resource cannot be committed to repository. You have to resolve it
            first, by using <uicontrol>Mark Resolved</uicontrol> action (after manually
            editing/merging file contents) or by using <uicontrol>Mark as Merged</uicontrol> action
            (for pseudo-conflicts).</li>
          <li><image href="../img/SynchronizeRealConflict.png"/> and <image
              href="../img/SVNSynchronizePseudoConflict9.png"/> decorators are presented only when
            one of the following view modes is selected: <uicontrol>Modified</uicontrol>,
              <uicontrol>Incoming</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Outgoing</uicontrol>,
              <uicontrol>Conflicts</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>The <image href="../img/SVNSynchronizePseudoConflict9.png"/> marker is used also for
            folders to signal that they contain a file in real conflict or pseudo-conflict
            state.</li>
        </ul>
      </note></p>
  </body>
</topic>