<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="Redundancy-Deployment-for-Web-Author">
  <title>Redundancy/Backup Deployments</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Replication</indexterm>
        <indexterm>High Availability</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Redundancy</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_epq_dgk_54b">Redundancy servers are often used to create high availability environments. In simpler terms,
      you create a second deployment of the servers called redundancy servers to take over the
      production servers in case of failure to avoid downtime.</p>
    <p id="p_fpq_dgk_54b">
      <note id="note_gpq_dgk_54b">A redundancy environment requires a special redundancy license key. To obtain one, you
        need to contact our sales department at <i>sales@oxygenxml.com</i>.</note>
    </p>
    <p id="p_hpq_dgk_54b"><image href="../img/Redundancy.png" id="image_jsb_cqy_wmb"/></p>
    <p id="p_ipq_dgk_54b">To achieve this, you need to create two environments:<ul id="ul_jpq_dgk_54b">
        <li id="li_kpq_dgk_54b">Production - The main environment.</li>
        <li id="li_lpq_dgk_54b">Redundancy - A secondary environment that takes over the production environment if
          failure occurs.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p id="p_mpq_dgk_54b">Each environment consists of two components: an HTTP License Server and a Web Author
      instance.</p>
    <p id="p_npq_dgk_54b">To create the environments:</p>
    <ol id="ol_u3j_r5h_jmb">
      <li id="li_opq_dgk_54b">Install an instance of the <b>Oxygen HTTP License Server</b> for each of the
        environments.</li>
      <li id="li_ppq_dgk_54b">Configure the license server to use the license keys . The production license key will be
        configured on the license server from the production environment while the redundancy
        license key will be configured on the license server from the redundancy environment.</li>
      <li id="li_qpq_dgk_54b">Install a Web Author instance for each of the environments. Choose <xref
          href="webapp-initial-installation.dita#webapp-initial-installation/flexible-setup"
              ><i><uicontrol>Flexible setup </uicontrol></i> on the initial configuration
          page</xref>.</li>
      <li id="li_rpq_dgk_54b">Go to the <xref href="webapp-admin-page.dita">Administration page</xref> and configure
        both Web Author instances to use the license server instances:<ul id="ul_x41_3zh_jmb">
          <li id="li_spq_dgk_54b">The production license server as the main server.</li>
          <li id="li_tpq_dgk_54b">The redundancy license server as the backup server.<note type="tip" id="note_upq_dgk_54b">Both Web Author
              instances have the same license server configuration.</note></li>
        </ul><p id="p_vpq_dgk_54b">
          <note id="note_wpq_dgk_54b">If only the production license server fails, Web Author automatically switches to
            the backup license server from the redundancy environment.</note>
        </p></li>
    </ol>
    <p id="p_xpq_dgk_54b">For the instance from the Redundancy environment to replace the one from Production, you will
      need to set up a load balancer that directs the users to the Redundancy Environment Web Author
      instance only when the Production Environment is down.</p>
    <p>For an example of a load-balancer configuration (Docker-based) on the public GitHub
      repository, see: <xref
        href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/web-author-docker/tree/master/load-balancer"
        format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
    <p id="p_ypq_dgk_54b">
      <note id="note_zpq_dgk_54b">Only the Web Author instances need to be handled by the load balancer because the
        License Server connections fallback is automatically handled by each Web Author instance if
        the main License Server fails.</note>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
