<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="refactoring-xml-documents">
  <title>Refactoring XML Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Refactoring</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Refactoring XML Documents</indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Refactoring tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>In the life cycle of XML documents there are instances when the XML structure needs to be
      changed to accommodate various needs. For example, when an associated schema is updated, an
      attribute may have been removed, or a new element added to the structure.</p>
    <p>These types of situations cannot be resolved with a traditional <i>Find/Replace</i>
      tool, even if the tool accepts regular expressions. The problem becomes even more complicated
      if an XML document is computed or referenced from multiple modules, since multiple resources
      need to be changed.</p>
    <p>To assist you with these types of refactoring tasks, <ph keyref="product"/> includes a
      specialized <uicontrol>XML Refactoring</uicontrol> tool that helps you manage the structure of
      your XML documents.</p>
    <section id="xml_refactoring_tool">
      <title>XML Refactoring Tool</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>XML Refactoring</uicontrol> tool is presented in the form of an easy to use
        wizard that is designed to reduce the time and effort required to perform various structure
        management tasks. For example, you can insert, delete, or rename an attribute in all
        instances of a particular element that is found in all documents within your project. </p>
      <p>To access the tool, select the <uicontrol><image href="../img/XMLRefactoring16.png"
            id="image_mv4_ptt_kr"/>XML Refactoring</uicontrol> action from one of the following
          locations:<ul id="ul_lrm_wz5_3r">
          <li>The <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol
              product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">XML Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol
              product="authorEclipse">XML</uicontrol> menu.</li>
          <li>The <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu from the contextual menu in the <xref
              href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view"><uicontrol
                product="author developer editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
                product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</uicontrol>
              view</xref>.</li>
          <li product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">The
              <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu from the contextual menu in the <xref
              href="dita-maps-manager.dita#dita-maps-manager"><uicontrol>DITA Maps
                Manager</uicontrol> view</xref>.</li>
        </ul><note>The predefined refactoring operations are also available from the
            <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu in the contextual menu of <ph
            product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> or
            </ph><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode. This is useful because by selecting the
          operations from the contextual menu, <ph keyref="product"/> considers the editing context
          to skip directly to the wizard page of the appropriate operation and to help you by
          preconfiguring some of the parameter values.<ph product="author developer editor"> For
            your convenience, the last 5 operations that were <xref
              href="#refactoring-xml-documents/finish" format="dita">finished</xref> or <xref
              href="#refactoring-xml-documents/preview" format="dita">previewed</xref> also appear
            in the <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu of the contextual menu in the
              <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view<ph product="author editor"> and the
                <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol></ph>.</ph><ph
            product="authorEclipse editorEclipse"> For your convenience, the last 5 operations that
            were <xref href="#refactoring-xml-documents/finish" format="dita">finished</xref> or
              <xref href="#refactoring-xml-documents/preview" format="dita">previewed</xref> also
            appear in the <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu of the contextual menu in the
              <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>.</ph></note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="xml_refactoring_wizard">
      <title>XML Refactoring Wizard</title>
      <p>The XML Refactoring tool includes the following wizard pages:<dl>
          <dlentry id="refactoring_operations_dlentry">
            <dt><uicontrol>Refactoring operations</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>The first wizard page presents the available operations, grouped by category. To
              search for an operation, you can use the filter text box at the top of the page.<p>
                <fig id="fig_vy5_pqv_3r">
                  <title>XML Refactoring Wizard</title>
                  <image href="../img/refactoring_operations.png" id="image_xyy_rqv_3r"/>
                </fig>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="parameters_dlentry">
            <dt><uicontrol>Configure Operation Parameters</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>The next wizard page allows you to specify the parameters for the refactoring
              operation. The parameters are specific to the type of refactoring operation that is
              being performed. For example, to delete an attribute you need to specify the parent
              element and the qualified name of the attribute to be removed.<p>
                <fig id="fig_ipl_1wv_3r">
                  <title>XML Refactoring 2nd Wizard Page (Delete Attribute Operation)</title>
                  <image href="../img/configure_operation_param.png" id="image_w32_cwv_3r"/>
                </fig>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Scope and Filters</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>The last wizard page allows you to select the set of files that represent the input
              of the operation.<p>
                <fig id="fig_ih5_q1w_3r">
                  <title>XML Refactoring - Scope and Filters Wizard Page</title>
                  <image href="../img/refactoring_scope_filters.png" id="image_q5b_s1w_3r"/>
                </fig>
              </p><p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> section</dt>
                    <dd>In the <uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> section, you can select from predefined
                      resource sets (such as the current file, your whole project, the current <xref
                        keyref="glossentry_ditamap"><term>DITA map</term></xref> hierarchy for DITA
                      projects, etc.) or you can define your own set of resources by creating a
                        <xref keyref="glossentry_working-set"><term>working set</term></xref>.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol>Filters</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>The <uicontrol>Filters</uicontrol> section includes the following
                        options:<ul id="ul_t3v_nzv_3r">
                        <li><uicontrol>Include files</uicontrol> - Allows you to filter the selected
                          resources by using a file pattern. For example, to restrict the operation
                          to only analyze build files you could use
                            <userinput>build*.xml</userinput> for the file pattern.</li>
                        <li><uicontrol>Restrict only to known XML file types</uicontrol> - When
                          selected, only resources with a known XML file type will be affected by
                          the operation.</li>
                        <li product="author developer editor"><uicontrol>Look inside
                            archives</uicontrol> - When selected, the resources inside archives will
                          also be affected.</li>
                      </ul></dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="preview">
                    <dt><uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>You can use the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> button to open a comparison
                      panel where you can review all the changes that will be made by the
                      refactoring operation before applying the changes.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="finish">
                    <dt><uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>After clicking the <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol> button, the operation will
                      be processed and <ph keyref="product"/> provides no automatic means for
                      reverting the operations. Any <uicontrol>Undo</uicontrol> action will only
                      revert changes on the current document.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
      <p>
        <note type="tip">If an operation takes longer than expected you can use the
              <uicontrol><image href="../img/StopExternalTool16.png" id="image_yx2_1bp_5r"
            />Stop</uicontrol> button in the progress bar to cancel the operation.</note>
        <?oxy_insert_start author="radu_pisoi" timestamp="20150316T162714+0200"?>
      </p>
      <?oxy_insert_end?>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
