<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="review-view">
  <title>The Review View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>change tracking<indexterm>the Review
            view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view is a framework-independent panel, available both for
      built-in, and custom XML document frameworks. It is designed to offer an enhanced way of
      monitoring all the changes that you make to a document. This means you are able to view and
      control highlighted, commented, inserted, and deleted content, or even changes made to
      attributes, using a single view.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view is useful when you are working with documents that
      contain large quantities of edits. The edits are presented in a compact form, in the order
      they appear in the document. Each edit is marked with a type-specific icon.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Review View</title>
      <image href="../img/review-view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>To activate the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, do one of the following:<ul>
        <li>click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ManageReviews20.png"/>Manage
            reviews</uicontrol> button on the <uicontrol>Author Review</uicontrol> toolbar;</li>
        <li>right click in a document and from the contextual menu go to
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Manage reviews</uicontrol>;</li>
        <li>go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Show View</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Review</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>This view and the editing area are synchronized. When you select an edit listed in the
        <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, its corresponding fragment of text is highlighted in the
      editing area and. The reverse is also true. For example, when you place the caret inside an
      area of text marked as inserted, its corresponding edit is selected in the list.</p>
    <p>The upper part of the view contains a filtering area which allows you to search for specific
      edits. Use the small arrow symbol from the right side of the search field to display the
      search history. The <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> button allows you to:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Show highlights</uicontrol> - controls whether the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the highlighting in your document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show comments</uicontrol> - controls whether the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the comments in the document you are
          editing;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show track changes</uicontrol> - controls whether the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the inserted and deleted content in your
          document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show review time</uicontrol> - displays the time when the edits from the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view were made.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The following actions are available when you hover the edits in the
        <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, using the cursor:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> - this action is available for highlights and comments
          presented in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view. Use this action to remove these
          highlights or comments from your document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Accept</uicontrol> - this action is available for inserted and deleted
          content presented in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view. Use this action to accept the
          changes in your document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Reject</uicontrol> - this action is available for inserted and deleted
          content presented in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view. Use this action to reject the
          changes in your document.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <p>Depending on the type of an edit, the following actions are available in its contextual menu
      in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Show comment</uicontrol> - this option is available in the contextual menu of
          changes not made by you and of any comment listed in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
          view. Use this option to view a comment in the <uicontrol>Show comment</uicontrol>
          dialog;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Edit comment</uicontrol> - this option is available in the contextual menu of
          your comments, listed in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view. Use this action to start
          editing the comment;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove comment</uicontrol> - this option is available in the contextual menu
          of a comment listed in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view. Use this action to remove
          the selected comment;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show only reviews by</uicontrol> - this option is available in the contextual
          menu of any edit listed in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view. Use this action to keep
          visible only the edits of a certain author in the view;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove all comments</uicontrol> - this option is available in the contextual
          menu of any comment listed in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view. Use this action to
          remove all the comments that appear in the edited document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Change color</uicontrol> - opens a palette that allows you to choose a new
          color for the highlighted content;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove highlight</uicontrol> - removes the selected highlighting; </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove highlights with the same color</uicontrol> - removes all the
          highlighting in a document that has the same color;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove all highlights</uicontrol> - clears all the highlighting in your
          document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Accept change</uicontrol> - accepts the selected change;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Reject change</uicontrol> - rejects the selected change;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Comment change</uicontrol> - this option is available in the contextual menu
          of an insertion or deletion that you made. Use this option to open the <uicontrol>Edit
            comment</uicontrol> dialog and comment the change you made;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Accept all changes</uicontrol> - accepts all the changes made to a
          document;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Reject all changes</uicontrol> - rejects all the changes made to a
          document.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, go to <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Review_Panel.html" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Review_Panel.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
