<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="review-view">
  <title>Review View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>change tracking<indexterm>the Review
            view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view is a framework-independent panel, available both for
      built-in, and custom XML document frameworks. It is designed to offer an enhanced way of
      monitoring all the changes that you make to a document. This means you can view and
      control highlighted, commented, inserted, and deleted content, or even changes made to
      attributes, using a single view.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view is useful when you are working with documents that
      contain large quantities of edits. The edits are presented in a compact form, in the order
      they appear in the document. Each edit is marked with a type-specific icon. This view and the
      editing area are synchronized. When you select an edit listed in the
        <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, its corresponding fragment of text is highlighted in the
      editing area and the reverse is also true. For example, when you place the cursor inside an
      area of text marked as inserted, its corresponding edit is selected in the list.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Review View</title>
      <image href="../img/review-view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, go to <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Review_Panel.html" format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
    <section><title>Activating the Review View</title>To activate the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
      view, do one of the following:<ul>
        <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ManageReviews16.png" id="image_ftz_hlf_wr"
            />Manage reviews</uicontrol> button on the toolbar.</li>
        <li>Right-click anywhere in a document and select <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Manage reviews</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</li>
        <li>Open it from the <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol> Show View</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> menu.</li>
      </ul></section>
    <section><title>Review View Settings</title>The upper part of the view contains a filtering area
      that allows you to search for specific edits. Use the small arrow symbol from the right side
      of the search field to display the search history.<p>The <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/Settings16.png"/>Settings</uicontrol> menu includes the following
        options:</p><ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Show highlights</uicontrol> - Controls whether or not the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the highlighting in your document.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show comments</uicontrol> - Controls whether or not the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the comments in the document you are
          editing.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show track changes</uicontrol> - Controls whether or not the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the inserted and deleted content in your
          document.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show review time</uicontrol> - Displays the time when the edits from the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view were made.</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Options16.png"/>Configure review options</uicontrol> -
        </li>
      </ul></section>
    <section><title>Hover Actions in the Review View</title>You can use this view to easily manage
      changes, highlights, and comments that have been added by you or other users. The following
      actions are available when you hover over the changes in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Available for highlights and comments presented in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
            view and it removes the particular highlight or comment from your document and moves to
            the next change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Accept</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Available for inserted and deleted content presented in the
              <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view and it accepts the particular change in your
            document and moves to the next change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Reject</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Available for inserted and deleted content presented in the
              <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view and it rejects the particular change in your
            document and moves to the next change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
    <section><title>Contextual Menu Actions in the Review View</title>Depending on the type of an
      edit, the following additional actions are available in the contextual menu of the
        <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Show comment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Available for comments added by other users and you can use this option to view it in
            a <uicontrol>Show comment</uicontrol> dialog box.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Edit comment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Available for comments you have added and you can use this action to edit a
            comment.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove comment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action to remove the selected comment.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Show only reviews by</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action to only keep the edits of a certain author visible in the view.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove all comments</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action to remove all the comments that appear in the edited document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Change color</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Available for highlights and it opens a palette that allows you to choose a new color
            for the highlighted content.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove highlight</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action to remove the selected highlight.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove highlights with the same color</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action to remove all the highlights with the same color from the entire
            document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Remove all highlights</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Use this action to remove all the highlights in your document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Accept change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Accepts the selected change and moves to the next change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Reject change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Rejects the selected change and moves to the next change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Comment change</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Available for insertions or deletions and you can use this option to add a comment for
            the particular change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Accept all changes</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Accepts all the changes made to a document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Reject all changes</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Rejects all the changes made to a document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="author-managing-changes.dita#author-managing-changes"/>
    <link href="author-managing-comments.dita#author-managing-comments"/>
    <link href="text-highlight.dita#text-highlight"/>
    <link href="author-callouts.dita#author-callouts"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
