<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="review-view">
  <title>Review View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Review tools<indexterm>Review
            view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Review
                tools<indexterm>Review view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Review view in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view is an independent panel, available both for built-in
      and custom XML document <xref keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>frameworks</term></xref>. It
      is designed to offer an enhanced way of monitoring all the changes that you make to a
      document. This means you can view and manage highlights, comments, and <xref
        keyref="glossentry_track-changes"><term>tracked changes</term></xref> using a single
      view.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view is useful when you are working with documents that
      contain large number of edits. The edits are presented in a compact form, in the order they
      appear in the document. Each type of edit is marked with a specific icon. This view and the
      editing area are synchronized. When you select an edit listed in the
        <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, its corresponding fragment of text is highlighted in the
      editing area and the reverse is also true. For example, when you place the cursor inside an
      area of text marked as inserted, its corresponding edit is selected in the list.</p>
    <p>You can use this view to quickly navigate through changes and it includes some useful hover
      actions and contextual menu actions to help you manage changes, comments, and highlights. You
      can also search for specific changes or comments and it includes some filtering options (for
      example, you can filter it to only show certain types of edits or to only show edits for a
      particular author).</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Review View</title>
        <image href="../img/review-view.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, go to <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/Review_Panel.html" format="html" scope="external"
      />.</p>
    <section id="activating_the_review_view">
      <title>Activating the Review View</title>
      <p>To activate the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view, do one of the following:<ul>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ManageReviews20.png"/>Manage
              reviews</uicontrol> button on the toolbar.</li>
          <li>Right-click anywhere in a document and select <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Manage reviews</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</li>
          <li>Open it from the <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> menu.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="review_view_settings">
      <title>Review View Settings</title>
      <p>The upper part of the view contains a filtering area that allows you to search for specific
        edits. Use the small arrow symbol from the right side of the search field to display the
        search history.</p>
      <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/Settings16.png"/>Settings</uicontrol> menu includes the
        following options:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Show highlights</uicontrol> - Controls whether or not the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the highlighting in your document.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show comments</uicontrol> - Controls whether or not the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the comments in the document you are
          editing.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show track changes</uicontrol> - Controls whether or not the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view displays the inserted and deleted content in your
          document.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show review time</uicontrol> - Displays the time when the edits from the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view were made.</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Options16.png"/>Configure review options</uicontrol> -
          Opens the <xref keyref="options_track-changes"><uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> preferences
            page</xref> where you can configure various options for review information.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="hover_actions_in_the_review_view">
      <title>Hover Actions in the Review View</title>
      <p>You can use this view to easily manage changes, highlights, and comments that have been
        added by you or other users. The following actions are available when you hover over the
        changes in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available for highlights and comments presented in the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol>
              view and it removes the particular highlight or comment from your document and moves
              to the next change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Accept</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available for inserted and deleted content presented in the
                <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view and it accepts the particular change in your
              document and moves to the next change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Reject</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available for inserted and deleted content presented in the
                <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view and it rejects the particular change in your
              document and moves to the next change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="contextual_menu_actions_in_the_review_view">
      <title>Contextual Menu Actions in the Review View</title>
      <p>Depending on the type of an edit, the following additional actions are available in the
        contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Reply</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Reply</uicontrol> dialog box where you can add a reply to
              comment or change. The replies are displayed with an indentation in this view.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Mark as Done</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>This toggles the comment or change as being done and grays it out. You can mark a
              whole discussion thread as being done by selecting the action on the first (parent)
              comment in the thread.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/EditComment16.png"/>Show Comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available for comments added by other users and you can use this option to view it
              in a <uicontrol>Show comment</uicontrol> dialog box.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/EditComment16.png"/>Edit Comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available for comments you have added and you can use this action to edit a
              comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveComment16.png"/>Remove Comment</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use this action to remove the selected comment.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Show only Reviews by '&lt;author name>'</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use this action to filter the edits to only show them for a certain author.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Remove All Comments</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use this action to remove all the comments that appear in the edited document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Change Color</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available for highlights and it opens a palette that allows you to choose a new
              color for the highlighted content.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Remove Highlight</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use this action to remove the selected highlight.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Remove Highlights with the Same Color</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use this action to remove all the highlights with the same color from the entire
              document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Remove All Highlights</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Use this action to remove all the highlights in your document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/AcceptChange16.png" placement="inline"/>Accept
                Change</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Accepts the selected change and moves to the next change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RejectChange16.png" placement="inline"/>Reject
                change</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Rejects the selected change and moves to the next change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/AddComment16.png"/>Comment change</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Available for insertions or deletions and you can use this option to add a comment
              for the particular change.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/AcceptAll16.png"/>Accept all changes</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Accepts all the changes in the current document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RejectAll16.png"/>Reject all changes</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Rejects all the changes in the current document.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="author-managing-changes.dita#author-managing-changes"/>
      <link href="author-managing-comments.dita#author-managing-comments"/>
      <link href="text-highlight.dita#text-highlight"/>
      <link href="author-callouts.dita#author-callouts"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
