<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="rng-editor-search-references-and-declarations">
  <title>Searching and Refactoring Actions</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing Relax NG Schemas<indexterm>searching and refactoring
          actions</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The following actions can be applied on <codeph>ref</codeph> and <codeph>parentRef</codeph>
      parameters and are available from the contextual menu of the current editor or from the
        <menucascade product="developer editor">
        <uicontrol>Document</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>References</uicontrol>
      </menucascade><uicontrol product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">RNG</uicontrol> menu:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SearchReferences16.png" id="image_ltl_bkq_2r"/>Search
          References</uicontrol> - Searches all references of the item found at current cursor
        position in the defined scope, if any. If a scope is defined, but the current edited
        resource is not part of the range of resources determined by this scope, a warning dialog is
        shown and you can define another search scope. A search scope includes the project or a
        collection of files and folders. You can choose to automatically use the defined scope for
        future operations by checking the corresponding checkbox.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Search References in...</uicontrol> - Searches all references of the item found
        at current cursor position in the file or files specified in the defined scope.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The following actions can be applied on named <codeph>define</codeph> parameters only.</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SearchDeclarations16.png" id="image_yjk_4kq_2r"/>Search
          Declarations</uicontrol> - Searches all declarations of the item found at current cursor
        position in the defined scope if any. If a scope is defined, but the current edited resource
        is not part of the range of resources determined by this scope a warning dialog is shown and
        you can define another search scope. A search scope includes the project or a collection of
        files and folders.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Search Declarations in...</uicontrol> - Searches all declarations of the item
        found at current cursor position in the files specified in the search scope.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Search Occurrences in File</uicontrol> - Searches all occurrences of the item
        at the caret position in the currently edited file.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Rename Component in...</uicontrol> - Renames the selected component.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
