<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="running-docbook-transformation-webhelp-plugin">
  <title>Running a DocBook Transformation Using the WebHelp Plugin</title>
  <body>
    <p>To run a DocBook to WebHelp (<uicontrol>webhelp</uicontrol>,
        <uicontrol>webhelp-feedback</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>webhelp-mobile)</uicontrol>
      transformation using the Oxygen WebHelp plugin, use:<ul>
        <li>the <filepath>docbook.bat</filepath> script file for Windows based systems;</li>
        <li>the <filepath>docbook.sh</filepath> script file for Unix/Linux based systems.<note>You
            can call these files in an automated process or from the command line. </note></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The <filepath>docbook.bat</filepath> and the <filepath>docbook.sh</filepath> files are
      located in the home directory of the Oxygen WebHelp Plugin. Before using them to generate an
      WebHelp system, customize them to match the paths to the JVM, DocBook XSL distribution and
      Saxon engine, and also to set the transformation type. To do this, open a script file and edit
      the following variables:<ul>
        <li><codeph>JVM_INSTALL_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the Java Virtual Machine
          installation directory on your disk;</li>
        <li><codeph>ANT_INSTALL_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the installation directory of
          ANT;</li>
        <li><codeph>SAXON_6_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the installation directory of Saxon
          6.5.5;</li>
        <li><codeph>SAXON_9_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the installation directory of Saxon
          9.1.0.8;</li>
        <li><codeph>DOCBOOK_XSL_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the installation directory of
          the DocBook XSL distribution;</li>
        <li><codeph>TRANSTYPE</codeph> - specifies the type of the transformation you want to
          execute. You can set it to <codeph>webhelp</codeph>, <codeph>webhelp-feedback</codeph> and
            <codeph>webhelp-mobile</codeph>;</li>
        <li><codeph>INPUT_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the input directory, containing the
          input XML file;</li>
        <li><codeph>XML_INPUT_FILE</codeph> - specifies the name of the input XML file;</li>
        <li><codeph>OUTPUT_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the output directory where the
          transformation output is generated;</li>
        <li><codeph>DOCBOOK_XSL_DIR_URL</codeph> - specifies the path to the directory of the
          DocBook XSL distribution in URL format.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
