<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_jpp_tmd_ml">
  <title>Running a DITA Transformation Using the WebHelp Plugin</title>
  <body>
    <p>To run a DITA to WebHelp (<uicontrol>webhelp</uicontrol>,
        <uicontrol>webhelp-feedback</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>webhelp-mobile)</uicontrol>
      transformation using the Oxygen WebHelp plugin, use:<ul>
        <li>the <filepath>dita.bat</filepath> script file for Windows based systems;</li>
        <li>the <filepath>dita.sh</filepath> script file for Unix/Linux based systems.<note>You can
            call these files in an automated process or from the command line. </note></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The <filepath>dita.bat</filepath> and the <filepath>dita.sh</filepath> files are located in
      the home directory of the Oxygen WebHelp Plugin. Before using them to generate an WebHelp
      system, customize them to match the paths to the JVM, DITA Open Toolkit and Saxon engine, and
      also to set the transformation type. To do this, open a script file and edit the following variables:<ul>
        <li><codeph>JVM_INSTALL_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the Java Virtual Machine
          installation directory on your disk;</li>
        <li><codeph>DITA_OT_INSTALL_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to DITA Open Toolkit
          installation directory on your disk;</li>
        <li><codeph>SAXON_9_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the directory on your disk where
          you unzipped the Saxon 9 archive files;</li>
        <li><codeph>TRANSTYPE</codeph> - specifies the type of the transformation you want to
          execute. You can set it to <codeph>webhelp</codeph>, <codeph>webhelp-feedback</codeph> and
            <codeph>webhelp-mobile</codeph>;</li>
        <li><codeph>DITA_MAP_BASE_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the directory where the input
          DITA Map file is located;</li>
        <li><codeph>DITAMAP_FILE</codeph> - specifies the input DITA Map file;</li>
        <li><codeph>DITAVAL_FILE</codeph> - specifies the <filepath>.ditaval</filepath> input filter
          that the transformation process applies to the input DITA Map file;</li>
        <li><codeph>DITAVAL_DIR</codeph> - specifies the path to the directory where the
            <filepath>.ditaval</filepath> file is located;</li>
        <li><codeph>Doutput.dir</codeph> - specifies the output directory of the
          transformation.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The <codeph>-Dargs.filter</codeph> and the <codeph>-Ddita.input.valfile</codeph> parameters
      are optional.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
