<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="sa-open-url-dialog">
  <title>The Open URL Dialog</title>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <ph><uicontrol>Open URL</uicontrol></ph>  dialog, go to<menucascade>
        <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Open URL ...</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> or click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_url.png"/>Open URL
        ...</uicontrol> toolbar button.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>Open URL Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_ftp_webdav.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The displayed dialog is composed of several parts:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>The <i>Identification</i> section contains the access credentials. To browse for a file
          on a server, you have to specify the user and password. This information is bound to the
          selected URL displayed in the <uicontrol>File URL</uicontrol> combo box, and used further
          in opening/saving the file. If the check box <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> is selected, then
          the user and password are saved between editing sessions. The password is kept encrypted
          in the options file.<note>
            <p>Your password is well protected. In the case the options file is used on other
              machine by a user with a different username the password will become unreadable, since
              the encryption is username dependent. This is also true if you add URLs having user
              and password to your project.</p>
          </note></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>In the server combo you can specify the protocol (HTTP, HTTPS or FTP) and the host name
          or IP of the server.<note type="tip">
            <p>Server URLs</p>
            <p>When you access a FTP server, you need to specify only the protocol and the host,
              like: ftp://server.com, or if using a nonstandard port: ftp://server.com:7800/.</p>
            <p>When you access a WebDAV server you must specify the path to the directory of the
              WebDAV repository  along with the protocol and the host name.<note type="important">
                <p>Make sure that the repository directory ends in a slash "/".</p>
              </note> Ex: https://www.some-webdav-server.com:443/webdav-repository/,
              http://devel:9090/webdav/</p>
            <p>When you access a SharePoint server you can also specify the path to a SharePoint
              site apart from the protocol a</p>
          </note></p>
        <p>By pressing the <uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol> button the directory listing will be shown
          in the component below. If the input URL points to a SharePoint server, a dedicated
          SharePoint browsing component is presented. When <uicontrol>Autoconnect</uicontrol> is
          selected, the browse action is performed every time when you open the dialog.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>The browser view:<ul>
            <li>In case you are browsing a WebDAV or FTP repository, the items are presented in a
              tree-like fashion. You can browse the directories, and make multiple selections.
              Additionally, you may use the <uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol>,
                <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>New Folder</uicontrol> actions to
              manage the file repository.<note>The file names are sorted in a case-insensitive
                way.</note></li>
            <li>
              <p>When you browse a SharePoint repository, a specialized component is presented
                instead of the WebDAV/FTP tree.</p>
              <p>
                <fig>
                  <title>Browsing a SharePoint Repository</title>
                  <image href="../img/sharepoint-filter-big.png"/>
                </fig>
              </p>
              <p>The left side of the browsing component displays the SharePoint site structure in a
                tree like fashion organized in sites, libraries, and folders. The contextual menu of
                a folder allows you to create new folders, new documents, and rename and delete the
                folder. The rename and delete actions are not available for library root folders
                (folders located at first level in a SharePoint library). </p>
              <p>The content of a folder selected in the tree is displayed in the right side table.
                The table columns are defined in the default view of the parent library. The rename
                and delete actions are available in the table view’s contextual menu both for
                documents and folders. You are able to check out, check in, and discard check out
                one or more documents at the same time. You can also filter and sort the displayed
                items. To display the available filters of a column, click the filter widget located
                on the column's header. You can apply multiple filters at the same time.<note>A
                  column can be filtered or sorted only if it was configured this way on the server
                  side.</note></p>
            </li>
          </ul></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>The editable combo box, in which it can be specified directly the URL to be opened or
          saved. <note type="tip">
            <p>You can type in here an URL like <filepath>http://some.site/test.xml</filepath>, in
              case the file is accessible through normal HTTP protocol, or
                <filepath>ftp://anonymous@some.site/home/test.xml</filepath> if the file is
              accessible through anonymous FTP.</p>
          </note>This combo box is also displaying the current selection when the user changes
          selection by browsing the tree of folders and files on the server.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
