<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="save-template-as">
    <title>Template Package Configuration Dialog Box</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Save template as button</indexterm>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Responsive Templates tab<indexterm>Save template as
          button</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>The <uicontrol>Save template as</uicontrol> button (at the bottom-left of the
      transformation dialog box for <b>WebHelp Responsive</b> transformations) can be used to export
      the currently selected template into a new template package that can be used as a starting
      point to <xref href="whr-create-publishing-template.dita#whr-create-publishing-template"
        >create your own custom template</xref>. The result will be a ZIP archive that contains a
        <xref href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#template_descritpor_file">template
        descriptor file</xref> and other resources (such as CSS files) that were attached to the
      selected template.</p>
    <p>Clicking the <uicontrol>Save template as</uicontrol> button opens a template package
      configuration dialog box contains the following options and components:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Name</dt>
          <dd>Required field used to specify the name for the new template. This will become the
            text value of the <codeph>name</codeph> element in the <xref
              href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#template_descritpor_file">template
              descriptor file</xref>. This information is displayed as the name of the template in
            the transformation scenario dialog box. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Description</dt>
          <dd>Optional field used to specify a template description. This will become the text value
            of the <codeph>description</codeph> element in the <xref
              href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#template_descritpor_file">template
              descriptor file</xref>. This information is displayed when the user hovers over the
            template in the transformation scenario dialog box.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Parameter Table</dt>
          <dd>This table displays the parameters that will be exported. Only relevant parameters are
            exported. The parameters and their values will be inserted in the <xref
              href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#transformation_parameters"
                ><codeph>parameters</codeph> section of the template descriptor file</xref>. If any
            of the parameter values point to a file path that references a template resource (such
            as CSS files, custom HTML fragments, images), those resources will automatically be
            copied to the new template package and their references will be changed
              accordingly.<note>Additional resources that are referenced in CSS files, HTML
              fragments, or other resources will not be copied to the new template package, so you
              will need to copy them manually and update their references in the <xref
                href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#template_descritpor_file">template
                descriptor file</xref>.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Include HTML Page Layout Files</dt>
          <dd>Select this option if you want to copy the default <xref
              href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#html_page_templates"><i>HTML Page Layout
                Files</i></xref> into your template package. They are helpful if you want to change
            the structure of the generated HTML pages.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Save as</dt>
          <dd>Use this field to specify the name and path of the ZIP file where the template will be
            saved.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Template Package Configuration Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/Save_template_as_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    </body>
</topic>
