<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="save-template-as">
  <title>Template Package Configuration Dialog Box</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Save template as button</indexterm>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Responsive Templates tab<indexterm>Save template as
          button</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_hsl_cgk_54b">The <uicontrol>Save template as</uicontrol> button (at the bottom-left of the transformation
      dialog box for <b>WebHelp Responsive</b> or <uicontrol>PDF - based on HTML5 &amp;
        CSS</uicontrol> transformations) can be used to export the currently selected template into
      a new template package that can be used as a starting point to <xref
        href="ope-create-publishing-template.dita#whr-create-publishing-template">create your own
        custom template</xref>. The result will be a ZIP archive that contains a template descriptor
      file and other resources (such as CSS files) that were attached to the selected template.</p>
    <p id="p_isl_cgk_54b">Clicking the <uicontrol>Save template as</uicontrol> button opens a template package
      configuration dialog box contains the following options and components:<dl id="dl_jsl_cgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ksl_cgk_54b">
          <dt>Name</dt>
          <dd>Required field used to specify the name for the new template. This will become the
            text value of the <xmlelement>name</xmlelement> element in the template descriptor file. This
            information is displayed as the name of the template in the transformation scenario
            dialog box. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_lsl_cgk_54b">
          <dt>Description</dt>
          <dd>Optional field used to specify a template description. This will become the text value
            of the <xmlelement>description</xmlelement> element in the template descriptor file. This
            information is displayed when the user hovers over the template in the transformation
            scenario dialog box.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_msl_cgk_54b">
          <dt>Parameter Table</dt>
          <dd>This table displays the parameters that will be exported. Only certain relevant
            parameters are exported. The parameters and their values will be inserted in the
              <xmlelement>parameters</xmlelement> section of the template descriptor file. If any of
            the parameter values point to a file path that references a template resource (such as
            CSS files, custom HTML fragments, images), those resources will automatically be copied
            to the new template package and their references will be changed
              accordingly.<note id="note_nsl_cgk_54b">Additional resources that are referenced in CSS files or other
              resources will not be copied to the new template package, so you will need to copy
              them manually and update their references in the template descriptor file.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_osl_cgk_54b">
          <dt>Include WebHelp Customization</dt>
          <dd>
            <p id="p_psl_cgk_54b">The same publishing template package can contain both a WebHelp Responsive and PDF
              customization and you can use the same template in both types of transformations
                (<xref keyref="wh-responsive-output"><uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp
                  Responsive</uicontrol></xref> or <xref keyref="ditamap-pdf-css-html5"><b>DITA Map
                  to PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS</b></xref>). This option specifies that the
              custom template will include a WebHelp Responsive customization.</p>
            <p id="p_qsl_cgk_54b">
              <dl id="dl_rsl_cgk_54b">
                <dlentry id="dlentry_ssl_cgk_54b">
                  <dt>Include HTML Page Layout Files</dt>
                  <dd>For <b>WebHelp Responsive</b> customizations, select this option if you want
                    to copy the default <xref href="html_page_templates.dita"><i>HTML Page Layout
                        Files</i></xref> into your template package. They are helpful if you want to
                    change the structure of the generated HTML pages.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_tsl_cgk_54b">
          <dt>Include PDF Customization</dt>
          <dd>The same publishing template package can contain both a WebHelp Responsive and PDF
            customization and you can use the same template in both types of transformations (<xref
              keyref="wh-responsive-output"><uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp
              Responsive</uicontrol></xref> or <xref keyref="ditamap-pdf-css-html5"><b>DITA Map to
                PDF - based on HTML5 &amp; CSS</b></xref>). This option specifies that the custom
            template will include a PDF customization.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_usl_cgk_54b">
          <dt>Save as</dt>
          <dd>Use this field to specify the name and path of the ZIP file where the template will be
            saved.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p id="p_vsl_cgk_54b">
      <fig id="fig_wsl_cgk_54b">
        <title>Template Package Configuration Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/Save_template_as_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link keyref="wh-publishing-template"/>
      <link href="pdf_publishing_template_contents.dita"/>
      <link href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
