<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="scan-locks">
  <title>Scanning for Locks</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Working Copy Resources<indexterm>lock/unlock resources<indexterm>scanning for
              locks</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>When starting to work on a file that is not contextually mergeable (usually a binary file),
      it is better to verify if someone else is not already working on that file. You can do this in
      the <xref href="working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref> by
      selecting one or more resources, then right clicking on them and choosing the <uicontrol>Scan
        for Locks</uicontrol> action from the context menu.</p>
    <fig id="figure-svn-locked-items-dialog">
      <title>The locked items dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_svn_locked_items_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p><indexterm>SVN working copy resources<indexterm>lock / unlock resources<indexterm>locked
            items</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>The <uicontrol>Locked items</uicontrol> dialog
      contains a table with all the resources that were found locked on the repository. For each
      resource there are specified: resource path, state of the lock, owner of the lock, lock
      comment, creation and expiration date for the lock (if any).</p>
    <p>The state of the lock can be one of:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><image href="../img/SVNLockRemote10.png" id="image_nwz_251_tc"/> - shown when: <ul>
          <li>another user has locked the file in the repository;</li>
          <li>the file was locked by the same user from another working copy;</li>
          <li>the file was locked from the <uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><image href="../img/SVNLockLocal10.png" id="image_lnj_vv1_tc"/> - displayed after you have
        locked a file from the current working copy.</li>
      <li><image href="../img/SVNLockBroken10.png"/> - a file already locked from your working copy
        is no longer locked in the repository (it was unlocked by another user).</li>
      <li><image href="../img/SVNLockStolen10.png" id="image_j11_dw1_tc"/> - a file already locked
        from your working copy is being locked by another user. Now the owner of the file lock is
        the user who stole the lock from you.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>You can unlock a resource by selecting it and pressing the <uicontrol>Unlock</uicontrol>
      button.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="working-copy-view.dita#working-copy-view/wc_locks">
      <linktext>Working Copy Locks</linktext>
    </link>
    <link href="repository-view.dita#repository-view/repos_locks">
      <linktext>Repository Locks</linktext>
    </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>