<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="scenarios-view">
  <title><uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Transforming Documents<indexterm>Transformation Scenarios
          view</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You are able to manage the transformation scenarios easily, using the
        <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view. To open this view, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <fig product="editor author developer">
      <title class="- topic/title ">The Scenarios view</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_scenarios_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Scenarios view</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_scenarios_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The following options are available in the contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Transformation
        Scenarios</uicontrol> view:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ApplyStyleSheet16.png"/>Apply selected
          scenarios</uicontrol> - select this option to run the current transformation
        scenario;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_debug_scenario.png"/>Debug selected scenario</uicontrol>
        - select this option to switch to the <uicontrol>Debugger</uicontrol> perspective and
        initialize it with the parameters from the scenario: the XML input, the XSLT, or XQuery
        input, the transformation engine, the XSLT parameters;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png"/>Duplicate</uicontrol> - adds a new scenario to
        the list that is a duplicate of the current scenario. It is useful for creating a scenario
        that is the same as an existing one but needs some changes;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_EditEntry16.png"/>Edit</uicontrol> - opens the dialog
        for editing the parameters of a transformation scenario;</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif"/>Remove</uicontrol> - removes the
        current scenario from the list. This action is also available on the
          <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> key;</li>
      <li product="author developer editor"><uicontrol>Change storage</uicontrol> - use this option
        to change the storage location of the selected scenario. You are also able to keep the
        original storage location and make a copy of the selected scenario in the target storage
        location;</li>
      <li><ph id="import-scenarios"><uicontrol><image href="../img/ImportScenario16.png"/>Import
            scenarios</uicontrol> - use this option to open the <uicontrol>Import
            scenarios</uicontrol> dialog. The <uicontrol>Import scenarios</uicontrol> dialog allows
          you to select which scenario of the <filepath>scenarios</filepath> file you want to
          import. In case one of the scenarios you import is identical with an existing scenario,
            <ph keyref="product"/> ignores the
          scenario you are importing. In case a conflict appears (an imported scenario has the same
          name with an existing one), you can choose between two options</ph>:<ul>
          <li>keep or replace the existing scenario;</li>
          <li>keep both scenarios.<note>When you keep both scenarios, <ph
                keyref="product"/> adds
                <filepath>imported</filepath> to the name of the imported scenario. </note></li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ExportScenario16.png"/>Export selected
          scenarios</uicontrol> - use this option to export transformation and validation scenarios
        individually. <ph keyref="product"/> creates
        a <filepath>scenarios</filepath> file which contains the scenarios you export; </li>
    </ul>
    <p>Apart from the options available in the contextual menu, the <uicontrol>Transformation
        Scenarios</uicontrol> view toolbar contains a <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/new_scenario.png"/>New</uicontrol> drop-down button. The menu of this drop
      down button contains a list of the scenarios you can create. <ph
        keyref="product"/> analyses which scenario is
      appropriate and displays it as the first item in the list of scenarios, separated by the rest
      through a horizontal line. </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/Settings16.png"/>Settings</uicontrol> drop-down menu of
      the <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view allows you to configure the following options:<ul>
        <li><ph id="show-all-scenarios"><uicontrol>Show all scenarios</uicontrol> - select this
            option to display all the available scenarios, regardless of the document they are
            associated with</ph>;</li>
        <li><ph id="scenarios-available-for-editor"><uicontrol>Show only the scenarios available for
              the editor</uicontrol> - select this option to display in the
              <uicontrol>Transformation scenarios</uicontrol> view only the scenarios which <ph
              keyref="product"/> can execute for the
            current document type</ph>;</li>
        <li><ph id="show-associated-scenarios"><uicontrol>Show associated scenarios</uicontrol> -
            select this option to display only the scenarios associated with the document you are
            editing</ph>; </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Change storage</uicontrol> - use this option to change the storage location
          of the selected scenario. You are also able to keep the original storage location and make
          a copy of the selected scenario in the target storage location;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ImportScenario16.png"/>Import scenarios</uicontrol> - use
          this option to open the <uicontrol>Import scenarios</uicontrol> dialog. The
            <uicontrol>Import scenarios</uicontrol> dialog allows you to select which scenario of
          the <filepath>scenarios</filepath> file you want to import. In case one of the scenarios
          you import is identical with an existing scenario, <ph
            keyref="product"/> ignores the scenario
          you are importing. In case a conflict appears (an imported scenario has the same name with
          an existing one), you can choose between two options:<ul>
            <li>keep or replace the existing scenario;</li>
            <li>keep both scenarios.<note>When you keep both scenarios, <ph
                  keyref="product"/> adds
                  <filepath>imported</filepath> to the name of the imported scenario.</note></li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><ph id="export-selected-scenarios"><uicontrol><image href="../img/ImportScenario16.png"
              />Export selected scenarios</uicontrol> - use this option to export transformation and
            validation scenarios individually. <ph
              keyref="product"/> creates a
              <filepath>scenarios</filepath> file which contains the scenarios you export</ph>; </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show Type</uicontrol> - use this option to display the transformation type of
          each scenario in the  <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Show Storage</uicontrol> - use this option to display the storage location of
          the scenarios in the <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view;</li>
        <li>
          <ph id="group-by-association"><uicontrol>Group by Association</uicontrol> - select this
            option to group the scenarios in the <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol>
            view depending on whether they are associated or not with the document you are
            editing;</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="group-by-type"><uicontrol>Group by Type</uicontrol> - select this option to
            group the scenarios in the <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view by their
            type;</ph></li>
        <li><ph id="group-by-storage"><uicontrol>Group by Storage</uicontrol> - select this option
            to group the scenarios in the <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view by
            their storage location;</ph></li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Flat16.png"/>Ungroup all</uicontrol> - select this option
          to ungroup all the scenarios of the <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol>
          view;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Reset Layout</uicontrol> - select this option to restore the default settings
          of the layout of the <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view. </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> supports multiple
      scenarios association. To associate multiple scenarios with a document, enable the check-boxes
      in front of each scenario. You can also associate multiple scenarios with a document from the
        <uicontrol>Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Configure
        Validation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> dialogs. </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> presents both global scenarios and
      project scenarios. By default, <ph
        keyref="product"/> presents the items in the
        <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> in the following order: scenarios matching
      the current framework, scenarios matching the current project, scenarios matching other
      frameworks. You can group the scenarios depending on the columns in the
        <uicontrol>Transformation Scenarios</uicontrol> view. Right click the name of a column to
      choose how to group the scenarios. The following grouping options are available:<ul>
        <li product="author developer editor"><ph conref="#scenarios-view/group-by-association"
          /></li>
        <li><ph conref="#scenarios-view/group-by-type"/></li>
        <li><ph conref="#scenarios-view/group-by-storage"/></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
