<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="schema-1-1-support">
  <title>XML Schema 1.1</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XML Schemas <indexterm>XML Schema 1.1 support</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> offers full support for XML Schema 1.1, including:<ul>
        <li>XML Documents Validation and Content Completion Based on XML Schema 1.1.</li>
        <li>XML Schema 1.1 Validation and Content Completion.</li>
        <li>Editing XML Schema 1.1 files in the Schema <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol> mode.</li>
        <li>The Flatten Schema action.</li>
        <li>Resource Hierarchy/Dependencies and Refactoring Actions.</li>
        <li>Master Files.</li>
        <li>Generating Documentation for XML Schema 1.1.</li>
        <li>Support for generating XML instances based on XML Schema.</li>
        <li>Support for validating XML documents with an NVDL schema that contains an XML Schema 1.1
          validation step.<note>To enable XML Schema 1.1 validation in NVDL, you need to pass the
            following option to the validation engine to specify the schema version:
              <codeph>http://www.thaiopensource.com/validate/xsd-version</codeph> (the possible
            values are <codeph>1.0</codeph> or <codeph>1.1</codeph>.</note><note type="tip">To
            enable the full XPath expression in assertions and type alternatives, you need to set
            the <codeph>http://www.thaiopensource.com/validate/full-xpath</codeph>
          option.</note></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p> XML Schema 1.1 is a superset of XML Schema 1.0, that offers lots of new powerful
      capabilities.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>XML Schema 1.1</title>
        <image href="../img/Schema11.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The significant new features in XSD 1.1 are:<ul>
        <li><b>Assertions</b> - Support to define assertions against the document content using
          XPath 2.0 expressions (an idea borrowed from Schematron).</li>
        <li><b>Conditional type assignment</b> - The ability to select the type of schema an element
          is validated against, based on the values of the attribute of the element.</li>
      <li><b>Open content</b> - Content models can use the <codeph>openContent</codeph> element to
          specify content models with <term>open content</term>. These content models allow elements
          not explicitly mentioned in the content model to appear in the document instance. It is as
          if wildcards were automatically inserted at appropriate points within the content model. A
          default may be set that causes all content models to be open unless specified otherwise. </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To see the complete list with changes since version 1.0, go to <xref
        href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema11-1/#ch_specs" format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
    <p>XML Schema 1.1 is intended to be mostly compatible with XML Schema 1.0 and to have
      approximately the same scope. It also addresses bug fixes and brings improvements that are
      consistent with the constraints on scope and compatibility.<note type="note">An XML document
        conforming to a 1.0 schema can be validated using a 1.1 validator, but an XML document
        conforming to a 1.1 schema may not validate using a 1.0 validator.</note>If you are
      constrained to use XML Schema 1.0 (for example, if you develop schemas for a server that uses
      an XML Schema 1.0 validator that cannot be updated), change the default XML Schema version to
      1.0. If you keep the default XML Schema version set to 1.1, the <xref
        keyref="glossentry_content-completion-assistant"><term>Content Completion
        Assistant</term></xref> presents XML Schema 1.1 elements that you can insert accidentally in
      an 1.0 XML Schema. So even if you make a document invalid conforming with XML Schema 1.0, the
      validation process does not signal any issues.</p>
    <p>To change the default XML Schema version, <ph
        conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol> XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> XML Parser</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> XML Schema</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the XML Schema 1.1 support, go to <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/XML_Schema_11.html" format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="set-xml-schema-version.dita#set-xml-schema-version"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
