<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="schematron-preferences-page">
  <title>Schematron Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p>To configure the <uicontrol>Schematron</uicontrol> options, <ph
				conkeyref="reusable.menus/open-the-preferences-page"/> and go to <menucascade>
				<uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
				<uicontrol>XML Parser</uicontrol>
				<uicontrol> Schematron</uicontrol>
			</menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in this preferences page:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Schematron XPath Version</uicontrol> - Selects the version of XPath for the
        expressions that are allowed in Schematron assertion tests: 1.0 or 2.0. This option is
        applied in both standalone Schematron schemas and in embedded Schematron rules, for
        Schematron 1.5.<note>To control the XPath version for ISO Schematron, you need to set the
          query language to be used with a <codeph>queryBinding</codeph> attribute on the schema
          root element.</note></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Optimize (visit-no-attributes)</uicontrol> - If your ISO Schematron assertion
        tests do not contain the attributes axis, you should check this option for faster ISO
        Schematron validation.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Allow foreign elements (allow-foreign)</uicontrol> - Enables support for
          <codeph>allow-foreign</codeph> on ISO Schematron. This option is used to pass
        non-Schematron elements to the generated stylesheet.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Use Saxon EE (schema aware) for xslt2 query binding</uicontrol> - When enabled,
        Saxon EE is used for <codeph>xslt2</codeph> query binding. If this option is disabled, Saxon
        PE is used.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Enable Schematron Quick Fixes (SQF) support</uicontrol> - Allows you to enable
        or disable the support for quick fixes in Schematron files. This option is enabled by
        default.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
