<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="send-changes">
  <title>Send Your Changes to the Repository</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Synchronize with the SVN repository<indexterm>Send changes to
              repository</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Sending the changes you made to your working copy is known as <i>committing</i> the changes.
      If your working copy is up-to-date and there are no conflicts, you are ready to commit your
      changes.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> action sends the changes from your local working copy to
      the repository. The <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> dialog box presents all the items that you
      can commit.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Commit dialog box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_svn_commit_dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>Enter a message to associate with the commit, or choose a previous message from the
        <uicontrol>Previous messages</uicontrol> list (the last 10 commit messages will be
      remembered even after restarting the SVN client application).</p>
    <p>An item that can be committed has one of the following states: <i>added</i>, <i>modified</i>
      (content or properties), <i>replaced</i>, and <i>deleted</i>. All items that have one of these
      states are selected in the dialog box by default. If you do not want to commit one of the
      items, deselect it.</p>
    <note type="attention" id="svn1_8_commit_moved_renamed_items">For SVN 1.8 working copies: when
      committing items that were moved and/or renamed, make sure you select both the source and the
      destination. Otherwise, the commit operation will fail.</note>
    <p>Besides the items that have one of the mentioned states, Syncro SVN Client also includes the
      files being <i>unversioned</i> or <i>missing</i> and these items are handled automatically:<ul>
        <li><i>Unversioned</i> items are added under version control.</li>
        <li><i>Missing</i> items are deleted.</li>
      </ul><note>If the <uicontrol>Show unversioned directories content</uicontrol> option is not
        selected, the <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> dialog box does not display the items inside an
          <i>unversioned</i>directory.</note></p>
    <p><i>Unversioned</i> or <i>missing</i> items are not selected by default in the
        <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> dialog box, unless you have selected them explicitly when
      issuing the commit command.</p>
    <note>In some cases, items that have one of the above states are not presented in the
        <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> dialog box.<p>For example:<ul>
          <li>Items that have been <i>added</i> or <i>replaced</i> previously, but now are presented
            as <i>missing</i> after being removed from the file system, outside of an SVN client.
            Such items do not exist in the repository and you should use the
              <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> action to remove them from your working copy.</li>
          <li>Items that have incoming changes from the repository, after a synchronization. You
            need to have your working copy up-to-date before committing your changes.</li>
          <li>Files that, after a synchronization, appear as locked by other users or from other
            locations than the current working copy.</li>
        </ul></p></note>
    <note>Due to dependencies between items, when you select or clear an <i>unversioned</i> ( <image
        href="../img/SVNWCUnversioned10.png" id="image_qh3_wy5_5r"/> ) or <i>added</i> ( <image
        href="../img/SVNWCAdded10.png" id="image_ejc_sjp_5r"/> ) item in the
        <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> dialog box, other items with one of these states can be
      selected or cleared automatically. </note>
    <p>The modifications that will be committed for each file can be reviewed in the compare editor
      window by double clicking a file in the <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> dialog box, or by right
      clicking and selecting the <uicontrol>Show Modifications</uicontrol> action from the
      contextual menu. This option is available to review only file content changes, not property
      changes.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNLocalContentStatusColumnHeader.png"/> Local file
        status</uicontrol> column indicates the actual state of the items and the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/SVNLocalPropertiesStatusColumnHeader.png"/> Local properties
        status</uicontrol> column indicates whether or not the properties of an item are
      modified.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNLockColumnHeader.gif" id="image_pkh_4r1_tc"/> Lock
        information</uicontrol> column is displayed if at least one of the files in the
        <uicontrol>Commit</uicontrol> dialog box has lock information associated with it, valid
      against the commit operation.</p>
    <p>The following options are available in this dialog box:<ul>
        <li>
          <p id="enable-auto-properties"><uicontrol>Enable automatic properties</uicontrol> or
              <uicontrol>Disable automatic properties</uicontrol> - enables or disables automatic
            property assignment (per runtime configuration rules), overriding the
              <codeph>enable-auto-props</codeph> runtime configuration directive, defined in the
              <codeph>config</codeph> file of the Subversion configuration directory.<note>This
              option is available only when there are defined properties to be applied automatically
              for resources newly added under version control. You can define these properties in
              the <codeph>config</codeph> file of the Subversion configuration directory, in the
                <codeph>auto-props</codeph> section. Based on the value of the
                <codeph>enable-auto-props</codeph> runtime configuration directive, the presented
              option is either <uicontrol>Enable automatic properties</uicontrol>, or
                <uicontrol>Disable automatic properties</uicontrol>.</note></p>
        </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Keep locks</uicontrol> - selecting the <uicontrol>Keep locks</uicontrol>
          option preserves any locks you set on various files.<note>This option is available only
            when files that you locked are presented in the dialog box.</note></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>Each of the above options is activated only when you select an item for which the option can
      be applied.</p>
    <p>Your working copy must be up-to-date with respect to the resources you commit. This is
      ensured by using the <uicontrol>Update</uicontrol> action prior to committing, resolving
      conflicts and re-testing as needed. If your working copy resources you are trying to commit
      are out of date you will get an appropriate error message.</p>
  </body>
</topic>