<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="servlet-report-page">
    <title>Floating License Server Management and Statistics Pages</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Installing Oxygen<indexterm>HTTP floating license server<indexterm>Management and
              Statistics</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p>A system administrator can manage and access information about the floating license server
      at: <codeph>http://hostName:port/oXygenLicenseServlet</codeph>.</p>
    <p>This page provides access to several statistics reports and management tasks. It also shows
      the current status of the server and provides additional instructions for using the license
      server with <ph keyref="product"/>.</p>
    <p>This page includes the following links for accessing statistics or managing tasks:<ul>
        <li><b>Current Allocated Licenses</b> - Opens the <xref
            href="#servlet-report-page/allocated_license_report_page" format="dita">Allocated
            License Report page</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>Usage Statistics</b> - Opens the <xref
            href="#servlet-report-page/floating_license_usage_statistics_page" format="dita"
            >Floating License Usage Statistics page</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>View License Key</b> - Use this link to view details about the license key.</li>
        <li><b>Replace License Key</b> - Use this link if you need to <xref
            href="replace-floating-license.dita#replace-floating-license">replace a license
            key</xref>.</li>
        <li><b>Configuration</b> - Opens a page where you can configure notification settings and
          specify whether or not users are allowed to lock licenses. This page can be used for
          setting up the mail server used for sending rejection emails.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="allocated_license_report_page">
      <title>Allocated License Report Page</title>
      <p>This report page provides a system administrator the ability to revoke or unlock current
        running instances of licenses and includes the following information:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol>License load</uicontrol> - A graphical indicator that shows how many
            licenses are available.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Floating license server status</uicontrol> - General information about the
            license server status, such as start time, license counts, rejected and acknowledged
            requests, average usage time, license refresh and timeout intervals, location of the
            license key, and the server version.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Current running instances</uicontrol> - Lists all currently acknowledged
            users, including user name, date and time when the license was granted, IP and MAC
            address of the computer where <ph keyref="product"/> runs, and lock status.<ul>
              <li><b>Revoke</b> - A system administrator can click on the <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/RemoveAllRanges12.gif"/>Revoke</uicontrol> icon next to a user name
                to release that particular license and return it to the pool.</li>
              <li product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
                  ><b>Unlock</b> - If a user has locked their floating license, the system
                administrator can also unlock it from this page.</li>
            </ul></li>
        </ul></p>
      <note>This report is also available in XML format at:
          <codeph>http://hostName:port/oXygenLicenseServlet/license-servlet/report-xml</codeph>.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="floating_license_usage_statistics_page">
      <title>Floating License Usage Statistics Page</title>
      <p>This report page provides some usage statistics for the floating licenses. It is helpful
        for determining the number of licenses that are needed and monitoring times when licenses
        are consumed. It includes the following information:<ul>
          <li><b>Maximum number of concurrent licenses</b> - Shows the maximum number of floating
            licenses that can be consumed at any given time.</li>
          <li><b>Concurrent license consumption per day</b> - A chart that shows the peak number of
            licenses that were consumed and the total number of users that were rejected, on a daily
            basis. This chart can be used to detect the amount of concurrent licenses that are
            needed to avoid having rejected users.<note type="tip">You can click on any bar to see
              the license consumption per hour for that particular day.</note><p>
              <fig>
                <title>Concurrent License Consumption per Day Chart</title>
                <image href="../img/License_per_day.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p></li>
          <li><b>Concurrent license consumption per hour</b> - A chart that shows the peak number of
            licenses that were consumed per hour throughout that particular month. This is useful
            for identifying the time of day when the most licenses were consumed.<p>
              <fig>
                <title>Concurrent License Consumption per Hour Chart</title>
                <image href="../img/Licenses_per_hour.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
