<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="servlet-report-page">
  <title>License Server Management and Statistics Pages</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>HTTP license server<indexterm>Management and Statistics</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_ehn_bgk_54b">A system administrator can manage and access information about the license server at:
        <codeph>http://hostName:port/oXygenLicenseServlet</codeph>.</p>
    <p id="p_fhn_bgk_54b">This page provides access to several statistics reports and management
      tasks. It also displays the current status of the server and provides additional instructions
      for using the license server with <uicontrol>Oxygen XML
      Editor/Author/Developer</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p id="p_ghn_bgk_54b">This page includes the following links for accessing statistics or managing tasks:<ul id="ul_hhn_bgk_54b">
        <li id="li_ihn_bgk_54b"><b>Current Allocated Licenses</b> - Opens the <xref
            href="#servlet-report-page/allocated_license_report_page" format="dita"
              ><uicontrol>Allocated License Report</uicontrol> page</xref>.</li>
        <li id="li_jhn_bgk_54b"><b>Usage Statistics</b> (Available only for floating licenses) -
          Opens the <xref href="#servlet-report-page/floating_license_usage_statistics_page"
            format="dita"><uicontrol>License Usage Statistics</uicontrol> page</xref>.</li>
        <li id="li_khn_bgk_54b"><b>View License Key</b> - Use this link to open a page where you can
          see details about the license key.</li>
        <li id="li_lhn_bgk_54b"><b>Replace/Remove License Key</b> - Use this link if you need to <xref
            href="replace-floating-license.dita#replace-floating-license">replace or remove the
            current license key</xref>.</li>
        <li id="li_mhn_bgk_54b"><b>Configuration</b> - Opens a page where you can configure
          notification settings and set up the mail server used for sending emails whenever license
          requests from users are rejected. This page also contains a <uicontrol>Allow users to lock
            licenses</uicontrol> option. Enabling this option allows the users to <xref
            href="reserve-floating-license.dita">lock/reserve a floating license</xref>.</li>
        <li id="li_nhn_bgk_54b"><b>Users management</b> (Available only for named-user licenses) -
          Opens a page where you can manage the list of users who are entitled to use the license
          key.</li>
        <li id="li_ehf_dhc_v4b"><b>Allowed users list</b> (Available only for named-user licenses) -
          Opens a page where you can see the allowed users list (if one has already been
          configured), along with instructions for configuring one.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="allocated_license_report_page">
      <title>Allocated License Report Page</title>
      <p id="p_ohn_bgk_54b">This report page provides a system administrator the ability to revoke or unlock current
        running instances of licenses and includes the following information:<ul id="ul_phn_bgk_54b">
          <li id="li_qhn_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>License load</uicontrol> - A graphical indicator that shows how many
            licenses are available.</li>
          <li id="li_rhn_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>License server status</uicontrol> - General information about the license
            server status, such as start time, license counts, rejected and acknowledged requests,
            average usage time, license refresh and timeout intervals, location of the license key,
            and the server version.</li>
          <li id="li_shn_bgk_54b"><uicontrol>Current running instances</uicontrol> - Lists all
            currently acknowledged users, including user name, date and time when the license was
            granted, IP and MAC address of the computer where <uicontrol>Oxygen</uicontrol> runs,
            and lock status.<ul id="ul_thn_bgk_54b">
              <li id="li_uhn_bgk_54b"><b>Revoke</b> - A system administrator can click on the
                    <uicontrol><image href="../img/Remove16.png"/>Revoke</uicontrol> icon next to a
                user name to release that particular license and return it to the pool.</li>
              <li
                product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse license-server"
                id="unlock"><b>Unlock</b> - If a user has locked their license, the system
                administrator can also unlock it from this page.</li>
            </ul></li>
        </ul></p>
      <note id="note_vhn_bgk_54b">This report is also available in XML format at:
          <codeph>http://hostName:port/oXygenLicenseServlet/license-servlet/report-xml</codeph>.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="floating_license_usage_statistics_page">
      <title>License Usage Statistics Page (Floating License Only)</title>
      <p id="p_whn_bgk_54b">This report page provides some usage statistics for the floating licenses. It is helpful
        for determining the number of licenses that are needed and monitoring times when licenses
        are consumed. It includes the following information:<ul id="ul_xhn_bgk_54b">
          <li id="li_yhn_bgk_54b"><b>Maximum number of concurrent licenses</b> - Shows the maximum number of floating
            licenses that can be consumed at any given time.</li>
          <li id="li_zhn_bgk_54b">
            <p id="p_a3n_bgk_54b"><b>Concurrent license consumption per day</b> - A chart that shows the peak number of
              licenses that were consumed and the total number of users that were rejected, on a
              daily basis. This chart can be used to detect the amount of concurrent licenses that
              are needed to avoid having rejected users.<note type="tip" id="note_b3n_bgk_54b">You can click on any bar to
                see the license consumption per hour for that particular day.</note></p>
            <p id="p_c3n_bgk_54b">
              <fig id="fig_d3n_bgk_54b">
                <title>Concurrent License Consumption per Day Chart</title>
                <image href="../img/License_per_day.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
          </li>
          <li id="li_e3n_bgk_54b">
            <p id="p_f3n_bgk_54b"><b>Concurrent license consumption per hour</b> - A chart that shows the peak number
              of licenses that were consumed per hour throughout that particular month. This is
              useful for identifying the time of day when the most licenses were consumed.</p>
            <p id="p_g3n_bgk_54b">
              <fig id="fig_h3n_bgk_54b">
                <title>Concurrent License Consumption per Hour Chart</title>
                <image href="../img/Licenses_per_hour.png"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
          </li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="users_management_page">
      <title>Users Management Page (Named-User License Only)</title>
      <p id="p_i3n_bgk_54b">When a named-user license key is used, the license server allocates
        available licenses in the order they are requested until the maximum number is reached. Any
        additional users attempting to obtain a license key will be rejected.</p>
      <p id="p_j3n_bgk_54b">This page provides access to the list of registered users and allows the server admin to:<ul id="ul_k3n_bgk_54b">
          <li id="li_l3n_bgk_54b">Revoke a user's right to use a license.</li>
          <li id="li_m3n_bgk_54b">Reactivate a previously deactivated user.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p id="p_n3n_bgk_54b">
        <fig id="fig_o3n_bgk_54b">
          <title>Users List Management Page</title>
          <image href="../img/LicenseServerUsersManagement.png" placement="inline"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
