<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="setting-a-default-schema">
  <title>Setting a Default Schema</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing XML Documents<indexterm>associate a schema to a
              document<indexterm>setting a default schema</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>When trying to detect a schema, <ph keyref="product"/> searches in multiple locations, in the
      exact following order:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>The <xref href="../concepts/validation-scenario.dita">validation scenario</xref>
        associated with the document.</li>
      <li>The validation scenario associated with the document type (if defined).</li>
      <li>The document schema declaration.<note product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"
          >If a DTD schema is specified in the document, the content completion for
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode is based on this schema (even if there is already one
          detected from the validation scenario).</note></li>
      <li>The document type schema definition. Each document type available in <ph
          conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/preferences-document-type-association"/> contains a
        set of rules for associating a schema with the current document.<note>The locations are
          sorted by priority, from high to low.</note></li>
    </ul>
    <p>The schema has one of the following types: XML Schema, XML Schema with embedded Schematron
      rules, Relax NG (XML syntax or compact syntax), Relax NG (XML syntax) with embedded Schematron
      rules, Schematron, DTD, NVDL.</p>
    <p>The rules are applied in the order they appear in the table and take into account the local
      name of the root element, the default namespace and the file name of the document.</p>
    <note type="important">
      <p>The editor is creating the content completion lists by analysing the specified schema and
        the current context (the position in the editor). If you change the schema, then the list of
        tags to be inserted is updated.</p>
      <p>
        <fig product="editor author developer">
          <title>Content Completion Driven by DocBook DTD</title>
          <image href="../img/sa_content_completion_docbook.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>
        <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
          <title>Content Completion Driven by DocBook DTD</title>
          <image href="../img/ec_content_completion_docbook.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </note>
  </body>
</topic>
