<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="sharing_tasks_with_reviewers">
  <title>Sharing Tasks</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Sharing tasks</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_tnt_dgk_54b">The task owner can share created tasks with reviewers by retrieving the
      link to the task and sending the link to the reviewers or by adding them as a collaborator on
      the task (in this case, an invitation email is sent to the collaborator). </p>
    <section id="section_khc_pd1_hmb">
      <title>Sharing a Task</title>
      <p id="p_xnt_dgk_54b">
        <ol id="ol_oyf_rd1_hmb">
          <li id="li_ynt_dgk_54b">Go to the Content Fusion browser interface and open the particular
            review task you want to share.</li>
          <li id="li_znt_dgk_54b">
            <p id="p_a4t_dgk_54b">Click the <uicontrol>Share</uicontrol> button located in the top
              stripe.</p>
            <p id="p_b4t_dgk_54b"><b>Step Result:</b> This opens the <uicontrol>Sharing
                settings</uicontrol> dialog box where you can retrieve the shareable link, decide
              who has access to the task, and add collaborators.</p>
            <p id="p_c4t_dgk_54b">
              <fig id="fig_pyf_rd1_hmb">
                <title>Sharing Settings Dialog Box</title>
                <image href="../img/cf_assign_owner.png" id="image_qyf_rd1_hmb"/>
              </fig>
            </p>
            <p id="p_a5x_tjg_zxb">This dialog box includes the following options:</p>
            <p id="p_tsb_vjg_zxb">
              <dl id="dl_usb_vjg_zxb">
                <dlentry id="dlentry_ctb_vjg_zxb">
                  <dt>Add collaborator field</dt>
                  <dd>To assign a collaborator to a task, start typing their name or email address
                    in the field at the top of the dialog box and the system will search for
                    assignable users that can be selected from a drop-down menu. Click the
                      <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> button to add them to the list. If the name/email
                    is not in the system, they will be listed as a <i>Pending Collaborator</i> until
                    they sign up for an account. An invitation email is automatically sent to the
                    specified email address or you can manually send them the link to access the
                    task (you can click the <uicontrol>Copy link</uicontrol> button to copy the link
                    to the clipboard).</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_wsb_vjg_zxb">
                  <dt>List of collaborators</dt>
                  <dd>The middle area of the dialog box displays the task owner along with anyone
                    who has been assigned to the task. Once a collaborator is no longer pending, the
                    task owner can use the drop-down menu on the right side to change the role for
                    the collaborator from <uicontrol>Reviewer</uicontrol> to
                      <uicontrol>Owner</uicontrol>, and vice versa. The drop-down menu also contains
                    a <uicontrol>Remove collaborator</uicontrol> button that the task owner can use
                    to remove a specific collaborator from the task.<note type="notice"
                      id="note_xsb_vjg_zxb">If the <uicontrol>Anyone who opens the link is
                        automatically granted access as a Reviewer</uicontrol> option is selected,
                      if a removed collaborator re-opens the task via its link, they will
                      automatically be re-added as a <b>Reviewer</b>. To prevent this, you can
                      simply deselect this option.</note></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_atb_vjg_zxb">
                  <dt>Anyone who opens the link is automatically granted access as a Reviewer</dt>
                  <dd><ph product="fusion">This option is available only if the <xref
                        href="cf-admin-page-general.dita#cf-admin-page-general/p_pf3_x1b_p2c"
                          ><uicontrol>Tasks can be shared publicly</uicontrol> toggle option</xref>
                      is selected in the Administration page. </ph>If this option is selected, then
                    anyone who accesses the link to the task is automatically granted access to the
                    task as a <b>Reviewer</b>.<note id="note_btb_vjg_zxb" product="fusion">If this
                      option is not selected and the <xref
                        href="cf-admin-page-general.dita#cf-admin-page-general/dlentry_sf3_x1b_p2c"
                          ><uicontrol>Tasks can only be accessed by specified
                          collaborators</uicontrol> toggle option</xref> is selected in the
                      Administration page, non-registered users attempting to access the task via
                      its link will receive a warning message indicating that they do not have
                      permission to access the task. They can request access by clicking the
                        <uicontrol>Request access</uicontrol> button that is displayed in that
                      warning message. This sends an email to the owner of the task and they have
                      the ability to accept the request for access and a link or button in the email
                      will direct the task owner to the <uicontrol>Sharing settings</uicontrol> page
                      with the requesting user's information already populated in the <uicontrol>Add
                        collaborator</uicontrol> field.</note></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="dlentry_vsb_vjg_zxb">
                  <dt>Copy link</dt>
                  <dd>You can click on the <uicontrol>Copy link</uicontrol> button at the bottom of
                    the dialog box to copy the link to the clipboard so that you can send it to
                    collaborators.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </li>
          <li id="li_d4t_dgk_54b">Click <uicontrol>Done</uicontrol> when you are finished
            configuring the share settings. If a collaborator was added, an invitation email is
            automatically sent to the specified email address (or you can manually send the task
            link to the reviewers using whatever method is appropriate in your work
            environment).</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_lv1_cd1_hmb">
      <title>Retrieving the Task Link Using the Content Fusion Task Manager</title>
      <p>It is possible to retrieve the task link directly within <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>
        but the person you send the link to must first be granted access to the task in the
          <uicontrol>Share</uicontrol> dialog box (in the browser).</p>
      <p id="p_unt_dgk_54b">
        <ol id="ol_bhn_nd1_hmb">
          <li id="li_bwv_x3g_zxb"><b>[Prerequisite]</b> Enable the <uicontrol>Anyone who opens the
              link is automatically granted access as a Reviewer</uicontrol> option in the
              <uicontrol>Share</uicontrol> dialog box.</li>
          <li id="li_vnt_dgk_54b">In the <uicontrol>Content Fusion Tasks Manager</uicontrol> view,
            right-click the particular task that you want to share and select <uicontrol>Copy task
              link</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li id="li_wnt_dgk_54b">Send the link to reviewers using whatever method is appropriate in
            your working environment.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
