<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="sharing-projects">
  <title>Sharing a Project - Team Collaboration</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Projects<indexterm>Sharing</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sharing project options file</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sharing Transformation Scenarios</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sharing Validation Scenarios</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can use XML projects to make team collaboration and synergy efficient and effective. Not
      only can you share the project files and folders, but <ph keyref="product"/> also allows you
      to store preferences, transformation scenarios, and validation scenarios at <xref
        keyref="glossentry_project-options">project level</xref> in a <term>project file</term>
        (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension). It can be saved on a version control system
      (such as SVN, CVS, or Source Safe) or in a shared folder, so that your team will have access
      to the same resources stored in the project file.</p>
    <section id="project-file-section">
      <title>Sharing Preferences (Creating a Project-Level Options File)</title>
      <p>To share options that are configured in certain preferences pages, you can store them in a
          <term>project file</term> (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension) that can easily be
        shared with others. To do so, follow these steps:<ol id="ul_bdf_d5t_zd">
          <li>You many want to use a fresh install for this procedure, to make sure that you do not
            copy personal or local preferences.</li>
          <li>In the <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref>, create a project or open an existing
            one.</li>
          <li><ph conkeyref="reusables-preferences-pages/Open-the-preferences-page"/>.</li>
          <li>Configure the options in each preferences page that you want to be included in the
            project file and switch the storage preference to <xref
              keyref="glossentry_project-options"><uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol></xref> in
            each page.<note>Some pages do not have the <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol>
              button, since the options they host might contain sensitive data (such as passwords,
              for example) that is unsuitable for sharing with other users.</note></li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> and close the <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
            dialog box.<p>All explicitly set values are now saved in the project file. You can then
              share the project file so that your team will have the same option configuration that
              you stored in the project file.<note
                conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/xpr-extension-note"/><note
                conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/security-note"/></p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="sharing_transformation_scenarios">
      <title>Sharing Transformation Scenarios </title>
      <p>To share created and edited transformation scenarios, you can store them in a <term>project
          file</term> (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension) by following these steps:<ol
          id="ol_lzq_pcq_gs">
          <li>In the <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref>, create a project or open an existing
            one.</li>
          <li>When you create a new transformation scenario or edit an existing one, there is a
              <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option. Switch the storage preference to <xref
              keyref="glossentry_project-options"><uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol></xref> in
            each transformation scenario you want to be included in the project file.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to store the scenario in the project file. <p>You can
              then share the project file so that your team will have access to the same
              transformation scenarios that you stored in the project file. When you create a
              scenario at the project level, the URLs from the scenario become relative to the
              project URL.<note conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/xpr-extension-note"/><note
                conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/security-note"/></p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="sharing_validation_scenarios">
      <title>Sharing Validation Scenarios</title>
      <p>To share created and edited validation scenarios, you can store them in a <term>project
          file</term> (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension) by following these steps:<ol
          id="ol_wzq_m2q_gs">
          <li>In the <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref>, create a project or open an existing
            one.</li>
          <li>When you create a new validation scenario or edit an existing one, there is a
              <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option. Switch the storage preference to <xref
              keyref="glossentry_project-options"><uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol></xref> in
            each validation scenario you want to be included in the project file.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to store the scenario in the project file. <p>You can
              then share the project file so that your team will have access to the same validation
              scenarios that you stored in the project file. When you create a scenario at the
              project level, the URLs from the scenario become relative to the project URL.<note
                conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/xpr-extension-note"/><note
                conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/security-note"/></p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="syncro_svn_client_">
      <title>Syncro SVN Client (<ph keyref="apacheSubversion"/>)</title>
      <p>To assist you with team collaboration and sharing projects, <ph keyref="product"/> includes
        an embedded <xref href="svn-quick-start.dita">SVN (Subversion) Client</xref>. Even if you
        start developing a new project, or you want to migrate an existing one to Subversion, the
          <ph keyref="svnProduct"/> allows you to easily share it with the rest of your team.</p>
      <p>It can be accessed from the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu and can be used for
        synchronizing your working copy with a central repository. </p>
      <p>It can also be started by selecting the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/SyncroSVNClient16.png" id="image_nsj_dhf_yr"/>Open in SVN
          Client</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu of the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol>
        view. This action opens the Syncro SVN Client and shows the selected project file in the
          <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="sharing-possibilities.dita#sharing-possibilities"/>
      <link href="transformation-scenarios-sharing.dita#transformation-scenarios-sharing"/>
      <link href="validation-scenarios-sharing.dita#validation-scenarios-sharing"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
