<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="sharing-projects">
  <title>Sharing a Project - Team Collaboration</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Projects<indexterm>Sharing</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sharing project options file</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sharing transformation scenarios</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sharing validation scenarios</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_bvt_bgk_54b">You can use XML projects to make team collaboration and synergy efficient
      and effective. Not only can you share the project files and folders, but <ph keyref="product"
      /> also allows you to store preferences, transformation scenarios, and validation scenarios at
        <xref keyref="glossentry_project-options">project level</xref> in a <term>project
        file</term> (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension). It can be saved on a version control
      system (such as SVN, CVS, or Source Safe) or in a shared folder, so that your team has access
      to the same resources stored in the project file.</p>
    <section id="project-file-section">
      <title>Sharing Preferences (Creating a Project-Level Options File)</title>
      <p id="p_cvt_bgk_54b">To share options that are configured in certain preferences pages, you can store them in a
          <term>project file</term> (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension) that can easily be
        shared with others. To do so, follow these steps:<ol id="ul_bdf_d5t_zd">
          <li id="li_dvt_bgk_54b">[Recommended] You may want to use a fresh install for this
            procedure to ensure that you do not copy personal or local preferences.</li>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/li_evt_bgk_54b" id="li_emn_kcd_dpb"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/li_fvt_bgk_54b" id="li_tj2_lcd_dpb"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/li_gvt_bgk_54b" id="li_tdx_lcd_dpb"/>
          <li conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/li_ivt_bgk_54b" id="li_ox2_ncd_dpb"/>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="sharing_transformation_scenarios">
      <title>Sharing Transformation Scenarios </title>
      <p id="p_nvt_bgk_54b">To share created and edited transformation scenarios, you can store them in a <term>project
          file</term> (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension) by following these steps:<ol
          id="ol_lzq_pcq_gs">
          <li id="li_ovt_bgk_54b">In the <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref>, create a project or open an existing
            one.</li>
          <li id="li_pvt_bgk_54b">When you <xref
              href="defining-new-transformation-scenario.dita#defining-new-transformation-scenario"
              >create a new transformation scenario</xref> or <xref
              href="edit-scenario-dialog.dita#edit-scenario-dialog">edit an existing one</xref>,
            there is a <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option. Switch the storage preference to <xref
              keyref="glossentry_project-options"><uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol></xref> in
            each transformation scenario you want to be included in the project file.</li>
          <li id="li_qvt_bgk_54b">
            <p id="p_rvt_bgk_54b">Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to store the scenario in the project file.</p>
            <p id="p_svt_bgk_54b">You can then share the project file so that your team will have
              access to the same transformation scenarios that you stored in the project file. When
              you create a scenario at the project level, the URLs from the scenario become relative
              to the project URL.<note conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/xpr-extension-note"
                id="note_tvt_bgk_54b"/><note conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/security-note"
                id="note_uvt_bgk_54b"/></p>
          </li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="sharing_validation_scenarios">
      <title>Sharing Validation Scenarios</title>
      <p id="p_vvt_bgk_54b">To share created and edited validation scenarios, you can store them in a <term>project
          file</term> (<filepath>.xpr</filepath> file extension) by following these steps:<ol
          id="ol_wzq_m2q_gs">
          <li id="li_wvt_bgk_54b">In the <xref href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view" format="dita"
                ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view</xref>, create a project or open an existing
            one.</li>
          <li id="li_xvt_bgk_54b">When you create a new validation scenario or edit an existing one,
            there is a <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option. Switch the storage preference to <xref
              keyref="glossentry_project-options"><uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol></xref> in
            each validation scenario you want to be included in the project file.</li>
          <li id="li_yvt_bgk_54b">
            <p id="p_zvt_bgk_54b">Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to store the scenario in the project file.</p>
            <p id="p_awt_bgk_54b">You can then share the project file so that your team will have
              access to the same validation scenarios that you stored in the project file. When you
              create a scenario at the project level, the URLs from the scenario become relative to
              the project URL.<note conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/xpr-extension-note"
                id="note_bwt_bgk_54b"/><note conkeyref="reusables-editing-documents/security-note"
                id="note_cwt_bgk_54b"/></p>
          </li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_ons_p4q_kpb">
      <title>Using Git for Collaboration</title>
      <p id="p_pns_p4q_kpb">To assist you with team collaboration, sharing projects, and version
        control, an add-on is available that contributes a built-in Git client directly in <ph
          keyref="product"/>. The <b>Git Client</b> is developed independent of the normal
          <b>Oxygen</b> release cycle, so it is updated and improved more frequently than the main
        application. It is an optional tool so it needs to be installed as an add-on. Once
        installed, a <uicontrol>Git Staging</uicontrol> view is available that includes various
        actions that perform common Git commands, such as <i>push</i>, <i>pull</i>, <i>change
          branch</i>, <i>commit</i>, and more. It also includes a built-in tool for comparing and
        merging changes.</p>
      <p id="p_syk_3qq_kpb">For more details, see <xref href="git-addon.dita"/>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="syncro_svn_client_">
      <title>Using Subversion (SVN) for Collaboration</title>
      <p id="p_dwt_bgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> also includes an embedded <xref
          href="svn-quick-start.dita">SVN (Subversion) Client</xref>. Even if you start developing a
        new project, or you want to migrate an existing one to Subversion, the <ph
          keyref="svnProduct"/> allows you to easily share it with the rest of your team. It can be
        accessed from the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu and can be used for synchronizing your
        working copy with a central repository. It can also be started by selecting the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/SyncroSVNClient16.png" id="image_nsj_dhf_yr"/>Open in SVN
          Client</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu of the <xref
          href="using-the-project-view.dita#using-the-project-view"><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol>
          view</xref>. This action opens the Syncro SVN Client and shows the selected project file
        in the <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
      <link href="sharing-possibilities.dita#sharing-possibilities"/>
      <link href="transformation-scenarios-sharing.dita#transformation-scenarios-sharing"/>
      <link href="validation-scenarios-sharing.dita#validation-scenarios-sharing"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
