<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="show-properties">
  <title>Management of SVN Properties</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>SVN properties</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>In the <xref href="properties-view.dita">Properties view</xref> you can read and set the <ph
        conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/apacheSubversion"/> properties of a
      file or folder. There is a set of predefined properties with special meaning to Subversion.
      For more information about properties in Subversion see the SVN Subversion specification.
      Subversion properties are revision dependent. After you change, add or delete a property for a
      resource, you have to commit your changes to the repository.</p>
    <p>If you want to change the properties of a given resource you need to select that resource
      from the <xref href="working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref> and run the
        <uicontrol>Show properties</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu. The
        <uicontrol>Properties</uicontrol> view will show the local properties for the resource in
      the working copy. Once the <u>Properties</u> view is visible, it will always present the
      properties of the currently selected resource. In the <uicontrol>Properties</uicontrol> view
        <xref href="properties-toolbar.dita">toolbar</xref> there are available actions which allow
      you to add, change and delete the properties.</p>
    <p>If you choose the <uicontrol>Add a new property</uicontrol> action, a new dialog will pop-up containing:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - Combo box which allows you to enter the name of the
          property. The drop down list of the combo box presents the predefined Subversion
          properties such as <uicontrol>svn:ignore</uicontrol>,
          <uicontrol>svn:externals</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>svn:needs-lock</uicontrol>, etc.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Current value</uicontrol> - Text area which allows you to enter the value of
          the new property.</li>
      </ul>If the selected item is a directory, you can also set the property recursively on its
      children by checking the <uicontrol>Set property recursively</uicontrol> checkbox.</p>
    <p>If you want to change the value for a previously set property you can use the <uicontrol>Edit
        property</uicontrol> action which will display a dialog where you can set:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - Property name (cannot be changed).</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Current value</uicontrol> - Presents the current value and allows you to change
        it.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Base value</uicontrol> - The value of the property, if any, from the resource
        in the pristine copy. It cannot be modified.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>If you want to completely remove a property previously set you can choose the
        <uicontrol>Remove property</uicontrol> action. It will display a confirmation dialog in
      which you can choose also if the property will be removed recursively.</p>
    <p>In the <xref href="properties-view.dita"><uicontrol>Properties</uicontrol> view</xref> there
      is a <uicontrol>Refresh</uicontrol> action which can be used when the properties have been
      changed from outside the view. This can happen, for example, when the view was already
      presenting the properties of a resource and they have been changed after an
        <uicontrol>Update</uicontrol> operation.</p>
  </body>
</topic>