<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_py2_gl2_1p">
  <title>Site-wide Deployment</title>
  <body>
    <p>If you are deploying <ph keyref="product"/> for a group, there are a number of things you can
      do to customize <ph keyref="product"/> for your users and to make the deployment more
        efficient.<draft-comment author="Mark">This topic is intended to expand as we identify more
        aspects of the product that apply here. I will probably end up moving the topics on
        unattended install here as they are mostly of interest to people doing site
        deployments.</draft-comment></p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Creating custom default options</dt>
        <dd>You can <xref keyref="options.customizing-default">create a custom set of default
            options</xref> for <ph keyref="product"/>. These will become the default options for the
          each of your users, replacing <ph keyref="product"/>'s normal default settings. Users can
          still set options to suit themselves in their own copies of <ph keyref="product"/>, but if
          they choose to reset their options to defaults, the custom defaults that you set will be
          used.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Creating default project files</dt>
        <dd><ph keyref="product"/> project files are used to configure a project. You can create and
          deploy default project files for your projects so that your users will have a
          preconfigured project file to begin work with.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Shared project files</dt>
        <dd>Rather than each user having their own project file, you can create and deploy shared
          project files so that all users share the same project configuration and settings and
          automatically inherit all project changes. </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Using the unattended installer</dt>
        <dd>You can speed up the installation process by using the unattended installer for Windows
          or Linux installs.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt>Using floating licenses</dt>
        <dd>If you have a number of people using <ph keyref="product"/> on a part-time basis or in
          different time zones, you can use a <xref keyref="install.license-key">floating
            license</xref> so that multiple people can share a license.</dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
  </body>
</topic>
