<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="smart-editing">
  <title>Smart Editing</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Editing XML Documents<indexterm>editor specific actions<indexterm>smart editing</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The following helper actions are available in the XML editor:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <i>Closing tag auto-expansion</i> - If you want to insert content into an auto closing tag like &lt;tag/&gt; deleting the /
            character saves some keystrokes by inserting a separate closing tag automatically and
            placing the cursor between the start and end tags: &lt;tag&gt;&lt;/tag&gt;
      </li>
      <li>
        <i>Auto-rename matching tag</i> - When you edit the name of the start tag, <ph keyref="product"/> will mirror-edit the name
            of the matching end tag. This feature can be controlled from the <xref href="preferences-content-completion.dita">
              <i>Content Completion</i> option page</xref>.
      </li>
      <li>
        <i>Auto-breaking the edited line</i> - The <xref href="preferences-editor-format.dita">
              <i>Hard line wrap</i> option</xref> breaks the edited line automatically when its
            length exceeds the maximum line length <xref href="preferences-editor-format.dita">defined</xref> for <xref href="formatting-and-indenting-xml-documents.dita">the
              pretty-print operation.</xref>
      </li>
      <li><i>Indent on Enter</i> - The <xref href="preferences-editor-format.dita">
          <i>Indent on Enter</i> option</xref> indents the new line inserted when Enter is
        pressed.</li>
      <li><i>Smart Enter</i> - The <xref href="preferences-editor-format.dita">
          <i>Smart Enter</i> option</xref> inserts an empty line between the start and end tags. If
        Enter is pressed between a start and an end tag the action places the cursor in an indented
        position on the empty line between the lines that contain the start and end tag.</li>
      <li><i>Double click</i> - A double click selects a different region of text of the current
        document depending on the position of the click in the document:<ul>
          <li>if the click position is inside a start tag or an end tag then the entire element
            enclosed by that tag is selected;</li>
          <li>if the click position is immediately after a start tag or immediately before an end
            tag then the entire content of the element enclosed by that tag is selected, including
            all the child elements but excluding the start tag and the end tag of the element;</li>
          <li>otherwise, the double click selects the entire current line of text.</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>