<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="smart-paste-support">
  <title>Smart Paste Mechanism</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Smart Paste</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Smart
            Paste</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Smart Paste support in Author Mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> editing mode includes a <xref
        keyref="glossentry_smart-paste"><term>Smart Paste</term></xref> feature that preserves
      certain style and structure information when copying content and pasting it into document
      types that support the feature. You can copy content from various sources, including web
      pages, external applications (such as Office-type applications), or other document types
      within <ph keyref="product"/>, and then paste it into DITA, TEI, DocBook, JATS, and XHTML
      documents. <ph keyref="product"/> preserves the original text styling (such as bold, italics,
      underline) and formatting (such as lists, tables, paragraphs) and considers various pasting
      solutions to keep the resulting document valid.</p>
    <p>The styles and general layout of the pasted content are converted to the equivalent XML
      markup for the target document type while preserving certain style and structure information.
      For example, if you copy content that includes multiple paragraphs and then paste it in
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, the multiple paragraph structure is preserved. If you
      paste the content in a location where the resulting XML would not be valid, <ph
        keyref="product"/> will attempt to place it in a valid location, and may prompt you with one
      or more choices for where to place it.</p>
    <section id="smart_paste_options">
      <title>Smart Paste Options</title>
      <p>By default, the <xref keyref="glossentry_smart-paste"><term>Smart Paste</term></xref>
        feature is enabled in <ph keyref="product"/>. There are several options in the <xref
          href="preferences-schema-aware.dita#preferences-schema-aware"><uicontrol>Schema
            Aware</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> that control the <term>Smart Paste</term> mechanism:<ul>
          <li><xref
              href="preferences-schema-aware.dita#preferences-schema-aware/smart-paste-drag-drop"
                ><uicontrol>Smart paste and drag and drop</uicontrol></xref> - This option
            determines whether or not <ph keyref="product"/> will try to find an appropriate insert
            position when the current location is not valid for the pasted content. This option is
            selected by default.</li>
          <li><xref href="preferences-schema-aware.dita#preferences-schema-aware/reject-action"
                ><uicontrol>Reject action when its result is invalid</uicontrol></xref> - If you
            select this option, <ph keyref="product"/> will not let you paste content into a
            position where it would be invalid. This option is deselected by default.</li>
          <li><xref
              href="preferences-schema-aware.dita#preferences-schema-aware/convert_external_content_on_paste"
                ><uicontrol>Convert external content on paste</uicontrol></xref> - This option
            determines whether or not <ph keyref="product"/> will convert the styling and formatting
            of copied content from external sources when pasting it into a document type that
            supports the feature. This option is selected by default.</li>
          <li><xref
              href="preferences-schema-aware.dita#preferences-schema-aware/convert-even-space-preserve"
                ><uicontrol>Convert even when pasting inside space-preserve
              elements</uicontrol></xref> - If you select this option, the <term>Smart Paste</term>
            feature will also work when pasting external content into a <term>space-preserve</term>
            element (such as a <codeph>codeblock</codeph>). This option is deselected by
            default.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="doc-types-sp-p">
      <title>Smart Paste Supported Document Types</title>
      <p>The <xref keyref="glossentry_smart-paste"><term>Smart Paste</term></xref> feature is
        supported for the following document types (<xref keyref="glossentry_framework"
            ><term>frameworks</term></xref>):<ul>
          <li>DITA</li>
          <li>DocBook 4</li>
          <li>DocBook 5</li>
          <li>TEI P4</li>
          <li>TEI P5</li>
          <li>XHTML</li>
          <li>JATS</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the <term>Smart Paste</term> support, go to <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/Smart_Paste_Copy_Paste_from_Web_Office_Documents_to_DITA_DocBook_TEI_XHTML_Documents.html"
        format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="author-customize-smart-paste.dita#author-customize-smart-paste"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
