<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="sort-entire-table">
  <title>Sorting a Table</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Sort entire table</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <!--Proofed-->
    <p>To sort rows in a table, select the entire table (or specific rows) and use the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/Sort16.png"/>Sort</uicontrol> action from the main toolbar
      or the contextual menu. This opens the <uicontrol>Sort</uicontrol> dialog box.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>The "Sort" Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sort-entire-dialog.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p1">This dialog box sets the range that is sorted and the sorting criteria. The range is
      automatically selected depending on whether you sort an entire table or only a selection of
      its rows.</p>
    <note>When you invoke the sorting operation over an entire table, the <uicontrol>Selected
        rows</uicontrol> option is disabled.</note>
    <p id="p2">The <uicontrol>Criteria</uicontrol> section specifies the sorting criteria (a maximum
      of three sorting criteria are available), defined by the following:<ul>
        <li>A name, which is collected from the column heading.</li>
        <li id="type-of-info-li">The type of the information that is sorted. You can choose between
          the following:<ul id="ul_z5l_ll2_ms">
            <li><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> - Alphanumeric characters.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Numeric</uicontrol> - Regular integer or floating point numbers are
              accepted.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Date</uicontrol> - Default date formats from the OS are accepted (such as
                <term>short</term>, <term>medium</term>, <term>long</term>, <term>full</term>,
                <term>xs:date</term>, and <term>xs:dateTime</term>).</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li id="sort-direction-li">The sorting direction (either <i>ascending</i> or
            <i>descending</i>).</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p id="p3">The sort criteria is automatically set to the column where the caret is located at
      the time when the sorting operation is invoked. </p>
    <p id="p4">After you finish configuring the options in the <uicontrol>Sort</uicontrol> dialog
      box, click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to complete the sorting operation. If you want to revert
      to the initial order of your content, press <uicontrol
        conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_z"/> on your keyboard.<note
        id="xml-lang-attribute">The sorting support takes the value of the <codeph>xml:lang</codeph>
        attribute into account and sorts the content in a natural order.</note></p>
  </body>
</topic>
