<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="sparse-checkouts">
  <title>Sparse Checkout</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Sparse checkouts</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Sometimes you only need to check out certain parts of a directory tree. In this case, you can
      check out the top directory (using the<xref href="repos-menu.dita"><uicontrol>Check
          out</uicontrol> action from the <uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view</xref>) and then
      recursively update only the needed directories (using the <xref
        href="working-copy-menu.dita#working-copy-menu" format="dita"><uicontrol>Update</uicontrol>
        action from the <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref>). Each directory then has a
      depth set to it, with four possible values:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Recursive (infinity)</uicontrol> - Updates all descendant directories and files
        recursively.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Immediate children (immediates)</uicontrol> - Updates the directory, including
        direct child directories and files, but does not populate the child directories.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>File children only (files)</uicontrol> - Updates the directory, including only
        child files without the child directories.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>This folder only (empty)</uicontrol> - Updates only the selected directory,
        without updating any children.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>For some operations, you can use as depth the current depth registered on the directories
      from the working copy (the value <uicontrol>Current depth</uicontrol>). This is the depth
      value defined in a previous check out or update operation.</p>
    <p>The sparse checked out directories are presented in the <xref
        href="working-copy-view.dita#working-copy-view" format="dita"><uicontrol>Working
          Copy</uicontrol> view</xref> with a marker corresponding to each depth value, in the top
      left corner, as follows: </p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNDepthInfinity16.png" id="image_ikw_1np_5r"/> Recursive
          (infinity)</uicontrol> - This is the default value and it is has no mark. The directory
        has no limiting depth.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNDepthImmediates16.png" id="image_npp_cnp_5r"/> Immediate
          children (immediates)</uicontrol> - The directory is limited to direct child directories
        (without contents) and files.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNDepthFiles16.png" id="image_ckd_cnp_5r"/> File children
          only (files)</uicontrol> - The directory is limited to direct child files only.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/SVNDepthEmpty16.png" id="image_emq_bnp_5r"/> This folder
          only (empty)</uicontrol> - The directory has <i>empty</i> depth set.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>A depth set on a directory means that some operations process only items within the specified
      depth range. For example, <uicontrol>Synchronize</uicontrol> on a working copy directory
      reports the repository modified items within the depth set on the directory and those existing
      in the working copy outside of this depth.</p>
    <p>The depth information is also presented in the <uicontrol>SVN Information</uicontrol> dialog
      box and in the tool tip displayed when hovering a directory in the <uicontrol>Working
        Copy</uicontrol> view.</p>
  </body>
  
</topic>