<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="supported-XSLT-processors">
    <title>Supported XSLT Processors</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Transformation Scenarios<indexterm>Supported XSLT processors</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes the following XSLT processors:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Xalan <ph keyref="xalanFullVersion"
                    /></b> - <xref href="http://xml.apache.org/xalan-j/" scope="external"
                    format="html">Xalan-Java</xref> is an XSLT processor for transforming XML
                documents into HTML, text, or other XML document types. It implements XSL
                Transformations (XSLT) Version 1.0 and XML Path Language (XPath) Version 1.0.</li>
            <li><b>Saxon <ph keyref="saxon6FullVersion"/></b> - <xref
          href="http://saxon.sourceforge.net/saxon6.5.5/" scope="external" format="html">Saxon <ph
            keyref="saxon6FullVersion"/></xref> is an XSLT processor that implements the Version 1.0
        XSLT and XPath with a number of powerful extensions. This version of Saxon also includes
        many of the new features that were first defined in the XSLT 1.1 working draft, but for
        conformance and portability reasons these are not available if the stylesheet header
        specifies <codeph>version="1.0"</codeph>.</li>
            <li><b>Saxon <ph keyref="saxon9FullVersion"/> Home Edition (HE), Professional Edition
          (PE)</b> - <xref href="http://saxon.sf.net/" scope="external" format="html">Saxon-HE/PE
        </xref> implements the basic conformance level for XSLT 2.0 / 3.0 and XQuery 1.0. The term
          <i>basic XSLT 2.0 / 3.0 processor</i> is defined in the draft XSLT 2.0 / 3.0
        specifications. It is a conformance level that requires support for all features of the
        language other than those that involve schema processing. The HE product remains open
        source, but removes some of the more advanced features that are present in Saxon-PE.</li>
            <li><b>Saxon <ph keyref="saxon9FullVersion"/> Enterprise Edition (EE)</b> - <xref
          href="http://www.saxonica.com/" scope="external" format="html">Saxon EE</xref> is the
        schema-aware edition of Saxon and it is one of the built-in processors included in <ph
          keyref="product"/>. Saxon EE includes an XML Schema processor, and schema-aware XSLT,
        XQuery, and XPath processors.<p>The validation in schema aware transformations is done
          according to the W3C XML Schema 1.0 or 1.1. This can be <xref
            href="xml-schema-preferences-page.dita">configured in Preferences</xref>.<note><ph
              keyref="product"/> implements a Saxon <term>framework</term> that allows you to create
            Saxon configuration files. Two templates are available: <uicontrol>Saxon collection
              catalog</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Saxon configuration</uicontrol>. Both of these
            templates support content completion, element annotation, and attribute annotation.
            </note><note>Saxon can use the <i>ICU-J localization library</i>
              (<filepath>saxon9-icu.jar</filepath>) to add support for sorting and date/number
            formatting in a wide variety of languages. This library is not included in the <ph
              keyref="product"/> installation kit. However, Saxon will use the default collation and
            localization support available in the currently used JRE. To enable this capability,
            follow these steps:<ol id="ol_a5f_gxq_4q">
              <li>Download Saxon <ph keyref="saxon9FullVersion"/> Professional Edition (PE) or
                Enterprise Edition (EE) from <xref href="http://www.saxonica.com"
                  format="html#download-saxon" scope="external"/>.</li>
              <li>Unpack the downloaded archive.</li>
              <li>Create a new XSLT transformation scenario (or edit an existing one). In the
                  <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol> tab, click the <uicontrol>Extensions</uicontrol>
                button to open the list of additional libraries used by the transformation
                process.</li>
              <li>Click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> and browse to the folder where you unpacked the
                downloaded archive and choose the <filepath>saxon9-icu.jar</filepath> file.</li>
            </ol><p>Note that the <filepath>saxon9-icu.jar</filepath> should NOT be added to the
              application library folder because it will conflict with another version of the ICU-J
              library that comes bundled with <ph keyref="product"/>.</p></note></p></li>
      <li product="developer editor developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Saxon-CE (Client
          Edition)</uicontrol> is Saxonica's implementation of XSLT 2.0 for use on web browsers. <ph
          keyref="product"/> provides support for editing stylesheets that contain Saxon-CE
        extension functions and instructions. This support improves the validation, content
        completion, and syntax highlighting.<note
          conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/saxon-ce-execution-limitation"/><note>A
          specific template, named <uicontrol>Saxon-CE stylesheet</uicontrol>, is available in the
            <xref href="new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa" product="developer editor"
              ><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> document wizard</xref><xref
            href="creating-from-templates.dita#creating-from-templates"
            product="developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>New from Templates</uicontrol>
            wizard</xref>.</note></li>
      <li><b>Xsltproc (libxslt)</b> - <xref format="html" href="http://xmlsoft.org/XSLT/"
          scope="external">Libxslt</xref> is the XSLT C library developed for the Gnome project.
          <b>Libxslt</b> is based on <i>libxml2</i>, the XML C library developed for the Gnome
        project. It also implements most of the EXSLT set of processor-portable extensions,
        functions, and some of Saxon's evaluate and expression extensions.<p><ph keyref="product"/>
          uses <b>Libxslt</b> through its command line tool (<i>Xsltproc</i>). Depending on your
          operating system, you must download the Libxslt libraries on your machine from <xref
            href="http://xmlsoft.org/XSLT/downloads.html" format="html" scope="external"/> and place
          them in a local folder. Then you need to update the <codeph>PATH</codeph> environmental
          variable to contain the parent folder where the <filepath>xsltproc</filepath> executable
          is located.<note type="tip">As an example, a Windows installation of the Xsltproc engine
            would follow these steps:<ol>
              <li>Go to <xref href="ftp://ftp.zlatkovic.com/libxml/" format="html" scope="external"
                /> and download the following ZIP files: <b>iconv-1.9.2.win32.zip</b>,
                  <b>libxml2-2.7.8.win32.zip</b>, <b>libxslt-1.1.26.win32.zip</b>,
                  <b>zlib-1.2.5.win32.zip</b>.</li>
              <li>Unzip all of them into the same folder of your choice.</li>
              <li>Edit the <codeph>PATH</codeph> environment variable and add the
                  <filepath>bin</filepath> folder for all four archives:<p><image
                    href="../img/xsltproc_path_var.png"/></p></li>
              <li>Restart <ph keyref="product"/>.<p><b>Result:</b> You can now use the
                    <b>xsltproc</b> processor as an XSLT engine in the XSLT transformation
                  scenario.</p></li>
            </ol></note></p><p>
          <note>The Xsltproc processor can be configured from the <xref
              href="preferences-xsltproc.dita"><uicontrol>XSLTPROC</uicontrol> options
            page</xref>.</note>
        </p><note type="caution">There is a known problem where file paths that contain spaces are
          not handled correctly in the LIBXML processor. For example, the built-in <xref
            keyref="glossentry_xml-catalog"><term>XML Catalog</term></xref> files of the built-in
          document types (DocBook, TEI, DITA, etc.) are not handled properly by LIBXML if <ph
            keyref="product"/> is installed in the default location on Windows (C:\Program Files).
          This is because the built-in <term>XML catalog</term> files are stored in the
              <filepath><term conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"
            />/frameworks</filepath> subdirectory of the installation directory, and in this case it
          contains a space character.</note></li>
      <li><b>MSXML 4.0</b> - <xref format="html" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/xml/"
          scope="external">MSXML 4.0</xref> is available only on Windows platforms. It can be used
        for <xref href="defining-new-transformation-scenario.dita">transformation</xref>
        <ph product="editor editorEclipse developer developerEclipse">and <xref
            href="xslt-custom-validation.dita">validation of XSLT stylesheets</xref></ph>.<p><ph
            keyref="product"/> uses the Microsoft XML parser through its command line tool <xref
            format="html" href="http://microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=21714"
            scope="external"><i>msxsl.exe</i></xref>.</p><p>Since
            <filepath>msxsl.exe</filepath> is only a wrapper, Microsoft Core XML Services (MSXML)
          must be installed on the computer. Otherwise, you will get a corresponding warning. You
          can get the latest Microsoft XML parser from <xref format="html"
            href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyId=3144B72B-B4F2-46DA-B4B6-C5D7485F2B42&amp;displaylang=en"
            scope="external">Microsoft web-site</xref>. </p></li>
      <li><b>MSXML .NET</b> - <xref format="html" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/xml/"
          scope="external">MSXML .NET</xref> is available only on Windows platforms. It can be used
        for <xref href="defining-new-transformation-scenario.dita">transformation</xref>
        <ph product="editor editorEclipse developer developerEclipse">and <xref
            href="xslt-custom-validation.dita">validation of XSLT stylesheets</xref></ph>.<p><ph
            keyref="product"/> performs XSLT transformations and validations using the .NET
            <term>Framework</term> XSLT implementation (<i>System.Xml.Xsl.XslTransform</i> class)
          through the <b>nxslt</b> command line utility. The <b>nxslt</b> version included in <ph
            keyref="product"/> is <ph keyref="nxsltVersion"/>. </p><p>You should have the .NET
            <term>Framework</term> version 1.0 already installed on your system. Otherwise, you will
          get the following warning: <codeph>MSXML.NET requires .NET Framework version 1.0 to be
            installed. Exit code: 128</codeph>.</p><p>You can get the .NET <term>Framework</term>
          version 1.0 from the <xref format="html"
            href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=d7158dee-a83f-4e21-b05a-009d06457787&amp;displaylang=en"
            scope="external"> Microsoft website</xref>.</p></li>
      <li><b>.NET 1.0</b> - A transformer based on the <b>System.Xml</b> 1.0 library available in
        the .NET 1.0 and .NET 1.1 <term>frameworks</term> from Microsoft (<xref format="html"
          href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/xml/" scope="external"/>). It is available only on
          Windows.<p>You should have the .NET <term>Framework</term> version 1.0 or 1.1 already
          installed on your system. Otherwise, you will get the following warning: <codeph>MSXML.NET
            requires .NET Framework version 1.0 to be installed. Exit code: 128</codeph>.</p><p>You
          can get the .NET <term>Framework</term> version 1.0 from the <xref format="html"
            href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=d7158dee-a83f-4e21-b05a-009d06457787&amp;displaylang=en"
            scope="external">Microsoft website</xref>.</p></li>
      <li><b>.NET 2.0</b> - A transformer based on the <b>System.Xml</b> 2.0 library available in
        the .NET 2.0 <term>Framework</term> from <xref format="html"
          href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/xml/" scope="external">Microsoft</xref>. It is available
        only on Windows.<p>You should have the .NET <term>Framework</term> version 2.0 already
          installed on your system. Otherwise, you will get the following warning: <codeph>MSXML.NET
            requires .NET Framework version 2.0 to be installed. Exit code: 128</codeph>.</p><p>You
          can get the .NET <term>Framework</term> version 2.0 from the <xref format="html"
            href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=9655156b-356b-4a2c-857c-e62f50ae9a55&amp;DisplayLang=en"
            scope="external">Microsoft website</xref>.</p></li>
        </ul>
        <p product="editor author developer">For information about configuring the XSLT preferences,
      see the <xref href="preferences-xslt.dita">XSLT options</xref> section.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
