<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="svn-share-project">
  <title>Share a Project</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Share projects</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Even if you start developing a new project, or you want to migrate an existing one to
      Subversion, the <ph keyref="svnProduct"/> allows you to easily share it with the rest of your
      team. The shared project directory is automatically converted to a working copy and added
      under <ph keyref="svnProduct"/> management. The <uicontrol>Share project</uicontrol> action is
      available in the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu and the contextual menu of the
        <uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Share Project Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/svn_share_project.png" id="image_1mm_gs3_hf" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The following options can be configured in the <uicontrol>Share project</uicontrol> dialog box:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><xref
              href="entering-local-paths-urls.dita#entering-local-paths-urls/local-path-section">The
              location of the project folder</xref> on the local disk by using the text box or the
              <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol> button. This folder should not be empty or already under
            version control.<note type="important">By default, the SVN system only imports the
              content of the specified folder, and not the root folder itself. Therefore, it is
              recommended to use the <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol> button to select the project
              folder so that the client will automatically append the name of it to the specified
              URL.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>URL</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><xref href="entering-local-paths-urls.dita#entering-local-paths-urls/url-section">The
              new location of the project</xref> (inside the repository) that will be used to access
                it.<note><i>Peg revisions</i> have no effect for this operation since it is
              used to send information to the repository.  </note><note type="attention">If the new
              location already exists, make sure that it is an empty directory to avoid mixing your
              project content with other files (if items exist with the same name, an error will
              occur and the operation will not proceed). Otherwise, if the address does not exist,
              it is created automatically.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The SVN format of the working copy. You can choose between <uicontrol>SVN
              1.8</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>SVN 1.7</uicontrol>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="share-files-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Share files matching global ignore patterns</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When selected, the file names that match the patterns defined in either of the
            following locations are also imported into the repository:<ul id="ul_xgf_cck_4r">
              <li>The <codeph>global-ignores</codeph> property in <xref
                  href="svn-preferences.dita#svn-preferences">the SVN configuration
                file</xref>.</li>
              <li>The <xref
                  href="preferences-svn-working-copy.dita#preferences-svn-working-copy/svn-options-app-global-ignores"
                    ><uicontrol>File name ignore patterns</uicontrol> option</xref> in the <xref
                  href="preferences-svn-working-copy.dita#preferences-svn-working-copy"><menucascade>
                    <uicontrol>SVN</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol>
                  </menucascade> preferences page</xref>.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="enable-disable-auto-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Enable automatic properties</uicontrol>/<uicontrol>Disable automatic
              properties</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Enables or disables automatic property assignment (per runtime configuration rules),
            overriding the <codeph>enable-auto-props</codeph> runtime configuration directive,
            defined in <xref href="svn-preferences.dita#svn-preferences">the SVN configuration
              file</xref>.<note>This option is available only when there are defined properties to
              be applied automatically for newly added items under version control. You can define
              these properties in the SVN <codeph>config</codeph> file (in the
                <codeph>auto-props</codeph> section). Based on the value of the
                <codeph>enable-auto-props</codeph> runtime configuration directive, the presented
              option is either <uicontrol>Enable automatic properties</uicontrol>, or
                <uicontrol>Disable automatic properties</uicontrol>.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
