<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="svn-patches">
    <title>Patches</title>
    <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>SVN
          branches/tags<indexterm>patch</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>This section explains how to work with patches in <ph keyref="svnProduct"/>.</p>
    <section>
      <?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150323T142831+0200" comment="Make this more clear"?>
      <title>What is a Patch</title>
      <?oxy_comment_end?>
      <p>Suppose you are working to a set of XML files that you distribute to other people and from
        time to time you tag the project and distribute the releases. If you continue working while
        correcting problems, you may find yourself in the situations where you need to notify your
        users that you have corrected a problem. In this case you may prefer to distribute a patch,
        which is a collection of differences, that applied over the last distribution, would correct
        the problem. The SVN client creates the patch in <xref
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diff#Unified_format" scope="external" format="html">the
          Unified Diff format</xref>. </p>
      <p>Creating a patch in <ph keyref="apacheSubversion"/> implies the access to either two
        revisions of a versioned item, or two different versioned items from the repository:</p>
      <ul id="ul_hqf_5cx_lr">
        <li><i>Two revisions of a version item</i> - the item can be local or remote and you can
          select two versions of it. This also applies when you need to generate a patch that only
          contains the changes in the working copy that were not yet committed.</li>
        <li><i>Two different versioned items from the repository</i> - the items are remote and you
          need to specify a revision for both.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>