<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="switch-repository-location">
  <title>Switch the Repository Location</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>Branches/Tags<indexterm>Switch repository
            location</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Switch</uicontrol> action is useful when the repository location of a working
      copy, or an already committed item in the working copy, must be changed within the same
      repository. The action is available on the <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu when a versioned
      resource is selected in the current working copy that is displayed in the <xref
        href="working-copy-view.dita#working-copy-view" format="dita"><uicontrol>Working
          Copy</uicontrol> view</xref>.</p>
    <note><i>External</i> items cannot be switched using this action. Instead, change the
      value of the <codeph>svn:externals</codeph> property set on the parent directory of the
      external item and update the parent directory.</note>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_nww_rzd_4r">
        <title><uicontrol>Switch</uicontrol> Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/svn_switch_dialog.png" id="image_wp3_n22_4r"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The following options can be configured in the <uicontrol>Switch</uicontrol> dialog box:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Switch to URL</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><xref href="entering-local-paths-urls.dita#entering-local-paths-urls/url-section">The
              new location in the same repository</xref> you are switching to.<note type="tip">You
              can switch to items that were deleted, moved, or replaced, by specifying the original
              URL (before the item was removed) and use a <xref
                href="../topics/using-peg-revisions.dita#using-peg-revisions"><term>peg</term>
                revision</xref> at the end (for example,
              <codeph>URL@rev1234</codeph>).</note><note>For items that are already <xref
                href="working-copy-view.dita#working-copy-view/switched-li"
                ><term>switched</term></xref> that you want to switch back, the proposed URL is the
              original location of the item.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Revision</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The specific version of the location that you are switching to.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Depth</uicontrol> - (This option is applicable only for directories)</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Current depth</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Obeys the depths registered for the directories in the working copy that are
                    to be switched.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Recursive (infinity)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Switches the location of the selected folder and all of its files and
                    folders.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>Immediate children (immediates)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Switches the location of the selected folder and its child files and folders
                    without recursing subfolders.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>File children only (files)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Switches the location of the selected folder and its child files.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol>This folder only (empty)</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Switches the location of the selected folder (no child files or folders are
                    included).</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Ignore "svn:externals" definitions</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When selected, external items are ignored in the switch operation. This option is only
            available if you choose the <uicontrol>Current depth</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Recursive
              (infinity)</uicontrol> depth.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Change the working copy item to the specified depth</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Changes the <i>sticky</i> depth on the directory in the working copy.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Ignore ancestry</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>When not selected, the SVN system does not allow you to switch to a location that does
            not share a common ancestry with the current location. If selected, the SVN does not
            check for a common ancestry. </dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>