<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="tagless-editor-introduction">
  <title>Tagless XML Authoring</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>WYSIWYG editing</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm>Author Editor<indexterm>roles: content author, framework
          developer</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Once the structure of an XML document and the required restrictions on its elements and their
      attributes are defined with an XML schema, the editing of the document becomes easier in a
      WYSIWYG (what-you-see-is-what-you-get) editor in which the XML markup is not visible.</p>
    <p>This tagless editor is available as the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode of the XML editor.
      To enter the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, click the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
      button at the bottom of the editing area. The <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode renders the
      content of the XML document visually based on a CSS stylesheet associated with the document.
      Many of the actions and features available in <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode are also
      available in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editor author">
        <title>Author Editing Mode</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_author_perspective_large.png" id="image_wqm_snj_mg"/>
      </fig>
      <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse">
        <title>Author Editing Mode</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_author_frame.png" id="image_urm_snj_mg"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <section>
      <title>Associating a CSS with an XML Document</title>
      <p>The tagless rendering of an XML document in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode is
        driven by a CSS stylesheet which conforms to the <xref href="http://www.w3.org/TR/CSS21/"
          scope="external" format="html">version 2.1 of the CSS specification</xref> from the W3C
        consortium. Some CSS 3 features like namespaces and custom extensions of the CSS
        specification are supported also.</p>
      <p>The CSS specification is convenient for driving the tagless rendering of XML documents as
        it is an open standard maintained by the W3C consortium. A stylesheet conforming to this
        specification is easy to <xref product="editor editorEclipse"
          href="content-completion-css-stylesheets.dita">develop and edit</xref>
        <ph product="author authorEclipse">develop and edit</ph> in <ph
          keyref="product"/> as it is a plain text
        file with a simple syntax.</p>
      <p>The association of such a stylesheet with an XML document is straightforward: an
          <codeph>xml-stylesheet</codeph> XML processing instruction with the attribute
          <codeph>type="text/css"</codeph> must be inserted at the beginning of the XML document. In
        case you do not want to alter your XML documents, you should set-up a <i>document type</i>. </p>
      <p>For XHTML documents, there is a second method for the association of a CSS stylesheet: an
        element <codeph>link</codeph> with the <codeph>href</codeph> and <codeph>type</codeph>
        attributes in the <codeph>head</codeph> child element of the <codeph>html</codeph> element
        as specified in the <xref
          href="http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/present/styles.html#h-14.3.2" scope="external"
          format="html">W3C CSS specification</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Author Mode User Roles</title>
      <p>There are two main types of users of the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode: <i>framework
          developers</i> and <i>content authors</i>. A <i>framework developer</i> is a technical
        person with advanced XML knowledge who defines the framework for authoring XML documents in
        the tagless editor. Once the framework is created or edited by the developer, it is
        distributed as a deliverable component ready to plug into the application to the content
        authors. A <i>content author</i> does not need to have advanced knowledge about XML tags or
        operations like validation of XML documents or applying an XPath expression to an XML
        document. The author just plugs the framework set-up by the developer into the application
        and starts editing the content of XML documents without editing the XML tags directly.</p>
      <p>The framework set-up by the developer is called <i>document type</i> and defines a type of
        XML documents by specifying all the details needed for editing the content of XML documents
        in tagless mode:</p>
      <ul id="ul_qsb_q4j_mg">
        <li>the CSS stylesheet which drives the tagless visual rendering of the document;</li>
        <li>the rules for associating an XML schema with the document which is needed for content
          completion and validation of the document;</li>
        <li>transformation scenarios for the document;</li>
        <li>XML catalogs;</li>
        <li>custom actions available as buttons on the toolbar.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>The tagless editor comes with some ready to use predefined document types for XML
        frameworks largely used today like DocBook, DITA, TEI, XHTML.</p>
    </section>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the basic functionality of the
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode, go to <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/WYSIWYG_XML_Editing.html" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://oxygenxml.com/demo/WYSIWYG_XML_Editing.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
