<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="templates-tab-whr">
  <title>Templates Tab (DITA OT Transformations)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA OT transformation scenario<indexterm>Templates tab</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/intro-for-transformation-tabs"/></p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> tab is available for DITA OT transformations with
        <uicontrol>WebHelp Responsive</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>WebHelp Responsive with
        Feedback</uicontrol> output types and it provides a set of predefined <xref
        keyref="wh-publishing-template">publishing templates</xref>. You can use one of them to
      publish your documentation or as a starting point for a new publishing template.</p>
    <p>There are two main types of templates, <i>Tiles</i> and <i>Tree</i> and each of the built-in
      templates includes of version of each type. You can click on the tags at the top of the pane
      to filter the templates and narrow your search. You can filter them by either
        <uicontrol>tiles</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>tree</uicontrol> and then various color schemes.
      Each built-in template also includes an <uicontrol>Online preview</uicontrol> link that opens
      a webpage in your default browser that provides a sample of how the main page will look when
      that particular template is used to generate the output.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_cdx_hpj_14">
        <title>Templates Tab</title>
        <image href="../img/templates_tab_WH_resp.png" id="image_r5k_gpj_14"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The two main types of layouts:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><i>Tiles</i></dt>
          <dd>The main page in the WebHelp output presents a tile for each main topic (chapter) of
            the documentation. Each tile includes a link to the topic and a short description.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><i>Tree</i></dt>
          <dd>The main page in the WebHelp output presents a tree-like table of contents with links
            to the first and second level topics in the publication.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <section id="section_djq_dn3_vcb">
      <title>Built-in Templates Location</title>
      <p>All built-in templates are stored in the following directory: <filepath><abbreviated-form
            keyref="glossentry-wh-plugin-dir"/>/templates</filepath>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="custom_templates">
      <title>Custom Templates</title>
      <p>You can use a built-in template as a starting point for <xref
          href="whr-create-publishing-template.dita#whr-create-publishing-template">creating your
          own custom template</xref>. Once you are finished configuring your template, you can click
        the <uicontrol>Choose Custom Publishing Template</uicontrol> link to select your
        template.</p>
      <p>You can also store your custom templates in a <term>templates gallery</term>. The templates
        stored in the gallery will be displayed as the first items in the
          <uicontrol>Template</uicontrol> tab.</p>
      <p>To define your templates gallery, click the <uicontrol>Configure Publishing Templates
          Gallery</uicontrol> link and add the directory where your custom templates are stored to
        list.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="custom_template_errors">
      <title>Custom Template Errors</title>
      <p>When the <uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> tab is opened, all templates (built-in and
        custom) are loaded and validated. Specifically, certain elements in the <xref
          href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#template_descritpor_file">template descriptor
          file</xref> are checked for validity. If errors are encountered that prevents the template
        from loading, the following message will be displayed toward the bottom of the dialog
        box:</p>
      <p><image href="../img/whr-templated-cannot-be-loaded.png"/></p>
      <p>If you click the <uicontrol>More details</uicontrol> link, a window will open with more
        information about the encountered error. For example, it might offer a hint for which
        element is missing from the expected <xref
          href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#template_descritpor_file">descriptor file
          structure</xref>.</p>
      <p>Also, if a valid <xref
          href="whr_publishing_template_contents.dita#template_descritpor_file/template_preview_image"
          >preview image</xref> cannot be found, a warning icon (<image href="../img/Warning16.png"
        />) will be displayed on the template's image (in the <uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> tab
        of the transformation dialog box).</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_olq_54f_xcb">
      <title>Sharing Publishing Template</title>
      <p>To share a publishing template with others, following these steps:</p>
      <ol id="ul_ms3_c5j_wcb">
        <li>Copy your template in a new folder.</li>
        <li>Go to <xref href="preferences-dita-publishing.dita#preferences-dita-publishing"><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Publishing</uicontrol>
            </menucascade></xref> and add that new folder to the list. </li>
        <li>Switch the option as the bottom of that preferences page to <uicontrol>Project
            Options</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li>Share your project file (<filepath>.xpr</filepath>).</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link keyref="wh-publishing-template"/>
      <link href="whr_publishing_templates.dita#whr_publishing_templates"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
