<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="templates-tab-whr">
  <title>Templates Tab (DITA OT Transformations)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA OT transformation scenario<indexterm>Templates tab</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/intro-for-transformation-tabs"/></p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> tab is available for DITA OT transformations with
        <uicontrol>WebHelp Responsive</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>WebHelp Responsive with
        Feedback</uicontrol> output types and it provides a set of predefined <i>skins</i>
      that you can use as a base for the layout of your WebHelp system output. </p>
    <p>A <i>skin</i> is a collection of CSS properties that can alter the look of the output
      by changing colors, font types, borders, margins, and paddings. This allows you to rapidly
      adapt the look and feel of your output. You can choose predefined skins in a <i>tile</i>
      style of layout or a <i>tree</i> style of layout, and you can also <xref
        href="webhelp_responsive_customization.dita#webhelp_responsive_customization">add your own
        customized skins</xref>.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_cdx_hpj_14">
        <title>Templates Tab</title>
        <image href="../img/templates_tab_WH_resp.png" id="image_r5k_gpj_14"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> tab comes by default with the following predefined
      collections of skins:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><i>Tiles</i></dt>
          <dd>This sections presents the predefined skins that are arranged in a <i>tiles</i>
            style of layout. These predefined skins include a variety of themes, ranging from a very
            light one to a high-contrast variant, and various styles. If you select
              <uicontrol>Choose custom skin</uicontrol>, you can select a custom CSS stylesheet to
            be used as your template.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><i>Tree</i></dt>
          <dd>This sections presents the predefined skins that are arranged in a <i>tree</i>
            style of layout. These predefined skins include a variety of themes, ranging from a very
            light one to a high-contrast variant, and various styles. If you select
              <uicontrol>Choose custom skin</uicontrol>, you can select a custom CSS stylesheet to
            be used as your template.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>When you add a new collection of skins, this tab will list them.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
