<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="text-mode-javascript">
  <title>JavaScript Editor Text Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing JavaScript Files<indexterm>Text mode</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> allows you to create and edit JavaScript files and assists you with
      useful features such as syntax highlight, content completion, and outline view. <ph
        id="selecting-blocks">To enhance your editing experience, you can select entire blocks
        (parts of text delimited by brackets) by double-clicking after an opening or in front of a
        closing bracket.</ph>
    </p>
    <fig>
      <title>JavaScript Editor Text Mode</title>
      <image href="../img/javascript_editor_text_mode.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The contextual menu of the <uicontrol>JavaScript</uicontrol> editor offers the following options:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_cut_button.png"/>Cut</uicontrol> - allows you to cut
          fragments of text from the editing area;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_copy.png"/>Copy</uicontrol> - allows you to copy
          fragments of text from the editing area;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_paste.png"/>Paste</uicontrol> - allows you to paste
          fragments of text in the editing area;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ToggleComment16.png"/>Toggle comment</uicontrol> - allows
          you to comment a line or a fragment of the JavaScript document you are editing. This
          option inserts a single comment for the entire fragment you want to comment;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/ToggleComment16.png"/>Toggle line comment</uicontrol> -
          allows you to comment a line or a fragment of the JavaScript document you are editing.
          This option inserts a comment for each line of the fragment you want to comment;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Go to matching bracket</uicontrol> - use this option to find the closing, or
          opening bracket, matching the bracket at the caret position. When you select this option,
            <ph keyref="product"/> moves the caret to the matching bracket, highlights its row, and
          decorates the initial bracket with a rectangle; <note>A rectangle decorates the opening,
            or closing bracket which matches the current one at all times. </note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Compare</uicontrol> - select this option to open the <uicontrol>Diff
            Files</uicontrol> dialog and compare the file you are editing with a file you choose in
          the dialog. </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Open</uicontrol> - allows you to select one of the following options:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Open File at Caret</uicontrol> - select this option to open the source of
              the file located at the caret position;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Open File at Caret in System Application</uicontrol> - select this option
              to open the source of the file located at the caret position with the application that
              the system associates with the file;</li>
            <li>
              <uicontrol>Open in Browser/System Application</uicontrol> - select this option to open
              the file in the system application associated with the file type.<note><ph
                  id="default_internet_browser_note">If you already set the <uicontrol>Default
                    Internet browser</uicontrol> option in the <uicontrol>Global</uicontrol>
                  preferences page, it takes precedence over the default system application
                  settings.</ph></note></li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Folding</uicontrol> - allows you to select one of the following options:<ul>
            <li><ph id="toggle-fold"><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_toggle_fold.png"/> Toggle
                  Fold</uicontrol> - toggles the state of the current fold</ph>;</li>
            <li><ph id="other-folds"><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_close_other_folds.png"/>
                  Collapse Other Folds <shortcut>(Ctrl (Meta on Mac OS)+NumPad
                  /)</shortcut></uicontrol> - folds all the elements except the current
              element</ph>;</li>
            <li><ph id="child-folds"><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_collapse_child_folds.png"/>
                  Collapse Child Folds <shortcut>(Ctrl (Meta on Mac OS)+NumPad
                  .)</shortcut></uicontrol> - folds the elements indented with one level inside the
                current element</ph>; </li>
            <li><ph id="expand-child-folds"><uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/bt_expand_child_folds.png"/> Expand Child Folds</uicontrol>-
                unfolds all child elements of the currently selected element</ph>; </li>
            <li><ph id="expand-all"><uicontrol><image href="../img/ExpandAll16.png"/> Expand All
                    <shortcut>(Ctrl (Meta on Mac OS)+NumPad *)</shortcut></uicontrol> - unfolds
                all elements in the current document</ph>.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Source</uicontrol> - allows you to select one of the following options:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>To Lower Case</uicontrol> - converts the selection content to lower case
              characters;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>To Upper Case</uicontrol> - converts the selection content to upper case
              characters;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Capitalize Lines</uicontrol> - converts to upper case the first character
              of every selected line;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Join and Normalize</uicontrol> - joins all the rows you select to one row
              and normalizes the content;</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Insert new line after</uicontrol> - inserts a new line after the line at
              the caret position.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
