<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="the-action-dialog">
  <title>The Action Dialog</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Action</uicontrol> dialog allows you to edit an existing document type action
      or create one. To open this dialog, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Option</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> Document Type Association</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>, select a document type, and click <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> or
        <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>. The <uicontrol>Document type</uicontrol> dialog is presented. In
      this dialog go to the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab, click <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol>,
      select an action, and click <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_EditEntry16.png"/>
        Edit</uicontrol> or <uicontrol><image href="../img/Add16.png"/> New</uicontrol>.</p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Action Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/the-action-dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The following options are available:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>ID</uicontrol> - specifies a unique action identifier;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - specifies the name of the action. This name is displayed
          as a tooltip or as a menu item;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Menu access key</uicontrol> - on Windows, the menu items are accessed using
          the <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/alt_letter"/>
          shortcut, when the menu is visible. The letter is visually represented by underlining the
          first letter from the menu item name having the same value;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> - a description of the action;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Large icon</uicontrol> - select an image that <ph keyref="product"/> uses for
          the toolbar action.<note>A good practice is to store the image files inside the framework
            directory and use the <codeph>${frameworks}</codeph>editor variable to make the image
            relative to the framework location. In case the images are bundled in a <term>jar</term>
            archive, together with some Java operations implementation for instance, it is
            convenient to refer the images by their relative path location in the
              <term>class-path</term>.</note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Small icon</uicontrol> - select an image that <ph keyref="product"/> uses for
          the contextual menu icon;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Shortcut key</uicontrol> - this field allows you to configure a shortcut key
          for the action you are editing. The <codeph>+</codeph> character separates the keys. The
          shortcut you are specifying in this field is platform-independent. The following modifiers
          are used:<ul>
            <li><codeph>M1</codeph> represents the
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Command</shortcut></uicontrol> key on MacOS X, and the
                  <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol> key on other platforms;</li>
            <li><codeph>M2</codeph> represents the <uicontrol><shortcut>Shift</shortcut></uicontrol>
              key;</li>
            <li><codeph>M3</codeph> represents the
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Option</shortcut></uicontrol> key on MacOS X, and the
                  <uicontrol><shortcut>Alt</shortcut></uicontrol> key on other platforms;</li>
            <li><codeph>M4</codeph> represents the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol>
              key on MacOS X, and is undefined on other platforms.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Operations</uicontrol><p>In this section of the <uicontrol>Action</uicontrol>
            dialog you are configuring the functionality of the action you are editing. An action
            has one or mode operation modes. The evaluation of an XPath expression activates an
            operation mode. The first enabled operation mode is activated when you trigger the
            action. The scope of the XPath expression must consist only of element nodes and
            attribute nodes of the edited document. Otherwise, the XPath expression does not return
            a match and does not fire the action. More details here:<xref
              href="xpath-activation-expressions.dita#xpath-activation-expressions"/>.</p><p>The
            following options are available in this section:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>When this XPath expression is true</uicontrol> - an XPath 2.0
                expression that applies to elements and attributes. More details here:<xref
                  href="xpath-activation-expressions.dita#xpath-activation-expressions"/>.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>invoke the operation</uicontrol> - specifies the invoked
                operation;</li>
              <li><uicontrol>with the arguments</uicontrol> - specifies the arguments of the invoked
                operation;</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> - allows you to edit the arguments of the
                operation.</li>
            </ul></p></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Operation priority</uicontrol> - increases or decreases the priority of an
          operation. The operations are invoked in the order of their priority. In case more than
          one XPath expression is true, the operation with the highest priority is invoked;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> - adds an operation;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> - removes an operation;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Duplicate</uicontrol> - duplicates an operation.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
