<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="track-changes-limitations">
  <title>Track Changes Limitations</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_dmx_bgk_54b">There are some inherent limitations to the <xref
        keyref="glossentry_track-changes"><term>Change Tracking</term></xref> feature. These limitations include the following:<ul id="ul_emx_bgk_54b">
        <li id="li_fmx_bgk_54b"><b>Limitations to rejected changes</b> - Recording changes has limitations and there is
          no guarantee that rejecting all changes will return the document exactly to its original
          state.</li>
        <li id="li_gmx_bgk_54b"><b>Limitations to hierarchical changes</b> - Recorded changes are not hierarchical, a
          change cannot contain other changes inside. For example, if you delete an insertion made
          by another user, then reject the deletion, the information about the author who made the
          previous insertion is not preserved.</li>
        <li id="li_hmx_bgk_54b"><b>Limitations to using certain actions</b> - Some actions cannot be implemented with
          the <xref keyref="glossentry_track-changes"><term>Track Changes</term> feature</xref>
          enabled. For example, some table-related actions (<uicontrol><image
              href="../img/DeleteRow16.png"/>Delete Row(s)</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/DeleteColumn16.gif"/>Delete Column(s)</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/TableJoin16.png"/>Join Cells</uicontrol>, <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/TableSplitCell16.png"/>Split Cell</uicontrol>) ignore the <term>Track
            Changes</term> feature. The <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/RenameElement16.png" id="image_d1s_y4d_cs"/>Rename Element</uicontrol> action also does not record tracked
          changes.</li>
        <li id="li_imx_bgk_54b"><b>Possible Serialization Limitation</b> - If you have equivalent
          adjacent tracked changes, for example, you see two back-to-back changes in the
            <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> pane that have identical properties (the same user,
          timestamp, content, etc.), when you save the document, it is sometimes possible for the
          document to only contain a single processing instruction.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="section_er4_mtj_nwb">
      <title>DITA-Specific Track Changes Limitations</title>
      <ul id="ul_ucn_ntj_nwb">
        <li>When presenting cross references or related links in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
          visual editing mode, if the link target element has a title that contains change tracking,
          the presented link reference content is shown as if all tracked changes in the target
          element's title have been accepted.</li>
        <li>When presenting phrases with key references in the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> visual
          editing mode, if the defined key has a keyword that contains change tracking, the
          presented referenced keyword reference content is shown as if all track changes inside it
          have been accepted.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="section_xpl_cxv_pxb">
      <title>Publishing-Specific Track Changes Limitations</title>
      <ul id="ul_f43_dxv_pxb">
        <li><b>Deletion Change Tracking Limitation</b> - When displaying tracked changes in
          published outputs (for example, when enabling the
            <codeph>show.changes.and.comments</codeph> DITA parameter in WebHelp and PDF
          publications), the deleted content will be presented as plain XML with the tag names
          serialized as plain text. Key references and content key references are also not resolved
          in the presented deleted content.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
