<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="transform-xquery-advanced-saxon-options">
  <title>Advanced Saxon HE/PE/EE XQuery Transformation Options</title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <body>
    <p>The XQuery transformation scenario allows you to configure advanced options that are specific
      for the Saxon HE (Home Edition), PE (Professional Edition), and EE (Enterprise Edition)
      engines. <ph product="editor editorEclipse developer developerEclipse"> They are the same
        options as <xref href="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita">the values set in the user
          preferences</xref> but they are configured as a specific set of transformation options for
        each transformation scenario. </ph>
    </p>
    <p>The advanced options for Saxon <ph keyref="saxon9FullVersion"/> Home Edition (HE),
      Professional Edition (PE), and Enterprise Edition (EE) are as follows:</p>
    <ul id="ul_gtk_n4r_4q">
      <li conref="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita#preferences-xquery-saxon/xquery-use-config-file"/>
      <li conref="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita#preferences-xquery-saxon/xquery-recoverable-errors"/>
      <li conref="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita#preferences-xquery-saxon/xquery-strip-whitespaces"/>
      <li><uicontrol>Optimization level ("-opt")</uicontrol> - This option allows optimization to be
        suppressed in cases where reducing the compiling time is important, where optimization
        conflicts with debugging, or causes extension functions with side-effects to behave
        unpredictably.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The following advanced option is specific for Saxon <ph keyref="saxon9FullVersion"/>
      Professional Edition (PE) and Enterprise Edition (EE) only:</p>
    <ul id="ul_oql_q4r_4q">
      <li conref="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita#preferences-xquery-saxon/xquery-allow-calls"/>
    </ul>
    <p>The advanced options that are specific for Saxon <ph keyref="saxon9FullVersion"/> Enterprise
      Edition (EE) are as follows:</p>
    <ul id="ul_jwk_n4r_4q">
      <li conref="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita#preferences-xquery-saxon/xquery-val-source-file"/>
      <li conref="preferences-xslt-saxon8.dita#preferences-xslt-saxon8/saxon-option-outval"/>
      <li conref="preferences-xslt-saxon8.dita#preferences-xslt-saxon8/generate_bytecode_option"/>
      <li conref="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita#preferences-xquery-saxon/xquery-enable-update"
        conrefend="preferences-xquery-saxon.dita#preferences-xquery-saxon/xquery-saxon-ee-advanced-options-end"
      />
    </ul>
    <ul>
      <li id="initializer-class">
        <uicontrol>Initializer class</uicontrol> - Equivalent to the <term>-init</term> Saxon
        command-line argument. The value is the name of a user-supplied class that implements the
          <apiname>net.sf.saxon.lib.Initializer</apiname> interface. This initializer is called
        during the initialization process, and may be used to set any options required on the
        configuration programmatically. It is particularly useful for tasks such as registering
        extension functions, collations, or external object models, especially in Saxon-HE where the
        option cannot be set via a configuration file. Saxon only calls the initializer when running
        from the command line, but the same code may be invoked to perform initialization when
        running user application code.<note type="important">The <xref
            href="xslt-tab.dita#xslt-tab/advanced-options">advanced Saxon-HE/PE/EE options
            configured in a transformation scenario</xref> override the Saxon-HE/PE/EE options
          defined globally.</note>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
