<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="transformation-scenarios-sharing" >
  <title>Sharing the Transformation Scenarios</title>
  <!--Proofed--><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Transformation Scenario<indexterm>sharing the transformation scenarios; project level
            scenarios</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The transformation scenarios can be shared with other users by saving them at project level.
      When you create a new transformation scenario or edit an existing one, there is a
        <uicontrol>Storage</uicontrol> option to control whether the scenarios are stored in
        <uicontrol>Global Options</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p><image href="../img/storage_options.png" id="image_vtt_rsr_1r"/></p>
    <p>Selecting <uicontrol>Global Options</uicontrol> stores the scenario in the global options
      that are stored in the user home directory.</p>
    <p>Selecting <uicontrol>Project Options</uicontrol> stores the scenario in the project file and
      can be shared with other users that have access to the project. If your project is saved on a
      source versioning/sharing system (CVS, SVN, Source Safe, etc.) then your team will have access
      to the scenarios that you define. When you create a scenario at the project level, the URLs
      from the scenario become relative to the project URL.</p>
    <p>When using the <uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_ApplyStyleSheet20.png" id="image_d2h_hdf_1r"
        />Apply Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> or <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/bt_transform_config.png" id="image_pw3_1rr_1r"/>Configure Transformation
        Scenario(s)</uicontrol> actions, the predefined scenarios are presented according to the
      current detected document type, along with your created custom scenarios. The following
      screenshot shows default scenarios for a <i>DITA</i> document along with several custom
      transformation scenarios. The <image href="../img/bt_Key16.png" id="image_qr5_npr_1r"/> key
      symbol before the scenario name indicates that the scenario can only be modified from the
        <xref href="preferences-document-type-association.dita"><uicontrol>Document Type
          Association</uicontrol></xref> preferences page.</p>
    <fig id="figure-project-level-options">
      <title>Transformation Scenario List Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_scenario_list_dialog.png" id="image_s2r_nqr_1r"/>
    </fig>
    <p>You can also change the storage options on existing transformation scenarios by using the
        <uicontrol>Change storage</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu of the list of
      scenarios.</p>
    <p>Other preferences can also be stored at the project level. For more information, see the
        <xref href="preferences-sharing.dita">Preference Sharing</xref> section.</p>
  </body>
</topic>