<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="translator-helper-addon">
  <title>Translator Helper Add-on</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Add-ons<indexterm>Translator Helper</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Translator helper</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> offers an add-on that provides experimental support for helping
      translators. Once the add-on is installed, you can use <xref
        href="https://translate.google.com" format="html" scope="external">Google Translate</xref>
      to create a preliminary translation for your XML content, translation which can later be
      manually improved. The add-on is useful also to quickly translate XML content and show
      potential customers how a DITA project will look like in their native language.</p>
    <p>To install the add-on, follow these instructions:</p>
    <ol id="ol_r12_jyz_rmb">
      <li>Go to <b>Help > Install new add-ons...</b> to open an add-on selection dialog box.</li>
      <li>Enter or paste <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Addons/default/updateSite.xml" scope="external"
          format="html"/> in the <b>Show add-ons from</b> field.</li>
      <li>Select the <b>Translator Helper</b> add-on and click <b>Next</b>.</li>
      <li>Select the <b>I accept all terms of the end user license agreement</b> option and click
          <b>Finish</b>.</li>
      <li>Restart <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
    </ol>
    <section id="section_s12_jyz_rmb">
      <title>Features:</title>
      <ol id="ol_t12_jyz_rmb">
        <li>You can translate the edited content using <uicontrol>Google Translate</uicontrol> to
          various languages:<ul id="ul_u12_jyz_rmb">
            <li>Select the content to translate in the <b>Author</b> visual editing mode. You can
              select multiple paragraphs and even select all the document's content.
                <uicontrol>Google Translate</uicontrol> is limited to translating 5000 characters so
              you might need to translate your XML document in incremental stages.</li>
            <li>Right click. Select <uicontrol>Google Translate To</uicontrol> and choose the target
              language.</li>
            <li>Copy the translated content from the web page which will open in your default
              configured web browser. You can use the <uicontrol>Copy translation</uicontrol> button
              in the <uicontrol>Google Translate</uicontrol> web page to make sure you have copied
              the entire translation.</li>
            <li>Click <b>Replace</b> in the <b>Translate using Google Translate</b> dialog that
              showed up in <ph keyref="product"/>. The selected content should now be replaced with
              the translated content, obeying the original XML markup.</li>
            <li>In addition you can choose in the <b>Translate using Google Translate</b> dialog to
              show the original document content in the <b>Translator Helper</b> side view. This
              will allow you to double check and improve on the translated text.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li>You can have your original content side by side with the content that you are editing,
          so you can translate correctly and easy by right clicking in the
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> visual editing mode and invoking the <b>Original Content
            Side By Side</b> action. The side view will automatically scroll to the original content
          while you are translating the current XML document.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
