<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="transformation-scenarios-sharing" >
  <title>Sharing the Transformation Scenarios</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Transformation Scenario<indexterm>sharing the transformation scenarios; project level
            scenarios</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The transformation scenarios can be shared with other users by saving them at project level.
      In the lower part of the dialog showing the list of scenarios you will find two radio buttons
      controlling where the scenarios are stored: <uicontrol>Global Scenarios</uicontrol> and
        <uicontrol>Project Scenarios</uicontrol>.</p>
    <fig id="figure-project-level-options">
      <title>Transformation Scenario List Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_scenario_list_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>Selecting <uicontrol>Global Scenarios</uicontrol> ensures that the scenarios are saved in the
      global options stored in the user home directory.</p>
    <p>After changing the selection to <uicontrol>Project Scenarios</uicontrol>, the scenario list
      will be stored in the project file. If your project is saved on a source versioning/sharing
      system (CVS, SVN, Source Safe, etc..) then your team can use the scenarios you defined. When
      you create a scenario at the project level, the URLs from the scenario become relative to the
      project URL.</p>
    <p>Predefined scenarios are presented according to the current document's detected type. The
      screenshot above shows all default scenarios for a <i>DITA</i> document and several custom
      transformation scenarios. The key symbol <image href="../img/bt_Key16.png"/> before the
      scenario name, indicates that the scenario can only be modified from the <xref
        href="preferences-document-type-association.dita"><uicontrol>Document Type
          Association</uicontrol></xref> preferences page.</p>
    <p>Other preferences can also be stored at the project level. For more information, see the
        <xref href="preferences-sharing.dita">Preference Sharing</xref> section.</p>
  </body>
</topic>