<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="unicode-toolbar">
  <title>Inserting Symbols</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit<indexterm>Unicode toolbar</indexterm><indexterm>Character
          map</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit Menu <indexterm>Insert from Character Map</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can insert symbols by using the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol><image href="../img/InsertFromCharactersMap16.png" id="image_p21_hsv_5r"/>Insert
          from Character Map</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action. This displays the <uicontrol>Character Map</uicontrol> dialog box.</p>
    <section id="section-character-map-dialog"><title>The Character Map Dialog Box</title><fig
        id="fig_tfx_btv_5r">
        <image href="../img/sa_character_map_dialog.png" id="image_jv2_dtv_5r"/>
      </fig>The <uicontrol>Character Map</uicontrol> dialog box allows you to visualize all
      characters available in a font, pick the character you need and insert it in the document you
      are editing. You can also access this dialog box by using the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Insert from Character Map</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> action.<p>Use the <uicontrol>Font</uicontrol> box to choose the font for which
        you want to display characters. To see only a certain range of characters, use the
          <uicontrol>Unicode Block</uicontrol> box. This will filter the number of characters
        displayed, showing only a contiguous range of characters corresponding to the selected
        block. Unassigned characters are displayed as empty squares.</p><p>The available characters
        are listed in two tabs:<ul id="ul_vb5_tp4_bp">
          <li><uicontrol>Compact</uicontrol> - matrix-like representation which displays only
            characters.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Details</uicontrol> - displays the available characters in a tabular
            format, presenting their decimal and hexadecimal value along with their
            description.</li>
        </ul></p><p>Use the <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> field to search for a character by one of
        the following attributes:<uicontrol>decimal</uicontrol> value,
          <uicontrol>hexadecimal</uicontrol> value or description. Selecting the
          <uicontrol>description</uicontrol> option places the focus on the
          <uicontrol>Details</uicontrol> tab. If you enter a character description in the
          <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> field, the <uicontrol>description</uicontrol> option is
        selected automatically. The searching operation starts as soon as you start typing
        characters in the <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> field.</p><p>Press the
          <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> button to insert the selected character in the current
        editor at caret position. You will see the character in the editor if <xref
          href="preferences-fonts.dita">the editor font</xref> is able to render it. The
          <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> button copies it to the clipboard without inserting it in the
        editor. You can see the name and range name of a character either at the bottom of the
        dialog box, or when hovering the mouse cursor over the character.</p><p>The
          <uicontrol>Character Map</uicontrol> dialog box cannot be used to insert Unicode
        characters in <xref href="grid-editor-introduction.dita">the grid version of a document
          editor</xref>. Accordingly, the <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> button of the dialog box
        will be disabled if the current document is edited in <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol>
      mode.</p></section>
  </body>
</topic>
