<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="unicode-toolbar">
  <title>The Symbols Toolbar</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit<indexterm>Unicode toolbar</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To display the <uicontrol>Insert from Character Map</uicontrol> action on the main toolbar,
      right click the toolbar and from the contextual menu select
      <uicontrol>Symbols</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_insert_from_charmap_button.png"/> Insert from Character
        Map</uicontrol> action opens the <uicontrol>Character Map</uicontrol> dialog allowing you to
      select one character in the matrix of all characters available in a font and insert it in the
      edited document. This action is available in the <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> menu also.</p>
    <fig id="figure-character-map-dialog">
      <title>The Character Map dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_charmap_dialog.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>You can search for a character by its <uicontrol>decimal</uicontrol> or
        <uicontrol>hexadecimal</uicontrol> value and also by its <uicontrol>description</uicontrol>,
      using the <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> field. Selecting the
        <uicontrol>description</uicontrol> option places the focus on the
        <uicontrol>Details</uicontrol> tab. This tab displays the available characters in a tabular
      format, presenting their decimal and hexadecimal value along with their description. In case
      you enter a character description in the <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> field, the
        <uicontrol>description</uicontrol> option is selected automatically. If the
        <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> field is filled in, the searching operation in the map
      starts.</p>
    <p>The character selected in the character table or an entity with the decimal code or the
      hexadecimal code of that character can be inserted in the current editor. You will see it in
      the editor if <xref href="preferences-fonts.dita">the editor font</xref> is able to render it.
      The <i>Insert</i> button inserts the selected character in the editor. The
        <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol> button copies it to the clipboard without inserting it in the
      editor. You can see the name and range name of a character either at the bottom of the dialog,
      or when hovering the cursor over the character.</p>
    <p>The <i>Character Map</i> dialog cannot be used to insert Unicode characters in <xref
        href="grid-editor-introduction.dita">the grid version of a document editor</xref>.
      Accordingly, the <i>Insert</i> button of the dialog will be disabled if the current document
      is edited in grid mode.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
