<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="using-webapp-github">
  <title>Using the <ph keyref="webapp"/> with a GitHub Repository</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webapp"/> includes a <i>GitHub</i> plugin that allows you to use the <ph
        keyref="webapp"/> to edit files stored in a GitHub repository. The procedure in this topic
      assumes that this plugin is enabled in your installation of <ph keyref="webapp"/>.</p>
    <p>To open a file stored in a GitHub repository, use the dedicated <i>GitHub Open Action</i>
      button in the <uicontrol>Open file</uicontrol> section of the main dashboard.</p>
    <p>To commit a file to a GitHub repository, select the <uicontrol>Commit on GitHub</uicontrol>
      action. A dialog box will open that allows you to enter a <i>commit message</i> and displays
      the branch on which the commit will be processed (you can also edit the name of the branch in
      this dialog box). <ul>
        <li>If you committed on the same branch as the currently opened document or on a new branch,
          and no conflicts were found, the operation is processed.</li>
        <li>If you commit on an existing branch that is different from branch of the currently
          opened documents or when someone else has committed the same file, and a conflict is
          detected, a confirmation dialog box will appear.<fig>
            <title>Commit Status Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/commit_status.png"/>
          </fig><p>The <uicontrol>Commit Status</uicontrol> dialog box allows you to choose the
            following options:<ul>
              <li>You can click the link at the top of the dialog box to see the difference between
                the two commits.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Commit on a fresh branch</uicontrol> - Creates a new branch that
                contains your version of the document so that you can merge the changes at a later
                time, after the conflicts have been solved.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Commit anyway</uicontrol> - Commits the changes regardless of whether
                or not there was a conflict.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Cancel</uicontrol> - Cancels the operation and your changes are not
                committed to the repository.</li>
            </ul></p></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
