<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="using-form-controls">
  <title>Using Form Controls in Author Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Author editing mode<indexterm>Form Controls</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML documents<indexterm>Author Mode editing<indexterm>Form
            Controls</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Form Controls in Author mode</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Form controls make it easier to capture, organize, and edit content. They are especially
      helpful for less technical users because form controls provide a way to interact with the
      content of a document in a graphical manner without intimidating the user with the XML
      structure.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> includes a variety of <xref href="form-controls.dita#form-controls"
        >built-in form controls</xref> that can be <xref
        href="form-controls.dita#form-controls/how_to_add_a_builtin_form_control_in_author_mode"
        >defined in CSS stylesheets that are used to render <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        mode</xref>. You can also <xref
        href="implementing-custom-form-controls.dita#implementing-custom-form-controls">implement
        custom form controls</xref> for more specific needs.  The types of built-in form controls
      that are available include: <ul
        conkeyref="reusables-author-mode-customization/built-in-form-controls-ul">
        <li/>
        <li/>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The following image is an example of several form controls rendered in
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. The first (<i>Direct manager</i>) is a combo box with
      both a drop-down menu and an editable text field. This is followed by a simple text field
        (<i>Homepage</i>), and the <uicontrol>[ + ]</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>[ - ]</uicontrol>
      icons also represent button form controls that are assigned specific actions to add or delete
      records from the document.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_rw1_jkt_1s">
        <title>Example of Form Controls in Author Mode</title>
        <image href="../img/form_control_ex.png" id="image_n2p_nkt_1s"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>You can use your imagination to envision the multitude of ways that you can use form controls
      to make the editing experience for content authors easier and more efficient. As a working
      example, a bundled <i>samples</i> project (located in the <filepath>samples</filepath> folder
      inside the <ph keyref="product"/> installation directory) contains a file called
        <filepath>personal.xml</filepath> that contains form controls. You can use this file, along
      with its corresponding <filepath>personal.css</filepath> file to experiment with an example of
      how form controls can be implemented in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode. </p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="form-controls.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
