<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="using-check-spelling">
  <title>Spell Checking</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Edit<indexterm>check spelling</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Spelling</uicontrol> dialog allows you to check the spelling of the edited
      document. To open this dialog, click the <uicontrol>
        <image href="../img/bt_check_spelling_button.png"/> Check Spelling</uicontrol> toolbar
      button.</p>
    <fig id="check-spelling-dialog-oxygen" product="editor author developer">
      <title>The Check Spelling Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_check_spelling.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="check-spelling-dialog-oxygenEclipse" product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The Check Spelling Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_check_spelling.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The dialog contains the following fields:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Unrecognized word</uicontrol> - contains the word that cannot be found in the
        selected dictionary. The word is also highlighted in the XML document;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> - the character string which is suggested to replace
        the unrecognized word;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Guess</uicontrol> - displays a list of words suggested to replace the unknown
        word. Double click a word to automatically insert it in the document and resume the spell
        checking process;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Default language</uicontrol> - allows you to select the default dictionary used
        by the spelling engine;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Paragraph language</uicontrol> - in an XML document you can mix content written
        in different languages. To tell the spell checker engine what language was used to write a
        specific section, you need to set the language code in the <codeph>lang</codeph> or
          <codeph>xml:lang</codeph> attribute to that section. <ph
          keyref="product"/> automatically detects such
        sections and instructs the spell checker engine to apply the appropriate dictionary;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol> - replaces the currently highlighted word in the XML
        document, with the selected word in the <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol> field;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Replace All</uicontrol> - replaces all occurrences of the currently highlighted
        word in the XML document, with the selected word in the <uicontrol>Replace with</uicontrol>
        field;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore</uicontrol> - ignores the first occurrence of the unrecognized word and
        allows you to continue checking the document. <ph
          keyref="product"/> skips the content of the
        XML elements <xref href="spell-check-ignore-words.dita#spell-check-ignore-words"
          format="dita">marked as ignorable</xref>;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Ignore All</uicontrol> - ignores all instances of the unknown word in the
        current document;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Learn</uicontrol> - includes the unrecognized word in the list of valid
        words;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Options</uicontrol> - sets the configuration options of the spell checker;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Begin at caret position</uicontrol> - instructs the spell checker to begin
        checking the document starting from the current cursor position;</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Close</uicontrol> - closes the dialog.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>