<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="using_cf_with_cms">
  <title>Using Content Fusion with a CMS</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Content Author Guide<indexterm>CMS information</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>CMS information</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Review Tasks can also be created using files from a CMS, provided that the CMS has a
      connector for <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>.</p>
    <note>The CMS usually provides a very customized version of <b>Oxygen</b>, so some of the
      methods presented below may not work.</note>
    <section id="section_fgz_wyx_rfb">
      <title>Uploading a Review Task</title>
      <p>To create a review task using files from a CMS, there are several possibilities:</p>
      <ul id="ul_jnt_rxx_rfb">
        <li>You can open the file in the editor and then use the <uicontrol><image
              href="../img/ShowFusion18.png" id="image_ivx_cl4_f1b"/>Add File to Review
            Task</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu.</li>
        <li>If you work with DITA resources, you can open the map in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
            Manager</uicontrol> view and use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowFusion18.png"
            />Add File to Review Task</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu. You can also drag
          the map entries and drop them in the <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box.</li>
        <li>If it is available in your customized version of <b>Oxygen</b>, you can drag resources
          from the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view and drop them in the
            <uicontrol>New Task</uicontrol> box.</li>
        <li>If you have a special view for exploring the server containing documents on your CMS,
          you can also drag resources from that view and drop them in the <uicontrol>New
            Task</uicontrol> box.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="section_cb5_yxx_rfb">
      <title>Specifying the Root DITA Map</title>
      <p>If you choose to add the files to the task from <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol>,
        the root map that is specified in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> is
        automatically added as the Context DITA Map. Otherwise, if you work with DITA projects, you
        should manually add the root DITA map to the task.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_ffs_dyx_rfb">
      <title>Getting the changes</title>
      <p>To retrieve the changes made by reviewers and save them in the CMS, follow these steps:<ol
          id="ol_w4w_myx_rfb">
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Get Changes</uicontrol> link in the task box. The <xref
              href="merging_changes.dita">merge tool</xref> is displayed.</li>
          <li>Merge the changes from the remote files with the current version of the files. The
            files are automatically opened in the editor as modified with all the changes applied. </li>
          <li>Save the files using the specific procedure for your CMS.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="creating_and_uploading_tasks.dita"/>
      <link href="merging_changes.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
