<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="validating-html">
  <title>HTML Validation</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>HTML documents<indexterm>Validation</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_pxh_cgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> includes a built-in default validator used for
      validating HTML documents. It is based upon the W3C HTML Validator and the HTML documents are
      validated against the <xref href="https://www.w3.org/TR/html53/" format="html"
        scope="external">W3C HTML5 specification</xref>. The validator in <ph keyref="product"/>
      only supports HTML5 structure. It presents the errors in the editor similar to XML documents.
      It also checks the embedded CSS content and the warnings and errors are presented similar to
      the <xref href="validating-css-stylesheets.dita">CSS editor</xref>.</p>
    <section id="section_ant_dts_flb">
      <title>Validating HTML Against a Schematron</title>
      <p id="p_qxh_cgk_54b">It is also possible to validate HTML documents against a Schematron schema. Besides the
        default HTML validator, <ph keyref="product"/> also includes a built-in <i>HTML Schematron
          Validator</i> engine. There are several ways to validate an HTML document against a
          Schematron:<ul id="ul_ck2_m5s_flb">
          <li id="li_rxh_cgk_54b"><b>Configure a Validation Scenario</b> - You can create or edit a
            validation scenario, change the <uicontrol>File type</uicontrol> column to <i>HTML
              Document</i>, change the <uicontrol>Validation engine</uicontrol> column to <i>HTML
              Schematron Validator</i>, and specify the Schematron document in the
              <uicontrol>Schema</uicontrol> column.</li>
          <li id="li_sxh_cgk_54b"><b>Manually Validate a Single Document</b> - You can use the <uicontrol>Validate
              with</uicontrol> action from the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ValidateDrop.png"
                id="image_ct1_cnd_w3b"/>Validation</uicontrol> drop-down menu on the toolbar. This
            opens a dialog box where you can specify the Schematron document to validate the current
            document against.</li>
          <li id="li_txh_cgk_54b"><b>Batch Validate Multiple Documents</b> - You can select multiple
            HTML documents in the <ph product="author developer editor json"
                ><uicontrol>Project</uicontrol></ph>
            <ph product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Project
                Explorer</uicontrol></ph> view, right-click, and use the <uicontrol>Validate with
              schema</uicontrol> action from the <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol> submenu. This opens
            a dialog box where you can specify the Schematron document to validate the selected
            documents against.</li>
        </ul><note type="other" othertype="Notes" id="note_uxh_cgk_54b">
          <ul id="ul_zjg_r1t_flb">
            <li id="li_vxh_cgk_54b">The Schematron must use the HTML5 namespace to reference the elements from the
              instance.</li>
            <li id="li_wxh_cgk_54b">Implicit HTML elements (i.e. <xmlelement>html</xmlelement>,
                <xmlelement>body</xmlelement>, <xmlelement>tbody</xmlelement>) must be included in
              an XPath expression in the Schematron document, even if they are missing from the HTML
              document.</li>
          </ul>
        </note></p>
      <note type="tip" id="note_xxh_cgk_54b">The <ph keyref="product"/> installation directory includes a
          <filepath>samples</filepath> folder that contains numerous sample files to help you learn
        about features, certain file types, and XML technologies. For example, inside the
          <filepath>samples</filepath> folder, there is an <filepath>html</filepath> folder with a
          <filepath>schematron</filepath> subfolder where you can find some samples that illustrate
        HTML validation against a Schematron schema.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="section_xmy_pts_flb">
      <title>Validating HTML Against Other Types of Schema</title>
      <p id="p_yxh_cgk_54b">If your HTML document is XML well-formed, you could also configure a
        validation scenario to validate it as an XML document against other types of schemas. You
        would create or edit a validation scenario, make sure the <uicontrol>File type</uicontrol>
        column is set to <i>XML Document</i>, select the appropriate <uicontrol>Validation
          engine</uicontrol>, and specify the schema document in the <uicontrol>Schema</uicontrol>
        column. </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
