<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-bitbucket-server-integration">
  <title>Link Bitbucket to Other Atlassian or External Apps Using OAuth 1.0</title>
  <body>
    <p>To link Bitbucket to other Atlassian products or external applications using OAuth 1.0,
      follow this procedure:</p>
    <ol id="ol_onp_zln_hdc">
      <li>Go to the Bitbucket server <uicontrol>Administration</uicontrol> page. Click on
          <uicontrol>Application links</uicontrol> and select <b>Create link</b>.</li>
      <li>Select <i>Atlassian product</i> as the link type. This option also works for external
        applications. This is the original application links mechanism – we’ve left it under this
        option so users can still use their OAuth 1.0 integrations.</li>
      <li>Select the <uicontrol>Application type</uicontrol> (either <i>Atlassian product</i> or
          <i>External application</i>. Enter the URL of your Atlassian product or external
        application (e.g. enter the home page address of your <b>Oxygen XML Web Author</b> instance
        as the application URL).<p id="p_rk2_hlr_ldc"><image href="../img/wa-bitbucket-screen1.png"
          /></p></li>
      <li>A <uicontrol>Configure Application URL</uicontrol> dialog box prompts you to confirm the
        URL. Check that it is correct and click <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol>.</li>
      <li>In the resulting <uicontrol>Link Applications</uicontrol> dialog box, define a name for
        the application link to Web Author in the <uicontrol>Application Name</uicontrol> field.
        Check that the <uicontrol>Application Type</uicontrol> is set to <i>Generic Application</i>.
        Leave all the other fields blank and click <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol>.</li>
      <li>The <uicontrol>Configure Application Links</uicontrol> page should display the new
        application link. Click on the pencil under the <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> column to
        edit the application link.</li>
      <li>Click on the <uicontrol>Incoming Authentication</uicontrol> tab to configure the OAuth 1.0
        parameters.</li>
      <li>Enter a <uicontrol>Consumer Key</uicontrol>. It must be unique in regard to other
        application links and be the same as the one you enter here. Next, enter a
          <uicontrol>Consumer Name</uicontrol>, the <uicontrol>Public Key</uicontrol>, and
          <uicontrol>Consumer Callback URL</uicontrol>. Then <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>Close</uicontrol>.</li>
    </ol>
  </body>
</topic>
