<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-cc-configuration">
  <title>Customizing the Content Completion Assistant</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Customizing the Content Completion Assistant</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <xref keyref="glossentry_content-completion-assistant"><term>Content Completion
          Assistant</term></xref> can be customized for <term>Oxygen XML Web Author</term> using
      similar methods that you would use to customize this feature in standalone distributions of
        <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>. There are several methods that you can use, including
      the following:</p>
    <section id="section_zzf_pns_vz">
      <title>Customizing Content Completion in the Document Type Configuration Dialog Box</title>
      <p>You can use the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
          format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Document Type</uicontrol> configuration dialog
          box</xref> to specify which elements or actions should be proposed in the <b>Content
          Completion Assistant</b>. To use this method, follow this procedure:<ol>
          <li>Open the <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol> dialog box <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>(Options</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Preferences)</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> and go to <uicontrol>Document Type Associations</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Select your document type and click the <uicontrol>Extend</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li>Go to the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab and <uicontrol>Content
              Completion</uicontrol> subtab. In this subtab, you can specify:<ul>
              <li>Elements to remove from the proposals listed in the <term>Content Completion
                  Assistant</term>.</li>
              <li>Actions to be added to the proposals listed in the <term>Content Completion
                  Assistant</term>.<note>To add an action that is implemented in JavaScript, you
                  need to define a stub action with the same ID in the
                    <uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> subtab and add it in the <uicontrol>Content
                    Completion</uicontrol> subtab.</note></li>
            </ul></li>
          <li> Create an archive that only contains your custom framework folder and <xref
              href="customizing_frameworks.dita#customizing_frameworks/deploying_a_framework">upload
              the changes to your <term>framework</term> to Web Author</xref>.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_hfb_vns_vz">
      <title>Customizing Content Completion Using a Configuration File</title>
      <p>You can use a <filepath>cc_config.xml</filepath> configuration file for your custom
        framework to configure the values that are proposed in certain contexts, to customize the
        attributes or elements that are proposed, or to customize how certain aspects of the
        proposals are rendered in the interface. You would then save the configuration file in the
          <filepath>resources</filepath> folder inside your custom framework directory and <xref
          href="customizing_frameworks.dita#customizing_frameworks/deploying_a_framework">upload
          your <term>framework</term> to Web Author</xref>.<ul>
          <li>To configure the possible elements or attributes that are proposed in the
              <term>Content Completion Assistant</term>, see <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/configure-elements-attr-cc-individually.html"
              format="html" scope="external">Configuring the Proposals for Elements and
              Attributes</xref>.</li>
          <li>To configure the possible values for attributes or elements that are proposed in the
              <term>Content Completion Assistant</term>, see <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/configuring-content-completion-proposals.html"
              format="html" scope="external">Configuring the Proposals for Attribute and Element
              Values</xref>.</li>
          <li>To configure how the elements are rendered in the <term>Content Completion
              Assistant</term>, see <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/rendering-elements-cc-author.html"
              format="html" scope="external">Customizing the Rendering of Elements</xref>.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_gxd_wns_vz">
      <title>Changing the Keyboard Shortcut for Invoking the Content Completion Assistant</title>
      <p>By default, the <term>Content Completion Assistant</term> is invoked automatically when you
        press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>. For non-technical users, it may be
        helpful to disable this feature and use the default behavior of typical word processors
        where pressing <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> will insert a new
        paragraph. For information about how to achieve this, see <xref
          href="wa-disable-content-completion.dita#wa-disable-content-completion"/>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
