<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-customization-dita-edit-topic-content">
  <title>Enabling the Mode for Editing DITA Map Content in One Document</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA specialization</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_hrs_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> offers a feature that can be enabled for Git
      integrations for displaying a DITA map with all of its referenced topic content expanded and
      editable in one document. This editing mode is supported for all Git repository providers
      except for <b>Bitbucket Server</b>. </p>
    <p id="p_irs_dgk_54b">To enable this feature, a <xref
        href="webauthor-integrating-file-storage.dita">custom file storage server</xref> connector
      must set the <codeph>inplaceReferenceEditingSupported</codeph>
      <xref href="web_author_api_concepts.dita#web_author_api_concepts/loading-option"
        >LoadingOption</xref> to <b>true</b>. When this feature is enabled, you need to take several
      aspects into account:</p>
    <ul id="ul_zlk_2gs_rnb">
      <li id="li_jrs_dgk_54b">Depending on the user workflow, you may need to add UI elements (such as form controls or
        contextual menu entries) to lock/unlock or check-in/check-out each topic reference.</li>
      <li id="li_krs_dgk_54b">If the connector implements a custom save behavior, you will need to use the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Editor/SDK/javadoc/ro/sync/ecss/extensions/api/access/AuthorEditorAccess.html#getUnsavedContentReferenceManager--"
          format="html" scope="external">UnsavedReferencesManager</xref> API to save the content in
        modified topic references.</li>
    </ul>
    <p id="p_lrs_dgk_54b">Once enabled, users can trigger this mode by selecting <uicontrol>Edit Topic
        Content</uicontrol> from the DITA Map  <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/DM_DisplayMode_drop.png" id="image_cg2_lt3_rnb"/>Display Mode</uicontrol>
      drop-down menu.</p>
    <p id="p_mrs_dgk_54b">When editing a DITA map in this mode, the editor provides actions for both editing topic
      content and editing map content. To implement this behavior, a special framework is used. This
      framework extends the DITA framework and adds some map-specific actions.<note type="other"
        othertype="Notes" id="note_nrs_dgk_54b">
        <ul id="ul_hrx_xr3_qnb">
          <li id="li_ors_dgk_54b">For performance reasons, only modified topics are validated.</li>
          <li id="li_prs_dgk_54b">Only top-level topics in a DITA file can be edited.</li>
        </ul>
      </note></p>
    <section id="section_wdp_g3d_ynb">
      <title>Document Type Customization</title>
      <p id="p_qrs_dgk_54b">When a DITA map is open for editing with topics expanded, the document type that is used is
          <b>DITA Map with Resolved Topics</b>. This is a built-in document type that can be
        customized according to your needs.</p>
      <p id="p_rrs_dgk_54b">This framework mixes configuration from the built-in DITA and DITA map
        document types. If you have a custom DITA framework extension, you have to make the same
        adjustments to the configuration of this framework.<note type="tip" id="note_srs_dgk_54b">To
          avoid duplicated configurations, you can use a <xref
            href="wa-framework-customization-script.dita">framework extension
        script</xref>.</note></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
