<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="WA-dita-map-tree-structure-editable">
  <title>Editable DITA Map Pane (Experimental)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editable DITA map pane</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_sl4_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> offers experimental support to make DITA maps
      editable as tree structures either in the main editor area or in the <xref
        href="WA-dita-topic-doc-type.dita#WA-dita-topic-doc-type/section_fhc_5qd_3jb"
          ><uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol> pane</xref>.</p>
    <p>The following URL GET parameters can be set to support this new feature:<ul
        id="ul_xll_1wv_rbc">
        <li><codeph>&amp;loadMapAsTree=true</codeph> - Load the editable map in the main editor area
          as an editable tree. The extra
            <codeph>&amp;editReferencesInPlace=true&amp;expandTopicRefs=false</codeph> GET
          parameters can be added to allow directly editing referenced sub maps.</li>
        <li><codeph>&amp;supportsEditableDitaMap=true&amp;showDitaMapView=true</codeph> - Load the
          editable map in the <b>DITA Map</b> side view. The extra
            <codeph>&amp;editReferencesInPlace=true&amp;expandTopicRefs=false</codeph> GET
          parameters can be added to allow directly editing referenced sub maps.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>When the <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol> pane becomes editable, the following features are
      available:</p>
    <ul id="ul_b2b_lr1_y1c">
      <li>An icon that represents its type of DITA resource is displayed on the left side of each
        topic or map reference. For example, a DITA <b>Map</b> is displayed with the <image
          href="../img/DITAMap16.png" id="image_brs_21k_nnb" alt="DITA map"/> icon, a DITA
          <b>Topic</b> is displayed with <image href="../img/DITATopic16.png" id="image_kp2_tzj_nnb"
          alt="DITA topic"/>, a DITA <b>Task</b> is displayed with <image
          href="../img/DITATask16.png" id="image_llk_l1k_nnb" alt="DITA task"/>, etc. If the
        referenced topic is missing or not well-formed XML, an error icon is presented instead.</li>
      <li>When you expand a topic or map reference, topic titles for the child topic references are
        computed and presented as the reference is expanded.</li>
      <li>Hovering over a topic reference presents a tooltip with information about the reference,
        such as the path of the file, any defined key name, key reference, key scope, processing
        role, or profiling attributes that are set on the topic reference or inherited by it. If the
        referenced topic is missing or not well formed XML, the tooltip presents details about the
        problem.</li>
      <li>Read-only content in referenced submaps is highlighted with a gray background color.</li>
      <li id="li_cn3_zgy_mbc">You can drag an external link and drop it within the editable DITA map
        to quickly insert a reference.</li>
      <li>You can use drag and drop to move topic references and organize your DITA map's
        content.</li>
    </ul>
    <section id="section_pzm_lnz_lbc">
      <title>Toolbar</title>
      <p>If the editable DITA map tree is open in the main editor area, the following actions are
        available on the upper toolbar:<ul id="ul_v2v_mnz_lbc">
          <li><uicontrol>Undo/Redo</uicontrol> - Undo/redo the most recent changes.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> - Saves changes.</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>More</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Download</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Downloads the currently edited DITA map.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog box where you can change the
            reference type or edit attributes for the currently selected topic reference.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog box where you can
            edit profiling attributes for the currently selected topic reference.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Topic Reference</uicontrol>  - Inserts a new topic reference at the
            specified location.</li>
          <li><b>Remove Reference</b> - Deletes the selected topic reference.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Move Up/Down/Promote/Demote</uicontrol> - Moves topic references up, down,
            promotes them, or demotes them using the toolbar actions or their corresponding
            shortcuts.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Show Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> - Displays profiling information
            directly on the topic reference. </li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_rbn_knz_lbc">
      <title>Contextual Menu</title>
      <p>You can right-click items in the <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol> pane and the following
        contextual menu actions become available:<ul id="ul_iw3_4r1_y1c">
          <li><uicontrol>Edit Properties</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog box where you can edit
            attributes/properties for the currently selected topic reference.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Edit Profiling Attributes</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog box where you can
            change the reference type or edit profiling attributes for the currently selected topic
            reference.</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Append child/Insert before/Insert after</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Topic Reference</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Inserts a new topic reference at the specified location.</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Append child/Insert before/Insert after</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Key Definition For Topic Reference</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Opens a dialog box where you can configure a new key name and browse
            for an associated topic reference. A key definition containing the defined key/topic
            reference combination will be inserted.</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Append child/Insert before/Insert after</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Key Definition with Keyword (Variable)</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Opens a dialog box where you can configure a new key name with an
            associated keyword value that will be inserted as a key definition containing the
            defined key/value combination.</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Append child/Insert before/Insert after</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Mapref</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Inserts a reference to a DITA map.</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Append child</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Frontmatter, Chapter, Part, Appendix, Backmatter</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Inserts a specific type of bookmap topic reference inside an opened
            bookmap.</li>
          <li><menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Insert before/Insert after</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Chapter, Part</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> - Inserts a chapter or part topic reference before or after an existing
            chapter or part inside an opened bookmap.</li>
          <li><b>Cut/Copy/Paste/Paste before/Paste after</b> - Cut or copy one or multiple selected
            topic references, then paste them inside, before, or after the selected topic
            reference.</li>
          <li><b>Remove Reference</b> - Deletes the selected topic reference.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Show profiling attributes</uicontrol> - Displays profiling information
            directly on the topic reference. </li>
          <li><uicontrol>Collapse all</uicontrol> - Collapses all levels on the currently selected
            reference. </li>
          <li><uicontrol>Undo/Redo</uicontrol> - Undo/redo changes using the available actions or
            the regular keyboard shortcuts.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Move Up/Down/Promote/Demote</uicontrol> - Moves topic references up, down,
            promotes them, or demotes them using the actions from the
              <uicontrol>Organize</uicontrol> contextual menu or their corresponding shortcuts.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
