<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="WA-dita-edit-topic-content">
  <title>Edit DITA Map Content in One Document</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Edit Topic Content</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit DITA map content in one document</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_sl4_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> offers a <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-waCustom/topics/wa-customization-dita-edit-topic-content.html"
        format="html" scope="external">feature that can be enabled for Git integrations for
        displaying a DITA map with all of the referenced topic content</xref> expanded and editable
      in one document. To trigger this mode, select <uicontrol>Edit Topic Content</uicontrol> from
      the <uicontrol><image href="../img/DM_DisplayMode_drop.png" id="image_cg2_lt3_rnb"/>DITA Map
        Display Mode</uicontrol> drop-down menu.</p>
    <p id="p_tl4_dgk_54b">When editing a DITA map in this mode, the editor provides actions for both
      editing topic content and editing map content. When you commit or save the map, all the
      modified topics are also saved. The structure of maps that are opened with the referenced
      topic content editable is also displayed in the <xref href="wa-outline-pane.dita"/>.</p>
    <p id="p_wvr_r25_mfc">If the DITA map references Markdown files, those files will be displayed
      with the content expanded and also converted to DITA, similar to how the Markdown content will
      look in the published output.</p>
    <p id="p_o1w_q25_mfc">
      <note type="other" othertype="Notes" id="note_ul4_dgk_54b">
        <ul id="ul_hrx_xr3_qnb">
          <li id="li_vl4_dgk_54b">This editing mode may not be available if the file server
            connector does not support it. For example, with the built-in connectors, this action is
            available for all types of Git repositories, except for <term>BitBucket
            Server</term>.</li>
          <li id="li_wl4_dgk_54b">For performance reasons, only modified topics are validated.</li>
          <li id="li_xl4_dgk_54b">Only top-level topics in a DITA file can be edited.</li>
          <li id="li_p1w_q25_mfc">Hovering over a topic reference presents a tooltip with
            information about the node, such as the path of the file, any defined key name, key
            reference, key scope, processing role, or profiling attributes that are set on the node
            or inherited by it.</li>
        </ul>
      </note>
    </p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
      <link format="html"
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-waCustom/topics/wa-customization-dita-edit-topic-content.html"
        scope="external">
        <linktext>Enabling Mode for Editing DITA Map Content in One Document</linktext>
      </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>
