<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-dita-ot-projects">
    <title>DITA-OT Projects</title>
    <body>
        <p id="p_azw_2cz_51c"><term>DITA-OT Projects</term> allow you to publish multiple
      deliverables at once. Each deliverable specifies a reusable source <i>context</i> that groups
      the maps or topics you want to publish, an output folder, and a publication format (such as
      HTML, or PDF) with transformation parameters.</p>
    <p id="p_bzw_2cz_51c">For more information about DITA-OT Projects, see the <xref
        href="https://www.dita-ot.org/4.1/topics/using-project-files" format="html" scope="external"
        >official DITA-OT documentation</xref>.</p>
    <p id="p_yq1_3cz_51c">In <ph keyref="product"/>, DITA-OT Projects can be used to define DITA
      Contexts (specified by the pair of the source DITA map and an optional filter). The DITA
      Context can specified directly in the <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol> pane.</p>
    <p id="p_rvg_fk3_51c">Click the settings button (<image href="../img/wa-Context16.png"/>) at the
      top-right corner of the pane to open the <uicontrol>Configure DITA Context</uicontrol> dialog
      box where you can specify the DITA-OT project file and context defined within it.</p>
    <p id="p_f2b_yk3_51c">
      <fig id="fig_svm_yk3_51c">
        <title>Configure DITA Context Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/wa-configure-context-project.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p id="p_gkx_bl3_51c">This dialog box contains the following options:</p>
    <p id="p_ehx_cl3_51c">
      <dl id="dl_ubd_dl3_51c">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_wbd_dl3_51c">
          <dt>DITA Project</dt>
          <dd>Select this option if you want to specify a DITA-OT project file and optionally, a
            context defined within it.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_xpb_3l3_51c">
          <dt>DITA Map</dt>
          <dd>Select this option if you want to specify a DITA map and optionally, a DITAVAL
            filtering file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_qxl_kl3_51c">
          <dt>Show excluded content</dt>
          <dd>If selected, content that is excluded by a DITAVAL context filter is shown as grayed
            out. If not selected, the excluded content is hidden.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p id="p_ksv_2m3_51c">
      <note id="note_kxy_2m3_51c" type="restriction">When opening a DITA map with the referenced
        topic content expanded and editable in one document while in a concurrent editing session,
        the <uicontrol>DITA Project</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol> options are
        disabled, and thus a DITA context cannot be selected.</note>
    </p>
    </body>
</topic>
