<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-file-templates">
  <title>Creating New Document Templates</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Creating new document templates</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can create your own custom document templates and attach them to a custom
        <term>framework</term>. Once the framework is uploaded, the document templates will be
      available when creating new documents.</p>
    <p>To create your own custom document template, follow these steps:<ol>
        <li>In <b>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</b>, create a new file and customize it to become a
          starting point for creating new files of this type.<note type="tip">You can use <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/editor-variables.html"
              format="html" scope="external">editor variables</xref> in the template file content
            and they will be expanded when the files are opened. Also, see <xref
              href="wa-customizing-templates.dita"/> for other template customization tips (for
            example, you could <xref
              href="wa-customizing-templates.dita#wa-customizing-templates/adding_placeholders_or_hints_in_a_document_templa"
              >add placeholders or hints to assist authors</xref>).</note></li>
        <li id="step2">Save the new template in a directory (for example, called
            <filepath>templates</filepath>) within your custom framework directory.<note
            type="attention">The name that you use to save the template will be the name that
            appears in the new document wizard, including capitalization, space, and characters (for
            example, <filepath>My Custom Template1.xml</filepath> will appear in the new file wizard
            as <b>My Custom Template1</b>). You can also configure the displayed name in a
            properties file by following the procedure found in the <xref
              href="wa-customizing-templates.dita#wa-customizing-templates/configure_the_displayed_names_for_document_templa"
            /> section.</note></li>
        <li id="step3">Open the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
            format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Document Type</uicontrol> configuration dialog
            box</xref> for that specific framework, go to the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/document-type-templates-tab.html"
            format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> tab</xref>, and click
          the <image href="../img/Add16.png" placement="inline"/> button in the bottom-right corner
          to add your new directory to the list. It is recommended that the reference be made
          relative to the framework directory (for example,
            <filepath>${frameworkDir}/templates</filepath>). Binding to an absolute file (e. g.:
            <filepath>C:\some_dir\templates</filepath>) makes the association difficult to share
          between users.</li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> for all of the dialog boxes to save your changes.</li>
        <li> Create an archive that only contains your custom framework folder and <xref
            href="customizing_frameworks.dita#customizing_frameworks/deploying_a_framework">upload
            the changes to your <term>framework</term> to Web Author</xref>.<p><b>Result:</b> The
            custom document template should now be available when <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-webauthor/topics/webapp-create-open-docs.html"
              format="html" scope="external">creating new documents</xref>.</p></li>
      </ol></p>
  </body>
</topic>
