<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-file-comparison-tool">
  <title>File Comparison Tool</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Diff tool</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Compare files</indexterm>
        <indexterm>File comparison tool</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes a file comparison tool that can be used to show
      differences between the current document and either its latest version from the repository or
      another document. To access the tool, select one of the following actions in the
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/WebappMore18.png" id="image_dj2_rfl_kjb"/>More</uicontrol>
      drop-down menu:<ul id="ul_o2q_bgl_kjb">
        <li><menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Compare with</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Latest version from repository</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> - Opens the file comparison tool with the current file displayed in the
          left-side pane and the latest version of the file from the repository displayed in the
          right-side pane.<note>If you are using a Git file repository integration (GitHub,
            Bitbucket, GitLab, or Git), this action automatically does a three-way comparison
            between the current document, its latest version from the repository, and the original
            base revision.</note></li>
        <li><menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Compare with</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Another file</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> - Opens a file chooser dialog box where you can specify a file to compare
          against the current file. Once you select a file and click <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol>,
          the file comparison tool is opened with the current file displayed in the left-side pane
          and the other file displayed in the right-side pane.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Compare with another file</uicontrol>
          <b>(this action replaces the <uicontrol>Compare with</uicontrol> submenu if
              <i>auto-save</i> is enabled)</b> - Opens a file chooser dialog box where you can
          specify a file to compare against the current file. Once you select a file and click
            <uicontrol>Choose</uicontrol>, the file comparison tool is opened with the current file
          displayed in the left-side pane and the other file displayed in the right-side pane.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_hns_pkr_kjb">
        <title>2-Way Comparison</title>
        <image href="../img/wa-2-way-diff.png" id="image_cst_skr_kjb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The resulting comparison will show you differences between the two files. It is a visual
      comparison tool, so the documents are displayed in each pane similar to how they look in the
      Web Author visual editor. Detected differences are grouped into highlighted blocks in each
      pane and content highlighted with a darker shade within the blocks identifies specific changes
      within the blocks. Each block of differences is connected with dynamic lines in between the
      two panes. </p>
    <p>The markers on the right-side vertical stripe help you to quickly identify the locations of
      the differences and you can navigate to specific differences by clicking the markers. </p>
    <p>The toolbar at the top also includes some navigation buttons, as well as a <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/TagsDisplayMode24.png" id="image_yhp_flk_kjb"/>Tags Display Mode</uicontrol>
      drop-down button that allows you to select the amount of tags to display.<note type="tip">The
        default tags display mode is <uicontrol>Full Tags With Attributes</uicontrol> so that XML
        structural differences, such as element name changes or attribute changes, are more visible.
        You can switch to a less cluttered view by choosing the <uicontrol>No Tags</uicontrol>
        mode.</note></p>
    <p>The comparison tool also presents differences that were made using the <xref
        href="perform_common_review_actions.dita#gkq_bfd_d2b/activate_change_tracking"
          ><uicontrol>Change Tracking</uicontrol> feature</xref>. Content that has a comment
      attached is highlighted in a colored shade the same as in the editor. To see the actual
      content of the comment, you can hover over it. </p>
    <note type="notice">If you are using a version of <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> that is
      integrated into another application (for example, a CMS), the file comparison tool may not be
      available by default.</note>
    <section id="section_ty1_s3l_kjb">
      <title>Three-Way Comparisons (Available for Git File Repository Integrations)</title>
      <p>If you are using a Git file repository integration (GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab, or Git),
        when comparing the current document to its latest version from the repository, it
        automatically does a three-way comparison between the current document, its latest version
        from the repository, and the original base revision.</p>
      <p>In this type of comparison, the differences are highlighted in additional possible
          colors:<ul id="ul_u4f_tlr_kjb">
          <li><b>Pink</b> - Identifies differences in both sides where conflicts are possible.</li>
          <li><b>Gray</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the left side (the current
            document).</li>
          <li><b>Blue</b> - Identifies an addition of a node in the right side (the latest version
            from the repository).</li>
          <li><b>Darker Shade</b> - Identifies specific changes within the blocks.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_l51_klr_kjb">
          <title>3-Way Comparison</title>
          <image href="../img/wa-3-way-diff.png" id="image_vhh_mlr_kjb"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
