<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-image-map-editor">
    <title>Editing Image Maps</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Image Map Editor</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes support for editing <b>image maps</b> in DITA documents
      through the use of the <codeph>imagemap</codeph> element. An <i>Image Map</i> provides an easy
      way to create hyperlinks in various areas within an image without having to divide the image
      into separate image files. <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes an <uicontrol>Image Map
        Editor</uicontrol> that helps you to edit image maps that already exist on images in DITA
        documents.<note type="tip">It is possible to manually add image maps in <ph
          keyref="webappProduct"/> by using the <xref
          href="webauthor-content-completion.dita#webauthor-content-completion">Content Completion
          Assistant</xref> to insert an <b>imagemap</b> element (and the <b>image</b> element needs
        to be inside the <b>imagemap</b> element).</note></p>
    <section id="how_to_edit_an_existing_image_map_in_dita">
      <title>How to Edit an Existing Image Map in Web Author</title>
      <p>To edit an existing image map, use either of the following methods:<ul>
          <li>Right-click the image and select <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> button below the image.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>Both methods open the <xref href="#wa-image-map-editor/image_map_editor_interface_in_dita"
          format="dita"><uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol></xref> where you can make changes to
        the image map in a visual editor:<ul>
          <li>You can edit, duplicate, or delete existing shapes, and <xref
              href="#wa-image-map-editor/overlapping_areas" format="dita">change their layer
              order</xref>.</li>
          <li>You can add new shapes that will become hyperlinks. To select the target link for a
            new shape, click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to close the visual editor, and in the <xref
              href="#wa-image-map-editor/shape-table" format="dita">Shape Table</xref> below the
              <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> button, click the <uicontrol><image
                href="../img/Edit16.png"/>Edit</uicontrol> button in the
              <uicontrol>Target</uicontrol> column for that particular shape. New shapes will have a
              <b>[Choose target]</b> message in the <uicontrol>Target</uicontrol> column and be
            presented as a validation warning until you select a target reference.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Image Map Details</title>
          <image href="../img/WA-image-map-details.png" placement="inline"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="shape-table"><u><b>Shape Table</b></u></p>
      <p>The shape table below the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> button is a sequential
        list of all the areas (shapes) that have been added in the image. The
          <uicontrol>Target</uicontrol> column displays the target links that exist in the image
        map. You can click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Edit16.png"/>Edit</uicontrol> button
        next to a target link to select a new reference for that particular hyperlinked area. You
        can choose between the following types of links: <uicontrol>Cross Reference</uicontrol>,
          <uicontrol>File Reference</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Web Link</uicontrol>. All three types
        will open a dialog box that allows you to browse for a target resource.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="image_map_editor_interface_in_dita">
      <title>Image Map Editor Interface in Web Author</title>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Image Map Editor in Web Author</title>
          <image href="../img/WA_image_map_editor.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The interface of the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> consists of the following
        sections and actions:<dl>
          <dlentry id="image-map-toolbar">
            <dt>Toolbar</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry id="circle">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/NewCircle20.png"/> New
                      Circle</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to draw a circle over an area in the image. You can drag any
                      of the four points to adjust the size of the circle.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="rect">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/NewRectangle20.png"/> New
                        Rectangle</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to draw a rectangular shape over an area in the image. You
                      can drag any of the four points to adjust the size and shape of the
                      rectangle.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="Free-Form">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/FreeForm20.png"/> New Free Form
                        Shape</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to draw a free form shape over an area in the image. After
                      selecting this button, left-click anywhere in the image to place the first
                      point of your shape. Then move the cursor to the location of the next desired
                      point and left-click to place the next point, and so on. To complete the shape
                      (area), press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> on your
                      keyboard.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="duplicate">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/CopyArea20.png"/>
                      Duplicate</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to create a duplicate of the currently selected shape.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="delete">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DeleteArea20.png"/>
                      Delete</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to delete the currently selected shape.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="zoom">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ZoomIn20.png"/> Zoom In</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this slider to zoom in on the image in the main image pane.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry>
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ZoomOut20.png"/> Zoom Out</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this slider to zoom out on the image in the main image pane.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="show-numbers">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowLayers20.png"/> Show/Hide
                        Numbers</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to toggle between showing or hiding the numbers for the
                      shapes.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="bring-front">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/BringShapeToFront20.png"/> Bring Shape to
                        Front</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to bring the currently selected shape forward to the top
                      layer.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="bring-forward">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/BringShapeForward20.png"/> Bring Shape
                        Forward</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to bring the currently selected shape forward one
                      layer.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="send-backward">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SendShapeBackward20.png"/> Send Shape
                        Backward</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to send the currently selected shape back one layer.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                  <dlentry id="send-back">
                    <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/SendShapeToBack20.png"/> Send Shape to
                        Back</uicontrol></dt>
                    <dd>Use this button to send the currently selected shape back to the bottom
                      layer.</dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="image-map-image-pane">
            <dt>Image Pane</dt>
            <dd>
              <p id="image-pane-p">This main Image Pane is where you work with shapes to add
                hyperlinks to multiple areas within an image. The editing mechanisms that are
                supported in the Image Pane include the following:</p>
              <p>
                <dl>
                  <dlentry id="mouse-controls-dlentry">
                    <dt><u>Mouse Controls and Keyboard Shortcuts</u></dt>
                    <dd>
                      <ul>
                        <li>Use the mouse to select and move shapes around in the image pane. It is
                          easy to see which shape is selected in this image pane because the border
                          of the selected shape changes from a solid line to a dotted one.</li>
                        <li>You can also drag any of the points of a selected shape to adjust its
                          size and shape.</li>
                        <li>You can hold down the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl</shortcut></uicontrol>
                          key to select multiple shapes and then move them simultaneously.</li>
                        <li>You can also move a selected shape by using the arrow keys on your
                          keyboard. In addition, you can hold down
                              <uicontrol><shortcut>Shift</shortcut></uicontrol> while using the
                          arrow keys to move the shape farther or
                              <uicontrol><shortcut>Alt</shortcut></uicontrol> to move it 1 pixel at
                          a time.</li>
                      </ul>
                    </dd>
                  </dlentry>
                </dl>
              </p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
    <section id="overlapping_areas">
      <title>Overlapping Areas</title>
      <p>If shapes overlap one another in the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol>, the one on
        the top layer takes precedence. The number shown inside each shape represent its layer (if
        the numbers are not displayed, click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowLayers20.png"/>
          Show/Hide Numbers</uicontrol> button on the <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol>
        toolbar). To change the layer order for a shape, use the layer buttons on the
          <uicontrol>Image Map Editor</uicontrol> toolbar (<image
          href="../img/BringShapeToFront20.png"/>, <image href="../img/BringShapeForward20.png"/>,
          <image href="../img/SendShapeBackward20.png"/>, <image href="../img/SendShapeToBack20.png"
        />).</p>
    </section>
    </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link format="html" href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/dita/1.3/specs/langRef/base/imagemap.html"
        scope="external">
        <linktext>DITA 'imagemap' Element Specifications</linktext>
      </link>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
