<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-integrate-CMIS">
  <title>Integrating Web Author with a Generic CMIS</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>CMIS integration</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes a generic CMIS connector plugin that provides the
      ability to integrate Web Author with various types of content management platforms (such as
      Alfresco, SharePoint On-Premise, or FileNet). It provides an interface for browsing files,
      opening the files in the editor, and submitting changes.</p>
    <section id="installing_the_plugin">
      <title>Configuring the CMIS Connector Plugin</title>
      <ol>
        <li>Go to your <xref href="webapp-admin-page.dita#webapp-admin-page">Administration
            Page</xref>.</li>
        <li>Select <uicontrol>Plugins</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li>Click the <uicontrol><image href="../img/ConfigureSearchScope16.png"
            />Configure</uicontrol> icon next to the CMIS plugin.<p><b>Step Result:</b> This opens
            the plugin configuration dialog box.</p><p>
            <fig>
              <title>CMIS Connector Plugin Configuration Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/wa-cmis-config.png"/>
            </fig>
          </p></li>
        <li>Enter the options in the <uicontrol>Plugin configuration</uicontrol> dialog box:<ul>
            <li><b>Server URL</b> - The URL of your server. Examples:<ul>
                <li><i>FileNet</i> -
                  <codeph>http://[host]:[port]/fncmis/resources/Service</codeph></li>
                <li><i>SharePoint On-Premise</i> -
                  <codeph>http://[host]/path/to/folder</codeph></li>
                <li><i>Alfresco</i> -
                    <codeph>http://[host]:[port]/alfresco/api/-default-/public/cmis/versions/1.1/atom</codeph></li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><b>Server name</b> - This name will appear in the Web Author Dashboard as the name
              for the tab that users will select to browse files. It will also appear in the Web
              Author editor interface as the name of a toolbar drop-down menu used for checking out
              an opened file or checking in modified files.</li>
            <li><b>Server logo URL</b> (Optional) - You can specify a URL for a logo that will
              appear in the Web Author Dashboard for the tab that users will select to browse for
              files.</li>
            <li><b>Autosave interval (seconds)</b> - Specifies how often modified files are
              automatically saved.</li>
            <li id="check-out-required"><b>Check out required</b> - If you select this option, files
              will be opened in the Web Author editor in read-only mode and users will need to check
              out the file to edit it.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li>Click <uicontrol>Apply</uicontrol>.</li>
        <li>Restart the server.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links product="webauthor">
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="wa-using-cmis.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
