<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-migrate-frameworks">
  <title>Migrating a Framework from Oxygen XML Editor/Author to Web Author</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Migrate Oxygen frameworks</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Frameworks developed for <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i> have a high degree of compatibility
      with <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>. However, in some cases, additional work is required to make
      the framework compatible with both products.</p>
    <section id="section_kjk_tkw_ljb">
      <title>General Recommendations</title>
      <p>You can use the <xref
          href="customizing_frameworks.dita#customizing_frameworks/developing_and_testing_a_framework_using_the_weba"
          >Web Author Test Server add-on</xref> to test your framework in both products with minimal
          overhead.<note>It is always useful to check out the server log. It can be found in the
          plugin's folder in: <filepath>tomcat/logs/oxygen.log</filepath>.</note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_zsm_flw_ljb">
      <title>Document Styles</title>
      <p>The CSS styles used to render the document in the desktop application can be re-used in Web
        Author, although there are some <xref href="webapp_css_limitations.dita"
        >limitations</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_k2h_qtx_jjb">
      <title>Toolbar and Contextual Menu Actions</title>
      <p>Actions in <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> can be specified in two ways:</p>
      <p>
        <ul id="ul_znv_ymm_nkb">
          <li>
            <p>In the <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
                format="html" scope="external">Document Type Configuration dialog box</xref> as a
              list of operation modes, each mode having an associated
                <codeph>AuthorOperation</codeph>. </p>
            <p>If the corresponding <codeph>AuthorOperation</codeph> is not <xref
                href="customizing_frameworks.dita#customizing_frameworks/author-mode-operation-li"
                >marked as compatible with Web Author</xref>, the action is not available for the
              users. Sometimes this is just a matter of annotating your custom Java class. In other
              cases (for example, when the <codeph>AuthorOperation</codeph> is used to show a custom
              Java Swing dialog box), it has to be re-implemented in JavaScript.</p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p><xref href="customizing_js.dita">Implemented in the framework's JavaScript
                code</xref>. </p>
            <p>The actions registered from JavaScript code can overwrite an action with the same ID
              defined in the <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
                format="html" scope="external">Document Type Configuration dialog box</xref>. The
              built-in frameworks already implement such actions that insert a table, image, or a
              link.</p>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Some of the toolbar actions may not appear in Web Author. The most common reason is that
        the toolbar actions use a custom <codeph>AuthorOperation</codeph> that is not <xref
          href="customizing_frameworks.dita#customizing_frameworks/author-mode-operation-li">marked
          as compatible with Web Author</xref>. </p>
      <p>This is how the toolbar structure is built:<ul id="ul_oyt_v5x_jjb">
          <li>The default structure of the toolbar is defined in the
              <filepath>*.framework</filepath> file and is common with the one in the desktop
            editor. You can visualize it using the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
              format="html" scope="external">Document Type Configuration dialog box</xref>.</li>
          <li>The client-side component of Web Author retrieves this configuration using an HTTP
            request to something like
              <codeph>./rest/VERSION/actions/actionsConfig/docNNN.NNN</codeph>. Actions that are not
            compatible are removed from this configuration. You can check it in the browser's Dev
            Tools <uicontrol>Network</uicontrol> tab.</li>
          <li>The framework's JavaScript code <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/maven/com/oxygenxml/oxygen-webapp/21.1.0.0/jsdoc/tutorial-removeaction.html"
              format="html" scope="external">overrides the configuration of the toolbar</xref>. If
            you are extending a framework, the JavaScript code of the base framework can also modify
            the configuration of the toolbar.<note>If you are extending the built-in DITA Map
              framework, make sure that the name of the framework extension contains the
                <codeph>ditamap</codeph> word. Otherwise, actions such as <uicontrol>Insert New
                Topic Reference</uicontrol> will not appear.</note></li>
          <li>When the contextual menu is shown, actions that are not enabled at a specific position
            are not shown.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <note>The actions on the Web Author toolbar are not disabled based on the location of the
        cursor. However, they always try to find a valid position for that element in a position
        that is close to the cursor location.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="section_klq_k42_4kb">
      <title>New Document Templates</title>
      <p>When editing a DITA map, there is a <uicontrol><image href="../img/NewTopic20.png"
            id="image_zrm_t42_4kb"/>Insert New DITA Resource</uicontrol> toolbar button that opens a
        dialog box where you can choose the type of DITA document to create and inserts a reference
        to it at the current position within the map. The templates that are listed include:<ul
          id="ul_phh_bp2_4kb">
          <li>Templates that have <codeph>type=dita</codeph> specified in its
              <filepath>.properties</filepath> file.</li>
          <li>Templates that do not have a <codeph>type</codeph> specified in its
              <filepath>.properties</filepath> file.</li>
          <li>Templates that do not have a <filepath>.properties</filepath> file.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>If you want to hide a particular template from appearing in the dialog box, you should
        modify the <filepath>.properties</filepath> file for the particular template and make sure
        it has a <codeph>type</codeph> and that the <codeph>type</codeph> is not set to <i>dita</i>.
        For more details about configuring the <filepath>.properties</filepath> file for a template,
        see <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/customizing-templates.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Customizing Document Templates</xref>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="webapp_css_limitations.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
