<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-merge-tool-cms">
  <title>Integrating the File Merge Tool with a CMS</title>
  <body>
    <p id="p_qpm_ltj_drb"><ph keyref="product"/> provides a <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-webauthor/topics/wa-merge-tool.html" format="html"
        scope="external">file merge tool</xref>. It is a useful feature for cases where multiple
      users work with the same documents concurrently because it can be used to resolve conflicts
      when committing changes to a repository. The Web Author Merge tool is offered as an API for
      CMS integrations.</p>
    <section id="id_2">
      <title>Use-cases</title>
      <ul id="ul_d54_zgc_drb">
        <li id="li_e54_zgc_drb">A CMS often keeps track of multiple versions of a file. For example,
          if a new legal requirement has to be addressed in the documentation, all the versions of
          the file have to be updated. One option is to make the change to the oldest version and
          merge those changes in the other versions.</li>
        <li id="li_m4h_1hc_drb">If a CMS supports a review workflow, the copy of the file that is
          sent for review can be changed in the CMS for other reasons. On the other hand, the review
          workflow also results in some updates to the file. At the end, these updates need to be
          merged in the version on the CMS.</li>
        <li id="li_lmr_1hc_drb">In other systems (such as Git), different users can edit the same
          file in parallel. When they finish editing, they have to merge the changes.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="id_3">
      <title>Integration Approach</title>
      <p>To launch the Merge tool, Web Author must be started with the following parameters:</p>
      <p>
        <dl id="dl_gjh_qkq_crb">
          <dlentry>
            <dt>url</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>The <xref href="oxy-url.dita">OXY-URL</xref> of one of the files to be merged. It
                will be loaded in the left part of the merge tool and will be edited to contained
                the merged version of the file.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>diffUrl</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>The <xref href="oxy-url.dita">OXY-URL</xref> of the other file to be merged.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>diffType</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>Use merge to launch the File Merge Tool.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>diffBaseUrl</dt>
            <dd>
              <p>The base file used for the 3-way merge process. Usually a file version where the
                two versions diverged.</p>
            </dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
      <p>These parameters need to be <xref
          href="webauthor-integrate-embedded-launch.dita#webauthor-integrate-embedded-launch/url_parameters"
          >set as URL parameters</xref> (there are others that can be used to configure various
        aspects of the editor).</p>
      <p>After the user finishes the merge, the merged content will be in the left-side pane. To get
        the merged content, you can use JavaScript code from a plugin as follows:</p>
      <codeblock id="pre_gm2_nkq_crb" outputclass="language-javascript">/** @type {sync.api.Editor} */
var editor = ...;
editor.getContent((err, content) => {
  if (!err) {
    // Save the content of the editor
  }
});</codeblock>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-webauthor/topics/wa-merge-tool.html" format="html"
      scope="external">
      <linktext>Web Author Merge Tool</linktext>
    </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>
