<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-outline-pane">
    <title>Outline Pane</title>
    <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> pane displays a general tag overview of the currently open
      document. The pane is available by default for DocBook, TEI, and XHTML documents, but it is
      possible to <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-waCustom/topics/wa-enabling-outline-pane.html"
        format="html" scope="external">configure other frameworks to make it available for those
        particular types of documents</xref>.</p>
    <p>The pane is synchronized with the main editing area, so when you make a selection in the
      editor, the corresponding nodes are highlighted in the <b>Outline</b> pane. Likewise, if you
      double-click a node in the <b>Outline</b> pane, the cursor will be placed in the corresponding
      element in the main editor.</p>
    <p>The benefits of its functionality include:<ul id="ul_ryx_4z5_flb">
        <li>It offers a quick way to navigate through the document.</li>
        <li>It gives you insight about the location of your modifications.</li>
        <li>It shows the hierarchical dependencies between elements.</li>
        <li>It makes it easy to visualize the XML structure.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="section_hsz_ym1_rlb">
      <title>Display Modes</title>
      <p>The <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> pane includes two different display modes that can be
        selected using the drop-down menu at the top-right of the pane. The possible display modes
          are:<ul id="ul_dtd_fn1_rlb">
          <li><b>Contents</b> - Displays the information in the pane like a table of contents.</li>
          <li><b>Structure</b> - Displays the information in the pane as a general tag overview of
            the current XML document.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_lf1_vkz_qlb">
      <title>Contextual Menu Actions</title>
      <p>The following actions are available in the contextual menu of the
          <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> pane:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Attribute16.gif" id="image_wzn_4kz_qlb"/>Edit
                Attributes</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> tab in the panel on the right side of
              the screen where you can add or edit attributes.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Displays a list of elements that can be inserted as a child of the current
              element.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Insert Before</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Displays a list of elements that can be inserted before the current element, as a
              sibling.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Insert After</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Displays a list of elements that can be inserted after the current element, as a
              sibling.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Cut16.png" id="image_u1f_hz1_5r"
              />Cut</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Cuts the currently selected node.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png" id="image_x2z_mst_tr"
              />Copy</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Copies the currently selected node to the clipboard.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RejectChange16.png" id="image_bxq_tbm_tlb"/>Delete
                Element</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Deletes the currently selected node.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry id="IX-Rename_element">
            <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RenameElement16.png" id="image_z52_xxz_tr"/>Rename
                Element</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens a content completion window where you can choose an element to rename the
              currently selected node.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-waCustom/wa-enabling-outline-pane.dita"
        format="html" scope="external">
        <linktext>Enabling the Outline Pane for DITA and Other Frameworks</linktext>
      </link>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
