<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-publishing-support">
  <title>PDF Preview Support</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Publishing</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Publish to PDF</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_yft_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> supports previewing Web Author content as a PDF. Users can
      either print the current document and a PDF preview will be generated that looks similar to
      the way the document is rendered in the Web Author editor. Users can also download the current
      document as the PDF preview. The <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/chemistry-html-to-pdf-converter.html" format="html"
        scope="external"><b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b></xref> engine is used behind the scenes to
      produce the PDF preview and it is customizable using CSS.</p>
    <section id="section_zgv_z2j_qnb">
      <title>Enabling PDF Preview Support</title>
      <p id="p_zft_dgk_54b">The Web Author PDF support can be enabled by <xref href="webapp-configure-plugins.dita"
          >installing the <i><uicontrol>Web Author Publishing</uicontrol></i> plugin</xref> that can
        be found in the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/xml_web_author/web_author_plugins.html" format="html"
          scope="external"><menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Download</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>Connectors/Plugins</uicontrol>
          </menucascade> webpage</xref>. Make sure that you read and understand the terms and
        conditions of its end-user license agreement. Once installed and enabled, two actions are
        contributed to the Web Author interface (available in the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/WebappMore18.png" id="image_ccw_shj_qnb"/>More drop-down
          menu</uicontrol>):<ul id="ul_zdx_jfj_qnb">
          <li id="li_agt_dgk_54b"><uicontrol>Print</uicontrol> - Generates a PDF preview from the current document and
            prints it. The PDF is generated using the same CSS files used by the editor.</li>
          <li id="li_bgt_dgk_54b"><uicontrol>Export as PDF</uicontrol> - Downloads a PDF preview version of the document
            based on the framework configuration:<ul id="ul_hxq_whj_qnb">
              <li id="li_cgt_dgk_54b">By default, the editor styles are used.</li>
              <li id="li_dgt_dgk_54b">If one or more publishing scenarios based on <b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b> are
                configured, they appear in a sub-menu of the <uicontrol>Export as PDF</uicontrol>
                menu item.</li>
            </ul></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_dgj_23j_qnb">
      <title>Notes About Configuring the Plugin in the Administration Page</title>
      <p id="p_egt_dgk_54b">When configuring the plugin in the <xref href="webapp-admin-page.dita">Administration
          Page</xref>, the PDF generation invokes an external process on the server. It includes its
        own configuration page where you can configure:</p>
      <ul id="ul_csq_g3j_qnb">
        <li id="li_fgt_dgk_54b">The memory allocated to a publishing process.</li>
        <li id="li_ggt_dgk_54b">The maximum number of concurrent publishing processes.</li>
      </ul>
      <note id="note_hgt_dgk_54b">The content communicated to and from the publishing process is encrypted.</note>
    </section>
    <section id="section_xx4_43j_qnb">
      <title>Configuring the CSS</title>
      <p id="p_igt_dgk_54b">Depending on the action (<uicontrol>Print</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Export as
          PDF</uicontrol>), some CSS files are used (either those configured to render the document
        in the editor or the ones specified in the transformation scenario).</p>
      <p id="p_jgt_dgk_54b">Some hints:</p>
      <ul id="ul_bn3_q3j_qnb">
        <li id="li_kgt_dgk_54b">You can use <xmlatt>media</xmlatt>
          <codeph>print {}</codeph> rules to configure CSS rules that apply only for generating
          PDF.</li>
        <li id="li_lgt_dgk_54b">For DITA, a file located at <filepath>css/webauthor/p-dita.css</filepath> is also loaded
          along with the editor styles.</li>
        <li id="li_mgt_dgk_54b">You can match an element based on its pseudo-classes. For example, to match a
            <codeph>-oxy-expanded</codeph> pseudo-class, you can use the following syntax:
          <codeblock outputclass="language-javascript" id="codeblock_ngt_dgk_54b">@namespace oxy-pseudo "https://oxygenxml.com/ns/pseudo-elements/";
*[oxy-pseudo|p-oxy-expanded]) {
  ... 
}</codeblock></li>
        <li id="li_ogt_dgk_54b">You can use any CSS extension supported by the <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/chemistry-html-to-pdf-converter.html" format="html"
            scope="external"><b>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</b></xref> engine.</li>
        <li id="li_pgt_dgk_54b">The PDF generation engine will work on a resolved document. If your content uses DITA
            <i>conrefs</i>, XInclude, or another content reference mechanism, the references will be
          expanded before the file is sent to the CMS.</li>
        <li id="li_qgt_dgk_54b">Links to other XML files will not work in the generated PDF. You may want to customize
          your CSS to handle this. </li>
        <li id="li_rgt_dgk_54b">Fonts that cover the characters in the document have to be installed on the server that
          run Web Author. For example, see: <xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-chemistry/topics/ch_internationalization.html"
            format="html" scope="external">Localization</xref>.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="limitations">
      <title>Limitations</title>
      <p>While the PDF preview support can be very useful to quickly download your content as PDF,
        it has several limitations that needs to be taken into account:<ul id="ul_htg_bx4_kpb">
          <li>For DITA documents, the PDF is not obtained by using DITA-OT which is the most popular
            DITA publishing tool.</li>
          <li>One can publish a whole DITA Map by switching to <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>Display Mode</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Show Topic Content</uicontrol>
            </menucascade> and then using the <uicontrol>Export as PDF</uicontrol> action. In this
            case, the links between topics will not work.</li>
          <li>As the PDF is obtained by applying a CSS and currently there is no support to generate
            additional content such as Table of Contents, List of Figures, etc.</li>
          <li>All the generated PDF files contain a watermark that consists of the <term>Oxygen PDF
              Chemistry</term> icon. To remove this watermark one can configure the plugin using an
              <term>Oxygen PDF Chemistry</term> license key.<p>To add the license key, follow these
              steps:</p><ul id="ul_e2q_ky4_kpb">
              <li>
                <p>Look inside the log file for a line that starts with <codeph>Loading plugins
                    from:</codeph> .</p>
              </li>
              <li>
                <p>Open the folder located at the path on the line mentioned above.</p>
              </li>
              <li>
                <p>Locate the PDF plugin folder. It starts with
                    <filepath>web-author-publishing-plugin-</filepath> followed by the version
                  number.</p>
              </li>
              <li>
                <p>Create a file called <filepath>licensekey.txt</filepath> in the
                    <filepath>oxygen-pdf-chemistry</filepath> folder inside the plugin and paste the
                  license key in this file.</p>
              </li>
            </ul></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
