<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-text-mode">
  <title>Text Editing Mode</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Text mode</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Source editing</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Edit as XML</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes a simple text editing mode where you can edit the XML
      source code. It includes syntax highlighting to make it easy to see the XML structure.</p>
    <p>To switch to this text editing mode, select <menucascade>
        <uicontrol><image href="../img/WebappMore18.png"/>More</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol><image href="../img/XmlIcon16.gif"/>Edit as XML</uicontrol>
      </menucascade> from the menu bar at the top of the screen.</p>
    <p>To switch back to the normal visual editing mode, click <uicontrol>Switch to Author
        mode</uicontrol> in the menu bar at the top of the screen.</p>
    <section id="keyboard_shortcuts">
      <title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
      <p>The text editor supports the usual keyboard shortcuts. For example:<ul>
          <li><uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+C (Command+C on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol> - Copy</li>
          <li><uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+X (Command+X on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol> - Cut</li>
          <li><uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+V (Command+V on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol> - Paste</li>
          <li><uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+Z (Command+Z on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol> - Undo</li>
          <li><uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+Y (Command+Y on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol> - Redo</li>
          <li><uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+A (Command+A on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol> - Select
            all</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="findreplace_actions">
      <title>Find/Replace Actions</title>
      <p>There is also a find/replace menu button (<image href="../img/wa_find_menu18.png"/>) in the
        top-right corner of the text editor that expands to reveal the following additional
        search-related actions along with their keyboard shortcuts:<ul>
          <li><b>Find (<uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+F (Command+F on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol>)</b> -
            Opens a stripe at the top of the text editor where you can enter a search pattern. It
            supports regular expression syntax. To use regular expressions, surround the search
            pattern with forward slashes (for example, <b>/word*/</b>).<note type="tip">When in
                <i>Find</i> mode, you can navigate to the next occurrence by pressing
                  <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>, or to the previous occurrence
              by pressing <uicontrol><shortcut>Shift+Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>.</note></li>
          <li><b>Find/Replace (<uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+Shift+F (Command+Shift+F on OS
                  X)</shortcut></uicontrol>)</b> - Opens a stripe at the top of the text editor
            where you can enter a search pattern to find and after you press
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>, you can enter the pattern to
            replace it with. Each occurrence is then highlighted in the editor, one by one. You can
            simply press <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> to perform the replace
            operation on each occurrence or you can use the buttons that then appear in the stripe
              (<b>Yes</b>, <b>No</b>, <b>All</b>, <b>Stop</b>). The find operation supports regular
            expression syntax. To use regular expressions, surround the search pattern with forward
            slashes (for example, <b>/word*/</b>).</li>
          <li><b>Jump to Line (<uicontrol><shortcut>Alt+F</shortcut></uicontrol>)</b> - Opens a
            stripe at the top of the text editor where you can enter the line number to navigate
            to.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section id="content_completion">
      <title>Content Completion</title>
      <p>The text editing mode includes basic content completion as long as the document has an
        associated DTD schema (other types of schema do not support content completion in the text
        editing mode, although they do support it in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode). The
        content completion functionality can be invoked using
            <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl+Space</shortcut></uicontrol> and it offers proposals that are
        valid in the element as the current cursor location (including elements, attributes, and
        attributes values).</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
