<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="wa-using-cmis">
  <title>Using Web Author with Alfresco, SharePoint On-Premise, FileNet</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Alfresco support</indexterm>
        <indexterm>SharePoint On-Premise support</indexterm>
        <indexterm>FileNet support</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_dkp_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes a generic <i>CMIS connector</i>
      plugin that enables you to connect Web Author to various types of content management platforms
      (such as <term>Alfresco</term>, <term>SharePoint</term>, or <term>FileNet</term>) and access
      files stored on those platforms. To connect and access the files, it is assumed that the <xref
        href="wa-integrate-CMIS.dita">CMIS plugin is enabled and configured</xref> in your
      installation of <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>.</p>
    <section id="open_or_create_a_file_stored_on_a_webdav_server">
      <title>Working With Files</title>
      <p id="p_ekp_dgk_54b">To open a file or create a new file, go to the main <xref
          href="webapp-create-open-docs.dita#webapp-create-open-docs">Dashboard</xref>, click the
        tab that corresponds to your type of CMIS (for example, <uicontrol>FileNet</uicontrol>), and
        log in. To create a new document, click on <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> in the top-right
        corner.</p>
      <p id="p_fkp_dgk_54b">
        <fig id="fig_gkp_dgk_54b">
          <title>CMIS Browsing Functionality</title>
          <image href="../img/wa-cmis-browsing.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <note conkeyref="reusables-webapp/upload-file-note" id="note_fnz_nzd_hwb"/>
      <p id="p_hkp_dgk_54b">To open an existing document, browse for the file and double-click it
        (or tap on a mobile device). If your plugin integration was configured with the <xref
          href="wa-integrate-CMIS.dita#wa-integrate-CMIS/check-out-required"><uicontrol>Check-out
            required</uicontrol> option selected</xref>, the file will be opened the Web Author
        editor in read-only mode.</p>
      <p id="p_ipf_czd_hwb">To edit a file, you need to check it out by using the <uicontrol>Check
          Out</uicontrol> action from the toolbar drop-down menu that corresponds to your type of
        CMIS (for example, <uicontrol>FileNet</uicontrol>).</p>
      <p id="p_yrt_dzd_hwb"><image href="../img/wa-cmis-drop-down.png"/></p>
      <p id="p_aw4_dzd_hwb">When you check out a file, it is locked and other users cannot edit it
        in Web Author.</p>
      <p id="p_wnk_qrg_hwb">To save a modified file, use the <uicontrol>Check In</uicontrol> action
        from that drop-down menu and choose between <uicontrol>Major version</uicontrol> or
          <uicontrol>Minor version</uicontrol>. When you check in a modified file, it is switched to
        read-only mode in your editor and it is unlocked for other users. You can also use the
          <uicontrol>Discard Check Out</uicontrol> action from the drop-down menu to cancel the
        check-out and unlock the file for others.</p>
      <p id="p_gns_5rg_hwb">Selecting the <uicontrol>Show Version History</uicontrol> option opens a
        window with information about the version history of commits for the current file. It
        includes columns that list the <uicontrol>Version</uicontrol>,
          <uicontrol>Creator</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Commit Message</uicontrol> for each
        commit.</p>
      <p id="p_lmd_msg_hwb"><image href="../img/wa-cmis-version-history.png"/></p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="wa-integrate-CMIS.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
