<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="web-author-docker">
  <title>Deploying Web Author in a Docker Container</title>
  <body>
    <p>It is a common practice to use Docker containers to deploy <ph keyref="product"/>. This topic
      contains some advice on how to create a custom Docker image.</p>
    <p id="p_usv_d4v_svb">For some sample Docker configurations, see the following public GitHub
      repository: <xref href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/web-author-docker" format="html"
        scope="external"/>.</p>
    <section id="section_gnv_qhs_xrb">
      <title>HTTP Configuration</title>
      <p>The HTTP/HTTPS ports of the container must be exposed.</p>
      <p>One of the benefits of using Docker containers is that you can deploy multiple instances of
          <ph keyref="product"/> to provide high availability. In this case, you may want to consult
        the documentation about <xref href="webapp-loadbalancing.dita">running <ph keyref="product"
          /> behind a load balancer</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_yrk_5fs_xrb">
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <p>The server configuration that can be changed using the administration page is stored in the
        <xref href="wa-oxygen-data-dir.dita">Data Directory</xref>. If you want to
        persist some of this configuration when containers are removed, you can map parts of this
        directory it to a volume.</p>
      <p>Alternatively, you can add the initial configuration of the server as part of the file
        system of the Docker image.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_tg2_vgs_xrb">
      <title>Licensing</title>
      <p>The license server has some protections built in to prevent users from duplicating a
        deployment with the same license. As a result,  deploying the license server in a Docker
        container is not supported.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_u5f_zgs_xrb">
      <title>Logging</title>
      <p><ph keyref="product"/> is configured to log to both standard output and to a file so that
        you are able to use the standard Docker commands to obtain the logs.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
