<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webauthor-security-configuration">
  <title>Configuring Security Settings</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes a built-in mechanism for restricting outgoing network
      connections. There is a <uicontrol>Security</uicontrol> page in the <xref
        href="webapp-admin-page.dita"/> that provides options for handling security-related
      features, including an option for specifying trusted code locations and a firewall option
      where you can choose to restrict access to hosts that are not specified as being trusted.</p>
    <section id="section_elh_p52_4kb">
      <title>Trusted Code</title>
      <p>By default, Web Author does not load code (such as CSS or Schematron) referenced directly
        in documents unless it comes from the framework (document type association) or a plugin.
        However, you can specify code locations to be considered trusted by adding them in the <xref
          href="webapp-admin-page.dita#webapp-admin-page/trusted-code"><uicontrol>Trusted
            Code</uicontrol> option</xref> in the <uicontrol>Security</uicontrol> section of the
          <xref href="webapp-admin-page.dita"/>. The code locations need to be declared with URL
        patterns, one per line. For
        example:<codeblock outputclass="language-bourne">*//github.com/*
webdav-https://my-server:8081/repo/*</codeblock></p>
      <p>
        <note>The location of a resource should be its <xref href="oxy-url.dita">OXY-URL</xref>. </note>
      </p>
      <p>To consider all code as trusted (which is equivalent to disabling this security feature and
        is not recommended), you can use a wildcard that matches any
        location:<codeblock outputclass="">*</codeblock></p>
    </section>
    <section id="trusted_hosts">
      <title>Firewall</title>
      <p>It is possible to restrict the domains that the Web Author server is allowed to connect to.
        The <uicontrol>Security</uicontrol> page in the <xref href="webapp-admin-page.dita"/>
        includes a <uicontrol>Firewall</uicontrol> section where you can choose to allow all
        connections or only allow connections to hosts that you specify as trusted. You can specify
        the hosts to be considered trusted by adding them (one per line) in the <xref
          href="webapp-admin-page.dita#webapp-admin-page/only-allow-connections"><uicontrol>Only
            allow connections to these trusted hosts</uicontrol> option</xref>. For
        example:<codeblock outputclass="language-bourne">www.oxygenxml.com:443
*.mycompany.intranet</codeblock></p>
      <p>To allow connections to a domain regardless of the port, you can specify just the domain
        name. The wildcard character <codeph>*</codeph> can also be used, for example to match any
        subdomain.</p>
      <p>When you choose to <uicontrol>Allow All Connections</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Log each
          connection</uicontrol>, a log entry will be added for each outgoing connection that
        contains the <codeph>[UNSECURE CONNECTION]</codeph> token. This is useful for monitoring and
        for determining which domains should be marked as trusted.</p>
      <note type="other" othertype="Notes">
        <ul id="ul_jky_rhj_4kb">
          <li>Plugins can specify whether a connection is allowed or denied, regardless of whether
            or not they are listed in the <uicontrol>Security</uicontrol> page. For example, the
            Perforce plugin, allows connections to the Perforce server configured in the <xref
              href="webapp-admin-page.dita"/>.</li>
          <li>Connections that have no security risks, such as connections to the License Server are
            also allowed regardless of this option.</li>
        </ul>
      </note>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
