<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webauthor-integrate-workflow">
    <title>Integrating Web Author in Your Workflow</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Integrating Web Author in your workflow</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
    <p id="p_wxr_dgk_54b">One of the advantages of <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> is that it allows contributors (such as
      reviewers or support engineers) to streamline the documentation workflow by proposing changes
      or adding comments directly in the XML source. The documentation team can then easily
      integrate the changes or suggestions without various additional steps being required somewhere
      in the process.</p>
    <p id="p_xxr_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> can be launched at any point during your content-related
      workflows by simply embedding a link in a web-page, e-mail message, or even in the published
      output. The user then simply clicks a link, and they will be redirected to the <ph
        keyref="webappProduct"/> editing page with that particular file open and editable.</p>
    <p id="p_yxr_dgk_54b">You can also streamline and control your workflow by embedding a custom action in the Web
      Author interface. For example, you could configure an action to check a file in or out to make
      the file management process easier for the user.</p>
    <section id="section_x2n_vhh_vrb">
      <title>Resources</title>
      <p id="p_orm_dgk_54b">For more information about how Web Author can be integrated within
        various stages of a documentation review workflow, see the following resources:<ul
          id="ul_kdg_v5v_tvb">
          <li id="li_fj4_nd5_mbc">Webinar: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/events/2024/webinar_web_author_customizations_getting_started.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Web Author Customizations - Getting
              Started</b></xref></li>
          <li id="li_ldg_v5v_tvb">Video: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/wa_web_author_into_your_documentation_review_workflow.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Integrating Oxygen XML Web Author Into Your
                Documentation Review Workflow</b></xref></li>
          <li id="li_b1q_x5v_tvb">Video: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/using_oxygen_xml_web_author_diff_functionality.html"
              format="html" scope="external"><b>Using Oxygen XML Web Author's Diff
              Functionality</b></xref></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
