<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webapp-loadbalancing">
  <title>Setting up a Load-Balanced Server</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Load-balanced server setup for Web Author</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To scale a deployment to a larger number of users and to increase the availability, <ph
        keyref="webappProduct"/> can be deployed on a set of <i>load-balanced</i> servers. This
      topic describes the required setup for such a scenario.</p>
    <section id="section_ltq_rdb_n5">
      <title>Configure Session <i>Stickiness</i></title>
      <p>Every <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> server keeps the state of the edited documents in memory
        for performance reasons. This implies that every user should connect to the same back-end
        server for the duration of an editing session. To achieve this result in a
          <i>load-balanced</i> setting, you should enable <b>session <i>stickiness</i></b>.<note>By
          default, Web Author does not use the <term>Servlet container</term> session management
          implementation. Some load-balancers that implement <b>session <i>stickiness</i></b> by
          modifying the <codeph>JSESSIONID</codeph> session cookie, may not work with this setup. In
          this case, you can change the <filepath>WEB-INF/shiro.ini</filepath> configuration file to
          enable the <term>Servlet container</term> session
          manager:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">sessionManager = org.apache.shiro.web.session.mgt.ServletContainerSessionManager</codeblock></note></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_s1s_32b_n5">
      <title>Configure Server Health Checks</title>
      <p>To detect unhealthy servers, <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> offers a health check <i>REST
          API</i>. The endpoint has the following interface:</p>
      <p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>URL</dt>
            <dd><filepath>rest-public/status</filepath></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Response status code</dt>
            <dd>200 for a healthy server and 503 for an unhealthy server.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Response body</dt>
            <dd>For an unhealthy server, the response body contains a text description of the
              problem.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_ejm_1qr_gv">
      <title>Configure the License Server</title>
      <p>All <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> servers can use the same pool of floating licenses. To
        this end, they all need to be <xref href="webapp_licensing.dita#webapp_licensing">configured
          to use the same license server</xref>. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="share_options_between_all_instances">
      <title>Share Configuration Between All Instances</title>
      <p>The configuration (including options, frameworks, and plugins) is stored in the file system
        in a directory that can be changed using the <xref href="wa-oxygen-data-dir.dita"
            ><i>oxygen.data.dir</i> system property</xref>. For all instances to use the same
        options, <codeph>oxygen.data.dir</codeph> should point to the same directory on a shared
        file system (for example, NFS). </p>
      <p>To manage the configuration, you have two options:</p>
      <ul id="ul_o4n_dvp_p1b">
        <li>Use the <xref href="webapp-admin-page.dita#webapp-admin-page">Administration Page</xref>
          of one of the instances to change these options and then restart all other instances so
          that they pick up the new configuration.</li>
        <li>Create a custom Web Application Archive (WAR) that contains <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>
          and all the configuration. Every time you want to change the configuration, create a new
          version of the WAR file and deploy it again. Such a custom WAR can be built using the
            <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen_sdk.html" format="html" scope="external"
            >Oxygen XML SDK project</xref>.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
