<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webapp_licensing">
  <title>Licensing the <ph keyref="webapp"/></title>
  <body>
    <p>oXygen WebApp uses a floating license model, where the license key is stored on a server and
      individual users consume license seats from a common pool. </p>
    <section>
      <title>How it works</title>
      <p>The license key contains the maximum number of users that can simultaneously access the
        WebApp at any given moment. After a period of inactivity, the license allocated to that user
        becomes available. </p>
      <p>While no personal information is sent to the server, a cookie that identifies the user is
        auto-generated. Note that the use of two different browsers (for example, Firefox and
        Chrome) by a single user, will consume two floating licenses. However, using two or more
        windows or tabs of the same browser, consumes a single floating license.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Licensing</title>
      <p>Follow these steps to license a deployment of <ph keyref="webapp"/>:</p>
      <ol id="ol_ctz_bzr_1r">
        <li>To obtain a license key, please contact <xref href="mailto:support@oxygenxml.com"
            scope="external" format="html">support@oxygenxml.com</xref>.</li>
        <li><xref
            href="installation-setting-up-license-server.dita#installation.setting-up-license-server"
            >Install a floating license server</xref>. If you decide to use an HTTP license server,
          you can deploy it in the same Tomcat server, alongside with <ph keyref="webapp"/>.</li>
        <li>Configure the license server connection.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Configuring the license server</title>
      <p>The connection to the server should be configured in a file located at
          <filepath>WEB-INF/license.properties</filepath>. It should have the following keys.<parml>
          <plentry>
            <pt>licensing.server.type</pt>
            <pd>Type of licensing server. Can be one of <codeph>http</codeph> or
                <codeph>standalone</codeph>.</pd>
          </plentry>
        </parml></p>
      <p>For an HTTP server, configure the following parameters:<parml>
          <plentry>
            <pt>licensing.server.url</pt>
            <pd>The URL of the license server</pd>
          </plentry>
          <plentry>
            <pt>licensing.server.user</pt>
            <pd>The user name used for the license server</pd>
          </plentry>
          <plentry>
            <pt>licensing.server.password</pt>
            <pd>The password used for the license server</pd>
          </plentry>
        </parml></p>
      <p>For a standalone server, configure the following parameters:<parml>
          <plentry>
            <pt>licensing.server.host</pt>
            <pd>The host name of the licensing standalone server</pd>
          </plentry>
          <plentry>
            <pt>licensing.server.port</pt>
            <pd>The port of the licensing standalone server</pd>
          </plentry>
        </parml></p>
      <p>A configuration file might look like this:</p>
      <pre>licensing.server.type=http
licensing.server.url=http://example.com:8080/oxygenLicenseServlet/license-servlet
licensing.server.user=admin
licensing.server.password=******</pre>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>

