<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webauthor-spell-checker">
  <title>Automatic Spell Checking</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Spell Checker</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Automatic spell checking</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="IX-Spell_check-p"><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> automatically checks for spelling errors
      when a document is loaded and every time a modification is made in the document. However, if
      the documented is edited before the initial spell check is finished, it is cancelled and
      errors will only be reported for modifications from that time forward.<note>If more than 500
        errors are detected in the initial spell check, <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> only shows the
        first 500 errors and then any errors detected as modifications are made.</note></p>
    <p>Words that are detected as spelling errors are underlined with a jagged red line. If you
      right-click on the word, you are presented with a list of suggestions that you can select from
      to replace the word and an <uicontrol>Ignore</uicontrol> option that instructs <ph
        keyref="webappProduct"/> to ignore all occurrences of that particular spelling error in the
      current document.</p>
    <section id="disabling_automatic_spell_checker">
      <title>Disabling Automatic Spell Checker</title>
      <p>The spell checking engine in <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> overrides any spell checking
        engines that are part of the browser. To disable this feature, go to the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/OptionsShortcut16.png"/>Preferences</uicontrol> action from the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/WebappMore16.png"/>More drop-down menu</uicontrol> on the
        toolbar and deselect the <uicontrol>Enable automatic spell checking</uicontrol> option.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="language_used_by_the_spell_checker">
      <title>Language Used by the Spell Checker</title>
      <p>If your document has the language specified in certain elements using the
          <codeph>xml:lang</codeph> or <codeph>lang</codeph> attribute, the automatic spell checker
        will use that language to detect errors in the content contained in those elements. You can
        also configure the <xref
          href="customizing-options.dita#customizing-options/spell-check-options-entry"
            ><codeph>spell.check.options</codeph> flag</xref> in a <xref
          href="customizing-options.dita">custom options file</xref> to specify a language to be
        used by the spell checker when no <codeph>xml:lang</codeph> or <codeph>lang</codeph>
        attribute is present. </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
