<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webapp-review-mode">
  <title>Review Actions</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> mode provides an intuitive interface that enables you to
      view documents and document edits. To switch to this mode, tap or click the
        <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> button. This panel presents comments, tracked changes, and
      document highlights. A <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> panel is also available at the bottom of
      the editing area. It displays the current comment or tracked change and the author who
      inserted it.</p>
    <p>To insert a comment, select the text that you want to comment on and press <uicontrol>Add
        comment</uicontrol> at the bottom of the editing area. You are able to navigate between
      comments using the two arrows (left and right) from the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> panel.
      To make changes to a comment, press <uicontrol>Change</uicontrol>.</p>
    <section>
      <title>To add a comment:</title>
      <ol>
        <li>Make a selection in the document content</li>
        <li>Tap or click the <uicontrol>Add comment</uicontrol> button from the bottom of the
          page</li>
        <li>Input a comment in the displayed dialog. Press <uicontrol>Comment</uicontrol> to commit
          it into the document</li>
        <li>The commented text is highlighted</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>To see the list of all comments (or tracked changes) from your document:</title>
      <ol>
        <li>Tap or click the button from the upper left side corner, or swipe from left to right. A
          side panel is shown with all the comments<fig>
            <image href="../img/oxygen_webapp_addon_review.png"/>
          </fig></li>
        <li>Tap or click one of the comments to see it in the document area</li>
        <li>On touch screen devices, swipe from left to right over a comment to activate the
            <b>Remove</b> and <b>Change</b> buttons. For the tracked changes the list of available
          actions are: <b>Accept</b>, <b>Reject</b> and <b>Comment</b></li>
        <li>To hide the list of comments, tap or click the menu button <image
            href="../img/oxygen_webapp_menu.png"/>, or swipe from right to left.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>To navigate through the comments (or tracked changes):</title>
      <ol>
        <li>Tap or click the left and right arrow buttons (<image
            href="../img/oxygen_webapp_review_prev_next.png"/>) from the bottom of the page</li>
        <li>The current comment (or tracked change) is highlighted in the document. Also, it is
          displayed in the left-side <uicontrol>Review panel</uicontrol>. If the <uicontrol>Review
            panel</uicontrol> is not displayed, it is shown in the preview area, located in the
          lower part of the screen</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
