<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webauthor-editing-docs">
  <title>Editing Documents</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Editing documents</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> provides an intuitive interface for editing various types of XML
      documents and includes a variety of powerful features and editing actions to help make your
      tasks as simple and efficient as possible.</p>
    <p>The visual editing mode in <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> includes a <xref
        href="editingActions.dita#editingActions">toolbar with actions</xref> that are specific to
      the type of document you are editing, an editing pane where you add and edit the content, and
      a <xref href="#webauthor-editing-docs/rightside_menu_panel" format="dita">menu panel on the
        right side</xref> with some helper views.</p>
    <section id="main_editing_area">
      <title>Main Editing Area</title>
      <p>The main editing pane includes a <i>breadcrumb</i> stripe at the top of the pane that shows
        the hierarchical XML structure of the current document, from document root to the current
        element. It is a useful tool that helps you to quickly navigate to specific elements in the
        document structure and allows you to visualize the XML element structure. The last element
        listed in the <term>breadcrumb</term> is the element at the current cursor position. The
        last element also has a thin blue bar above it for easier identification. Clicking an
        element from the <term>breadcrumb</term> selects the entire element in the editor area. The
          <term>breadcrumb</term> also includes a contextual menu with some common editing actions
        (such as <uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>,
          <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Rename Element</uicontrol>).</p>
      <p>The main editing pane allows you to create, review, and edit structured content in a visual
        editor that is similar to common word processors. It includes a large variety of
        user-friendly authoring features to help even novice users work with XML content, including
        numerous <xref href="editingActions.dita#editingActions">toolbar, contextual menu, and
          shortcut actions</xref>, a powerful <xref
          href="webauthor-content-completion.dita#webauthor-content-completion"><term>Content
            Completion Assistant</term></xref>, <xref
          href="webapp_smart_paste.dita#webapp_smart_paste"><term>Smart Paste</term> support</xref>,
        and <xref href="checking-for-errors.dita#checking-for-errors">validation
        features</xref>.</p>
      <p>
        <fig>
          <title>Web Author Main Editing Area</title>
          <image href="../img/wa_editing_area.png"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="rightside_menu_panel">
      <title>Right-Side Menu Panel</title>
      <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> also has a panel on the right side of the screen that includes
        useful views and a variety of editing actions. If this panel is not displayed, click the
        arrow button (<image href="../img/WA_open_arrow.png"/>) on the far right side of the
        editor.</p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_hvx_yyf_wr">
          <title>Web Author Right-Side Menu Panel</title>
          <image href="../img/webapp_edit_views.png" id="image_ifz_1zf_wr" placement="inline"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The following views can be accessed from the panel on the right side of the editor:<ul
          id="ul_egv_3pb_gr">
          <li><uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> - Displays the <term>tracked changes</term> and comments
            that have been added to the document by you or other content authors. Each change or
            comment includes actions such as <uicontrol>Reply</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Mark as
              Done</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Accept</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Reject</uicontrol>
            changes, and <uicontrol>Change</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Remove</uicontrol> comments.
            See the <xref href="perform_common_review_actions.dita#perform_common_review_actions"/>
            topic for more information.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> - Displays the attributes of the selected element
            and their values. The <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> panel also presents attribute
            values that are imposed by a <i>subject scheme</i>.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> - Provides <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol>Replace</uicontrol> actions for searching the current document.</li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
