<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webauthor-customize-with-css">
  <title>Customizing the Editing Experience Using CSS</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Customizing Web Author using CSS</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> allows you to edit XML documents with a visual presentation
      mode. The document rendering is controlled by CSS stylesheets. You can control how the XML
      elements are visually presented, from basic aspects such as fonts, colors, and layout (tables,
      lists, etc.) to more advanced aspects such as the in-place XML attribute editor, placeholders
      for empty elements, or controlling which elements can be folded. </p>
    <p><term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term> has a very useful <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/author-css-inspector-view.html"
        format="html" scope="external">CSS inspector</xref> similar to those found in most modern
      browsers. It can be used to quickly modify the CSS used to render your XML documents. </p>
    <section id="section_y4h_vqx_hz">
      <title>Example: Customizing the Background for the Note Element in DITA</title>
      <p>Suppose you want to configure Web Author to render the default DITA <codeph>note</codeph>
        elements with a yellow background while rendering those with the <codeph>type</codeph>
        attribute set to <codeph>danger</codeph> with light red background. You could do this by
        following these steps:<ol id="ol_tzy_2rx_hz">
          <li>In <term>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</term>, create a new DITA topic and insert two
              <codeph>note</codeph> elements (one without setting the <codeph>type</codeph>
            attribute and the other setting the <codeph>type</codeph> attribute to
            <b>danger</b>.</li>
          <li>Right-click on the first <codeph>note</codeph> element and choose <uicontrol>Inspect
              Styles</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>CSS Inspector</uicontrol> view, you can see all the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/author-css-inspector-view.html#author-css-inspector-view__displaying_rules"
              format="html" scope="external">rules currently applied</xref> for notes. Click the
            link associated with one of them to take you to the source CSS file.</li>
          <li>Add the following code in the CSS
            file:<codeblock outputclass="language-css">[class*="topic/note"] {
  padding: 15px;
  margin-bottom: 20px;
  border: 1px solid transparent;
  border-radius: 4px;
  
  color: #8a6d3b;
  background-color: #fcf8e3;
  border-color: #faebcc;
}
[class*="topic/note"][type="danger"] {
  color: #a94442;
  background-color: #f2dede;
  border-color: #ebccd1;
}</codeblock></li>
          <li>Switch to the XML document and see that the colors have changed.</li>
          <li>You can check to see how <codeph>notes</codeph> look in Web Author by using the <xref
              href="customizing_frameworks.dita#customizing_frameworks/developing_and_testing_a_framework_using_the_weba"
              >Web Author Test Server add-on</xref>.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
