<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webauthor-concurrent-editing">
  <title>Concurrent Editing</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Share session</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Concurrent editing</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="webappProduct"/> offers a feature that provides the ability for authoring teams
      to edit and review content concurrently. You can share your editing session and then send its
      URL to other collaborators and then you and your colleagues can edit and review the same
      document simultaneously.</p>
    <p>To initiate a shared editing session, use the <uicontrol><image
          href="../img/wa-share-session-button.png" id="image_kyj_315_rnb"/>Share
        Session</uicontrol> toolbar button. This opens the first window of the <uicontrol>Share
        Editing Session</uicontrol> dialog box. It provides some information, and after clicking
        <uicontrol>Share</uicontrol>, the second window of the dialog box is displayed.</p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_pv5_5h5_rnb">
        <title>Share Editing Session Dialog Box (Second Window)</title>
        <image href="../img/wa-share-session-dialog.png" id="image_eql_xh5_rnb"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>This is where you can retrieve a URL that you can send to other collaborators. While the
      session is shared, other users can join and each user can see the changes made by others, as
      well as their own modifications, in real-time. The person who originally shared the session is
      the only one who can save the document and the concurrent editing session continues as long as
      that person keeps the document open.<note>The <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/wa-share-session-button.png" id="image_pcn_ch5_rnb"/>Share
          Session</uicontrol> action is only present, by default, for some of the built-in
        connectors (Git and WebDAV).</note></p>
    <section id="section_z23_1jt_rnb">
      <title>Important Notes About Concurrent Editing</title>
      <p>
        <ul id="ul_r51_fc5_rnb">
          <li>The <uicontrol>Edit as XML</uicontrol> action (used for switching to the text-based
            mode) is not available in concurrent editing mode.</li>
          <li>Change tracking cannot be enabled during concurrent editing mode. Tracked changes that
            are already present in the document when the concurrent editing session is created are
            still preserved.</li>
          <li>The <uicontrol>Mark as Done</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Reply</uicontrol> actions (for
            comments) are removed during concurrent editing sessions.</li>
          <li>The <uicontrol>Edit Topic Content</uicontrol> option that is usually available from
            the <uicontrol><image href="../img/DM_DisplayMode_drop.png" id="image_cg2_lt3_rnb"/>DITA
              Map Display Mode</uicontrol> drop-down menu is not available in concurrent editing
            sessions.</li>
          <li>Changes made prior to the session being shared cannot be undone.</li>
          <li>This feature is currently in an <i>experimental</i> BETA stage so it is possible to
            encounter stability and performance issues that will be solved in future releases.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link format="html"
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-waCustom/topics/webauthor-concurrent-editing-api.html"
        scope="external">
        <linktext>Integrating Concurrent Editing</linktext>
      </link>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
