<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webapp-initial-installation">
  <title>Installation</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Installing Web Author</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To install the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>, follow these steps:<ol>
        <li>Go to the <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/webauthor/#download" format="html"
            scope="external"><uicontrol>Download</uicontrol> section of the Web Author
            website</xref>.</li>
        <li>Download the type of installation kit that suits your operating system.</li>
        <li>Follow the instructions listed on that page.</li>
        <li>If you used the <uicontrol>Linux</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Windows</uicontrol>, or
            <uicontrol>All Platforms</uicontrol> installation kits, at the end of the installation
          process you will be directed to a license configuration page where you will choose the
          type of license configuration that you want to use.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <section id="license_configuration_page">
      <title>License Configuration Page</title>
      <p>In the license <uicontrol>Configuration Page</uicontrol>, you can choose one of the
        following types of configurations:<ul>
          <li><b>Trial</b> - This is recommended if you want to try the <ph keyref="webappProduct"
            />. <p>It will install all the required components on your computer, it will
              automatically request a trial license based upon the information that you enter in the
              form, and you will have access to the product for 30 days.</p></li>
          <li><b>Fast setup</b> - This is recommended if you have a commercial license and you want
            the installation and the license server to be hosted on the same computer.<p>The
              floating license server and <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> are already installed and
              connected. To activate your license key, follow this procedure:<ol>
                <li>Click the <uicontrol>License server setup page</uicontrol> button.</li>
                <li>Paste your license key in the subsequent form.</li>
                <li>Click <uicontrol>Activate</uicontrol>.<note>This will lock your license key to a
                    particular license server deployment and no multiple uses of the same license
                    key are possible. During the activation process, a code that uniquely identifies
                    your license server deployment is sent to the Oxygen servers, which in turn will
                    sign the license key.</note></li>
                <li>Enter the administration credentials that you provided during the initial
                  setup.</li>
                <li>You will be redirected to the main page of the license server. Click the
                    <uicontrol>Go to Oxygen XML Web Author Dashboard</uicontrol> button and start
                  using the product.</li>
              </ol></p></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Flexible setup</uicontrol> - This is recommended if you want to have a more
            complex deployment (for example, a load-balanced pool of <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>
            instances or if you want to have different servers for the testing and production
              phases).<p>Follow this procedure:<ol>
                <li><xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/license_server.html" format="html"
                    scope="external">Install an external license server</xref>.</li>
                <li>Activate your license key with the newly installed license server.</li>
                <li>Connect <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> to the newly installed license server by
                  using the <xref
                    href="webapp-configure-license-server.dita#webapp-configure-license-server"
                      ><uicontrol>License</uicontrol> section of the Administration
                  Page</xref>.</li>
                <li>Enter the administration credentials that you provided during the initial
                  setup.</li>
                <li>Click on the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> logo at the top-left corner of the
                  page to navigate to the <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> to start using the
                  product.</li>
              </ol></p></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
