<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_responsive_customization">
  <title>WebHelp Responsive Customization Methods</title>
    <body>
    <draft-comment author="radu_pisoi">This topic is designed to contains some customization
      tips.</draft-comment>
    <p>There are several ways of customization, depending on the volume of changes you need to
      apply:</p>
    <p>There are several methods that you can use to customize the Webhelp Responsive output. Each
      method allows you to make a number of customizations and each method has his own limitations.
      So, you can choose a method depending on your needs.</p>
    <section id="section_kqn_g5l_qv"><title>Use one of the predefined placeholders to insert custom
        HTML fragments</title>You can use this method when you like an existing skin, but you need
      to change a bit the generated HTML. A such situation is when you want to insert a welcome
      message above the search text field.<p>The predefined placeholders that you can use to insert
        custom fragments are: [we need a picture here]</p></section>
    <section id="section_nbw_mvl_qv">
      <p>Method</p>
      <p>Each place holder has an associated a transformation parameter. So, if you want to use this
        method to change the Webhelp output you have to:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Edit the <term>WebHelp Responsive</term> transformation scenario</li>
        <li>go to Parameters tab and find the parameter associated with the place holder that you
          want to use</li>
        <li>Specify the parameter value to a HTML file that contains the content you want to insert.
          Also you can specify a small XML fragment as the parameter value.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="customizing_webhelp_output_with_a_custom_css">
      <title>Customizing WebHelp Output with a Custom CSS</title>
      <p>You can use this method when you like an existing skin, and it is very close to what you
        need, but is necessary to personalize it. A such situation could be when you want change a
        color, where you want to adjust a little bit the margins or paddings.</p>
      <p>Advantages</p>
      <p>
        <ul>
          <li>The custom CSS can be included in the project.</li>
          <li>Easy to setup.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Disadvantages</p>
      <p>
        <ul>
          <li>the fonts, images and other resources must be remote, on a server</li>
          <li>Does not appear in the <codeph>Themes</codeph> tab in the transformation scenario,
            instead it should be set as a parameter.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>Method</p>
      <ul id="ul_ux5_4pl_qv">
        <li>Edit the <term>WebHelp Responsive</term> transformation scenario</li>
        <li><ph
            conref="../reusables/topics/reusable-webhelp-customizing.dita#reusable-webhelp-customizing/DITA-parameters-ph"
          /></li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="section_xmn_wpl_qv"><title>Create a WebHelp Responsive skin</title>This method is
      useful when you need some design that is not similar to any of the oXygen predefined skins, or
      you want to heavily change one of the skins. Also this method is useful when you want to
      distribute additional resources (font, images) together with CSS.<p>Advantages</p><p>
        <ul id="ul_ttt_qrl_qv">
          <li>The resources are encapsulated into the skin directory, together with the CSS
            file</li>
          <li>Appears in the transformation scenario dialog <codeph>Themes</codeph> tab.</li>
        </ul>
      </p><p>Disadvantages</p><p>
        <ul id="ul_uzj_trl_qv">
          <li>You need access to the installation folder, or to use an external DITA-OT, with the
            webhelp plugin installed.</li>
        </ul>
      </p><p>Method</p><p>First of all you have to locate the DITA-OT you are using. (Look into the
        preferences for "DITA"). For instance if you are using DITA-OT 2.X, look into the folder: </p><p>
        <codeblock>{oXygenInstallDir}/frameworks/dita/DITA-OT2.x/plugins/com.oxygenxml.webhelp/templates/dita/bootstrap/variants/</codeblock>
      </p><p>Here you can see some subdirectories, corresponding to different variants of the same
        template. For instance:<ol id="ol_fgc_vrl_qv">
          <li>tiles (the main page contains a section with tiles for each chapter)</li>
          <li>tree (the main page contains a section with some expandable tree)</li>
        </ol></p><p>In each variant, you will find a directory with a collection of
        skins.</p><p>Copy the folder of one skin and change the <codeph>skin.css</codeph>
        file.</p><p>You can place fonts, images or other resources in the
          <filepath>resources</filepath> folder next to the <filepath>skin.css</filepath>
        file.</p><p>Tip: Use a small map for a speedy publishing time. Use the browser CSS inspector
        to lookup for CSS classes you need to modify.</p></section>
    <section id="section_zjl_5sl_qv"><title>Create a new Webhelp Responsive Template</title>This
      method can be used when you need to make significant structural changes, for instance moving
      some components to other positions, or you want to use a different layout library than
      Bootstrap (for instance switch to Foundation).<p>Advantages</p><p>
        <ul id="ul_akl_5sl_qv">
          <li>Full customization is possible, change the structure of the generated HTML files and
            create multiple skins for the new template.</li>
        </ul>
      </p><p>Disadvantages</p><p>
        <ul id="ul_bkl_5sl_qv">
          <li>You need access to the installation folder, or to use an external DITA-OT, with the
            webhelp plugin installed.</li>
        </ul>
      </p><p>Method</p><p>Locate the DITA-OT you are using. (Look into the preferences for "DITA").
        For instance if you are using DITA-OT 2.X, look into the folder: </p><p>
        <codeblock>{oXygenInstallDir}/frameworks/dita/DITA-OT2.x/plugins/com.oxygenxml.webhelp/templates/dita/</codeblock>
      </p><p>Copy the <filepath>bootstrap</filepath> folder, clean up the variants directory and
        keep just one. In that variant, keep just a skin. Modify the .html files, CSS-s,
        etc.</p><p>Tip: Use a small map for a speedy publishing time. Use the browser CSS inspector
        to lookup for CSS classes you need to modify.</p></section>
  </body>
</topic>
