<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_templates_mechanism">
  <title>Webhelp templates mechanism</title>
    <body>
    <draft-comment author="webapp">This topic will describe how Webhelp templates
      works.</draft-comment>
    <draft-comment author="webapp"><xref href="https://jira.sync.ro:8443/browse/EXM-35129"
        format="html" scope="external" id="key-val">EXM-35129</xref><b>Create a special/separate
        index.html page for responsive webhelp</b></draft-comment>
    <p>A Webhelp template consist of a set of HTML template pages. Each HTML template file can
      contains one or more predefined components.</p>
    <p><?oxy_comment_start author="Radu Pisoi" timestamp="20160318T154100+0200" comment="Where are the Webhelp templates located? Which is the structure of a Webhelp template?"?>All
      the Webhelp templates are stored in the <b>templates</b> folder located in the root folder of
      the webhelp plugin. The structure of an Webhelp template is the
      following:...<?oxy_comment_end?></p>
    <p>The next sections describes the HTML template pages.</p>
    <section id="section_mdk_ljx_3v">
      <title>The template for the Webhelp main page</title>
      <p>This template is used to generate the main page (index.html) of the Webhelp output.</p>
      <p><?oxy_comment_start author="Radu Pisoi" timestamp="20160318T164724+0200" comment="Maybe a picture."?>Basically,
        this template is used to generate links to the main topics of the publication. These links
        can be presented in two modes: tiles and accordion.<?oxy_comment_end?></p>
      <p>Besides the above components, the components that could be used in this page are:</p>
      <ul id="ul_h2n_55x_3v">
        <li>Publication main title</li>
        <li>Company logo</li>
        <li>Search input</li>
        <li>Print link</li>
        <li>Menu</li>
        <li>Index terms link</li>
      </ul>
      <p>A sample main page can be found below: (screenshot)</p>
      <p>It is comprised of the next components:</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_qwp_bst_jv">
      <title>How to refer resources from the WebHelp template pages</title>
      <draft-comment author="webapp"><xref href="https://jira.sync.ro:8443/browse/EXM-35224"
          format="html" scope="external" id="key-val">EXM-35224</xref><b>What happens with resources
          referenced by a template?</b></draft-comment>
      <p>When you develop a Webhelp template you can refer the next resource categories:</p>
      <ul id="ul_jt1_stt_jv">
        <li>
          <p>Resources that are part of the template</p>
          <p>A template can have specific resources like images or CSS files that can be accessed
            using the <codeph>{$oxygen-webhelp-template-dir}</codeph> macro.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>Resources that are shared by all templates</p>
          <p>The <b>oxygen-webhelp</b>folder contains resources that will be copied in the WebHelp
            output and that could be shared by all templates. A such sample resource is the JQuery
            library. To access a such resource you should use the macro
              <b>{$oxygen-webhelp-resources}</b>.</p>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
