<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_with_feedback_system">
  <title>WebHelp with Feedback System Description</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebHelp with Feedback System</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>WebHelp with Feedback is a form of online help system that consists of a series of web pages
      (XHTML format). Its advantages include platform independence, continuous content update, and a
      feedback mechanism that allows your authors and audience to interact with one another through
      comments.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Layout</title>
      <p>The layout of the feedback-enabled WebHelp system is similar to the layout of the basic
        WebHelp and the left section is identical. However, the bottom of the right section contains
        a <uicontrol>comments</uicontrol> bar. You can click on the <uicontrol>Log in</uicontrol>
        button on the right side of this bar to be authenticated as a user for the WebHelp system
        and your user name will be included in any comments that you add. If you do not have a user
        name, you can click on the <uicontrol>Sign Up</uicontrol> button to create a new user. Under
        the <uicontrol>comments</uicontrol> bar, you can click the <uicontrol>Add New
          Comment</uicontrol> button to add a comment, regardless of whether or not you are logged
        in. <note><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/toc-highlight"/></note></p>
      <fig id="fig_f31_cbf_dr">
        <title>The Layout of the Feedback-Enabled WebHelp System</title>
        <image href="../img/dita-layout-webhelp-feedback.png" id="image_sj1_cbf_dr"/>
      </fig>
      <p>After you log in, your name and user name are displayed in the
          <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> bar together with the <uicontrol>Log off</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> buttons. Click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button to open
        the <uicontrol>User Profile</uicontrol> dialog box. In this dialog box, you can customize
        the following options:<ul id="ul_ik1_cbf_dr">
          <li><uicontrol>Your Name</uicontrol> - You can use this field to edit the initial name
            that you used to create your user profile.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Your email address</uicontrol> - You can use this field to edit the initial
            email address that you used to create your profile.</li>
          <li>You can choose to receive an email in the following situations:<ul id="ul_qs2_4dk_vs">
              <li>When a comment is left on a page that you commented on.</li>
              <li>When a comment is left on any topic in the WebHelp system.</li>
              <li>When a reply is left to one of my comments.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><uicontrol>New Password</uicontrol> - Allows you to enter a new password for your user
              account.<note>The <uicontrol>Current Password</uicontrol> field from the top of the
                <uicontrol>User Profile</uicontrol> is mandatory if you want to save the changes you
              make. </note></li>
        </ul></p>
    </section>
    <section conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/search-tab-section"/>
  </body>
</topic>
