<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_skin_builder">
  <title>The WebHelp Skin Builder</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>WebHelp Skin Builder</uicontrol> is a simple, easy-to-use tool, specially
      designed to assist users to visually customize the look and feel of the WebHelp output. It is
      implemented as an online tool hosted on the <ph keyref="product"/> website and allows you to
      experiment with different styles and colors over an inert documentation sample.</p>
    <p>To be able to use the <uicontrol>Skin Builder</uicontrol>, you need:<ul id="ul_nvb_ppl_14">
        <li>an Internet connection and unrestricted access to <ph keyref="product"/> website;</li>
        <li>a later version web browser.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To start the <uicontrol>Skin Builder</uicontrol>, do one of the following:<ul
        id="ul_hfz_xvk_14">
        <li>from a web browser navigate to <xref
            href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/webhelp-skin-builder" format="html" scope="external"
          />;</li>
        <li>from the <ph keyref="product"/> in the <xref
            href="dita-transformation-skins-tab.dita#dita-transformation-skins-tab"><uicontrol>Skins
              tab</uicontrol></xref>, click the <uicontrol>Online preview</uicontrol> link. In the
          upper section of the preview, click the <uicontrol>Select Skin</uicontrol> button, then
          choose <uicontrol>Customize Skin</uicontrol>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <section>
      <title>The Skin Builder Layout</title>
      <p>The left side panel of the <term>Skin Builder</term>
        is divided into 3 sections:<ul id="ul_nkp_z2q_14">
          <li><uicontrol>Actions</uicontrol> - holds two buttons:<ul id="ul_ahq_hfq_14">
              <li><uicontrol>Import</uicontrol> - allows you to load a CSS stylesheet and applies it
                over the documentation sample;</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Export</uicontrol> - saves all properties as a CSS file.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> - contains the <uicontrol>Highlight
              selection</uicontrol> checkbox which helps you identify the areas affected by a
            particular element customization:<ul id="ul_bwb_xgq_14">
              <li>when hovering an item in the customizable elements menu, the affected sample area
                is highlighted with a dotted blue border;</li>
              <li>when an item in the customizable elements menu is selected, the affected sample
                area is highlighted with a solid red border.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Customize</uicontrol> - provides a series of customizable elements
            organized under four main categories:<ul id="ul_gyp_rzk_14">
              <li>Header</li>
              <li>TOC Area</li>
              <li>Vertical Splitter</li>
              <li>Content</li>
            </ul>For each customizable element you can alter properties like background color or
            font face. Any alteration made in the customizable elements menu is applied in real time
            over the sample area.</li>
        </ul></p></section>
    <section>
      <title>Create a Customization Skin</title>
      <p>
        <ul id="ul_cyf_m4q_14">
          <li>The starting point can be either one of the predefined skins or a CSS stylesheet
            applied over the sample using the <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol> button.</li>
          <li>Use the elements in the <uicontrol>Customize</uicontrol> section to set properties
            that modify the skin's look. By default, all customizable elements display a single
            property, but you can make more properties visible if you click the <image
              href="../img/AddProp20.png" id="image_xy3_fgl_14"/> button and choose from the
            available ones.<note>If you want to revert a setting of a particular property to its
              initial value, press the <image href="../img/ResetProp20.png" id="image_mfw_lhl_14"/>
              button.</note></li>
          <li>When you are happy with the skin customization you have made, press the
              <uicontrol>Export</uicontrol> button. All settings will be saved in a CSS file.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Apply a Customization Skin to a DITA Map to WebHelp Transformation Scenario</title>
      <p>
        <ul id="ul_cxb_trq_14">
          <li>Start <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
          <li>Load the DITA Map you want to produce as a WebHelp output.</li>
          <li>Edit a <term>DITA Map to WebHelp</term>-type transformation scenario. Set the
            previously exported CSS file in the <uicontrol>Custom</uicontrol> section of the
              <uicontrol>Skins</uicontrol> tab.</li>
          <li>Execute the transformation to obtain the WebHelp output.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Apply a Customization Skin to a Docbook to WebHelp Transformation Scenario</title>
      <ul id="ul_hrr_mgs_14">
        <li>Start <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
        <li>Load the Docbook file you want to produce as a WebHelp output.</li>
        <li>Edit a <term>Docbook to WebHelp</term>-type transformation scenario. previously exported
          CSS file in the <uicontrol>Custom</uicontrol> section of the <uicontrol>Skins</uicontrol>
          tab.</li>
        <li>In the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab, set the <codeph>webhelp.skin.css</codeph>
          parameter to point to the previously exported CSS.</li>
        <li>To customize the logo, use the following parameters:<ul id="ul_ff4_tks_14">
            <li conref="docbook4-web-help.dita#docbook4_web_help/param_webhelp_logo_img"/>
            <li conref="docbook4-web-help.dita#docbook4_web_help/param_webhelp_logo_target"/>
          </ul></li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="dita-transformation-skins-tab.dita#dita-transformation-skins-tab"/>
    <link href="dita-ot-transformation.dita#dita-ot-transformation"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
