<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_system_description">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150220T105323+0200" comment="Should we include deployment instructions as we do with the feedback system?"?>WebHelp
    System Description<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
    <body>
      <p>WebHelp is a form of online help that consists of a series of web pages (XHTML format). Its
      advantages include platform independence and continuous content update, since it can be viewed
      using a regular web browser.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Layout</title>
      <p>The layout of the WebHelp system is comprised of two parts:<ul id="ul_dtz_p2f_dr">
          <li>The left section that contains separate tabs for<uicontrol> Content</uicontrol>,
              <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Index</uicontrol>.<note>If your
              documents contain no <codeph>indexterm</codeph> elements, the
                <uicontrol>Index</uicontrol> tab is not generated.</note><note><ph
                id="toc-highlight">You can enhance the appearance of the selected item in the Table
                of Contents. See the <xref href="customize_webhelp.dita#customize_webhelp"
                  >Customizing WebHelp chapter</xref> for more details.</ph></note></li>
          <li>The right section where help pages are displayed.</li>
        </ul>You can navigate through the content of your output using the arrows in the upper-right
        part of the page. These arrows allow you to move to the parent, previous, and next topic.
        The parents of the currently opened topic are also presented at the top of the page.</p>
      <note>You can edit the <codeph>args.hide.parent.link</codeph> parameter to hide the
          <uicontrol>Parent</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>, and
          <uicontrol>Previous</uicontrol> links.</note>
      <p>You can use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CollapseAll16.png" id="image_b3q_53t_tr"
          />Collapse all</uicontrol> button that is displayed in the <uicontrol>Content</uicontrol>
        tab to collapse all the topics presented in the Table of Contents.</p>
      <p>The top-right corner of the page contains the following options:<ul id="ul_i5z_p2f_dr">
          <li><uicontrol>With Frames</uicontrol> - Displays the output using HTML frames to render
            two separate sections (a section that displays the Table of Contents in the left side
            and a section that displays the content of a topic in the right side).</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Print this page</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog with various printing options
            and a print preview.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <fig id="fig_y5z_p2f_dr">
        <title>WebHelp Output</title>
        <image href="../img/WebHelpOutput.png" id="image_nvz_p2f_dr"/>
      </fig>
    </section>
    <section id="search-tab-section">
      <title>Search Tab</title>
      <p id="search_tab_webhelp">The <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol> tab is enhanced with a rating
        mechanism that computes scores for every page that matches the search criteria. These scores
        are then translated into a 5-star rating scheme. The search results are sorted depending on
        the following:<ul id="ul_ely_wvx_cr">
          <li>The number of keywords found in a single page (the higher the number, the
            better).</li>
          <li>The context (for example, a word found in a title scores better than a word found in
            unformatted text). The search ranking order, sorted by relevance is as follows:<ul
              id="ul_swf_qzg_dr">
              <li>The search phrase is included in a meta keyword</li>
              <li>The search phrase is in the title of the page</li>
              <li> The search phrase is in bold text in a paragraph</li>
              <li>The search phrase is in normal text in a paragraph</li>
            </ul></li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>
        <fig id="search-webhelp">
          <title>WebHelp Search with Stemming Enabled</title>
          <image href="../img/WebHelp-search-stemming.png" id="image_jmy_wvx_cr"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p id="search_rules_webhelp">Rules that are applied during a search include:<ul
          id="ul_zmy_wvx_cr">
          <li>The space character separates keywords (an expression such as <i>grow flowers</i>
            counts as two separate keywords: <i>grow</i> and <i>flowers</i>).</li>
          <li>Do not use quotes to perform an exact search for multiple word expressions (an
            expression such as <i>"grow flowers"</i>, returns no results since it searches for two
            separate words).</li>
          <li><codeph>indexterm</codeph> and <codeph>keywords</codeph> DITA elements are an
            effective way to increase the ranking of a page (for example, content inside
              <i>keywords</i> elements weighs twice as much as content inside an <i>H1</i> HTML
            element).</li>
          <li>Words composed by merging two or more words with colon (":"), minus ("-"), underline
            ("_"), or dot (".") characters count as a single word.</li>
          <li>Always search for words containing three or more characters (shorter words, such as
              <term>to</term> or <term>of</term> are ignored). This rule does not apply to CJK
            (Chinese, Japanese, Korean) languages.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>This output format is compatible with the following browsers:<ul id="ul_rbs_yvx_cr">
          <li>Internet Explorer (8 or newer)</li>
          <li>Chrome</li>
          <li>Firefox</li>
          <li>Safari</li>
          <li>Opera</li>
        </ul></p>
      <note type="important" id="chrome_issues">Due to some security restrictions in Google Chrome,
        WebHelp pages loaded from the local system (through URLs of the
          <filepath>file:///...</filepath> format) may not work properly. We recommend that you load
        WebHelp pages in Google Chrome only from a web server.</note>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
