<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_template_resources">
  <title>WebHelp Template Resources</title>
  <body>
    <draft-comment author="webapp">This topic will describe where are the Webhelp templates stored
      and which is the structure of an webhelp template.</draft-comment>
    <p><?oxy_comment_start author="Radu Pisoi" timestamp="20160318T154100+0200" comment="Where are the Webhelp templates located? Which is the structure of a Webhelp template?"?>All
      the Webhelp templates are stored in the <b>templates</b> folder located in the root folder of
      the webhelp plugin. The structure of an Webhelp template is the
      following:<?oxy_comment_end?></p>
    <image href="../img/webhelp_template_resources.png" id="image_uyh_x33_kv"/>
    <p>At the first level of the template directory we can find the predefined directories
        <b>resources</b> and <b>variants</b> that will be copied to the output in the
      {outDir}/oxygen-webhep/template directory.</p>
    <p>Also this folder contains all the HTML template pages used to generate the Webhelp pages:</p>
    <ul id="ul_ghm_ck3_kv">
      <li>wt_index.html - Used to generate main page.</li>
      <li>wt_topic.html - Used to generate HTML pages for each DITA topic.</li>
      <li>wt_search - Used to generate the HTML page for presenting the search result.</li>
      <li>wt_terms - Used to generate the page for index terms.</li>
    </ul>
    <section>
      <title>Template, variant and skin concept</title>
      <p>An HTML <b>template</b> could be seen as a set WebHelp component that are put in a
        predefined HTML layout.</p>
      <p>If we option the displaying of one of more template's components we could obtain one or
        more <b>variants</b> of the template. So, a WebHelp <b>template variant</b> is an instance
        of the template with a specific set of parameters. For instance, we could have two variants
        of the WebHelp main page, one that displays the topics as <i>tiles</i> and another that
        displays the map topics from the first level in a tree-like fashion.</p>
      <p>Each variant has its own directory which gives the name of the variant. The name of the
        variant is displayed also by UI when you choose a variant. </p>
      <p>The variant's directory could contains the following resources:</p>
      <ul id="ul_lns_yxm_kv">
        <li><b>params.properties</b> - This file specifies the values for the parameters imposed by
          this variant.</li>
        <li><b>resources</b> - if this folder exist it should contains resources that are specific
          for a variant. They will be copied to the output directory.</li>
        <li>one or more <b>skins</b> directories that represents custom skins of a variant.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>A variant's <b>skin</b> represents a custom CSS together with some additional resources
        referenced by this skin (images, fonts). The name of the skin directory will give the name
        of the skin and it will be displayed in the UI when you choose a variant's skin.</p>
      <p>The CSS associated with a skin should be named <b>skin.css</b> and it should exists as
        first child of the skin's directory. The additional resources that are specific for this
        skin should stay in the <b>resources</b> directory as first level for the skin
        directory.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
