<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_template_resources">
  <title>WebHelp Responsive Template Directory Structure</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Responsive system<indexterm>Templates<indexterm>Directory
              structure</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>A certain directory structure is required for the WebHelp Responsive templates. The names of
      folders at certain levels correspond to the names of template variants and skins, components
      are defined in specific files, and various resources need to be located in specific locations
      within the directory structure.</p>
    <p>The templates are stored in <filepath><term keyref="glossentry_dita_ot_dir"
        />/plugins/com.oxygenxml.webhelp/templates/dita</filepath>.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>Templates Directory Structure</title>
        <image href="../img/webhelp_template_resources.png" id="image_uyh_x33_kv" placement="inline"
        />
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>At the first level of the template directory we can find the following predefined files and folders:<ul>
        <li><b><filepath>resources</filepath> Folder</b> - Contains all additional resources used by
          the template, such as images, CSS, and JavaScript files.</li>
        <li><b><filepath>variants</filepath> Folder</b> - Contains the template variants, including
          folders for each skin. See <xref
            href="#webhelp_template_resources/template_variant_and_skin_concept" format="dita"
          />.</li>
        <li><b>Template Files</b> - The HTML template files that are used to generate the output:<ul>
            <li><filepath>wt_index.html</filepath> - Used to produce the main home page of the
              WebHelp Responsive output. See <xref
                href="whr-main-page-template.dita#whr-main-page-template"/>.</li>
            <li><filepath>wt_topic.html</filepath> - Used to generate the HTML pages associated with
              individual topics. See <xref href="whr-topic-template.dita#whr-topic-template"/>.</li>
            <li><filepath>wt_search.html</filepath> - Used to generate the HTML page that presents
              the search results. See <xref href="whr-search-template.dita#whr-search-template"
              />.</li>
            <li><filepath>wt_terms.html</filepath> - Used to generate the HTML page that presents
              the documentation index. See <xref
                href="whr-index-terms-template.dita#whr-index-terms-template"/>.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>After the transformation scenario is executed, the resources and variants folders are copied
      in the <filepath>/oxygen-webhelp/template/</filepath> folder within the output directory
      (defined in the <uicontrol>Output</uicontrol> tab of the transformation scenario). </p>
    <section id="template_variant_and_skin_concept">
      <title>Template Variants and Skins</title>
      <p>You could think of a <i>template</i> as being a set of WebHelp components that are
        placed in a predefined HTML layout. You can have multiple variants of the template. A
        WebHelp <i>template variant</i> is an instance of the template with a specific set of
        parameters. For example, you could have two variants of the WebHelp main page, one that
        displays the topics in a <i>tiles</i> style of layout, and another one that displays the
        topics in a <i>tree</i> style.</p>
      <p>Each variant has its own directory that corresponds to the name of the variant. The name of
        the variant is displayed in the user interface when the variants are displayed (for example,
        in the <uicontrol>templates</uicontrol> tab of the transformation scenario). </p>
      <p>Each variant directory may contain the following resources:</p>
      <ul id="ul_lns_yxm_kv">
        <li><b>Skin Directories</b> - These folders represent skin templates for the current
          variant.</li>
        <li><b><filepath>params.properties</filepath> File</b> - This file specifies the values for
          the parameters imposed by the variant.</li>
        <li><b><filepath>resources</filepath> Folder</b> - This is an optional directory that
          contains resources that are specific to the current variant (such as images, CSS files,
          etc.) They will be copied to the output directory.</li>
      </ul>
      <sectiondiv id="skin-div"><b>Skins</b><p>A variant <i>skin</i> represents a CSS file that
          allows you to alter the styling of the template. The CSS associated with a skin must be
          named <b><filepath>skin.css</filepath></b> and it must be stored as a first child of the
          skin directory.</p><p>Each skin might need additional resources (images, fonts) that must
          be stored in the <filepath>resources</filepath> directory in the root folder for that
          particular skin. The name of the skin directory is displayed in the user interface when
          you choose a skin (in the <uicontrol>templates</uicontrol> tab of the transformation
          scenario).</p><p>Each skin directory can also contain a
            <b><filepath>skin.png</filepath></b> preview image that will be displayed in the user
          interface and a properties file that contains a URL for the online preview of the skin.
          This image file must be stored as a first child of the skin directory.</p><p>For
          information about creating or customizing skins, see <xref
            href="webhelp_responsive_customization.dita#webhelp_responsive_customization/section_create_whr_skin"
          />.</p></sectiondiv>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>

