<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="webhelp_system_description">
  <title>WebHelp System Description</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebHelp System</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
    <body>
      <p>WebHelp is a form of online help that consists of a series of web pages (XHTML format). Its
      advantages include platform independence and continuous content update, since it can be viewed
      using a regular web browser.</p>
    <section>
      <title>Layout</title>
      <p>The layout of the WebHelp system is comprised of two parts:<ul id="ul_dtz_p2f_dr">
          <li>The left section that contains separate tabs for<uicontrol> Content</uicontrol>,
              <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Index</uicontrol>.<note>If your
              documents contain no <codeph>indexterm</codeph> elements, the
                <uicontrol>Index</uicontrol> tab is not generated.</note><note><ph
                conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/toc-highlight"/></note></li>
          <li>The right section where help pages are displayed.</li>
        </ul>You can navigate through the content of your output using the arrows in the upper-right
        part of the page. These arrows allow you to move to the parent, previous, and next topic.
        The parents of the currently opened topic are also presented at the top of the page.</p>
      <note>You can edit the <codeph>args.hide.parent.link</codeph> parameter to hide the
          <uicontrol>Parent</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Next</uicontrol>, and
          <uicontrol>Previous</uicontrol> links.</note>
      <p>You can use the <uicontrol><image href="../img/CollapseAll16.png" id="image_b3q_53t_tr"
          />Collapse all</uicontrol> button that is displayed in the <uicontrol>Content</uicontrol>
        tab to collapse all the topics presented in the Table of Contents.</p>
      <p>The top-right corner of the page contains the following options:<ul id="ul_i5z_p2f_dr">
          <li><uicontrol>With Frames</uicontrol> - Displays the output using HTML frames to render
            two separate sections (a section that displays the Table of Contents in the left side
            and a section that displays the content of a topic in the right side).</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Print this page</uicontrol> - Opens a dialog box with various printing
            options and a print preview.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <fig id="fig_y5z_p2f_dr">
        <title>WebHelp Output</title>
        <image href="../img/WebHelpOutput.png" id="image_nvz_p2f_dr"/>
      </fig>
    </section>
    <section id="search-tab" conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/search-tab-section"/>
    <note type="important" id="chrome_issues">Due to some security restrictions in Google Chrome,
      WebHelp pages loaded from the local system (through URLs of the
        <filepath>file:///...</filepath> format) may not work properly. We recommend that you load
      WebHelp pages in Google Chrome only from a web server (with a URL such as
        <filepath>http://your.server.com/webhelp/index.html</filepath> or
        <filepath>http://localhost/web_pages/index.html</filepath>).</note>
    <note type="warning">Due to some restrictions in web browsers in regards to JavaScript code, the
        <term>frameless</term> version (<filepath>index.html</filepath> start page) of the WebHelp
      system should only be loaded from a web server (with a URL such as
        <filepath>http://your.server.com/webhelp/index.html</filepath> or
        <filepath>http://localhost/web_pages/index.html</filepath>). When loading WebHelp pages from
      the local file system, the <term>frameset</term> version
        (<filepath>index_frames.html</filepath> start page) of the WebHelp system should be used
      instead (<filepath>file:///...</filepath>).</note>
    </body>
</topic>
