<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="whc-feedback-system">
  <title>Deploying the Oxygen Feedback Comments Component</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          >WebHelp Classic<indexterm>Comments component</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm product="webhelp">Comments component</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can add a comments component in your WebHelp Classic output to provide a simple and
      efficient way for your community to interact and offer feedback. The comments component is
      contributed by <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>, a modern comment management system that can be
      integrated with your WebHelp Classic output to provide a comments area at the bottom of each
      WebHelp page where readers can add new comments or reply to existing ones.</p>
    <p><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> includes a modern, user-friendly administration interface where you
      can moderate comments, manage users, view statistics, and configure settings. It is very easy
      to integrate and there are no requirements for installing additional software.</p>
    <p>An add-on is also available that contributes a <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/ofb-feedback-comments-manager.html"
        format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Feedback Comments Manager</uicontrol> view</xref>
      in <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i> where the documentation team can see all the comments added
      in your WebHelp output. This means they can react to user feedback by making corrections and
      updating the source content without leaving the application.</p>
    <section id="section_csd_rhx_fjb">
      <title>Adding the Feedback System to WebHelp Classic Documentation</title>
      <p><b><u>Prerequisite</u></b></p>
      <p>To install and manage <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>, you will need to obtain a license for the
        product. This requires that you choose a subscription plan during the installation
        procedure. To see the subscription plans prior to installing the product, go to: <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen_feedback/buy_feedback.html" format="html"
          scope="external"/>.</p>
      <p><b><u>Installation Procedure</u></b><ol id="ol_pwy_sjx_fjb">
          <li>Log in to your Feedback account from the <i>administration login page</i> (<xref
              href="https://feedback.oxygenxml.com/login" format="html" scope="external"/>). You can
            click on <uicontrol>Log in with Google</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Log in with
              Facebook</uicontrol> to create an account using your Google or Facebook credentials,
            or click the <uicontrol>Sign Up</uicontrol> tab to create an account using your name and
            email address.</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Add site</uicontrol> button to create a site configuration. If
            you have not already selected a subscription plan, you will be directed to a page where
            you can choose from several options.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> page, enter a <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> for the site configuration. There are some optional
            settings that can be adjusted according to your needs. For more details, see the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/ofb-creating-site.html#ariaid-title2"
              format="html" scope="external">Site Settings topic</xref>. Click
              <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Initial version</uicontrol> page, enter the <uicontrol>Base
              URL</uicontrol> for your website (you can add additional URLs by clicking the
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/ofb-Add18.png" id="image_sxt_dmx_fjb"
              />Add</uicontrol> button). You can also specify an <uicontrol>Initial
              version</uicontrol> if you want it to be something other than <i>1.0</i>. If you do
            not plan to have multiple versions, leave the version as <i>1.0</i>. For more details,
            see the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/ofb-creating-site.html#ariaid-title3"
              format="html" scope="external">Initial Version topic</xref>. Click
              <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Installation</uicontrol> page, choose a site generation option:<ol
              id="ol_pmh_dnx_fjb">
              <li>If you will generate the documentation using a transformation scenario in
                  <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i>, select the <uicontrol>Oxygen XML
                  Editor</uicontrol> option and continue with these steps:<ol id="ol_i3r_xny_pkb">
                  <li>Copy the generated HTML fragment and click <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>.</li>
                  <li>Create an XML file (for example, <codeph>feedback-install.xml</codeph>) with
                    the generated installation fragment.</li>
                  <li>In <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i>, open the <uicontrol>Configure
                      Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> dialog box.</li>
                  <li>Select and duplicate the <xref href="docbook5_webhelp_output.dita"
                      product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
                        ><uicontrol>DocBook WebHelp Classic</uicontrol> scenario</xref><xref
                      href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/docbook5_webhelp_output.html"
                      format="html" scope="external" product="webhelp"><uicontrol>DocBook WebHelp
                        Classic</uicontrol> scenario</xref>.</li>
                  <li>Go to the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab.</li>
                  <li>Set the <codeph>webhelp.footer.file</codeph> parameter to reference the path
                    of the fragment file created earlier.</li>
                </ol></li>
              <li>If you will generate the documentation using a command-line script, select the
                  <uicontrol>Oxygen XML WebHelp</uicontrol> option and continue with these steps:<ol
                  id="ol_myt_djb_qkb">
                  <li>Copy the generated HTML fragment and click <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>.</li>
                  <li>Create an XML file (for example, <filepath>feedback-install.xml</filepath>)
                    with the generated installation fragment.</li>
                  <li>Use the <codeph>webhelp.footer.file</codeph> parameter in your command-line
                    script to specify the path to the file you just created. For
                    example:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">docbook.bat -Dwebhelp.footer.file=c:\path\to\feedback-install.xml</codeblock></li>
                </ol></li>
            </ol></li>
          <li>[Optional] If you want the <b>Oxygen Feedback</b> comments component to fill the
            entire page width, contribute a custom CSS file (use the
              <codeph>html.stylesheet</codeph> parameter to reference it) that contains the
            following style rule:<codeblock outputclass="language-ini">div.footer {
  float: none;
}</codeblock></li>
        </ol></p>
      <p>For more details about <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>, how to configure settings, moderate
        comments, view statistics, and much more, see the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/index.html" format="html" scope="external"
            ><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> user guide</xref>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
