<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="whr-feedback-system">
  <title>Oxygen Feedback Comments Component</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          >WebHelp Responsive<indexterm>Comments section</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm product="webhelp-responsive">Comments section</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>You can add a comments component in your WebHelp Responsive output to provide a simple and
      efficient way for your community to interact and offer feedback. The comments component is
      contributed by <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>, a modern comment management system that can be
      integrated with your WebHelp Responsive output to provide a comments area at the bottom of
      each WebHelp page where readers can add new comments or reply to existing ones.</p>
    <p><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> includes a modern, user-friendly administration interface where you
      can moderate comments, manage users, view statistics, and configure settings. It is very easy
      to integrate and there are no requirements for installing additional software. You simply need
      to create an <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/ofb-administrator-guide.html"
        format="html" scope="external"><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> site configuration in the
        administration interface</xref>, copy the HTML installation fragment that is generated at
      the end of the creation process, and paste the generated fragment in the <xref
        href="dita-map-edit-feedback.dita"
        product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          ><uicontrol>Feedback</uicontrol> tab in the WebHelp Responsive transformation scenario
        dialog box</xref><xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/dita-map-edit-feedback.html"
        format="html" scope="external" product="webhelp-responsive"><uicontrol>Feedback</uicontrol>
        tab in the WebHelp Responsive transformation scenario dialog box</xref>.</p>
    <p>An add-on is also available that contributes a <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/ofb-feedback-comments-manager.html"
        format="html" scope="external"><uicontrol>Feedback Comments Manager</uicontrol> view</xref>
      in <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i> where the documentation team can see all the comments added
      in your WebHelp output. This means they can react to user feedback by making corrections and
      updating the source content without leaving the application.</p>
    <section id="section_csd_rhx_fjb">
      <title>Adding the Feedback System to WebHelp Responsive Documentation</title>
      <p><b><u>Prerequisites</u></b><ul id="ul_cbv_d3x_fjb">
          <li>To install and manage <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>, you need to obtain a license for the
            product. For details, go to: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen_feedback/buy_feedback.html" format="html"
              scope="external"/>.</li>
          <li>If this is your first time using <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>, you need to sign up for a
            Feedback account from the <i>administration login page</i> (<xref
              href="https://feedback.oxygenxml.com/login" format="html" scope="external"/>). To do
            this, you can click on <uicontrol>Log in with Google</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Log in
              with Facebook</uicontrol> to create an account using your Google or Facebook
            credentials, or click the <uicontrol>Sign Up</uicontrol> tab to create an account using
            your name and email address.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p><b><u>Installation Procedure</u></b><ol id="ol_pwy_sjx_fjb">
          <li>Log in to your Feedback account from the <i>administration login page</i> (<xref
              href="https://feedback.oxygenxml.com/login" format="html" scope="external"/>).</li>
          <li>Click the <uicontrol>Add site</uicontrol> button to create a site (a Feedback
            configuration).</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol> page, enter a <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> for the site configuration. There are some optional
            settings that can be adjusted according to your needs. For more details, see the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/ofb-site-settings-page.html"
              format="html" scope="external">Site Settings topic</xref>.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Initial version</uicontrol> page, enter the <uicontrol>Base
              URL</uicontrol> for your website (you can add additional URLs by clicking the
                <uicontrol><image href="../img/ofb-Add18.png" id="image_sxt_dmx_fjb"
              />Add</uicontrol> button). You can also specify an <uicontrol>Initial
              version</uicontrol> if you want it to be something other than <i>1.0</i>. If you do
            not plan to have multiple versions, leave the version as <i>1.0</i>. For more details,
            see the <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/ofb-site-initial-version.html"
              format="html" scope="external">Initial Version topic</xref>.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Installation</uicontrol> page, choose a site generation option:<ol
              id="ol_pmh_dnx_fjb">
              <li>If you will generate the documentation using a transformation scenario in
                  <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i>, select the <uicontrol>Oxygen XML
                  Editor</uicontrol> option. Then, click <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>, open
                  <i>Oxygen XML Editor/Author</i>, and continue with these steps:<ol
                  id="ol_i3r_xny_pkb">
                  <li>Open the <uicontrol>Configure Transformation Scenario(s)</uicontrol> dialog
                    box.</li>
                  <li>Select and duplicate the <uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp Responsive</uicontrol>
                    scenario.</li>
                  <li>Go to the <uicontrol>Feedback</uicontrol> tab.</li>
                  <li>Click the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button and paste the generated
                    installation fragment.</li>
                </ol></li>
              <li>If you will generate the documentation using a command-line script, select the
                  <uicontrol>Oxygen XML WebHelp</uicontrol> option and follow the onscreen
                instructions.</li>
            </ol></li>
        </ol></p>
      <p>For more details about <b>Oxygen Feedback</b>, how to configure settings, moderate
        comments, view statistics, and much more, see the <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-feedback/topics/index.html" format="html"
          scope="external"><b>Oxygen Feedback</b> user guide</xref>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
