<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="whr-configure-tiles">
  <title>How to Configure the Main Page Tiles</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <term>tiles</term> version of the main page of the WebHelp Responsive output displays a
      tile for each topic found on the first level of the DITA map source. However, you might want
      to customize the way they look or even to hide some of them.</p>
    <p>Depending on your particular setup, you can choose to customize the these tiles either by
      setting metadata information in the DITA map or by customizing the transformation scenario
      DITA map.</p>
  </body>
  <topic id="whr-hiding-tiles-ditamap">
    <title>Hiding some of the tiles displayed in the main page</title>
    <body>
      <p>When the documentation is very large and the number of topics on the first level is very
        large, you might want to hide some of them. Also, this might prove useful when you want to
        display in the first page only the topics that are most relevant to your intended
        audience.</p>
      <p>There are two methods of doing this: one of them involves editing the DITA map and marking
        the topics that do not need to be displayed as tiles, and another one that uses a small CSS
        customization level to hide some tiles identified by the id of the topic.</p>
      <section id="editing_the_dita_map">
        <title>Editing the DITA Map</title>
        <p>To control which topic on the first level of the DITA map will not be displayed as a tile:<ol>
            <li>Open the DITA map in the Text mode of <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
            <li>Add the following metadata information in the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element (or
              any of its specializations) for each first-level topic you do not want to be displayed
              as a
              tile:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;topicmeta>
  &lt;data name="wh-tile">
    &lt;data name="hide" value="yes"/>        
  &lt;/data>
&lt;/topicmeta></codeblock></li>
          </ol></p>
      </section>
      <section id="customizing_the_css">
        <title>Customizing the CSS</title>
        <p>To control which topic on the first level of the DITA map will not be displayed as a tile:<ol>
            <li>Make sure you set an id to the topic you want to hide. For the purpose of this
              procedure, we suppose that the id you set to a topic has the value
                <codeph>growing-flowers</codeph>.</li>
            <li>Create a new CSS file that contains a rule that hides the tile generated for our
              topic (identified by the topic id <codeph>growing-flowers</codeph>). The CSS file has
              the following
              content:<codeblock>* [data-id='growing-flowers'] {
  display:none;
}</codeblock></li>
            <li>Use the <xref
                href="webhelp_responsive_customization.dita#webhelp_responsive_customization/customizing_webhelp_output_with_a_custom_css"
                >Customizing WebHelp Output with a Custom CSS</xref> method to pass the CSS file you
              just created to the transformation scenario.</li>
          </ol></p>
      </section>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="whr-setting-tile-image">
    <title>Setting an Image in the Tiles Displayed in the Main Page</title>
    <body>
      <p>There are two methods to set an image in a tile: one of them involves setting
          <term>metainformation</term> in a DITA map and the other one that uses a CSS .</p>
      <section id="editing_the_dita_map">
        <title>Editing the DITA Map</title>
        <p>
          <ol>
            <li>Open the DITA map in the Text mode of <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
            <li>Add the following metadata information in the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element (or
              any of its specializations) for each first-level topic that will have an image
              displayed in the corresponding
                tile:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;topicmeta>
  &lt;data name="wh-tile">
    &lt;data name="image" href="img/tile-image.png" format="png">
     &lt;data name="attr-width" value="64"/>
     &lt;data name="attr-height" value="64"/>
  &lt;/data>  
&lt;/topicmeta></codeblock><note>The
                  <codeph>attr-width</codeph> and <codeph>attr-height</codeph> attributes can be
                used to control the size of the image, but they are optional.</note></li>
          </ol>
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="customize_an_existing_skin">
        <title>Using a Customized CSS</title>
        <p>
          <ol>
            <li>Make sure you set an id to the topic for which the tile will be decorated with an
              image. For the purpose of this procedure, we suppose that the id you set to a topic
              has the value <codeph>growing-flowers</codeph>.</li>
            <li>Create a new CSS file that contains a rule that associates an image with a specific
              tile. The CSS file has the following
              content:<codeblock>.wh_tile[data-id='growing-flowers']> div {
    background-image:url('resources/flower.png');
}</codeblock></li>
            <li>Use the <xref
                href="webhelp_responsive_customization.dita#webhelp_responsive_customization/customizing_webhelp_output_with_a_custom_css"
                >Customizing WebHelp Output with a Custom CSS</xref> or the <xref
                href="webhelp_responsive_customization.dita#webhelp_responsive_customization/section_create_whr_skin"
                >Create a WebHelp Responsive Skin</xref> method to pass the CSS file you just
              created to the transformation scenario.</li>
          </ol>
        </p>
      </section>
    </body>
  </topic>
</topic>
