<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="whr-customize-menu">
  <title>Customizing the Menu</title>
  <body>
    <p>By default, the menu component is displayed in all WebHelp Responsive pages. However, for
      some reasons you might want to hide it completely, or, display only some of its menu
      entries.</p>
  </body>
  <topic id="whr-hide-menu-entries">
    <title>Hiding Some Menu Entries</title>
    <body>
      <section id="hiding_some_menu_entries">
        <title>Editing the DITA map</title>
        <p>
          <ol>
            <li>Open the DITA map in the Text mode of <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
            <li>Add the following metadata information in the <codeph>topicref</codeph> element (or
              any of its specializations) for each topic you do not want to be displayed in the
              menu:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;topicmeta>
  &lt;data name="wh-menu">
    &lt;data name="hide" value="yes"/>        
  &lt;/data>
&lt;/topicmeta></codeblock></li>
          </ol>
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="customizing_the_css">
        <title>Customizing the CSS</title>
        <p>To hide some of the menu entries:<ol>
            <li>Make sure you set an id to the topic for which you do not want to have a menu entry.
              For the purpose of this procedure, we suppose that the id you set to a topic has the
              value <codeph>growing-flowers</codeph>.</li>
            <li>Create a new CSS file that contains a rule that hides the menu entry generated for
              our topic (identified by the topic id <codeph>growing-flowers</codeph>). The CSS file
              has the following
              content:<codeblock>.wh_top_menu *[data-id='growing-flowers'] {
  display:none;
}</codeblock></li>
            <li>Use the <xref
                href="webhelp_responsive_customization.dita#webhelp_responsive_customization/customizing_webhelp_output_with_a_custom_css"
                >Customizing WebHelp Output with a Custom CSS</xref> method to pass the CSS file you
              just created to the transformation scenario.</li>
          </ol></p>
      </section>
    </body>
  </topic>
  <topic id="whr-hiding-main-menu">
    <title>Hiding the Entire Menu</title>
    <body>
      <p>If you do not need to include a main menu in the pages of the WebHelp Responsive output,
        you can instruct the transformation scenario to skip the menu generation completely. Follow
        this procedure:<ol>
          <li>Edit a WebHelp Responsive transformation scenario.</li>
          <li>Open the <xref href="templates-tab-whr.dita#templates-tab-whr"
                ><uicontrol>Templates</uicontrol> tab</xref> and choose a <term>skin</term> that
            suits you best.</li>
          <li>Open the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> tab and set the value of the
              <codeph>webhelp.show.top.menu</codeph> parameter to <codeph>no</codeph>.</li>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>, then click the <uicontrol>Apply
              associated</uicontrol> button to execute the transformation scenario.</li>
        </ol></p>
    </body>
  </topic>
</topic>
