<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="whr-override-xslt-processing">
  <title>Overriding an XSLT Processing Step of the DITA WebHelp Responsive Transformation</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Responsive system<indexterm>Overriding the XSLT processing
            step</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>WebHelp Responsive system<indexterm>Customizing<indexterm>Overriding the XSLT
              processing step</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XSLT Import extension points for WebHelp Responsive</indexterm>
        <indexterm>XSLT Parameter extension points for WebHelp Responsive</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Since WebHelp Responsive output is primarily obtained by running XSLT transformations over
      the DITA input files (through the <uicontrol>DITA Map WebHelp Responsive</uicontrol>
      transformation scenarios), one customization method would be to override the default XSLT
      templates that are used by the WebHelp Responsive transformations.</p>
    <p>There are two methods available to override the XSLT stylesheets implied by the WebHelp
      Responsive transformation. </p>
    <ul id="ul_tz1_s3t_hz">
      <li>The first method is to use one of the <xref
          href="whr-override-xslt-dita-xslt-import.dita#whr-override-xslt-dita-xslt-import"
            ><b>WebHelp Responsive XSLT-import extension points</b></xref> that allow you to import
        an XSLT stylesheet so that it becomes part of the normal build. This method uses the same
        mechanism as the <xref
          href="http://www.dita-ot.org/dev/extension-points/plugin-extension-points-xslt-import.html"
          format="html" scope="external">DITA-OT XSLT-import extension points</xref>. Note that this
        method will affect all the outputs generated with the WebHelp system.</li>
      <li>The second method implies that you will <xref
          href="whr-xslt-customization.dita#whr-xslt-customization">create a DITA-OT extension
          plugin</xref> with a custom <i>transtype</i> and use an Ant build file to define the
        transformation process. The main difference from the first customization method is that you
        will not affect all WebHelp Responsive transformations. Only the transformations that use
        the declared plugin <i>transtype</i> will be affected.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
  
</topic>
