<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="writer-helper-addon">
  <title>Writer Helper Add-on</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Add-ons<indexterm>Technical Writer Helper</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Technical Writer helper</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_kdh_dgk_54b"><ph keyref="product"/> offers an add-on that provides support for helping
      technical writers. Once the add-on is installed, you can use one if its available tabs to
      access the functionality.</p>
    <p id="p_ldh_dgk_54b">To install the add-on, follow these instructions:</p>
    <ol id="ol_r12_jyz_rmb">
      <li id="li_mdh_dgk_54b">Go to <b>Help > Install new add-ons</b> to open an add-on selection dialog box.</li>
      <li id="li_ndh_dgk_54b">Enter or paste <b>http://www.oxygenxml.com/InstData/Addons/default/updateSite.xml</b>
        in the <b>Show add-ons from</b> field.</li>
      <li id="li_odh_dgk_54b">Select the <b>Technical Writer Helper</b> add-on and click
        <b>Next</b>.</li>
      <li id="li_pdh_dgk_54b">Read the end-user license agreement. Then select the <uicontrol>I accept all terms of
        the end-user license agreement</uicontrol> option and click <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol>.</li>
      <li id="li_qdh_dgk_54b">Restart <ph keyref="product"/>.</li>
    </ol>
    <section id="section_s12_jyz_rmb">
      <title>Review</title>
      <p>You can select folders or files in the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view and start a
        review session for them. The review by default is done in random order and all reviewed
        documents are opened with track change enabled. During the review process you can see a list
        of already reviewed documents and check the status of your progress.</p>
      <p>This feature is useful when the technical writer is tasked with reviewing a set of
        documents.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_z2g_cjv_5qb">
      <title>Similar Content</title>
      <p>You can select folders or files in the <uicontrol>Project</uicontrol> view, then choose a
        list of elements to check for similarity. Once you start the <uicontrol>Find elements with
          similar content</uicontrol> processing, information from all XML, HTML and Markdown files
        is be gathered to determine elements which have similar text content. Once the similar
        matches are presented, you can click on each of them to show a detailed list of places where
        the matches are found.</p>
      <p>This feature is useful to find possible elements which can be reused instead of copy-pasted
        between documents. </p>
      <p>If the <uicontrol>Show similar content for the current file</uicontrol> checkbox is enabled
        and the similar elements have been found, once you open a document, a results tab will show
        elements the current document has in common with all other documents that were analyzed.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_byt_4jv_5qb">
      <title>Read Aloud</title>
      <p>Select content in the current opened document and use the <uicontrol>Play</uicontrol>
        button to listen to how it is read by an operating system specific narrator.</p>
      <p>This feature is useful to review content by listening to it.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_o2b_5jv_5qb">
      <title>Tips</title>
      <p>A list of editing tips, tuned for technical writers can be consulted. Each tip can have a
          <uicontrol>Mode details</uicontrol> link to the <ph keyref="product"/> user's guide.</p>
      <p>This feature is useful to provide productivity tips for making your editing with <ph
          keyref="product"/> more efficient and enjoyable.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
