<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="Writing-Java-Extensions-for-DITA">
  <title>Writing Java Extensions for DITA</title>
  <body>
    <p>Although most of the editor configuration for a specific document type can be done using
      configuration files, for some of the most advanced customization requirements, you need to
      write <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/dg-extensions-bundle.html"
        format="html" scope="external">Java extensions</xref>.</p>
    <p>Such Java extensions can be registered using the <xref
        href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/ug-editor/topics/the-document-type-dialog.html"
        format="html" scope="external">Document Type Configuration dialog box</xref>. When extending
      a framework that already has Java extensions registered (such as DITA), you want to inherit
      the behavior of the extensions from the base framework.</p>
    <p>Suppose you want to register an <codeph>AuthorReferenceResolver</codeph> subclass called
        <codeph>MyConrefResolver</codeph>. Here are the required steps:</p>
    <p>
      <ol id="ol_jv5_vqj_mmb">
        <li>Create a Maven project for your Java extension and add the following
          dependencies:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;dependency>
      &lt;groupId>com.oxygenxml&lt;/groupId>
      &lt;artifactId>oxygen-sdk&lt;/artifactId>
      &lt;version>${oxygen.version}&lt;/version>
&lt;/dependency>
&lt;dependency>
      &lt;groupId>com.oxygenxml&lt;/groupId>
      &lt;artifactId>oxygen-dita-extensions&lt;/artifactId>
      &lt;version>${oxygen.version}&lt;/version>
&lt;/dependency></codeblock></li>
        <li>Create a <codeph>MyConrefResolver.java</codeph> Java source file that contains your
          reference resolver implementation. To inherit the default behavior for resolving
          references, this class should extend the default reference resolver implementation for
          DITA: <codeph>ro.sync.ecss.extensions.dita.conref.DITAConRefResolver</codeph>. You can
          then override some of the methods according to your
              needs.<note><codeph>DITAConRefResolver</codeph> has only one non-deprecated
            constructor, which receives a
              <codeph>ro.sync.ecss.dita.ContextKeyManagerProvider</codeph> parameter.</note></li>
        <li>Create a <codeph>MyDITAExtensionsBundle</codeph> Java source file that extends
            <codeph>ro.sync.ecss.extensions.dita.DITAExtensionsBundle</codeph>. Override the
            <codeph>createAuthorReferenceResolver</codeph> method to return an instance of
            <codeph>MyConrefResolver</codeph> passing the <codeph>keyManagerProvider</codeph> field
          of the base class to the constructor.<note>The <codeph>MyConrefResolver</codeph> can also
            be specified as an extension directly in the Document Type Configuration dialog box.
            However, if specified directly, the default constructor will be used. In the case of the
              <codeph>DITAConRefResolver</codeph>, this causes keys to not be resolved in Web
            Author.</note></li>
        <li>Create a JAR file with your compiled Java classes and add it to your framework's
          classpath using the Document Type Configuration dialog box.</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
