<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xhive-parser-configuration">
  <title><ph conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/xhiveDB"/> Parser Configuration for
    Adding XML Instances</title>
  <body>
    <p>When an XML instance document is added to a <ph conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/xhiveDB"/> connection or library it is
      parsed with an internal XML parser of the database server. The following options are available
      for configuring this parser:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>DOM Level 3 parser configuration parameters. More about each parameter can be found here:
          <xref href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2004/REC-DOM-Level-3-Core-20040407/core.html#DOMConfiguration" scope="external" format="html">DOM Level 3 Configuration</xref>.</li>
      <li><ph conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/xhiveDB"/> specific parser
        parameters (for more information please consult the <ph conref="oxygenEntitiesDictionary.dita#OxygenEntities/xhiveDB"/> manual): <ul>
          <li><uicontrol>xhive-store-schema</uicontrol> - If checked, the corresponding DTD's or XML
            schemas are stored in the catalog during validated parsing.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>xhive-store-schema-only-internal-subset</uicontrol> - Stores only the
            internal subset of the document (not any external subset). This options modifies the
              <uicontrol>xhive-store-schema</uicontrol> one (only has a function when that parameter
            is set to true, and when DTD's are involved). Select this option this option if you only
            want to store the internal subset of the document (not the external subset).</li>
          <li><uicontrol>xhive-ignore-catalog</uicontrol> - Ignores the corresponding DTD's and XML
            schemas in the catalog during validated parsing.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>xhive-psvi</uicontrol> - Stores <b>psvi</b> information on elements and
            attributes. Documents parsed with this feature turned on, give access to <b>psvi</b>
            information and enable support of data types by XQuery queries.</li>
          <li><uicontrol>xhive-sync-features</uicontrol> - Convenience setting. With this setting
            turned on, parameter settings of <apiname>XhiveDocumentIf</apiname> are synchronized
            with the parameter settings of <apiname>LSParser</apiname>. Note that parameter settings
              <uicontrol>xhive-psvi</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>schema-location</uicontrol> are
            always synchronized.</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>