<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-refactoring-operation-descriptor">
  <title>Custom Refactoring Operation Descriptor File</title>
  <body>
    <p>The second step in creating a custom refactoring operation is to create an operation
      descriptor file. The easiest way to do this is to use the <b>New</b> document wizard and
      choose the <b>XML Refactoring Operation Descriptor</b> template.</p>
    <section id="introduction_to_the_descriptor_file">
      <title>Introduction to the Descriptor File</title>
      <p>This file contains information (such as <codeph>name</codeph>,
        <codeph>description</codeph>, and <codeph>id</codeph>) that is necessarily when loading an
        XML Refactoring operation . It also contains the path to the XQuery Update script or XSLT
        stylesheet that is associated with the particular operation through the
          <codeph>script</codeph> element.</p>
      <p>You can specify a <codeph>category</codeph> for your custom operations to logically group
        certain operations. The <codeph>category</codeph> element is optional and if it is not
        included in the descriptor file, the default name of the category for the custom operations
        is <i>Other operations</i>. </p>
      <p>The descriptor file is edited and validated against the following schema:
          <filepath>frameworks/xml_refactoring/operation_descriptor.xsd</filepath>. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="declaring_parameters_in_the_descriptor_file">
      <title>Declaring Parameters in the Descriptor File</title>
      <p>If the XQuery Update script or XSLT stylesheet includes parameters, they should be declared
        in the <b>parameters</b> section of the descriptor file. All the parameters specified in
        this section of the descriptor file will be displayed in the <uicontrol>XML
          Refactoring</uicontrol> tool within <xref
          href="refactoring-xml-documents.dita#refactoring-xml-documents/parameters_dlentry">the
            <uicontrol>Configure Operation Parameters</uicontrol> wizard page</xref> for that
        particular operation.</p>
      <p>The value of the first <codeph>description</codeph> element in the <b>parameters</b>
        section will be displayed at the top of <xref
          href="refactoring-xml-documents.dita#refactoring-xml-documents/parameters_dlentry">the
            <uicontrol>Configure Operation Parameters</uicontrol> wizard page</xref>.</p>
      <p>To declare a parameter, specify the following information:</p>
      <ul id="ul_irs_glv_gr">
        <li><b><codeph>label</codeph></b> - This value is displayed in the user interface for the
          parameter.</li>
        <li><b><codeph>name</codeph></b> - The parameter name used in the XQuery Update script or
          XSLT stylesheet and it should be the same as the one declared in the script.</li>
        <li><b><codeph>type</codeph></b> - Defines the type of the parameter and how it will be
          rendered. There are several types available:<ul id="ul_xm5_j4v_gr">
            <li><codeph>TEXT</codeph> - Generic type used to specify a simple text fragment.</li>
            <li>
              <p><codeph>XPATH</codeph> - Type of parameter whose value is an XPATH expression. For
                this type of parameter, <ph keyref="product"/> will use a text input with
                corresponding content completion and syntax highlighting.</p>
              <note>The value of this parameter is transferred as plain text to the XQuery Update or
                XSLT transformation without being evaluated. You should evaluate the XPath
                expression inside the XQuery Update script or XSLT stylesheet. For example, you
                could use the <codeph>saxon:evaluate</codeph> Saxon extension function. </note>
              <note>A relative XPath expression is converted to an absolute XPath expression by
                adding <codeph>//</codeph> before it (<codeph>//XPathExp</codeph>). This conversion
                is done before transferring the XPath expression to the XML refactoring
                engine.</note>
              <note>When writing XPath expressions, you can only use prefixes declared in the <xref
                  href="preferences-xpath.dita"><menucascade>
                    <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol>XSLT-FO-XQUERY</uicontrol>
                    <uicontrol>XPath</uicontrol>
                  </menucascade></xref> options page.</note>
            </li>
            <li><codeph>NAMESPACE</codeph> - Used for editing namespace values.</li>
            <li><codeph>REG_EXP_FIND</codeph> - Used when you want to match a certain text by using
              Perl-like regular expressions.</li>
            <li><codeph>REG_EXP_REPLACE</codeph> - Used along with <codeph>REG_EXP_FIND</codeph> to
              specify the replacement string.</li>
            <li><codeph>XML_FRAGMENT</codeph> - This type is used when you want to specify an XML
              fragment. For this type, <ph keyref="product"/> will display a text area specialized
              for inserting XML documents.</li>
            <li><codeph>NC_NAME</codeph> - The parameter for <codeph>NC_NAME</codeph> values. It is
              useful when you want to specify the local part of a <xref keyref="glossentry_qname"
                  ><term>QName</term></xref> for an element or attribute.</li>
            <li><codeph>BOOLEAN</codeph> - Used to edit boolean parameters.</li>
            <li><codeph>TEXT_CHOICE</codeph> - It is useful for parameters whose value should be
              from a list of possible values. <ph keyref="product"/> renders each possible value as
              a radio button option.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b><codeph>description</codeph></b> - The description of the parameter. It is used by
          the application to display a tooltip when you hover over the parameter.</li>
        <li><b><codeph>possibleValues</codeph></b> - Contains the list with possible values for the
          parameter and you can specify the default value, as in the following
          example:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;possibleValues onlyPossibleValuesAllowed="true">
    &lt;value name="before">Before&lt;/value>
    &lt;value name="after"default="true"&gt;After&lt;/value>
    &lt;value name="firstChild">First child&lt;/value>
    &lt;value name="lastChild">Last child&lt;/value>
&lt;/possibleValues></codeblock></li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="specialized_parameters_to_match_elements_or_attri">
      <title>Specialized Parameters to Match Elements or Attributes</title>
      <p>If you want to match elements or attributes, you can use some specialized parameters, in
        which case <ph keyref="product"/> will propose all declared elements or attributes based on
        the schema associated with the currently edited file. The following specialized parameters
        are supported:<dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><codeph>elementLocation</codeph></dt>
            <dd>This parameter is used to match elements. For this type of parameter, the
              application displays a text field where you can enter the element name or an XPath
              expression. The text from the <codeph>label</codeph> attribute is displayed in the
              application as the label of the text field. The <codeph>name</codeph> attribute is
              used to specify the name of the parameter from the XQuery Update script or XSLT
              stylesheet. If the value of the <codeph>useCurrentContext</codeph> attribute is set to
                <userinput>true</userinput>, the element name from the cursor position is used as
              proposed values for this parameter. <p>Example of an
                <codeph>elementLocation</codeph>:</p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;elementLocation name="elem_loc" useCurrentContext="false">
                &lt;element label="Element location">
                    &lt;description>Element location description.&lt;/description>
                &lt;/element>
&lt;/ ElementLocation></codeblock></dd></dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><codeph>attributeLocation</codeph></dt>
            <dd>This parameter is used to match attributes. For this type of parameter, the
              application displays two text fields where you can enter the parent element name and
              the attribute name (both text fields accept XPath expressions for a finer match). The
              text from the <codeph>label</codeph> attributes is displayed in the application as the
              label of the associated text fields. The <codeph>name</codeph> attribute is used to
              specify the name of the parameter from the XQuery Update script or XSLT stylesheet.
              The value of this parameter is an XPath expression that is computed by using the
              values of the expression from the <codeph>element</codeph> and
                <codeph>attribute</codeph> text fields. For example, if
                <userinput>section</userinput> is entered for the element and a
                <userinput>title</userinput> is entered for the attribute, the XPath expression
              would be computed as <codeph>//section/@title</codeph>. If the value of the
                <codeph>useCurrentContext</codeph> attribute is set to <userinput>true</userinput>,
              the element and attribute name from the cursor position is used as proposed values for
              the operation parameters. <p>Example of an
              <codeph>attributeLocation</codeph>:</p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;attributeLocation name="attr_xpath" useCurrentContext="true">
                &lt;element label="Element path">
                    &lt;description>Element path description.&lt;/description>
                &lt;/element>
                &lt;attribute label="Attribute" >
                    &lt;description>Attribute path description.&lt;/description>
                &lt;/attribute>
&lt;/ AttributeLocation></codeblock></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><codeph>elementParameter</codeph></dt>
            <dd>This parameter is used to specify elements by local name and namespace. For this
              type of parameter, the application displays two combo boxes with elements and
              namespaces collected from the associated schema of the currently edited file. The text
              from the <codeph>label</codeph> attribute is displayed in the application as label of
              the associated combo. The <codeph>name</codeph> attribute is used to specify the name
              of the parameter from the XQuery Update script or XSLT stylesheet. If you specify the
                <codeph>allowsAny</codeph> attribute, the application will propose <i>&lt;ANY></i>
              as a possible value for the <b>Name</b> and <b>Namespace</b> combo boxes. You can also
              use the <codeph>useCurrentContext</codeph> attribute and if its value is set to
                <userinput>true</userinput>, the element name and namespace from the cursor position
              is used as proposed values for the operation parameters. <p>Example of an
                  <codeph>elementParameter</codeph>:</p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;elementParameter id="elemID">
    &lt;localName label="Name" name="element_localName" allowsAny="true"
 useCurrentContext="true">
        &lt;description>Local name of the parent element.&lt;/description>           
    &lt;/localName>
    &lt;namespace label="Namespace" name="element_namespace" allowsAny="true">
        &lt;description>Local name of the parent element&lt;/description>           
    &lt;/namespace>        
&lt;/elementParameter></codeblock></dd></dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><codeph>attributeParameter</codeph></dt>
            <dd>This parameter is used to specify attributes by local name and namespace. For this
              type of parameter, the application displays two combo boxes with attributes and their
              namespaces collected from the associated schema of the currently edited file. The text
              from the <codeph>label</codeph> attribute is displayed in the application as the label
              of the associated combo box. You can also use the <codeph>useCurrentContext</codeph>
              attribute and if its value is set to <userinput>true</userinput>, the attribute name
              and namespace from the cursor position is used as proposed values for the operation
                parameters.<note>An <codeph>attributeParameter</codeph> is dependant upon an
                  <codeph>elementParameter</codeph>. The list of attributes and namespaces are
                computed based on the selection in the <codeph>elementParameter</codeph> combo
                boxes.</note><p>Example of an
              <codeph>attributeParameter</codeph>:</p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;attributeParameter dependsOn="elemID">
    &lt;localName label="Name" name="attribute_localName" useCurrentContext="true">
        &lt;description>The name of the attribute to be converted.&lt;/description>
    &lt;/localName>
    &lt;namespace label="Namespace" name="attribute_namespace" allowsAny="true">
        &lt;description>Namespace of the attribute to be converted.&lt;/description>
    &lt;/namespace>        
&lt;/attributeParameter> </codeblock></dd></dlentry>
        </dl></p>
    </section>
    <note>All predefined operations are loaded from the <filepath><term
          conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/oxy-install-dir"/>/refactoring</filepath> folder.</note>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist><title>Related Information:</title><link href="custom_operation_sample.dita#custom_operation_sample"/></linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
