<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-schema-diagram-facets-view">
  <title>The Facets View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>XML Schema Diagram Editor<indexterm>Facets
      view</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view presents the facets for the selected component, if
      available. If hidden, you can open it from <menucascade product="editor developer">
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editor developer">Facets</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>
      <menucascade product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Other</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>oXygen</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">Facets</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.<fig product="editor developer">
        <title>The Facets View</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_diagram_schema_facets_view.png"/>
      </fig><fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <title>The Facets View</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_diagram_schema_facets_view.png"/>
      </fig></p>
    <p>The default value of a facet is rendered in the <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view with a
      blue color. The facets that can't be edited are rendered with a gray color. The grouping
      categories (eg: <uicontrol>Enumerations</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Patterns</uicontrol>) are
      not editable. If these categories contain at least one child they are rendered with bold. Bold
      facets are facets with values set explicitly to them.</p>
    <note type="important">Usually inherited facets are presented as default in the
        <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view but if patterns are inherited from a base type and also
      specified in the current simple type only the current specified patterns will be presented.
      You can see the effective pattern value obtained by combining the inherited and the specified
      patterns as a tooltip on the <uicontrol>Patterns</uicontrol> category.</note>
    <p>Facets for components which do not belong to the current edited schema are read-only but if
      you double-click them you can choose to open the corresponding schema and edit them.</p>
    <p>You can edit a facet by double-clicking on it or by pressing Enter, when that facet is
      selected. For some facets you can choose valid values from a list or you can specify another
      value. If a facet has an invalid value or a warning, it will be highlighted in the table with
      the corresponding foreground color. By default facets with errors are presented with red and
      the facets with warnings with yellow. You can customize the error colors from the <xref
        href="preferences-editor-document-checking.dita">Document Checking user
      preferences</xref>.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view has four toolbar actions available also on the
      contextual menu:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>
          <image href="../img/schema_actions_add.png"/> Add</uicontrol> - Allows you to add a new
        enumeration or a new pattern.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>
          <image href="../img/schema_actions_remove.png"/> Remove</uicontrol> - Allows you to remove
        the value of a facet.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>
          <image href="../img/schema_actions_move_up.png"/> Move Up</uicontrol> - Allows you to move
        up the current enumeration/pattern in <uicontrol>Enumerations/Patterns</uicontrol>
        category.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>
          <image href="../img/schema_actions_move_down.png"/> Move Down</uicontrol> - Allows you to
        move down the current enumeration/pattern in <uicontrol>Enumerations/Patterns</uicontrol>
        category.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>
          <image href="../img/sa_copy_button.png"/> Copy</uicontrol> - Copy the attribute
        value.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Open in Regular Expressions Builder</uicontrol> - Allows you to open the
        pattern in the <xref href="XML-schema-regexp-builder.dita">XML Schema Regular Expressions
          Builder</xref></li>
    </ul>
    <p>Facets can be fixed to prevent a derivation from modifying its value. To fix a facet value
      just press the <image href="../img/diagram_schema_unpin.png"/> pin button.</p>
  </body>
</topic>