<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-schema-diagram-facets-view">
  <title>XML Schema Facets View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Design editing mode<indexterm>Facets view</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Schema Diagram Editor<indexterm>Facets view</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Facets view in Design mode</indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Schemas<indexterm>Design mode editing<indexterm>Facets
            view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view for XML Schemas presents the facets for the selected
      component, if available. <ph conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/reopen-view"/></p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editor developer">
        <title>Facets View</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_diagram_schema_facets_view.png" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <title>Facets View</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_diagram_schema_facets_view.png" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The default value of a facet is rendered in the <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view with a
      blue color. The facets that can not be edited are rendered with a gray color. The grouping
      categories (for example: <uicontrol>Enumerations</uicontrol> and
        <uicontrol>Patterns</uicontrol>) are not editable. If these categories contain at least one
      child they are rendered with bold. Bold facets are facets with values set explicitly to
      them.</p>
    <note type="important">Usually inherited facets are presented as default in the
        <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view but if patterns are inherited from a base type and also
      specified in the current simple type only the current specified patterns will be presented.
      You can see the effective pattern value obtained by combining the inherited and the specified
      patterns as a tooltip on the <uicontrol>Patterns</uicontrol> category.</note>
    <p>Facets for components that do not belong to the current edited schema are read-only but if
      you double-click them you can choose to open the corresponding schema and edit them.</p>
    <p>You can edit a facet by double-clicking it or by pressing Enter, when that facet is selected.
      For some facets you can choose valid values from a list or you can specify another value. If a
      facet has an invalid value or a warning, it will be highlighted in the table with the
      corresponding foreground color. By default, facets with errors are presented with red and the
      facets with warnings with yellow. You can customize the error colors from the <xref
        href="preferences-editor-document-checking.dita">Document Checking user
      preferences</xref>.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Facets</uicontrol> view provides the following actions in its toolbar and
      contextual menu:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Add16.png" id="image_ydz_jt1_5r"/> Add</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to add a new enumeration or a new pattern.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Remove16.png" id="image_kpl_pt1_5r"/>
              Remove</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to remove the value of a facet.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Edit Annotations</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to edit an annotation for the selected facet.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MoveUp16.gif" id="image_o1m_3r1_5r"/> Move
              Up</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to move up the current enumeration/pattern in
              <uicontrol>Enumerations/Patterns</uicontrol> category.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MoveDown16.gif" id="image_cy2_fr1_5r"/> Move
              Down</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to move down the current enumeration/pattern in
              <uicontrol>Enumerations/Patterns</uicontrol> category.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png" id="image_ekp_4st_tr"/>
            Copy</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copy the attribute value.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Open in Regular Expressions Builder</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Rather than editing regular expressions manually, this action allows you to open the
            pattern in the <xref href="XML-schema-regexp-builder.dita">XML Schema Regular
              Expressions Builder</xref> that guides you through the process of testing and
            constructing the pattern..</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <p>Facets can be fixed to prevent a derivation from modifying its value. To fix a facet value
      just press the <uicontrol><image href="../img/UnpinValue16.gif" id="image_qjb_fxz_vr"/>
        Pin</uicontrol> button.</p>
  </body>
</topic>