<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-schema-diagram-attributes-view">
  <title>The Attributes View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>XML Schema Diagram Editor<indexterm>Attributes
        view</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view presents the properties for the selected component
      in the schema diagram. If hidden, you can open it from <menucascade product="editor developer">
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editor developer">Attributes</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>
      <menucascade product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Other</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>oXygen</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">Attributes</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. <fig product="editor developer">
        <title>The Attributes View</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_diagram_schema_attributes_view.png"/>
      </fig><fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <title>The Attributes View</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_diagram_schema_attributes_view.png"/>
      </fig></p>
    <p>The default value of a property is presented in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view
      with blue foreground. The properties that can't be edited are rendered with gray foreground. A
      non-editable category which contains at least one child is rendered with bold. Bold properties
      are properties with values set explicitly to them. </p>
    <p>Properties for components which do not belong to the current edited schema are read-only but
      if you double-click them you can choose to open the corresponding schema and edit them.</p>
    <p>You can edit a property by double-clicking on by pressing Enter. For most properties you can
      choose valid values from a list or you can specify another value. If a property has an invalid
      value or a warning, it will be highlighted in the table with the corresponding foreground
      color. By default properties with errors are highlighted with red and the properties with
      warnings are highlighted with yellow. You can customize these colors from the <xref
        href="preferences-editor-document-checking.dita">Document checking user
      preferences</xref>.</p>
    <p>For imports, includes and redefines, the properties are not edited directly in the
        <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view. A dialog will be shown allowing you to specify
      properties for them.</p>
    <p>The schema namespace mappings are not presented in <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view.
      You can view/edit these by choosing <uicontrol>Edit Schema Namespaces</uicontrol> from the
      contextual menu on the schema root. See more in the <xref
        href="xml-schema-diagram-schema-namespaces.dita">Edit Schema Namespaces</xref> section.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view has five actions available on the toolbar and also
      on the contextual menu: </p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/schema_actions_add.png"/> Add</uicontrol> - Allows you to
        add a new member type to an union's member types category.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/schema_actions_remove.png"/> Remove </uicontrol> - Allows
        you to remove the value of a property.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/schema_actions_move_up.png"/> Move Up</uicontrol> - Allows
        you to move up the current member to an union's member types category.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/schema_actions_move_down.png"/> Move Down</uicontrol> -
        Allows you to move down the current member to an union's member types category.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_copy_button.png"/> Copy</uicontrol> - Copy the attribute
        value.</li>
      <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/schema_actions_show_definition.png"/> Show
            Definition<shortcut>Ctrl (Meta on MAC OS) + Click</shortcut></uicontrol> - Shows the
        definition for the selected type.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Show Facets</uicontrol> - Allows you to edit the facets for a simple type.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>