<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-schema-diagram-navigation">
  <title>Navigation in the Schema Diagram</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>XML Schema Diagram
      Editor<indexterm>navigation</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The following editing and navigation features work for all types of schema components:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Move/refer components in the diagram using drag-and-drop actions.</li>
      <li>Select consecutive components on the diagram (components from the same level) using the
          <i>Shift</i> key. You can also make discontinuous selections in the schema diagram using
        the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl (Meta on Mac OS)</shortcut></uicontrol> key. To deselect one
        of the components, use <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_click"/>. </li>
      <li>Use the arrow keys to navigate the diagram vertically and horizontally.</li>
      <li>Use <i>Home</i>/<i>End</i> keys to navigate to the first/last component from the same
        level. Use <uicontrol conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_home"/>
        key combination to go to the diagram root and <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_end"/> to go to the last
        child of the selected component.</li>
      <li>You can easily go back to a previously visited component while moving from left to right.
        The path will be preserved only if you use the left arrow key or right arrow key. For
        example, if the current selection is on the second attribute from an attribute group and you
        press the left arrow key to navigate to the attribute group, when you press the right arrow
        key, then the selection will be moved to the second attribute.</li>
      <li>Go back and forward between components viewed or edited in the diagram by selecting them
        in the <uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol> view: <ul>
          <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_go_back.png"/> Back</uicontrol> (go to previous
            schema component);</li>
          <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_go_forward.png"/> Forward</uicontrol> (go to next
            schema component);</li>
          <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_go_to_last_modification.png"/> Go to Last
              Modification</uicontrol> (go to last modified schema component).</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li>Copy, refer or move global components, attributes, and identity constraints to a different
        position and from one schema to another using the <uicontrol>Cut/Copy</uicontrol> and
          <uicontrol>Paste/Paste as Reference</uicontrol> actions.</li>
      <li>Go to the definition of an element or attribute with the <uicontrol>Show
          Definition</uicontrol> action.</li>
      <li product="editor developer">Search in the diagram using the <xref href="find-replace-dialog.dita"
          >Find/Replace dialog</xref> or the <xref href="quick-find-toolbar.dita">Quick find
          toolbar</xref>. You can find/replace components only in the current file scope.</li>
      <li>You can expand and see the contents of the imports/includes/redefines in the diagram. In
        order to edit components from other schemas the schema for each component will be opened as
        a separate file in <ph keyref="product"
          />.<note type="tip">If an XML Schema referenced by the current opened schema was modified
          on disk, the change will be detected and you will be asked to refresh the current schema
          contents.</note></li>
      <li><p>Recursive references are marked with a recurse symbol: <image
            href="../img/xsd_recurse_symbol.png"/>. Click this symbol to navigate between the
          element declaration and its reference.</p><image
          href="../img/xml_schema_diagram_recurse.png"/>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>