<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-schema-diagram-attributes-view">
  <title>XML Schema Attributes View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Design editing mode<indexterm>Attributes view</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Schema Diagram Editor<indexterm>Attributes view</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>Attributes view in Design mode</indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Schemas<indexterm>Attributes view</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view for XML Schemas presents the properties for the
      selected component in the schema diagram. By default, it is displayed on the right side of the
      editor. <ph conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/reopen-view"/></p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editor developer">
        <title>Attributes View</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_diagram_schema_attributes_view.png" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>
      <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <title>Attributes View</title>
        <image href="../img/ec_diagram_schema_attributes_view.png" placement="inline"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The default value of a property is presented in the <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view
      with blue foreground. The properties that can not be edited are rendered with gray foreground.
      A non-editable category that contains at least one child is rendered with bold. Bold
      properties are properties with values set explicitly to them. </p>
    <p>Properties for components that do not belong to the current edited schema are read-only but
      if you double-click them you can choose to open the corresponding schema and edit them.</p>
    <p>You can edit a property by double-clicking by pressing Enter. For most properties you can
      choose valid values from a list or you can specify another value. If a property has an invalid
      value or a warning, it will be highlighted in the table with the corresponding foreground
      color. By default, properties with errors are highlighted with red and the properties with
      warnings are highlighted with yellow. You can customize these colors from the <xref
        href="preferences-editor-document-checking.dita">Document checking user
      preferences</xref>.</p>
    <p>For imports, includes and redefines, the properties are not edited directly in the
        <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view. A dialog box will open that allows you to specify
      properties for them.</p>
    <p>The schema namespace mappings are not presented in <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view.
      You can view/edit these by choosing <uicontrol>Edit Schema Namespaces</uicontrol> from the
      contextual menu on the schema root. See more in the <xref
        href="xml-schema-diagram-schema-namespaces.dita">Edit Schema Namespaces</xref> section.</p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Attributes</uicontrol> view has five actions available on the toolbar and also
      on the contextual menu: </p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Add16.png" id="image_xsm_kt1_5r"/>Add</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to add a new member type to an union's member types category.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Remove16.png" id="image_oll_qt1_5r"/>Remove
            </uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to remove the value of a property.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MoveUp16.gif" id="image_isc_3r1_5r"/>Move
              Up</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to move up the current member to an union's member types category.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/MoveDown16.gif" id="image_h3w_fr1_5r"/>Move
              Down</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to move down the current member to an union's member types category.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Copy16.png" id="image_x4s_nst_tr"
            />Copy</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Copy the attribute value.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/ShowDefinition16.png" id="image_lf2_vt1_5r"/>Go to
              Definition</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Shows the definition for the selected type.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Show Facets</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to edit the facets for a simple type.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>