<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="XML-schema-regexp-builder">
  <title>XML Schema Regular Expressions Builder</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>XML Schemas<indexterm>Regular Expressions Builder</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XML Schema Regular Expression Builder tool</indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The XML Schema regular expressions builder allows you to test regular expressions on a
      fragment of text as they are applied to an XML instance document. Start the tool by selecting
        <uicontrol>XML Schema Regular Expressions Builder</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol
        product="developer editor">Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol
        product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">XML Tools</uicontrol> menu.</p>
    <p>
      <fig>
        <title>XML Schema Regular Expressions Builder Dialog Box</title>
        <image href="../img/sa_xml_schema_regexp_builder.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The dialog box contains the following:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Regular expressions editor</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to edit the regular expression to be tested and used. Content completion is
            available and presents a list with all the predefined expressions. It is triggered by
            pressing <uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_space"/>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Error display area</dt>
          <dd>If the edited regular expression is incorrect, an error message will be displayed
            here. The message contains the description and the exact location of the error. Also,
            clicking the quick navigation button (<uicontrol><image href="../img/LeavingXml12.png"
              /></uicontrol>) highlights the error inside the regular expression.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Category</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>You can choose from several categories of predefined expressions. The selected
            category influences the displayed expressions in the <uicontrol>Available
              expressions</uicontrol> table.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Available expressions</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This table includes the available regular expressions and a short description for each
            of them. The set of expressions depends on the category selected in the previous
              <uicontrol>Category</uicontrol> combo box. You can add an expression in the
              <uicontrol>Regular expressions editor</uicontrol> by double-clicking the expression
            row in the table. You will notice that in the case of <uicontrol>Character
              categories</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Block names</uicontrol>, the expressions are
            also listed in complementary format.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Evaluate expression on</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>You can choose between two options:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>Evaluate expression on each line</uicontrol> - The edited expression
                will be applied on each line in the <uicontrol>Test</uicontrol> area.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Evaluate expression on all text</uicontrol> - The edited expression
                will be applied on the whole text.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Test</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>A text editor that allows you to enter a text sample for which the regular expression
            will be applied. All matches of the edited regular expression will be highlighted.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>After editing and testing your regular expression you can insert it in the current editor.
      The <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> button will become active when an editor is opened in the
      background and there is an expression in the <uicontrol>Regular expressions
      editor</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The regular expression builder cannot be used to insert regular expressions in the <xref
        href="grid-mode-editor.dita#grid-mode-editor"><uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol> mode</xref> or
        <xref href="xml-schema-diagram-introduction.dita">schema <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol>
        mode</xref>. Accordingly, the <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> button will be not available if
      the current document is edited in these modes.</p>
    <note>Some regular expressions may indefinitely block the Java Regular Expressions engine. If
      the execution of the regular expression does not end in about five seconds, the application
      displays a dialog box that allows you to interrupt the operation.</note>
  </body>
</topic>