<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-schema-preferences-page">
  <title>XML Schema Preferences</title>
  <body>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>XML Schema</uicontrol> preferences page, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor author svnClient developer">Options</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">oXygen XML Editor</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol product="authorEclipse">Author</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML Parser</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol> XML Schema</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>This preferences page allows you to configure the following options:</p>
    <section>
      <title>Xerces validation features</title>
      <ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Default XML Schema version</uicontrol> - allows you to select the version of
          W3C XML Schema: XML Schema 1.0 or XML Schema 1.1;<note>You are also able to set the XML
            Schema version using the <xref
              href="../tasks/new-dialog-sa.dita#new-dialog-sa/customize-xml-schema-dialog"
              product="developer editor"><uicontrol>Customize</uicontrol></xref><xref
              href="../tasks/new-dialog-eclipse.dita#new-dialog-eclipse"
              product="developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol>Customize</uicontrol></xref>
            option in <uicontrol>New</uicontrol> dialog box.</note></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Default XML Schema validation engine</uicontrol> - allows you to set the
          default XML Schema validation engine either to Xerces, or to Saxon EE; </li>
        <li><uicontrol>Enable full schema constraint checking
            (http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/schema-full-checking)</uicontrol> - sets the
            <i>schema-full-checking</i> feature to true. This enables a validation of the parsed XML
          document against a schema (W3C XML Schema or DTD) while the document is parsed;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Enable honour all schema location feature
            (http://apache.org/xml/features/honour-all-schema-location)</uicontrol> - sets the
            <i>honour-all-schema-location</i> feature to true. All the files that declare W3C XML
          Schema components from the same namespace are used to compose the validation model. In
          case this option is disabled, only the first W3C XML Schema file that is encountered in
          the XML Schema import tree is taken into account;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Enable XSD 1.1 CTA full XPath 2.0 checking (
            http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/cta-full-xpath-checking )</uicontrol> -
          controls whether full XPath or an XPath subset is used to evaluate CTA instructions for
          XSD 1.1;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Enable comments and PIs in XDM model, for XSD 1.1 assertion processing (
            http://apache.org/xml/features/validation/assert-comments-and-pi-checking )</uicontrol>
          - controls whether comments and processing instructions are visible to the XPath
          expression used to define an assertion for XSD 1.1;</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Saxon validation features</title>
      <ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Multiple schema imports</uicontrol> - forces xs:import to fetch the
          referenced schema document. By default, the xs:import fetches the document only if no
          schema document for the given namespace has already been loaded. With this option in
          effect, the referenced schema document is loaded unless the absolute URI is the same as a
          schema document already loaded;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Assertions can see comments and processing instructions</uicontrol> -
          controls whether comments and processing instructions are visible to the XPath expression
          used to define an assertion. By default (unlike Saxon 9.3), they are not made
          visible.</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
