<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-contextual-editing">
  <title>Editing Modular XML Files in the Master Files Context</title>
  <body>
    <p>Smaller interrelated modules that define a complex XML modular structure cannot be correctly
      edited or validated individually, due to their interdependency with other modules. <ph
        keyref="product"/> provides the support for defining the main module (or modules), allowing
      you to edit any file from the hierarchy in the context of the master XML files.</p>
    <p>You cat set a main XML document either using the <xref
        href="defining_master_files.dita#defining_master_files">master files support from the
          <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Project</uicontrol><ph
          product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</ph> view</xref>, or
      using a validation scenario.</p>
    <p>To set a main file using a validation scenario, add validation units that point to the main
      modules. <ph keyref="product"/> warns you if the current module is not part of the
      dependencies graph computed for the main XML document. In this case, it considers the current
      module as the main XML document.</p>
    <p>The advantages of editing in the context of a master file include: <ul>
        <li>correct validation of a module in the context of a larger XML structure;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol> displays all collected entities and
          IDs starting from the master files;</li>
        <li><ph keyref="product"/> uses the schema defined in the master file when you edit a module
          which is included in the hierarchy through the <term>External Entity</term>
          mechanism;</li>
        <li>the master files defined for the current module determines the <xref
            href="search-refactor-scope.dita">scope of the search and refactory
            actions</xref> for ID/IDREFS values and for updating references when renaming/moving a
          resource. <ph keyref="product"/> performs the search and refactory actions in the context
          that the master files determine, improving the speed of execution.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about editing modular XML files in the master files context,
      go to <xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Working_With_XML_Modules.html" format="html"
        scope="external">http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Working_With_XML_Modules.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="xml-resource-hierarchy-view.dita"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
