<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="XML-schema-regexp-builder">
  <title>XML Schema Regular Expressions Builder</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Editing XML Schemas<indexterm>schema regular expressions
          builder</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The XML Schema regular expressions builder allows testing regular expressions on a fragment
      of text as they are applied to an XML instance document. Start the tool from menu <menucascade>
        <uicontrol product="editor developer">Tools</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XML Schema Regular Expressions Builder</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <fig product="editor developer">
      <title>XML Schema Regular Expressions Builder Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_xml_schema_regexp_builder.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>XML Schema Regular Expressions Builder Dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_xml_schema_regexp_builder.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The dialog contains the following sections:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>Regular expressions editor</uicontrol> - allows you to edit the regular
        expression to be tested and used. Content completion is available and presents a list with
        all the predefined expressions. It is triggered by pressing <uicontrol
          conref="oxygen-shortcuts-list.dita#oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_space"/>.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Error display area</uicontrol> - if the edited regular expression is incorrect,
        an error message will be displayed here. The message contains the description and the exact
        location of the error. Also, a click on the quick navigation button (<uicontrol><image
            href="../img/LeavingXml12.png"/></uicontrol>) highlights the error inside the regular
        expression.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Category</uicontrol> combo box - here you can choose from several categories of
        predefined expressions. The selected category influences the displayed expressions in the
          <uicontrol>Available expressions</uicontrol> table.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Available expressions</uicontrol> table - holds the available regular
        expressions and a short description for each of them. The set of expressions depends on the
        category selected in the previous combo box. You can add an expression in the
          <uicontrol>Regular expressions editor</uicontrol> by double-clicking on the expression row
        in the table. You will notice that in the case of <uicontrol>Character
          categories</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Block names</uicontrol> the expressions are also
        listed in complementary format. For example: <i>\p{Lu}</i> - Uppercase letters;
          <i>\P{Lu}</i> - Complement of: Uppercase letters.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Evaluate expression on</uicontrol> radio buttons - there are available two
        options: <ul>
          <li><uicontrol>Evaluate expression on each line</uicontrol> - the edited expression will
            be applied on each line in the <uicontrol>Test</uicontrol> area;</li>
          <li><uicontrol>Evaluate expression on all text</uicontrol> - the edited expression will be
            applied on the whole text.</li>
        </ul></li>
      <li><uicontrol>Test</uicontrol> area - a text editor which allows you to enter a text sample
        on which the regular expression will be applied. All matches of the edited regular
        expression will be highlighted.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>After editing and testing your regular expression you can insert it in the current editor.
      The <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> button will become active when an editor is opened in the
      background and there is an expression in the <uicontrol>Regular expressions
      editor</uicontrol>.</p>
    <p>The regular expression builder cannot be used to insert regular expressions in <xref
        href="grid-editor-introduction.dita">the grid version</xref> or <xref
        href="xml-schema-diagram-introduction.dita">the schema version</xref> of a document editor.
      Accordingly, the <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol> button of the dialog will be disabled if the
      current document is edited in grid mode.</p>
    <note><ph id="regexp_interrupt_dialog"
        >Some regular expressions may block indefinitely the Java Regular Expressions engine. If the execution of the regular expression does not end in about five seconds, the application displays a dialog that allows you to interrupt the operation.</ph></note>
  </body>
</topic>