<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xml-refactoring-tool">
  <title>XML Refactoring Tool</title>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>XML Refactoring</uicontrol> tool is presented in the form of as an easy to use
      wizard that is designed to reduce the time and effort required to perform various structure
      management tasks. For example, you can insert, delete, or rename an attribute in all instances
      of a particular element that is found in all documents within your project.  </p>
    <p>To access the tool, select the <uicontrol>XML Refactoring...</uicontrol> action from one of
      the following locations:<ul id="ul_lrm_wz5_3r">
        <li>The <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol
            product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">XML Tools</uicontrol> menu.</li>
        <li>The <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu from the contextual menu in the
            <uicontrol product="author developer editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
            product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</uicontrol> view.</li>
        <li product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse">The
            <uicontrol>Refactoring</uicontrol> submenu from the contextual menu in the
            <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager</uicontrol> view.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The tool includes the following dialog boxes:<dl>
        <dlentry id="refactoring_operations_dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Refactoring Operations</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This dialog box displays, and allows you to select, the available operations, which
            are grouped by category. To search for an operation, you can use the filter text box at
            the top of the dialog box.<fig id="fig_vy5_pqv_3r">
              <image href="../img/refactoring_operations.png" id="image_xyy_rqv_3r"
                product="author developer editor"/>
              <image href="../img/ec_refactoring_operations.png" id="image_jwr_j5v_3r"
                product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"/>
            </fig></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="parameters_dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol>Configure Operation Parameters</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This dialog box allows you to specify the parameters for the refactoring operation.
            The parameters are specific to the type of refactoring operation that is being
            performed. For example, to delete an attribute you need to specify the parent element
            and the qualified name of the attribute to be removed.<fig id="fig_ipl_1wv_3r">
              <image href="../img/configure_operation_param.png" id="image_w32_cwv_3r"
                product="author developer editor"/>
              <image href="../img/ec_configure_operation_param.png" id="image_vvc_xwv_3r"
                product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"/>
            </fig></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Scope and Filters</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The <uicontrol>Scope</uicontrol> section of this dialog box allows you to select the
            scope of the set of files that represent the input of the operation. You can select from
            predefined resource sets (such as the current file, your whole project, the current DITA
            Map hierarchy, etc.) or you can define your own set of resources by creating a working
            set.</dd>
          <dd>The <uicontrol>Filters</uicontrol> section includes the following options:<ul
              id="ul_t3v_nzv_3r">
              <li><uicontrol>Include files</uicontrol> - Allows you to filter the selected resources
                by using a file pattern. For example, to restrict the operation to only analyze
                build files you could use "build*.xml" for the file pattern.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Restrict only to known XML file types</uicontrol> - When enabled, only
                resources with a known XML file type will be affected by the operation.</li>
              <li product="author developer editor"><uicontrol>Look inside archives</uicontrol> -
                When enabled, the resources inside archives will also be affected.</li>
            </ul><fig id="fig_ih5_q1w_3r">
              <image href="../img/refactoring_scope_filters.png" id="image_q5b_s1w_3r"
                product="author developer editor"/>
              <image href="../img/ec_refactoring_scope_filters.png" id="image_csm_t1w_3r"
                product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"/>
            </fig></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>
      <note type="warning">It is recommended that you use the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> button
        to review all the changes that will be made by the refactoring operation before implementing
        the changes. After clicking the <uicontrol>Finish</uicontrol> button, the operation will be
        processed and any <uicontrol>Undo</uicontrol> action will only revert changes on the current
        document. If the scope of an operation is <uicontrol product="author developer editor"
          >Project</uicontrol><uicontrol product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
          >Enclosing project</uicontrol> and it takes longer than expected to process after clicking
        the <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> button, you can use the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/bt_stop.png" id="image_xzl_f3y_jr"/>Stop</uicontrol> button in the progress
        bar to stop the operation.</note>
    </p>
    <p>It is considered best practice to run a validation check after all XML refactoring operations
      that affect multiple files. To validate all possible affected files, right-click on the root
      project folder in the <uicontrol product="author developer editor"
        >Project</uicontrol><uicontrol product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
        >Navigator</uicontrol> view and select one of the actions in the
        <uicontrol>Validate</uicontrol> submenu<ph
        product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"> or click the <uicontrol><image
            href="../img/bt_validate_and_check_button.png" id="image_otg_yzb_jr"/>Validate and Check
          for Completeness</uicontrol> button on the toolbar of the <uicontrol>DITA Maps
          Manager</uicontrol></ph>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
