<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xpath-tooltip-helper">
  <title>Tooltip Helper for the XPath Functions Arguments</title>
  <body>
    <p>When editing the arguments of an XPath/XSLT function, <ph keyref="product"/> tracks the current entered
      argument by displaying a tooltip containing the function signature. The currently edited
      argument is highlighted with a bolder font.</p>
    <p>When moving the caret through the expression, the tooltip is updated to reflect the argument
      found at the caret position.</p>
    <example><p>We want to concatenate the absolute values of two variables, named <i>v1</i> and
          <i>v2</i>.</p><codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;xsl:template match="/"&gt;
    &lt;xsl:value-of select="concat(abs($v1), abs($v2))"&gt;&lt;/xsl:value-of&gt;
&lt;/xsl:template&gt;</codeblock>When
      moving the caret before the first <codeph>abs</codeph> function, <ph keyref="product"/> identifies it as the first
      argument of the <codeph>concat</codeph> function. The tooltip shows in bold font the following
      information about the first argument:<ul>
        <li>its name is <codeph>$arg1</codeph>;</li>
        <li>its type is <codeph>xdt:anyAtomicType</codeph>;</li>
        <li>it is optional (note the <codeph>?</codeph> sign after the argument type).</li>
      </ul>The function takes also other arguments, having the same type, and returns a
        <codeph>xs:string</codeph>.<fig id="figure-xpath-arguments-helper-concat1">
        <title>XPath Tooltip Helper - Identify the <codeph>concat</codeph> Function's First
          Argument</title>
        <image href="../img/bt_content_completion_xpath_helper_concat1.png"/>
      </fig>Moving the caret on the first variable <codeph>$v1</codeph>, the editor identifies the
        <codeph>abs</codeph> as context function and shows its signature:<fig id="figure-xpath-arguments-helper-abs">
        <title>XPath Tooltip Helper - Identify the <codeph>abs</codeph> Function's Argument</title>
        <image href="../img/bt_content_completion_xpath_helper_abs.png"/>
      </fig>Further, clicking the second <codeph>abs</codeph> function name, the editor detects that
      it represents the second argument of the <codeph>concat</codeph> function. The tooltip is
      repainted to display the second argument in bold font.<fig id="figure-xpath-arguments-helper-concat2">
        <title>XPath Tooltip Helper - Identify the <codeph>concat</codeph> Function's Second
          Argument</title>
        <image href="../img/bt_content_completion_xpath_helper_concat2.png"/>
      </fig></example>
    <p> The tooltip helper is available also in the XPath toolbar and the <uicontrol>XPath
        Builder</uicontrol> view.</p>
  </body>
</topic>