<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xpath-builder-view">
  <title>The XPath/XQuery Builder View</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Querying Documents<indexterm>running XPath and XQuery
              expressions<indexterm>XPath/Xquery Builder view</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>XPath/XQuery Builder</uicontrol> view allows you to compose complex XPath and
      XQuery expressions and execute them over the currently edited XML document. For XPath 2.0 /
      3.0, or XQuery expressions, you are able to use the <codeph>doc()</codeph> function to specify
      the source file over which the expressions are executed. When you connect to a database, the
      expressions are executed over that database. If you are using the <uicontrol>XPath/XQuery
        Builder</uicontrol> view and the current file is an XSLT document, <ph keyref="product"/>
      executes the expressions over the XML document in the associated scenario.</p>
    <p>To open the <uicontrol>XPath/XQuery Builder</uicontrol> view, go to <menucascade>
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>XPath/XQuery Builder</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>. </p>
    <p>The upper part of the view contains the following actions:<ul>
        <li>
          <p>a drop-down list that allows you to select the type of the expression you want to
            execute. You can choose between:<ul>
              <li>XPath 1.0 (Xerces-driven);</li>
              <li>XPath 2.0, XPath 2.0SA, Xpath 3.0, Xpath 3.0SA, XQuery 1.0, XQuery 3.0, Saxon-HE
                XQuery, Saxon-PE XQuery, or Saxon-EE XQuery (all of them are Saxon-driven);</li>
              <li>custom connection to XML databases that can execute XQuery expressions.<note>The
                  results returned by XPath 2.0 SA and XPath 3.0 SA have a location limited to the
                  line number of the start element (there are no column information and no end
                  specified).</note><note><ph keyref="product"/> uses Saxon to execute XPath 3.0
                  expressions. Because Saxon implements a part of the 3.0 functions, when using a
                  function that is not implemented, <ph keyref="product"/> returns a compilation
                  error. </note></li>
            </ul></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <uicontrol><image href="../img/ApplyStyleSheet16.png"/>Execute XPath</uicontrol> button -
          press this button to start the execution of the XPath or XQuery expression you are
          editing. The result of the execution is displayed in the <xref
            href="results-view.dita#results-view" format="dita"><uicontrol>Results</uicontrol>
            view</xref> in a separate tab;</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Favorites</uicontrol> button - allows you to save certain expressions that
          you can later reuse. To add an expression as favorite, press the star button and enter a
          name under which the expression is saved. The star turns yellow to confirm that the
          expression was saved. Expand the drop-down list next to the star button to see all your
          favorites. <ph keyref="product"/> automatically groups favorites in folders named after
          the method of execution;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/XPathHistory16.png"/>History</uicontrol> drop-down box -
          keeps a list of the last 15 executed XPath or XQuery expressions;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/Settings16.png"/>Settings</uicontrol> drop-down menu -
          contains three options:<ul>
            <li id="xpath-update-on-caret-move"><uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/outline_update_caret.png"/>Update on caret move</uicontrol> - when
              enabled and you navigate through a document, the XPath expression corresponding to the
              XML node at the current cursor position is displayed;</li>
            <li id="xpath-evaluate-as-you-type"><uicontrol><image href="../img/XPathEvaluate16.png"
                />Evaluate as you type</uicontrol> - when you select this option, the XPath
              expression you are composing is evaluated in real time;<note>The <uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/XPathEvaluate16.png"/>Evaluate as you type</uicontrol> option and
                the automatic validation are disabled <ph product="author developer editor">when you
                  edit <xref href="editing-large-documents.dita#editing-large-documents">huge
                    documents</xref> or </ph>when the scope is other than <uicontrol>Current
                  file</uicontrol>.</note></li>
            <li id="xpath-options"><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_diff_options.png"
                />Options</uicontrol> - opens the Preferences page of the currently selected
              processing engine.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li>
          <p id="xpath-scope-menu"><uicontrol>XPath scope</uicontrol> menu - <ph><ph
                keyref="product"/></ph> allows you to define a scope on which the XPath operation
            will be executed. You can choose where the XPath expression will be executed:<ul
              id="ul_bnt_g5c_vn">
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/xpathScopeCurrentFile16.png" id="image_on3_p5c_vn"
                  /> Current file</uicontrol> - current selected file only;</li>
              <li product="author developer editor"><uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/xpathScopeProject16.png" id="image_v5d_t5c_vn"/>
                  Project</uicontrol> - all the files in the project;</li>
              <li product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/xpathScopeProject16.png" id="image_nbq_dwc_vn"/> Enclosing
                  project</uicontrol> - all the files of the project that encloses the current
                edited file;</li>
              <li product="author developer editor"><uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/xpathScopeProjectSelection16.png" id="image_v1c_5xc_vn"/> Selected
                  project resources</uicontrol> - the files selected in the project;</li>
              <li product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/xpathScopeProjectSelection16.png" id="image_nbz_vxc_vn"/> Workspace
                  selected files</uicontrol> - the files selected in the workspace. The files are
                collected from the last selected resource provider view
                  (<uicontrol>Navigator</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Project Explorer</uicontrol> or
                  <uicontrol>Package Explorer</uicontrol>);</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/xpathScopeOpenedFiles16.png" id="image_dpx_cyc_vn"
                  /> All opened files</uicontrol> - all files opened in the application;</li>
              <li product="author editor authorEclipse editorEclipse"><uicontrol><image
                    href="../img/xpathScopeDitaMap16.png" id="image_efy_gyc_vn"/> Current DITA Map
                  hierarchy</uicontrol> - all resources referred in the DITA maps opened in the DITA
                Maps Manager view;</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/xpathScopeWorkingSets16.png" id="image_xgh_4yc_vn"
                  /> Working sets</uicontrol> - selected working sets.</li>
            </ul>At the bottom of the scope menu there are available the following scope
            configuration actions:<ul id="ul_bj5_q1d_vn">
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_configureSearchScope.png" id="image_n41_v1d_vn"
                  /> Configure XPath working sets</uicontrol> - allows you to configure and manage
                collections of files and folders, encapsulated in logical containers called
                  <term>working sets</term>;</li>
              <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/sa_project_panel_filters.png" id="image_zkq_1cd_vn"
                  /> XPath file filter</uicontrol> - you can filter the files from the selected
                scope on which the XPath expression will be executed. By default the XPath
                expression will be executed only on XML files, but you can also define a set of
                patterns that will filter out files from the current scope.</li>
            </ul></p>
        </li>
      </ul></p>
    <fig product="editor author developer">
      <title>The XPath/XQuery Builder View</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_xpath_builder_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>The XPath/XQuery Builder View</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_xpath_builder_view.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p product="authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">When you hover your cursor over the
      XPath/XQuery version icon <image href="../img/XPathVersion16.png"/>, a tooltip is displayed to
      let you know what engine <ph keyref="product"/> currently uses. </p>
    <p>While you edit an XPath or XQuery expression, <ph keyref="product"/> assists you with the
      following features:<ul>
        <li>
          <p>Content Completion Assistant - It offers context-dependent proposals and takes into
            account the cursor position in the document you are editing. The set of functions
            proposed by the <uicontrol>Content Completion Assistant</uicontrol> also depends on the
            engine version. Select the engine version from the drop-down menu available in the
            toolbar.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>Syntax highlight - allows you to identify the components of an expression. To customize
            the colors of the components of the expression, go to <xref
              href="preferences-colors-sh.dita#preferences-colors-sh"><menucascade>
                <uicontrol>Options</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol> Preferences</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol> Editor</uicontrol>
                <uicontrol> Colors</uicontrol>
              </menucascade> preference page</xref>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>automatic validation of the expression as you type;<note>When you type invalid syntax a
            red serrated line underlines the invalid fragments.</note></li>
        <li>function signature and documentation balloon, when the cursor is located inside a
          function. </li>
      </ul></p>
    
    <p product="author developer editor">The <xref href="undoing-and-redoing-user-actions.dita"
        >usual edit actions</xref>
      <uicontrol>Cut</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol>,
        <uicontrol>Select All</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Undo</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Redo</uicontrol>
      are available in the pop-up menu of the top editable part of the view.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="xpath-results.dita#xpath-results"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
