<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xquery-marklogic-debugger-limitations">
  <title>Peculiarities and Limitations of the MarkLogic Debugger</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Databases<indexterm>debugging with MarkLogic</indexterm>
            <indexterm>limitations of the MarkLogic debugger</indexterm>
          </indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>MarkLogic debugger has the following peculiarities and limitations:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Debugging support is available only for MarkLogic server versions 4.0 or newer;</li>
      <li>For MarkLogic server versions 4.0 or newer there are three XQuery syntaxes which are
        supported: '0.9-ml' (inherited from MarkLogic 3.2), '1.0-ml' and '1.0';</li>
      <li>The local debugger user interface presents all the debugging steps that the MarkLogic
        server executes and the results or possible errors of each step;</li>
      <li>All declared variables are presented as strings. The <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column
        of the <uicontrol>Variables</uicontrol> view contains the expression from the variable
        declaration. It can be evaluated by copying the expression with the <uicontrol>Copy
          value</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu of <xref
          href="debug-variables-view.dita#debug-variables-view" format="dita">the
            <uicontrol>Variables</uicontrol> view</xref> and pasting it in <xref
          href="debug-xwatch-view.dita#debug-xwatch-view" format="dita">the
            <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol> view</xref>;</li>
      <li>No support for <xref
          href="../tasks/determining-what-template-generated-particular-output.dita">Output to
          Source Mapping</xref>;</li>
      <li>No support for <xref href="debug-trace-view.dita">showing the trace</xref>;</li>
      <li>You can set <xref href="debug-breakpoints-view.dita">Breakpoints</xref> in imported
        modules in one of the following cases:<ul>
          <li>when you open the module from the context of the application server involved in the
            debugging, using the <uicontrol>data source explorer</uicontrol>;</li>
          <li>when the debugger automatically opened the modules in the Editor. </li>
        </ul></li>
      <li>Set no breakpoints in modules from the same server which are not involved in the current
        debugging session;</li>
      <li>No support for <xref href="working-with-XSLT-profiler.dita">profiling</xref> when an
        XQuery transformation is executed in the debugger.</li>
    </ul>
  </body>
</topic>
