<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xquery-debugging-with-marklogic">
  <title>Debugging with MarkLogic</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Databases<indexterm>debugging with MarkLogic</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>To start a debug session against the MarkLogic engine, configure a <xref
        href="../tasks/configure-marklogic-datasource.dita">MarkLogic data source</xref> and a <xref
        href="../tasks/configure-marklogic-connection.dita">MarkLogic connection</xref>. Make sure
      that the debugging support is enabled in the MarkLogic server which <ph
        keyref="product"/> accesses. On the
      server-side, debugging must be activated in the XDBC server and in the <i>Task Server</i>
      section of the server control console (the switch <i>debug allow</i>). In case the debugging
      is not activated, the MarkLogic server reports the <msgph>DBG-TASKDEBUGALLOW</msgph>
      error.</p>
    <p>The MarkLogic XQuery debugger integrates seamlessly into the <xref
        href="xquery-debugger-perspective.dita">XQuery Debugger perspective</xref>. If you have a
      MarkLogic scenario configured for the XQuery file, you can choose to <xref
        href="../tasks/steps-in-typical-debug-process.dita">debug the scenario</xref> directly. If
      not, switch to the XQuery Debugger perspective, open the XQuery file in the editor and select
      the MarkLogic connection in the XQuery engine selector from the <xref
        href="debug-control-toolbar.dita">debug control toolbar</xref>. For general information
      about how a debugging session is started and controlled see the <xref
        href="../tasks/steps-in-typical-debug-process.dita">Working with the Debugger</xref>
      section.</p>
    <p>In case you want to debug an XQuery file stored on the MarkLogic server, we recommend you to
      use the <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view to open the module and start the
      debugging session. This improves resolving of any imported modules.</p>
    <p product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">Before starting a debugging session, we recommend
      you to link the MarkLogic connection with an Eclipse project. To do this, go to the
        <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view and select <uicontrol>Link to
        project</uicontrol> in the contextual menu of the MarkLogic connection. The major benefit of
      linking a debugging session with a project is that you can add breakpoints in the XQuery
      modules stored on the server. You are also able to access these modules from the Eclipse
      navigator and run debugging sessions starting from them.</p>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> supports collaborative
      debugging. This feature allows multiple users of <ph
        keyref="product"/> to participate in the same
      debugging session. You can start a debugging session and from a certain point another user can
      continue it. </p>
    <p>In a MarkLogic debugging session, when you add a breakpoint on a line where the debugger
      never stops, <ph keyref="product"/> displays a warning message. These warnings are displayed
      for breakpoints you add either in the main XQuery (which you can open locally or from the
      server), or for breakpoints you add in any XQuery opened from the connection that participates
      at the debugging session.</p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration about the XQuery debugger for MarkLogic, go to <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/XQueryDebuggerforMarkLogic.html" format="html"
        scope="external">http://oxygenxml.com/demo/XQueryDebuggerforMarkLogic.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>