<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xquery-debugger-perspective">
  <title><ph product="developer editor">XQuery Debugger Perspective</ph><ph
      product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">Oxygen XQuery Debugger Perspective</ph>
  </title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Perspectives<indexterm>XQuery Debugger</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XQuery Debugger perspective</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>XQuery Debugger</uicontrol>
      <xref keyref="glossentry_perspective"><term>perspective</term></xref> allows you to detect
      problems in an XQuery transformation process by executing the process step by step in a
      controlled environment and inspecting the information provided in the special views. To switch
      the focus to this <term>perspective</term>, select <ph product="developer editor">the
            <uicontrol><image href="../img/DebuggerXQuery18.png"/> XQuery Debugger</uicontrol> button
        in the top-right corner of the interface or <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Open perspective</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XQuery Debugger</uicontrol>
        </menucascade></ph><menucascade product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Open Perspective</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Other </uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Oxygen XQuery Debugger</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The workspace in this <term>perspective</term> is organized as an editing area assisted by
      special helper views. The editing area contains editor panels that you can <xref
        href="preferences-debugger.dita">split horizontally or vertically</xref> in a stack of XML
      editor panels and a stack of XQuery editor panels. The XML files and XQuery files can be
      edited in <xref href="text-mode-editor.dita#text-mode-editor"><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>
        mode</xref> only.</p>
    <p>The layout of this <term>perspective</term> is composed of the following components:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Menus</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Provides menu driven access to all the features and functions available in the
              <uicontrol>XQuery Debugger</uicontrol>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Toolbars</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Contains all actions needed to configure and control the debugging process. <ph
              product="developer editor">The <xref href="configure-toolbars.dita#configure-toolbars"
                >toolbars can be configured</xref> to suit your specific needs.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>XML Source Pane</dt>
          <dd>The editing pane where you can display and edit data or document-oriented XML
            documents.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>XQuery Source Pane</dt>
          <dd>The editing pane where you can display and edit XQuery files.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Output</uicontrol> View</dt>
          <dd>Displays the transformed output that results from the input of a selected document
            (XML) and selected XQuery document to the XQuery transformer. The result of
            transformation is dynamically written as the transformation is processed. There are two
            types of views for the output: a text view (with XML syntax highlight) and an XHTML
            view.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><xref href="debug-info-view.dita#debug-info-view">Debugging Information
            Views</xref></dt>
          <dd>Presented in two panes, they display various types of information that can be used to
            understand the transformation process. For each information type there is a
            corresponding tab. While running a transformation, relevant events are displayed in the
            various information views. This allows you to obtain a clear view of the transformation
            progress. See the <xref href="debug-info-view.dita#debug-info-view">Debugging
              Information Views</xref> topic for a list of all the information views (and links to
            more details on each view).<note>You can add XPath expression automatically in the
                <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol> view using the <uicontrol>Watch expression</uicontrol>
              action from the contextual menu. If you select an expression, or a fragment of it, and
              then click <uicontrol>Watch expression</uicontrol> in the contextual menu, the entire
              selection is presented in the <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol> view. Expressions
              displayed in the <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol> view are normalized (unnecessary white
              spaces are removed from the expression).</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl> To watch our video demonstration about the XQuery debugging capabilities in <ph
        keyref="product"/>, go to <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/demo/XQuery_Debugger.html"
        format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="debugging.dita#debugging"/>
      <link href="xslt-debugger-perspective.dita#xslt-debugger-perspective"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
