<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xslt-tab">
  <title>The XSLT Tab</title>
  <body>
    <p id="xml-xslt-tabs">The <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol> tab contains the following options:<ul>
        <li><ph id="xml-url"><uicontrol>XML URL</uicontrol> - specifies the source XML file. This
            URL is resolved through the catalog resolver. If the catalog does not have a mapping for
            the URL, then the file is used directly from its remote location.</ph><note><ph
              id="note1-xml-url">In case the transformer engine is Saxon 9 and a custom URI resolver
              is configured in <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol> for Saxon 9, the XML input of the
              transformation is passed to that URI resolver.</ph></note><note><ph id="note2-xml-url"
              >In case the transformer engine is one of the built-in XSLT 2.0 / 3.0 engines and
                <xref href="#xslt-tab/advanced-options" format="dita">the name of an initial
                template</xref> is specified in the scenario, the <uicontrol>XML URL</uicontrol>
              field can be empty. The <uicontrol>XML URL</uicontrol> field can also be empty in case
              of <xref
                href="configuring-custom-xslt-processors.dita#configuring-custom-xslt-processors"
                format="dita">external XSLT processors</xref>. In all other cases a non-empty XML
              URL value is mandatory.</ph></note></li>
        <li><ph id="xsl-url"><uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> - specifies the source XSL file that the
            transformation uses. This URL is resolved through the catalog resolver. If the catalog
            does not have a mapping for the URL, the file is used directly from its remote
            location.</ph></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>You can use the following browsing buttons to enter values in the <uicontrol>XML
        URL</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> fields:<ul id="browsing-buttons">
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_insert_editor_variables.png"/>Insert Editor
            Variables</uicontrol> - opens a pop-up menu allowing to introduce special <xref
            href="editor-variables.dita"><ph
              keyref="product"/> editor
            variables</xref> or <xref href="custom-editor-variables.dita">custom editor
            variables</xref> in the XML URL field;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_local_file.png"/>Browse for local
            file</uicontrol> - opens a local file browser dialog box allowing to select a local
          file;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_remote_file.png"/>Browse for remote
            file</uicontrol> - opens an URL browser dialog box allowing to select a remote
          file;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_from_archive.png"/>Browse for archived
            file</uicontrol> - opens a zip archive browser dialog box allowing to select a file from
          a zip archive;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/OpenDatasourceExplorer16.png"/>Browse Data Source
            Explorer</uicontrol> - opens the <xref
            href="relational-database-explorer.dita#relational-database-explorer" format="dita"
              ><uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol></xref> window;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image id="image_qc4_xct_3f" href="../img/OpenResource16.png"/>Search for
            file</uicontrol> - allows you to find a file in the current project;</li>
        <li><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_open_resource.png"/>Open in editor</uicontrol> - opens
          in an editor panel the file with the path specified in the <uicontrol>XML URL</uicontrol>
          text box. </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>The rest of the options available in the <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol> tab allow you to further
      customize the transformation scenario:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Use "xml-stylesheet" declaration</uicontrol> - use the stylesheet declared
          with an <codeph>xml-stylesheet</codeph> declaration instead of the stylesheet specified in
          the <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> field. By default this checkbox is not selected and the
          transformation applies the XSLT stylesheet specified in the <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol>
          field. If it is checked, the scenario applies the stylesheet specified explicitly in the
          XML document with the <codeph>xml-stylesheet</codeph> processing instruction;</li>
        <li><ph id="transformer"><uicontrol>Transformer</uicontrol> - this combo box presents all
            the transformation engines available to <ph
              keyref="product"/> for
            performing a transformation. These are the built-in engines and <xref
              href="preferences-custom-engines.dita">the external engines defined in the Custom
              Engines preferences page</xref>. The engine you choose in this dialog is used as the
            default transformation engine. In case no validation scenario is associated with an XSLT
            or XQuery document, the transformation engine is used in the validation process, if it
            provides validation support</ph>;<ul>
            <li><ph id="advanced-options"><uicontrol><image href="../img/bt_options_shortcut.png"
                  />Advanced options</uicontrol> - allows you to configure advanced options of the
                Saxon HE / PE / EE engine for the current transformation scenario. To configure the
                same options globally, go to the <xref href="preferences-xslt-saxon8.dita"
                  >Saxon-HE/PE/EE preferences page</xref>. For the current transformation scenario,
                these <uicontrol>advanced options</uicontrol> override the options configured in the
                  <xref href="preferences-xslt-saxon8.dita">Saxon-HE/PE/EE preferences page</xref>.
                The <uicontrol>Initial mode and template</uicontrol> option is available only in the
                  <uicontrol>advanced options</uicontrol>. It is a Saxon-specific option that sets
                the name of the first XSLT template which starts the XSLT transformation or the
                initial mode of transformation</ph>.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><ph id="parameters"><uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> - opens <xref
              href="xslt-transformation-parameters.dita">the <uicontrol>Configure
                parameters</uicontrol> dialog</xref>, allowing you to configure the XSLT parameters
            used in the current transformation. In this dialog you can also configure the parameters
            of additional stylesheets, set with the <uicontrol>Additional XSLT
              stylesheets</uicontrol> button. If the XSLT transformation engine is custom-defined
            you can not use this dialog to configure the parameters sent to the custom engine. In
            this case, you can copy all parameters from the dialog using the contextual menu actions
            and edit the custom XSLT engine to include the necessary parameters  in the command line
          </ph>;</li>
        <li><ph id="extensions"><uicontrol>Extensions</uicontrol> - opens <xref
              href="xslt-xquery-extensions.dita">the dialog for configuring the XSLT/XQuery
              extension jars or classes</xref> which define extension Java functions or extension
            XSLT elements used in the transformation</ph>;</li>
        <li><ph id="Additional-XSLT-stylesheets"><uicontrol>Additional XSLT stylesheets</uicontrol>
            - opens <xref href="additional-xslt-stylesheets.dita">the dialog for adding XSLT
              stylesheets</xref> which are applied on the result of the main stylesheet specified in
            the <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> field. This is useful when a chain of XSLT
            stylesheets must be applied to the input XML document</ph>;</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
