<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xslt-tab">
  <title>The XSLT Tab</title>
  <body>
    <p id="xml-xslt-tabs">The <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol> tab contains the following options:<ul>
        <li><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/xml-url"/><note><ph
              conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/ph-note1-xml-url"/></note><note><ph
              id="note2-xml-url">If the transformer engine is one of the built-in XSLT 2.0 / 3.0
              engines and <xref href="#xslt-tab/advanced-options" format="dita">the name of an
                initial template</xref> is specified in the scenario, the <uicontrol>XML
                URL</uicontrol> field can be empty. The <uicontrol>XML URL</uicontrol> field can
              also be empty if you use <xref
                href="configuring-custom-xslt-processors.dita#configuring-custom-xslt-processors"
                format="dita">external XSLT processors</xref>. Otherwise, a value is mandatory in
              the <uicontrol>XML URL</uicontrol> field.</ph></note></li>
        <li><ph id="xsl-url"><uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> - Specifies the source XSL file that the
            transformation will use. This URL is resolved through the catalog resolver. If the
            catalog does not have a mapping for the URL, the file is used directly from its remote
            location.</ph></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>You can use the following browsing buttons to enter values in the <uicontrol>XML
        URL</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> fields:<dl
        conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/browsing-buttons">
        <dlentry>
          <dt/>
          <dd/>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
    <p>The rest of the options available in the <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol> tab allow you to further
      customize the transformation scenario:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Use "xml-stylesheet" declaration</uicontrol> - Use the stylesheet declared
          with an <codeph>xml-stylesheet</codeph> declaration instead of the stylesheet specified in
          the <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> field. By default, this checkbox is not selected and
          the transformation applies the XSLT stylesheet that is specified in the <uicontrol>XSL
            URL</uicontrol> field. If it is checked, the scenario applies the stylesheet specified
          explicitly in the XML document with the <codeph>xml-stylesheet</codeph> processing
          instruction.</li>
        <li><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/transformer"/><ul>
            <li><ph id="advanced-options"><uicontrol><image href="../img/OptionsShortcut16.gif"
                    id="image_rt5_5nt_tr"/>Advanced options</uicontrol> - Allows you to configure
                the advanced options of the Saxon HE / PE / EE engine for the current transformation
                scenario. To configure the same options globally, go to the <xref
                  href="preferences-xslt-saxon8.dita">Saxon-HE/PE/EE preferences page</xref>. For
                the current transformation scenario, these <uicontrol>Advanced options</uicontrol>
                override the options configured in the <xref href="preferences-xslt-saxon8.dita"
                  >Saxon-HE/PE/EE preferences page</xref>. The <uicontrol>Initial mode and
                  template</uicontrol> option is only available in the <uicontrol>Advanced
                  options</uicontrol>. It is a Saxon-specific option that sets the name of the first
                XSLT template that starts the XSLT transformation or the initial mode of the
                transformation</ph>.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><ph id="parameters"><uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> - Opens <xref
              href="xslt-stylesheet-parameters.dita">the <uicontrol>Configure parameters</uicontrol>
              dialog box</xref>, allowing you to configure the XSLT parameters used in the current
            transformation. In this dialog box, you can also configure the parameters of additional
            stylesheets by using the <uicontrol>Additional XSLT stylesheets</uicontrol> button. If
            the XSLT transformation engine is custom-defined, you can not use this dialog box to
            configure the parameters sent to the custom engine. Instead, you can copy all parameters
            from the dialog box using contextual menu actions and edit the custom XSLT engine to
            include the necessary parameters in the command line that starts the transformation
            process.</ph></li>
        <li id="extensions"><ph conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/extensions"/></li>
        <li><ph id="Additional-XSLT-stylesheets"><uicontrol>Additional XSLT stylesheets</uicontrol>
            - Opens <xref href="additional-xslt-stylesheets.dita">the dialog box for adding XSLT
              stylesheets</xref> that are applied on the main stylesheet that is specified in the
              <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> field. This is useful when a chain of XSLT stylesheets
            must be applied to the input XML document.</ph></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
