<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xslt-debugger-perspective">
  <title><ph product="developer editor">XSLT Debugger </ph><ph
      product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">Oxygen XSLT Debugger Perspective</ph></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Perspectives<indexterm>XSLT Debugger</indexterm></indexterm>
        <indexterm>XSLT Debugger perspective</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>XSLT Debugger</uicontrol>
      <xref keyref="glossentry_perspective"><term>perspective</term></xref> allows you to detect
      problems in an XSLT transformation by executing the process step by step in a controlled
      environment. To switch the focus to this <term>perspective</term>, select <ph
        product="developer editor">the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Debugger18.png"/>XSLT
          Debugger</uicontrol> button in the top-right corner of the interface or <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Open perspective</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>XSLT Debugger</uicontrol>
        </menucascade></ph><menucascade product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
        <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Open Perspective</uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Other </uicontrol>
        <uicontrol>Oxygen XSLT Debugger</uicontrol>
      </menucascade>.</p>
    <p>The workspace in this <term>perspective</term> is organized as an editing area assisted by
      special helper views. The editing area contains editor panels that you can <xref
        href="preferences-debugger.dita">split horizontally or vertically</xref> in a stack of XML
      editor panels and a stack of XSLT editor panels. The XML files and XSL files can be edited in
        <xref href="text-mode-editor.dita#text-mode-editor"><uicontrol>Text</uicontrol> mode</xref>
      only.</p>
    <p>The layout of this <term>perspective</term> is composed of the following components:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Menus</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Provides menu driven access to all the features and functions available in the
              <uicontrol>XSLT Debugger</uicontrol>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Toolbars</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Contains all actions needed to configure and control the debugging process. <ph
              product="author developer">The <xref href="configure-toolbars.dita#configure-toolbars"
                >toolbars can be configured</xref> to suit your specific needs.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>XML Source Pane</dt>
          <dd>The editing pane where you can display and edit data or document-oriented XML
            documents.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>XSL Source Pane</dt>
          <dd>The editing pane where you can display and edit XSL stylesheets.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol id="debug-output-view">Output</uicontrol> View</dt>
          <dd>Displays the transformed output that results from the input of a selected document
            (XML) and selected stylesheet (XSL) to the transformer. The result of transformation is
            dynamically written as the transformation is processed. There are three types of views
            for the output: a text view (with XML syntax highlight), an XHTML view, and one text
            view for each <codeph>xsl:result-document</codeph> element used in the stylesheet (if it
            is an XSLT 2.0 / 3.0 stylesheet).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><xref href="debug-info-view.dita#debug-info-view">Debugging Information
            Views</xref></dt>
          <dd>Presented in two panes, they display various types of information that can be used to
            understand the transformation process. For each information type there is a
            corresponding tab. While running a transformation, relevant events are displayed in the
            various information views. This allows you to obtain a clear view of the transformation
            progress. See the <xref href="debug-info-view.dita#debug-info-view">Debugging
              Information Views</xref> topic for a list of all the information views (and links to
            more details on each view).<note>You can add XPath expression automatically in the
                <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol> view using the <uicontrol>Watch expression</uicontrol>
              action from the contextual menu. In case you select an expression or a fragment of it
              and then click <uicontrol>Watch expression</uicontrol> in the contextual menu, the
              entire selection is presented in the <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol> view. Using
                <uicontrol>Watch expression</uicontrol> without selecting an expression displays the
              value of the attribute from the cursor position in the <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol>
              view. Variables detected at the cursor position are also displayed. Expressions
              displayed in the <uicontrol>XWatch</uicontrol> view are <i>normalized</i> (unnecessary
              white spaces are removed from the expression).</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>For more information about the XSLT debugging capabilities in <ph keyref="product"/>,
      watch our video demonstration:</p>
    <p><object width="450" height="250" data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m9d8c4V-LJw"
        outputclass="iframe">
        <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
      </object></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="debugging.dita#debugging"/>
      <link href="xquery-debugger-perspective.dita#xquery-debugger-perspective"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
