<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xslt-tab-json">
  <title>XSLT Tab (JSON Transformations)</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>JSON transformation scenario<indexterm>XSLT tab</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p id="p_tgl_cgk_54b"><ph
        conkeyref="reusables-transforming-documents/intro-for-transformation-tabs"/></p>
    <p id="xml-xslt-tabs">The <uicontrol>XSLT</uicontrol> tab contains the following options:<dl
        id="dl_wgl_cgk_54b">
        <dlentry id="dlentry_lxy_tm5_5zb">
          <dt><uicontrol>JSON URL</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Specifies the source JSON file. <ph conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path-ph"
              /><ph product="author developer editor"> You can also use the <uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/Edit16.gif"/>Open in editor</uicontrol> button to open the specified
              file in the editor panel.</ph> This URL is resolved through the catalog resolver. If
            the catalog does not have a mapping for the URL, then the file is used directly from its
            remote location.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="xsl-url">
          <dt><uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Specifies the source XSL file that the transformation will use. <ph
              conkeyref="reusables-user-guide/specify-path-ph"/><ph
              product="author developer editor"> You can also use the <uicontrol><image
                  href="../img/Edit16.gif"/>Open in editor</uicontrol> button to open the specified
              file in the editor panel.</ph> This URL is resolved through the catalog resolver. If
            the catalog does not have a mapping for the URL, the file is used directly from its
            remote location.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_xgl_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Transformer</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>This drop-down menu presents all the transformation engines available to <ph
              keyref="product"/> for performing a transformation. The engine you choose is used as
            the default transformation engine. Also, if an XSLT or XQuery document does not have an
            associated validation scenario, this transformation engine is used in the validation
            process (if it provides validation support).</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="advanced-options">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Options16.png"/>Advanced options</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to configure the <xref
              href="advanced-saxon-xslt-options.dita#advanced-saxon-xslt-options">advanced options
              of the Saxon HE/PE/EE engine</xref> for the current transformation scenario. To
            configure the same options globally, go to the <xref href="preferences-xslt-saxon8.dita"
              >Saxon-HE/PE/EE preferences page</xref>. For the current transformation scenario,
            these <uicontrol>Advanced options</uicontrol> override the options configured in that
            preferences page.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dlentry_ygl_cgk_54b">
          <dt><uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a <xref href="xslt-stylesheet-parameters.dita"><uicontrol>Configure
                parameters</uicontrol> dialog box</xref> that allows you to configure the XSLT
            parameters used in the current transformation. In this dialog box, you can also
            configure the parameters for <xref href="#xslt-tab-json/additional-stylesheets"
              format="dita">additional XSLT stylesheets</xref>. If the XSLT transformation engine is
            custom-defined, you cannot use this dialog box to configure the parameters sent to the
            custom engine. Instead, you can copy all parameters from the dialog box using contextual
            menu actions and edit the custom XSLT engine to include the necessary parameters in the
            command line that starts the transformation process.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="extensions">
          <dt><uicontrol>Extensions</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a <xref href="xslt-xquery-extensions.dita#xslt-xquery-extensions">dialog box for
              configuring the XSLT extension <term>JARS</term> or classes</xref> that define
            extension Java functions or extension XSLT elements used in the transformation.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="additional-stylesheets">
          <dt><uicontrol>Additional XSLT stylesheets</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a <xref href="additional-xslt-stylesheets.dita">dialog box for adding XSLT
              stylesheets</xref> that are applied on the main stylesheet specified in the
              <uicontrol>XSL URL</uicontrol> field. This is useful when a chain of XSLT stylesheets
            must be applied to the input XML document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
