<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="xslt-stylesheet-parameters">
  <title>XSLT Stylesheet Parameters</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Transformation Scenario<indexterm>new transformation scenario<indexterm>XSLT
              parameters</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The global parameters of the XSLT stylesheet used in the transformation scenario are
      configured from the dialog available from the <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> button of the
        <uicontrol>Configure Transformation</uicontrol> dialog:</p>
    <fig id="figure-configure-XSLT-params-dialog-oxygen" product="editor author developer">
      <title>Configure parameters dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/sa_configure_XSLT_params.png"/>
    </fig>
    <fig id="figure-configure-XSLT-params-dialog-oxygenEclipse"
      product="editorEclipse authorEclipse developerEclipse">
      <title>Configure parameters dialog</title>
      <image href="../img/ec_configure_XSLT_params.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>The table presents all the parameters of the XSLT stylesheet, all imported and included
      stylesheets and all <xref href="additional-xslt-stylesheets.dita#additional-xslt-stylesheets"
        format="dita">additional stylesheets</xref> with their current values. The following font
      type and color conventions are used:<ul>
        <li>blue font values are the defaults collected from the stylesheet;</li>
        <li>black font values and bold font names indicate edited parameters.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>If a parameter value was not edited, then the table presents its default value. The bottom
      panel presents:<ul id="ul_1rt_dbb_hf">
        <li>the default value of the parameter selected in the table</li>
        <li>a description of the parameter, if available</li>
        <li>the system ID of the stylesheet that declares it</li>
      </ul></p>
    <example>
      <p>For example setting the value of a parameter having a declared namespace like:</p>
      <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;xsl:param name="p:param" xmlns:p="namespace"&gt;default&lt;/xsl:param&gt;</codeblock>
      <p>use the following expression in the <uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> column of the
          <uicontrol>Parameters</uicontrol> dialog:</p>
      <codeblock>{namespace}param</codeblock>
    </example>
    <p>If the <uicontrol>XPath</uicontrol> column is checked, the parameter value is evaluated as an
      XPath expression before starting the XSLT transformation. </p>
    <example>
      <p>For example, you can use expressions
        like:<codeblock>doc('test.xml')//entry
//person[@atr='val']</codeblock></p>
    </example>
    <note>
      <ol>
        <li>The <b>doc</b> function solves the argument relative to the XSL stylesheet location. You
          can use full paths or editor variables like <b>${cfdu}</b> (current file directory) to
          specify other locations: <codeph>doc('${cfdu}/test.xml')//*</codeph></li>
        <li>You cannot use XSLT Functions. Only XPath functions are allowed. </li>
      </ol>
    </note>
    <p>The following actions are available for managing parameters:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><uicontrol>New</uicontrol> - Adds a new parameter to the list.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> - Edits the value of the selected parameter.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Unset</uicontrol> - Resets the selected parameter to its default value.
        Available only for parameters with set values.</li>
      <li><uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> - Removes the selected parameter from the list. It is
        enabled only for parameters added to the list with the <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
        button.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The <xref href="../topics/editor-variables.dita">editor variables</xref> displayed at the
      bottom of the dialog can be used in the values of the parameters to make them independent of
      the location of the XSLT stylesheet or the XML document.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="editor-variables.dita#editor-variables"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
