<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xslt-contextual-editing">
  <title>Editing XSLT Stylesheets in the Master Files Context</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>XSLT<indexterm>Editing in Master Files context</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Smaller interrelated modules that define a complex stylesheet cannot be correctly edited or
      validated individually, due to their interdependency with other modules. For example, a
      function defined in a main stylesheet is not visible when you edit an included or imported
      module. <ph keyref="product"/> provides the support for defining the main module (or modules),
      allowing you to edit any of the imported/included files in the context of the larger
      stylesheet structure.</p>
    <p>You cat set a main XSLT stylesheet <ph>either using the <xref
          href="defining_master_files.dita#defining_master_files"><term>master files</term> support
          from the <uicontrol product="developer editor">Project</uicontrol><uicontrol
            product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">Navigator</uicontrol> view</xref>, or</ph>
      using a validation scenario.</p>
    <p>To set a <term>master file</term> using a validation scenario, add validation units that
      point to the main modules. <ph keyref="product"/> warns you if the current module is not part
      of the dependencies graph computed for the main stylesheet. In this case, it considers the
      current module as the main stylesheet.</p>
    <p>The advantages of editing in the context of <xref keyref="glossentry_master-file"
          ><term>master file</term></xref> include: <ul>
        <li>Correct validation of a module in the context of a larger stylesheet structure.</li>
        <li><xref keyref="glossentry_content-completion-assistant"><term>Content Completion
              Assistant</term></xref> displays all components valid in the current context.</li>
        <li>The <xref href="xslt-outline.dita#xslt-outline"><uicontrol>Outline</uicontrol>
            view</xref> displays the components collected from the entire stylesheet structure.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>For more information about editing XSLT stylesheets in the <term>master files</term> context,
      watch our video demonstration:</p>
    <p><object width="450" height="250" data="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UZwg385RKNw"
        outputclass="iframe">
        <param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"/>
      </object></p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related Information:</title>
      <link href="xslt-hierarchy-view.dita"/>
      <link href="xslt-component-dependencies.dita"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</topic>
