<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="xslt-quick-fix">
  <title>XSLT Quick Fix Support </title>
  <body>
    <p>The <ph keyref="product"/> Quick Fix support helps you resolve different errors that appear
      in a stylesheet by offering quick fixes to problems like a missing template, misspelled
      template name, missing function or references to an undeclared variable or parameter.</p>
    <fig id="fig_kx2_lnx_xn">
      <title>XSLT Functions Quick Fix</title>
      <p><image href="../img/quickFixes.png" id="image_zcj_tnx_xn"/></p>
    </fig>
    <p>To activate the feature, when <ph keyref="product"/> finds a validation error in an XSLT
      stylesheet, place the caret in the highlighted area of text. If <ph keyref="product"/> can
      provide a quick fix for that error, the <image href="../img/AutomaticErrorQF.gif"
        id="image_w2j_s2y_xn" product="developerEclipse editorEclipse"/><image
        href="../img/QuickFix16.png" id="image_zts_v2y_xn" product="developer editor"/> icon is
      displayed in the left side stripe. When you click this icon, the list of available fixes is
      displayed. Also, you can invoke the quick fix menu if you press <ph product="developer editor"
          ><b>Alt + 1</b> keys (<b>Meta + Alt + 1</b> on Mac OS X)</ph><b
        product="developerEclipse editorEclipse">Ctrl + 1</b> on your keyboard.</p>
    <note>The quick fixes are available only when validating an XSLT file with Saxon
      HE/PE/EE.</note>
    <fig id="fig_axz_34x_xn">
      <title>XSLT Variables and Parameters Quick Fix</title>
      <image href="../img/quickFixesVar.png" id="image_scv_j4x_xn"/>
    </fig>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> provides quick fixes for the following cases:<ul id="ul_ugd_p4x_xn">
        <li><b>Template does not exist</b>, when the template name referred in a
            <codeph>call-template</codeph> element does not exist. The following fixes are
            available:<ul id="ul_p1w_t4x_xn">
            <li><uicontrol>Create template "templateName"</uicontrol> - creates a template and
              generates its corresponding parameters. The template name and parameter names and
              types are collected from the <codeph>call-template</codeph> element.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change reference to "newTemplateName"</uicontrol> - changes the name of
              the missing template referred in the <codeph>call-template</codeph> element. The
              proposed new names are the existing templates with names similar with the missing
              one.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Variable/Parameter not declared</uicontrol>, when a parameter or variable
          reference cannot be found. The following fixes are available:<ul id="ul_rft_jsx_xn">
            <li><uicontrol>Create global variable "varName"</uicontrol>  - creates a global variable
              with the specified name in the current stylesheet. The new variable is added at the
              beginning of the stylesheet after the last global variable or parameter
              declaration.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Create global parameter "paramName"</uicontrol> - creates a global
              parameter with the specified name in the current stylesheet. The new parameter is
              added at the beginning of the stylesheet after the last global parameter or variable
              declaration.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Create local variable "varName"</uicontrol> - creates a local variable
              with the specified name before the current element.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Create template parameter "paramName"</uicontrol> - creates a new
              parameter with the specified name in the current template. This fix is available if
              the error is located inside a template.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Create function parameter "paramName"</uicontrol> - creates a new
              parameter with the specified name in the current function. This fix is available if
              the error is located inside a function.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change reference to "varName"</uicontrol> - changes the name of the
              referred variable/parameter to an existing local or global variable/parameter, that
              has a similar name with the current one.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Parameter from a called template is not declared</uicontrol>, when a
          parameter referred from a <codeph>call-template</codeph> element is not declared. The
          following fixes are available:<ul id="ul_obr_4yx_xn">
            <li><uicontrol>Create parameter "paramName" in the template "templateName"</uicontrol> -
              creates a new parameter with the specified name in the referred template.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change "paramName" parameter  reference to "newParamName"</uicontrol> -
              changes the parameter reference from the <codeph>call-template</codeph> element to a
              parameter that is declared in the called template.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Remove parameter "paramName" from call-template</uicontrol> - removes the
              parameter with the specified name from the <codeph>call-template</codeph>
              element.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Function "prefix:functionName()" has not been defined</uicontrol>, when a
          function declaration is not found. The following quick fixes are available:<ul
            id="ul_i4j_hzx_xn">
            <li><uicontrol>Create function "prefix:functionName(param1, param2)"</uicontrol> -
              creates a new function with the specified signature, after the current top level
              element from stylesheet.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change function to "newFunctionName(..)"</uicontrol> - changes the
              referred function name to an already defined function. The proposed names are
              collected from functions with similar names and the same number of parameters.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Attribute-set "attrSetName" does not exist</uicontrol>, when the referred
          attribute set does not exist. The following quick fixes are available:<ul
            id="ul_at4_v1y_xn">
            <li><uicontrol>Create attribute-set "attrSetName"</uicontrol> - creates a new attribute
              set with the specified name, after the current top level element from stylesheet.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change reference to "attrSetName"</uicontrol> - changes the referred
              attribute set to an already defined one.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Character-map "chacterMap" has not been defined</uicontrol>, when the
          referred character map declaration is not found. The following quick fixes are
            available:<ul id="ul_vwq_vby_xn">
            <li><uicontrol>Create character-map "characterMapName"</uicontrol> - creates a new
              character map with the specified name, after the current top level element from
              stylesheet.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Change reference to "characterMapName"</uicontrol> - changes the referred
              character map to an already defined one.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
