<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="doc-rules">
  <title>Documentation Rules</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Documentation rules </indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <p>The vast amount of rules that pertain to writing in the English language can be daunting,
        to say the least. There are also a lot of different opinions about which of those rules
        should be followed. There is a difference between the ability to speak in coherent and
        grammatically correct English and the ability to write effectively in English. Perhaps many
        of the common rules are not as important when it comes to verbal communication, but written
        documentation clearly needs to be consistent and follow a set of defined rules. It is also
        important to distinguish between concrete grammar rules that should always be followed and
        style rules that are simply guidelines or choices that will help make documentation to be
        more consistent and potent.</p>
      <p>As a general rule for writing technical documentation, it is important to keep it as simple
        as possible while using enough creativity and solid writing skills to keep the reader
        engaged long enough to absorb whatever information they need to satisfy the reason they
        found the particular documentation in the first place. All talented writers have developed
        their skill over the course of time by writing <i>A LOT</i>. However, following a set of
        rules and guidelines can help less experienced writers, as well as those without
        native-level language skills. Especially when documentation is written by multiple writers,
        it is important to have a common set of rules and guidelines to keep the documentation
        consistent, effective, and professional.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title><ph keyref="product"/> Documentation Rules</title>The rules, guidelines, and
      tips presented in this topic are meant to help maintain a high level of consistency,
      effectiveness, and accuracy within the documentation for <ph keyref="product"/>. This guide
      includes the following sections:<ul>
        <li><b><xref href="#doc-rules/grammar-rules-section" format="dita">Grammar Rules</xref></b> - This
          section contains grammar rules that should always be followed in any of the
          documentation.</li>
        <li><b><xref href="#doc-rules/ug-style-rules-section" format="dita">Style Rules for the User
              Guide</xref></b> - This section includes a variety of style rules that were chosen to
          serve as guidelines to maintain consistency and improve the overall usefulness of the User
          Guide.</li>
        <li><b><xref href="#doc-rules/website-style-rules-section" format="dita">Style Rules for the
              Website</xref></b> - This section includes some basic style rules for documenting the
          certain parts of the oXygen website.</li>
        <li><b><xref href="#doc-rules/writing-tips-section" format="dita">Writing Tips and
              Suggestions</xref></b> - This section includes numerous writing suggestions and tips
          (for both general and technical writing) that are meant to help content authors improve
          their writing skills.</li>
      </ul></section>
    <section id="grammar-rules-section"><title>Grammar Rules</title>This section includes some
      common concrete grammar rules that should always be followed when writing documentation.<p>
        <dl>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Common Grammar Errors</dt>
            <dd>The following grammar errors are some of the most common mistakes that are made
              while writing in general:<dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Incomplete Comparisons</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> When you are implying that something is being compared to
                    something else, you must always clarify what you are comparing it to. Otherwise,
                    it will be difficult for the reader to discern what the comparison actually
                    means.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of an error:</i></b>
                    <i>Our software is more powerful and efficient.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b>Problem:</b> The software is more powerful and efficient <b>than
                    what</b>?</dd>
                  <dd><b>Solution:</b> Simply finish the comparison. <i>For example: Our software is
                      more powerful and efficient than all other XML editors.</i></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Dangling Modifiers</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This happens when a descriptive phrase does not apply to
                    the noun that immediately follows it. In other words, a word or phrase that
                    modifies a word not clearly stated in the sentence.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of an error:</i></b>
                    <i>Before performing the merge, the target item needs to be ready for the
                      operation.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b>Problem:</b> It is unclear what is "performing the merge". Is this implying
                    that the user is performing the merge, or is the "target item", or maybe "the
                    operation"?</dd>
                  <dd><b>Solution:</b> To fix this problem, try rearranging the structure of the
                    sentence or be more specific. <i>For example: Before you perform the merge, make
                      sure the target item is ready for the operation.</i></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Vague Pronouns</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> A pronoun should refer clearly to the word or words it
                    replaces (called the <term>antecedent</term>) elsewhere in the sentence or in a
                    previous sentence. Pronouns are words that take the place of a noun (such as
                      <i>"you"</i>, <i>"it"</i>, <i>"who"</i>, <i>"they"</i>,
                    <i>"everyone"</i>).</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of an error:</i></b>
                    <i>Maximize the reuse possibilities for keys in topics by reflecting different
                      values depending on <b>their</b> defined scope.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b>Problem:</b> What is <i>"their"</i> referring to? It probably referring to
                    the defined scope of <i>"keys"</i>, but with the way this sentence is written,
                    it could also be referring to the scope of <i>"topics"</i>, <i>"values"</i>, or
                    possibly even <i>"reuse possibilities"</i>.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Solution:</b> If more than one word could be the antecedent (or if no
                    specific antecedent is present) you should edit the sentence to make the meaning
                    more clear. <i>For example: Maximize the reuse possibilities for keys in topics
                      by reflecting different values depending on the defined scope of the
                    keys.</i></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Sentence Fragments</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> Quite simply, a <term>sentence fragment</term> is a piece
                    of a sentence that is disconnected from the main clause and cannot stand by
                    itself as a complete sentence.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>Because the URL alone might point to a different item than the one you want
                      and a peg revision is needed.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b>Problem:</b> This fragment does not express a complete thought. The
                    subordinating conjunction <i>"because"</i> is dependent upon an independent
                    clause that is missing in this sentence fragment.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Solution:</b> Every sentence must have at least one main clause and express
                    a complete thought. It is important to proofread your work carefully to identify
                    possible sentence fragments.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Misusing Homonyms</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> It is impossible for spell checkers to detect misused
                    homonyms. A <term>homonym</term> is a word that is spelled the same way as
                    another word but has a different meaning.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Examples of homonyms:</i></b>
                    <i>"affect"/"effect"</i>, <i>"illicit"/"elicit"</i>,
                      <i>"complement"/"compliment"</i>, <i>"obtain"/"attain"</i>,
                      <i>"personal"/"personnel"</i>, <i>"suit"/"suite"</i>,
                      <i>"principal"/"principle"</i>, <i>"write"/"right"</i></dd>
                  <dd><b>Problem:</b> The obvious problem with misusing homonyms is that your
                    content will have unintended meaning.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Solution:</b> Since spell checkers will not detect misused homonyms, you
                    need to proofread your work carefully. Also, if you are not completely sure
                    about the difference between certain homonyms, avoid using those words
                    entirely.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Specific Grammar Rules in Regards to Adverbs</dt>
            <dd>There are a lot of rules that apply to adverbs in English writing. The following are
              some of the most important grammar rules in regards to adverbs:<dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Conjunctive Adverbs</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b>...often can move almost anywhere in a sentence and they
                    are often used as transitions between sentences, but they are not conjunctions
                    and cannot be used to join two sentences.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Examples of conjunctive adverbs:</i></b>...Accordingly, Also,
                    Consequently, For Example, For Instance, Furthermore, Hence, However, In Fact,
                    Instead, Likewise, Otherwise, Nevertheless, Therefore, Thus.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Position of Adverbs in a Sentence</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> There are so many complex rules for where to position
                    different types of adverbs within a sentence that it is not even worth
                    discussing most of them. Essentially, an <term>adverb</term> is a word that
                    modifies another word or phrase. In most cases, you should make sure the adverb
                    is placed as close to the word or phrase that it is modifying as possible and
                    you should always pay attention to how the placement of the adverb can change
                    the meaning of the sentence. For more specific rules in regards to the placement
                    of adverbs, the following website defines some very clear rules for various
                    situations: <xref
                      href="http://www.englishpractice.com/improve/position-adverbs-2/"
                      format="html" scope="external"/>.<dl>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><b><term>Focusing Adverbs</term> (<i>"also"</i>, <i>"only"</i>,
                              <i>"either"</i>, <i>"neither"</i>, <i>"just"</i>,
                            <i>"mostly"</i>):</b></dt>
                        <dd>For the purposes of our documentation, we should concentrate on making
                          sure certain <term>focusing adverbs</term> are placed in the proper
                          position because they represent the most common errors and improper
                          positioning of these adverbs can lead to sentences that are awkward or
                          where the meaning is unclear. Since focusing adverbs point to a particular
                          part of a sentence, the meaning conveyed often depends upon their
                          position. The adverbs <i>"also"</i> and <i>"only"</i> are the most common
                          examples that are used in our documentation.<p><b><i>"Only"</i></b> -
                            Consider how the placement of the word <i>"only"</i> changes the meaning
                            in the following examples:<ul>
                              <li><b><i>Example 1:</i></b>
                                <i><b>Only</b> John gave Paul one dollar.</i> [No one else besides
                                John game him a dollar].</li>
                              <li><b><i>Example 2:</i></b>
                                <i>John gave <b>only</b> Paul one dollar.</i> [John gave Paul a
                                dollar and no one else].</li>
                              <li><b><i>Example 3:</i></b>
                                <i>John gave Paul <b>only</b> one dollar.</i> [John gave Paul one
                                dollar and nothing more].</li>
                              <li><b><i>Example 4:</i></b>
                                <i>John <b>only</b> gave Paul one dollar.</i> [John did nothing else
                                besides giving Paul a dollar.]</li>
                            </ul></p><p><b><i>"Also</i></b> - Consider how the placement of the word
                              <i>"also"</i> changes the meaning in the following examples:<ul>
                              <li><b><i>Example 1:</i></b>
                                <i><b>Also</b>, John thinks that Paul should stop smoking.</i> [In
                                addition to other ideas, John thinks Paul should stop smoking.]</li>
                              <li><b><i>Example 2:</i></b>
                                <i>John thinks that Paul <b>also</b> should stop smoking.</i> [John
                                thinks Paul should stop smoking, along with other people.]</li>
                              <li><b><i>Example 3:</i></b>
                                <i>John thinks Paul should <b>also</b> stop smoking.</i> [John
                                thinks Paul should stop smoking, along with stopping other
                                things.]</li>
                              <li><b><i>Example 4:</i></b>
                                <i>John <b>also</b> thinks that Paul should stop smoking.</i>
                                [Someone else and John think that Paul should stop smoking.]</li>
                            </ul></p></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Most of the time it is best to place focusing
                          adverbs in front of and next to the word or words they are modifying.
                          However, be aware that doing so will not always eliminate ambiguity.
                          Therefore, you have to also rely on the context and consider the meaning
                          of the sentence based upon the placement of the adverb. If you find it
                          difficult to decide where to place them, try rephrasing the sentence
                          entirely.</dd>
                      </dlentry>
                    </dl></dd>
                  <dd>
                    <dl>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt><b><i>Using Adverbs with Modal Verbs</i> (<i>"can"</i>, <i>"could"</i>,
                              <i>"may"</i>, <i>"might"</i>, <i>"must"</i>, <i>"will"</i>,
                              <i>"would"</i>, <i>"shall"</i>, <i>"should"</i>):</b></dt>
                        <dd>A <term>modal verb</term> is a type of auxiliary verb that is used to
                          indicate the likelihood, possibility, necessity, or ability. Deciding how
                          to position adverbs in relation to model verbs can also become very
                          confusing, especially when the modal verb is used with another verb (such
                          a form of the <term>infinitive verb</term>
                          <i>"to be"</i>.</dd>
                        <dd>Consider the following examples:<ul>
                            <li><b><i>Example 1:</i></b>
                              <i>The sample file <b>also</b> can be found in the SDK
                                distribution.</i> [Awkward]</li>
                            <li><b><i>Example 2:</i></b>
                              <i>The sample file can <b>also</b> be found in the SDK
                                distribution.</i> [Better]</li>
                          </ul></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> While both of the previous examples are
                          grammatically correct and they both have the same meaning, the second one
                          sounds and reads better, and you never want to cause your reader to pause
                          to consider the awkwardness of the flow. There are a lot of exceptions to
                          this rule, but MOST of the time, you should use the following word order
                          when using this type of combination: <b><i>[Modal Verb] + [Adverb] +
                              [Verb]</i></b>. </dd>
                      </dlentry>
                    </dl>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Specific Grammar Rules in Regards to Specific Words or Phrases</dt>
            <dd>The following grammar rules are meant to distinguish when and how to use specific
              words or which form of a word to use in particular situations:<dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b><i>"a"</i></b> vs. <b><i>"an"</i></b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This is one of the most common errors made in English
                    writing. There is a common misperception that the rule is that you use
                      <i>"a"</i> before words that start with a consonant and <i>"an"</i> before
                    words that start with a vowel. However, that is only partially correct.
                    REMEMBER, it is how the subsequent word SOUNDS, not how it is written. The
                    letters 'H' and 'U' usually cause the most confusion because some words that
                    start with those letters have a consonant sound and some have a vowel
                    sound.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rule to follow:</b> The rule is that you use <i>"a"</i> before words that
                    start with a consonant SOUND and <i>"an"</i> before words that start with a
                    vowel SOUND.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Examples for "a":</i></b>
                    <i>"<u>Unique</u>" or "<u>URL</u>" - You would use "a'" before both words
                      because they both begin with a 'you' SOUND.</i>
                    <i>"<u>Historic</u>" or "<u>High</u>" - You would use "a'" before them because
                      they begin with a consonant 'h' SOUND.</i>
                  </dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Examples for "an":</i></b>
                    <i>"<u>Unusual</u>" or "<u>Uumbrella</u>" - You would use "an'" before both
                      words because they both begin with an 'uh' SOUND.</i>
                    <i>"<u>Hour</u>" or "<u>HTTP</u>" - You would use "an'" before them because they
                      begin with an 'a-wer' and 'aye' SOUND, respectively.</i>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b><i>"That"</i></b> vs. <b><i>"Which"</i></b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> There are some experts who believe this is more of a style
                    choice than a grammar rule, but those people are completely ignoring the fact
                    that when these two words are used interchangeably they are usually two
                    completely different types of grammatical words (<i>"that"</i> being an
                    adjective in these instances, and <i>"which"</i> being a pronoun/determiner).
                    Some people might also argue that the rules are more complex and flexible than
                    the rules we will use, but it is important to keep the rules simple and for the
                    purposes of our User Guide, we use these two words in ways that are only
                    grammatically correct and clear if we follow the rules listed below. Also, in
                    most cases, it looks and sounds much better to use this common grammar rule.
                    )</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> To make a complex topic as simple as possible, use
                      <i>"that"</i> before a <term>restrictive clause</term> and <i>"which"</i>
                    before <term>nonrestrictive clauses</term>. A <term>restrictive clause</term> is
                    part of a sentence that you can not get rid of because it specifically restricts
                    some other part of the sentence and without the clause the meaning of the
                    sentence would change (or the sentence would be incomplete). A
                      <term>nonrestrictive clause</term> is something that can be left off without
                    changing the meaning of the sentence (or making it incomplete) and it is simply
                    additional information.<note type="important">Nonrestrictive clauses are almost
                      always surrounded by, or preceded by, commas. Therefore, whenever you use
                        <i>"which"</i> before a nonrestrictive clause, it should be preceded with a
                      comma.</note></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of an improper use of "that":</i></b>
                    <i>This section lists and describes all the contextual menu actions <b>that</b>
                      are also available in various submenus.</i> [You should not use <i>"that"</i>
                    in this instance because the reader might understand that the section only lists
                    the actions that are in both locations instead of understanding that the section
                    includes ALL the contextual menu actions (and that they are ALSO available in
                    submenus). The clause that follows <i>"that"</i> in this case is a
                    nonrestrictive clause that simply provides additional information. Therefore,
                    you should use <i>", which"</i> in this type of instance. </dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of a proper use of "that":</i></b>
                    <i>This section explains the actions <b>that</b> are available for a Berkeley DB
                      XML connection.</i> [The clause that follows <i>"that"</i> cannot be omitted
                    without causing an incomplete sentence and it does not simply provide additional
                    information (it is essential to the meaning of the sentence). Therefore, it is a
                    restrictive clause and you must use <i>"that"</i> instead of
                    <i>"which"</i>].</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of  an improper use of "which":</i></b>
                    <i>The stylesheet contains templates <b>which</b> output the static header and
                      footers for various parts of the PDF.</i> [You cannot use <i>"which"</i> in
                    this case because the information that follows it is essential to the meaning of
                    the sentence and is not simply providing additional information. In this case,
                    you would need to use <i>"that"</i> instead.]</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of  a proper use of "which":</i></b>
                    <i>While you are working on your own branch, other team members can continue to
                      make important changes in the parent branch<b>, which</b> could be the trunk
                      itself or any other branch.</i> [The clause that follows <i>"which"</i> could
                    be omitted without changing the meaning of the sentence since it simply provides
                    additional information and could even be an independent idea of its own (for
                    example, by changing <i>"which"</i> to <i>"It"</i> and making it a new
                    sentence.]</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b><i>"That"</i></b> vs. <b><i>"Who"</i></b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This can be tricky and complicated, but to make it as
                    simple as possible, consider who or what is being described. Some experts say
                    that it is acceptable to use either word when describing a person, but it seems
                    to dehumanize the person when using <i>"that"</i> to describe a person.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rule to follow:</b> Use <i>"that"</i> when describing an object, or
                      <i>"who"</i> when describing a person.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "that"</i></b>: <i>Permanent reassignment of a Named User to
                      a position <b>that</b> does not involve the use of the Software.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "who"</i></b>: <i>Permanent reassignment of a Named User
                        <b>who</b> owns the rights to the software.</i></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>"To either"</b> vs. <b>"Either to"</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This is one of those rules that differ depending on
                    whether you are speaking or writing. Both phrases mean exactly the same thing
                    and when speaking, both phrases are acceptable. However, when writing, <i>"to
                      either"</i> is simply MORE grammatically correct.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> As a general rule, it is better to use <i>"to
                      either"</i> since the word "either" implies a choice of two options and by
                    placing the <i>"to"</i> in the front, you are removing it from the grammatical
                    construction <i>'either A or B'</i>. If you do use <i>"either to"</i>, you would
                    need to include a second <i>"to"</i> to make the construction grammatically
                    correct (<i>'either <u>to</u> A or <u>to</u> B'</i>).</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "either to":</i></b>
                    <i>You can use this API <b>either to</b> print the document or <b>to</b> show
                      the Print Preview dialog box.</i> [To make this sentence grammatically
                    correct, notice that you have to use a second <i>"to"</i> in front of the second
                    clause.]</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "to either":</i></b>
                    <i>You can use this API <b>to either</b> print the document or show the Print
                      Preview dialog box..</i> [Notice that by using <i>"to either"</i> you do not
                    need a second <i>"to"</i> before the second clause to make the sentence
                    grammatically correct.]</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>"Such as"</b> vs. <b>"Like"</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This is another one of the most common problems found in
                    English writing. Many grammarians consider both to be acceptable, especially
                    when speaking, but when using them in writing, you should not use them
                    interchangeably because they have different implications. <i>"Like"</i> suggests
                    comparison (something is similar to something else), while <i>"such as"</i>
                    implies inclusion (something is precisely included as an example of
                    something).</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> In most cases, avoid using <i>"like"</i> when you can
                    use <i>"such as"</i> instead and only use <i>"like"</i> when making some sort of
                    comparison to something similar.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "such as":</i></b>
                    <i>You can specify a set of transformation scenarios to convert XML documents to
                      various formats, <b>such as</b> HTML and PDF.</i><note>When <i>"such as"</i>
                      is part of a <term>nonrestrictive clause</term>, as it is in the above
                      example, it needs to be preceded with a comma (or the whole clause placed in
                      parentheses).</note></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "like":</i></b>
                    <i>A DITA book map is intended for creating output that is <b>like</b> a
                      book.</i></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>Affect</b> vs. <b>Effect</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> These two words are often confused when referring to
                    something changing another thing. The word <i>"effect"</i> is a noun, while
                      <i>"affect"</i> is a verb.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Basically, use <i>"Effect"</i> when referring to the
                    change itself (noun), and <i>"Affect"</i> when referring to the act of changing
                    (verb).</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "effect":</i></b>
                    <i>Documents that contain long lines can have a negative <b>effect</b> on
                      performance.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "affect":</i></b>
                    <i>Documents that contain long lines can <b>affect</b> performance.</i></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>Less</b> vs. <b>Fewer</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> Despite popular belief, there is a clear difference
                    between when these two words should be used.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Use <i>"less"</i> for things that are not
                    quantifiable, and <i>"fewer"</i> for things that you can clearly count.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "less":</i></b>
                    <i>It uses less memory.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "fewer":</i></b>
                    <i>It uses fewer than 300 MB.</i>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>Between</b> vs. <b>Among</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This rule can be confusing, but you simply need to think
                    about whether or not the referenced things are clearly separated.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Use <i>"between"</i> when referring to multiple things
                    that are clearly separated, and <i>"among"</i> for things that you can cannot
                    clearly separate because they are part of a group of objects.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "between":</i></b>
                    <i>The DITA Maps Manager organizes the relationships <b>between</b> maps and
                      topics.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "among":</i></b>
                    <i>DITA maps organize the relationships <b>among</b> various topics.</i>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>Different</b> vs. <b>Various</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> Misusing the word <i>"different"</i> is one of the most
                    common problems in formal and technical writing. When speaking, or perhaps in
                    colloquial writing, the two words are often used synonymously, but in formal or
                    technical writing it is important to differentiate between the two.
                      <i>"Different"</i> implies a comparison (<i>different</i> from what?), whereas
                      <i>"various"</i> implies multiplicity or diversity.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Do not use <i>"different"</i> when you mean
                      <i>"various"</i>. Only use <i>"different"</i> to refer to comparison or
                    distinction between things. Also, if you are to use the word <i>"different"</i>,
                    stop and ask yourself "it is different from what?" If you cannot answer that
                    question or it does not make sense, avoid using <i>"different"</i>.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "different":</i></b>
                    <i>You can create variables in your content by substituting another map with
                        <b>different</b> key values.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "various":</i></b>
                    <i>The Quick Fix support helps you resolve <b>various</b> errors that appear in
                      documents.</i>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>However</b> vs. <b>But</b> vs. <b>Although</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> These three words are often misunderstood in English
                    writing and many people incorrectly think they are completely synonymous. While
                    their meanings are very similar, <i>"however"</i> and <i>"but"</i> introduces a
                    contrast or contradiction to a previous statement, while <i>"although"</i> does
                    not necessarily imply contrast and can be used if both statements could be true.
                    Also, <i>"but"</i> and <i>"although"</i> and conjunctions, while
                      <i>"however"</i> is an adverb and needs to be used differently in the sentence
                    structure.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> To make it as simple as possible, follow these rules
                    for each word:<ul>
                      <li><b><i>"However"</i></b> - When using <i>"however"</i>, you should begin a
                        new sentence and it needs to be followed by a comma. Use it when you want to
                        stress contrast or contradiction AND you want to start a new sentence
                        (therefore contrasting the two sentences).</li>
                      <li><b><i>"But"</i></b> - When using <i>"but"</i>, do not start a new sentence
                        and it needs to be preceded by a comma. Use it when you want to stress
                        contrast or contradiction AND you do not want to start a new sentence
                        (therefore contrasting the two parts of the same sentence).</li>
                      <li><b><i>"Although"</i></b> - When using <i>"although"</i>, do not start a
                        new sentence and it needs to be preceded by a comma. Use it when you want to
                        stress that both parts of the statement may be true.</li>
                    </ul></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "however":</i></b>
                    <i>He knows a lot about general programming. <b>However,</b> he has some
                      confusion about Java programming.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "but":</i></b>
                    <i>She said the book is blue, <b>but</b> I think it is green.</i>
                  </dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "although":</i></b>
                    <i>We usually speak in Romanian, <b>although</b> sometimes we use English.</i>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><b>Whether</b> vs. <b>Whether or not</b></dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> There are so many conditions to this rule that it seems
                    that many modern writers have decided that it is too complicated and not worth
                    their time to consider so they simply ignore all of them and never include
                      <i>"or not"</i> even when doing so leads to ambiguity. They justify this by
                    suggesting that the <i>"or not"</i> is implied when appropriate and is therefore
                    optional. However, this is clearly not always the case. Your meaning can easily
                    become unclear or ideas might seem incomplete if you omit <i>"or not"</i> in
                    many cases. In the very least, it might irritate your reader if they have to
                    pause and re-read the sentence, and its surrounding sentences, to decipher the
                    intended meaning.<p>Consider the following example: <i>Oxygen prompts you to
                        choose <b>whether</b> you want to paste the content as XML.</i> The intended
                      meaning could have been any of the following:<ul>
                        <li>Oxygen prompts you to choose whether you want to paste the content as
                          XML or something else. [In this case, the sentence and idea is incomplete
                          and you need to specify what that 'something else' is.]</li>
                        <li>Oxygen prompts you to choose whether you want to paste the content as
                          XML, or not at all. [In this case, it is imperative to use <i>whether or
                            not</i> to avoid breaking the flow and possible ambiguity.]</li>
                        <li>Oxygen prompts you to choose something that was previously mentioned,
                          regardless of whether or not you want to paste the content. [In this case,
                          you would need a commas after choose and use <i>whether or not</i> or
                            <i>regardless of whether or not</i>.]</li>
                      </ul></p></dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Consider the following rules when using the word
                      <i>"whether"</i>:<ul>
                      <li>If you are differentiating between whether to do something, or to not do
                        something entirely, always use <i>"whether or not"</i>.</li>
                      <li>If you are differentiating between two different things, use
                          <i>"whether"</i> and specify both things.</li>
                      <li>In situations where <i>"or not"</i> might be considered optional, it is
                        far better to include it than to omit it. Remember to make sure the meaning
                        of the sentence is clear and that it will not require the reader to stop and
                        re-read it simply because you left out a few extra words that would make it
                        more clear.</li>
                      <li>In some cases, it might be better to simply use some sort of <i>"if"</i>
                        statement instead.</li>
                      <li>Whenever the use of the word <i>"whether"</i> is synonymous to
                          <i>regardless of whether or not</i>, you must use <i>"whether or not"</i>
                        or <i>"regardless of whether or not"</i>. </li>
                    </ul></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "whether":</i></b>
                    <i>Oxygen prompts you to choose <b>whether</b> you want to paste the content as
                      XML or plain text.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of "whether or not":</i></b>
                    <i>Oxygen prompts you to choose <b>whether or not</b> you want to paste the
                      content.</i></dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Tenses</dt>
            <dd>There are a lot of very complicated rules when it comes to using tenses in English
              writing. The proper use of tenses is important because improper use could lead to
              ambiguity and the intended meaning can be inadvertently changed if the wrong tense is
              used. Without making it more complicated than it needs to be, the following rules are
              simply guidelines for using tenses to help avoid glaring mistakes:<dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Consistency in Tenses</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> If you shift the tense of verbs from one tense to another
                    without a clear reason, it can confuse your readers. There are instances where
                    it is necessary to change tense, even within the same sentence, but it should
                    only be done when the reason is clear or to make things even more clear.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> In general, keep tenses consistent within sentences
                    and paragraphs, avoid changing tenses when there is no time change for an
                    action, and if you do need to change tenses, make sure that there is a clear
                    reason for it and as always, avoid ambiguity.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>Write the description of the problem that <b>was</b> encountered, <b>send</b>
                      it to our support team, and we <b>will reply</b> as soon as possible.</i>
                    Notice that past, present, and future tenses are used in the same sentence. The
                    reason for the switch to future tense (<i>"we will reply"</i>) is quite clear.
                    The part of the sentence that is in past tense (<i>"that was encountered"</i>)
                    could certainly be omitted without changing the meaning, but there is absolutely
                    nothing wrong with keeping it because it simply makes it even more clear.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Future Tense</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> In English grammar, future tense is not considered a true
                    tense because tenses express the time of a state or action and the future has
                    not yet happened. Obviously, you need to future tense when referring to
                    something that will clearly happen in the future, but in professional or
                    technical writing, using present tense (whenever possible) enhances your message
                    by making it more clear and precise.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rule to follow:</b> Avoid future tense unless you are referring to
                    something that will specifically happen in the future and you cannot use present
                    tense in the specific context.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of when NOT to use it:</i></b>
                    <i>Our sample documentation framework <b>will be</b> very simple.</i> This was
                    an actual example from our User Guide. Notice how ambiguous this sentence is. It
                    will be simple when? Why is it not simple now? Does the user need to do
                    something to make it simple? Clearly, this sentence should be <i>"Our sample
                      documentation framework <b>is</b> very simple."</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of when you should use it:</i></b>
                    <i>We <b>will reply</b> as soon as possible.</i> You have to use future tense in
                    this case because the action will very clearly happen in the future.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Progressive Tense</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> The <term>progressive tense</term> is formed with a form
                    of the helping <i>"to be"</i> verb, plus the present participle of a main verb
                    with an <i>"ing"</i> ending.  The use of progressive tenses is not grammatically
                    incorrect, but it requires the use of extra auxiliary verbs and makes your ideas
                    less precise, and possibly less clear. Particularly in technical writing, it
                    should only be used to refer to something that is very clearly an ongoing action
                    and present tense cannot be used in the precise context.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rule to follow:</b> Simply avoid progressive tense unless it is absolutely
                    necessary.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of when NOT to use it:</i></b>
                    <i>Oxygen <b>is changing</b> the way you edit documents.</i> This sentence
                    should be <i>"Oxygen <b>changes</b> the way you edit documents."</i> Notice that
                    the second version is more powerful and precise.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example of when you should use it:</i></b>
                    <i>Unfortunately, you cannot minimize the dialog box while the operation <b>is
                        processing</b>.</i> In this instance, it is actually better to use
                    progressive tense since it is referring to the time period during an ongoing
                    event. You could replace <i>"is processing"</i> with <i>"processes"</i>, but the
                    progressive form is actually more clear and precise in this case. </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Punctuation Rules</dt>
            <dd>Some punctuation rules are really just style choices (see the <xref
                href="#doc-rules/punctuation-style-rules-section" format="dita"><i>Punctuation Rules</i> in
                the <i>Style Rules</i> section</xref>), although there are some concrete grammar
              rules in regards to punctuation. This section includes some of those concrete rules:<dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Commas</dt>
                  <dd>There are entire courses that provide all sorts of information about the
                    proper usage of commas. For the purposes of our documentation, a few of the most
                    common rules are described in this section.<dl>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt>Comma to Separate Each Segment  in a Series</dt>
                        <dd><b>Description:</b></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rule:</b> When there are more than two segments in a series, each
                          segment should be separated by a comma. The comma before the last segment,
                          called a <term>Serial Comma</term>, is considered optional and therefore
                          becomes a style choice. For our purposes, the <xref
                            href="#doc-rules/serial-comma-dlentry" format="dita">style rule is that
                            we always include the <term>serial comma</term></xref> when there is
                          more than two segments, to avoid any possible ambiguity.</dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                          <i>It provides support to help you edit<b>,</b> transform<b>,</b> and
                            debug XML-based documents. </i><note>Do not separate TWO segments with a
                            comma unless they are <xref
                              href="#doc-rules/comma-independent-clause-dlentry" format="dita"
                                ><term>independent clauses</term></xref>. No comma is needed when a
                            conjunction joins two phrases that modify the same verb.</note></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry id="comma-independent-clause-dlentry">
                        <dt>Comma to Separate Independent Clauses</dt>
                        <dd><b>Description:</b></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rule:</b> You should use commas to separate <term>independent
                            clauses</term> that are joined by <xref
                            href="#doc-rules/coordinating-conjunctions-li" format="dita"
                            >coordinating conjunctions</xref>. An independent clause is a sentence
                          that can stand on its own. Here is how to test it: Would the second part
                          of the sentence (following the coordinating conjunction) make a full
                          sentence on its own? If so, add a comma. If not, leave it out.</dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                          <i>This tool is very powerful<b>,</b> and it includes a lot of
                            user-friendly features.</i></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt>Comma to Separate an Introductory Word or Phrase</dt>
                        <dd><b>Description:</b></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rule:</b> At the beginning of a sentence, introductory words or
                          phrases require a subsequent comma. These include <xref
                            href="#doc-rules/start-sentence-adverbs-dlentry" format="dita"
                            >conjunctive adverbs</xref> (such as <i>"however"</i>, <i>"also"</i>,
                            <i>"therefore"</i>, etc.)</dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                          <i>In the beginning<b>,</b> I had no idea how to use a comma.</i></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt>Commas (or Parentheses) Before and After Parenthetical Expressions</dt>
                        <dd><b>Description:</b></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rule:</b> Use commas or parentheses (brackets) to separate
                            <term>parenthetical expressions</term>. A parenthetical expression is a
                          phrase or clause that is inserted within another phrase or clause.</dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example with commas:</i></b>
                          <i>This is useful if, for instance, you want to upgrade your existing
                            license.</i></dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example with parentheses:</i></b>
                          <i>This is useful if (for instance) you want to upgrade your existing
                            license.</i></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt>Comma to Separate Nonrestrictive Clauses</dt>
                        <dd><b>Description:</b></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rule:</b> Use commas to separate <term>nonrestrictive clauses</term>.
                          Similar to parenthetical expressions, nonrestrictive clause adds extra
                          information that is not essential to the basic meaning of the sentence.
                          When a nonrestrictive clause appears in the middle of a sentence, place
                          commas before and after it. When a nonrestrictive clause appears at the
                          end of a sentence, place a comma before it.</dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                          <i>You can use the visual WebHelp Skin Builder tool<b>,</b> which does not
                            require knowledge of CSS language<b>,</b> to change the overall
                            appearance of the output.</i></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                      <dlentry>
                        <dt>Comma After an Introductory Infinitive Phrase</dt>
                        <dd><b>Description:</b></dd>
                        <dd><b>Rule:</b> Always use a comma after an introductory <term>infinitive
                            phrase</term>, unless the infinitive phrase is the subject of the
                          sentence. It would be extremely rare for an introductory infinitive phrase
                          to be the subject in our documentation, so you can ignore the second part
                          of the rule. Also, when an infinitive phrase concludes a clause (rather
                          than introducing it), no punctuation is necessary.</dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example of an introductory infinitive phrase:</i></b>
                          <i>To add index terms to a map<b>,</b> open the map in the editor and add
                            the elements.</i></dd>
                        <dd><b><i>Example of an infinitive phrase that concludes a clause:</i></b>
                          <i>This section explains how to create and work with projects.</i></dd>
                      </dlentry>
                    </dl>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl></dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt>Common Grammar Rule Myths or Misperceptions</dt>
            <dd>Some English grammar rules are ambiguous and debatable. Various grammar guides and
              experts sometimes differ when it comes to certain rules. Most experts come to a common
              consensus in regards to many of these ambiguous rules, while others simply become
              style choices when there does not seem to be a common opinion. Some of these
              complicated rules have also evolved or changed over time and can therefore become
                misperceptions.<p>This section includes some of the most common misperceptions in
                regards to grammar rules:</p><dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Misperception: Do not start a sentence with conjunctions!</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This is one of those rules in English grammar where most
                    people are taught that it is wrong, but most experts agree that it is acceptable
                    to do so. However, even though it is technically acceptable, it does not mean
                    that it should be done because it could lead to incomplete sentences, it can
                    sound quite monotonous, and it is often perceived as being unprofessional and
                    irritating to the reader. Ultimately, it really depends on the type of writing
                    and it becomes a style choice. For example, it is far more acceptable and common
                    in general writing than in technical writing.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> In technical writing, it is only appropriate to begin
                    sentence with certain <xref href="#doc-rules/subordinating-conjunctions-li"
                      format="dita"><term>subordinating conjunctions</term></xref>, but never with
                      <xref href="#doc-rules/coordinating-conjunctions-li" format="dita"
                        ><term>coordinating conjunctions</term></xref>. In most cases, you do not
                    use a comma after a subordinating conjunction that begins a sentence and the
                    most important thing to remember is that you need to avoid sentence
                    fragments.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Examples of conjunctions that are acceptable to begin a sentence with
                        (as long as it does not lead to a sentence fragment):</i></b> Certain
                    subordinating conjunctions (<i>"after"</i>, <i>"although"</i>, <i>"as soon
                      as"</i>, <i>"before"</i>, <i>"even though"</i>, <i>"if"</i>, <i>"in case"</i>,
                      <i>"now that"</i>, <i>"once"</i>, <i>"since"</i>, <i>"though"</i>,
                      <i>"unless"</i>, <i>"until"</i>, <i>"when"</i>
                    <i>"whenever"</i>, <i>"while"</i>)</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Examples of conjunctions that you should NOT begin a sentence
                      with:</i></b> All coordinating conjunctions (<i>"and"</i>, <i>"or"</i>,
                      <i>"but"</i>, <i>"nor"</i>, <i>"so"</i>, <i>"for"</i>, <i>"yet"</i>), along
                    with some subordinating conjunctions (<i>"because"</i>, <i>"so that"</i>,
                      <i>"than"</i>, <i>"why"</i>). Again, the most important thing is to avoid
                    sentence fragments.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="start-sentence-adverbs-dlentry">
                  <dt>Misperception: Do not start a sentence with adverbs! (such as 'Also' or
                    'However')</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> This rule is highly debated and often becomes a matter of
                    style choice, but it also depends on the type of adverb and proper punctuation
                    is important. An adverb describes, modifies, or provides more information about
                    a verb, and they usually end in <i>"ly"</i>. In general, you should not begin
                    sentences with common adverbs. However, this is not the case with conjunctive
                    adverbs. These adverbs are used as transitions between sentences, they often can
                    move almost anywhere in a sentence, and it is absolutely acceptable to begin a
                    sentence with most conjunctive adverbs as long as you use proper punctuation
                    (they should be followed by a comma).</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> It is fine to begin a sentence with most conjunctive
                    adverbs as long as they are followed by a comma. As a general rule, you should
                    not begin a sentence with any other type of adverb.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Examples of conjunctive adverbs that are acceptable to begin a sentence
                        with:</i></b>
                    <i>Accordingly</i>, <i>Also</i>, <i>Consequently</i>, <i>Finally</i>, <i>For
                      example</i>, <i>For instance</i>, <i>Furthermore</i>, <i>Hence</i>,
                      <i>However</i>, <i>Incidentally</i>, <i>In fact</i>, <i>In other words</i>,
                      <i>Instead</i>, <i>Likewise</i>, <i>Meanwhile</i>, <i>On the contrary</i>,
                      <i>On the other hand</i>, <i>Otherwise</i>, <i>Nevertheless</i>, <i>Next</i>,
                      <i>Nonetheless</i>, <i>Similarly</i>, <i>Therefore</i>, <i>Thus</i>.
                      <b>Remember that if you begin a sentence with any of these, they need to be
                      followed by a comma.</b></dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Misperception: Do not end a sentence with a preposition!</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> There is simply more to it than that. The rule is really
                    that you should not end a sentence with a preposition when the sentence would
                    mean the same thing if you left off the preposition. However, there are
                    instances where it is better to end a sentence with a preposition. Examples of
                    prepositions include: <i>about</i>, <i>above</i>, <i>after</i>, <i>below</i>,
                      <i>before</i>, <i>between</i>, <i>except</i>, <i>for</i>, <i>from</i>,
                      <i>in</i>, <i>off</i>, <i>on</i>, <i>onto</i>, <i>out</i>, <i>to</i>,
                      <i>until</i>, <i>with</i>, <i>without</i>.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Do not end a sentence with a preposition if removing
                    it would not change the meaning. Also, it is better to end a sentence with a
                    preposition that cannot be removed than to make the sentence sound awkward
                    trying to avoid it.</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>The new location in the same repository you are switching <b>to</b>.</i>
                    [OK]</dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>The new location in the same repository <b>to which</b> you are
                      switching.</i> [AWKWARD]</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Misperception: Do not split infinitives!</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> There is actually nothing wrong with splitting
                    infinitives, although in technical writing it often means that you are adding an
                    unnecessary word. However, there are quite a few instances where using split
                    infinitives add meaning to a sentence. For example, "to better understand".</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b>
                  </dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>.</i>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt>Misperception: Paragraphs must include more than one sentence!</dt>
                  <dd><b>Description:</b> A paragraph can be a single sentence. There is no rule
                    against it and if you can say what you need to say in a single sentence that
                    lacks a direct connection with other sentences, it is better to stop there and
                    go to a new paragraph.</dd>
                  <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b>
                  </dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>.</i></dd>
                  <dd><b><i>Example:</i></b>
                    <i>.</i>
                  </dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl></dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p></section>
    <section id="ug-style-rules-section"><title>Style Rules for the User Guide</title>Style rules
      are not concrete writing rules. Instead, they are style choices. There are no concrete right
      or wrong ways to choose style rules. However, it is important to be consistent with style
      choices to make documentation readable and appealing. You certainly do not want to irritate
      your audience by using multiple, inconsistent, and incompatible styles.<p>To maintain
        consistency and visually appealing documentation, we will use the following <i>Style
          Rules</i> for the oXygen User Guide:</p><dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>General Style Rules</dt>
          <dd>The following <i>Style Rules</i> provide guidelines for general documentation style choices:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>American vs. British English</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>There are some words that are spelled differently in these two forms of English.
                  It is certainly acceptable to use either convention as long as you are consistent.
                  Since we have more customers in North America than in the Great Britain, we will
                  always use American English for our documentation.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Titles/Headings</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Capitalize all nouns, verbs, and any other words that are more than 3 letters
                  (Exception: do not capitalize prepositions "from", "with", "like", "over", "into"
                  or the conjunction "that"). Do not capitalize other words that are 3 letters or
                  less unless it is at the beginning of the title/heading, or if it is an acronym.
                  Do not capitalize: a, an, and, as, at, but, by, for, in, it, of, nor, on, or, the,
                  to, up (Exceptions: do not capitalize specific names of elements, attributes, etc.
                  [use italics even in titles]; when listing company names or products in titles use
                  the same capitalization format that they use)</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Titles with hyphens</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Always capitalize the word before the hyphen, and also the words after the
                  hyphen, except for articles (a, an, the), short prepositions (at, by, from, into,
                  like, on, to, via, etc.) and short conjunctions (and, but, for, nor, or, that,
                  etc.) (Exceptions: same as above)</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>List Items (Bullet points)</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>In general, do not use punctuation at the end of a bullet point (Use numbered
                  lists if punctuation at the end is desired). The specific rule is that you should
                  not include punctuation at the end of a bullet point unless it is a complete
                  sentence (but even then it is not necessary). If multiple sentences are necessary
                  within a single bullet, then you SHOULD use punctuation, but perhaps you can use a
                  number list instead.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Plural Acronyms</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>You do not need an 's' at the end for plural acronyms (i.e. 'CMS' rather than
                  'CMSs')</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Terms</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use term for names of ...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Company or Product Names</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>When listing company names or products use the same capitalization format that
                  they use</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Parentheses</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Typically, you should not place text surrounded by brackets outside
                  sentences</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Parentheses vs. Hyphens</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use brackets instead of hyphens to offer examples of something, descriptions of
                  acronyms, etc. Example: Use "XSL FO (Formatting Objects) Editor" instead of "XSL
                  FO - Formatting Objects - Editor"</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Time Zones</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>When referring to time zones in North America use the 2 letter abbreviation (ET
                  for Eastern Time). Do NOT use the 3 letter abbreviation (for example, EDT or EST)
                  to avoid causing confusion or listing an inaccurate time.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Icons</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>When using icons before the name of actions do not add a space between the icon
                  and the action name</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Images</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>when?</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Numbers</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Acceptable Conjunctions for Starting a Sentence</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>and/but - no So/if- ok</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Links</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b> It is better to include more links than what is necessary,
                  than not enough.</dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Provide links whenever more clarification could be helpful. The
                  types of things that should be linked include:<ul>
                    <li>Pronouns and other specific terms that may not be common knowledge. Glossary
                      terms should be used in many of these cases.</li>
                    <li>When listing a specific option (such as options in a Preference page,
                      specific dialog box, menu, etc.) a link should be included to reference the
                      specific topic that describes the option.</li>
                    <li>Whenever referring to certain specifications or other external resources,
                      provide links to those specific resources.</li>
                    <li>Use cross references to other topics that have more information about
                      specific ideas.</li>
                    <li>Use related links to other topics that include similar information about the
                      current topic.</li>
                  </ul>
                </dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Use of Specific Words (Style Rules)</dt>
          <dd>The following <i>Style Rules</i> provide guidelines for the use of particular words:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Schema</b> (plural)</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'Schemas' instead of 'Schemata' for plural</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Combo Box</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'combo box' rather than 'combobox'</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Includes</b> vs. <b>Comes with</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'includes' instead of 'comes with' (for example, "oXygen includes a
                  user-friendly interface...")</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Cursor</b> vs. <b>Caret</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'cursor' when referring to the HOVERING cursor and 'caret' when referring to
                  the actual placement of the caret</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Multiple</b> vs. <b>More than one</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'multiple' instead of 'more than one'</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>You</b> vs. <b>One</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'you' rather than an impersonal 'one'</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>They</b> vs. <b>He/She</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'they' rather than 'he/she'</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Authors</b> vs. <b>Writers</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'authors' instead of 'writers', or 'content authors' instead of 'technical
                  writers' for our documentation.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Following</b> vs. <b>Next</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'following' or 'subsequent' instead of 'next' (for example, "In the
                  following image..." rather than "In the next image...")</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Dialog Box</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'dialog box' instead of just 'dialog'</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>Drop-down list</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use 'drop-down list' or 'drop-down menu' for composite buttons</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b>"etc."</b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Typically, only use 'etc.' inside brackets. Example: "(XML parser, XSLT
                  transformer, XQuery engine, etc.)"</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><b><i>"i.e."</i></b> vs. <b><i>"e.g."</i></b></dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b> Many people incorrectly use these interchangeably, but they
                  do not mean the same thing. Basically, <i>"i.e."</i> means "that is" or "in other
                  words", while <i>"e.g."</i> means "for example".</dd>
                <dd><b>Rule:</b> Since there is a lot of ambiguity in regards to when and how to use
                  these abbreviations, it is safer to NEVER use either of them. Instead, be specific
                  and use the full versions ("In other words" or "For example").</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl><dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>oXygen Related Naming Convention Rules</dt>
          <dd>The following <i>Style Rules</i> provide guidelines for using oXygen-related names and components:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>oXygen</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Product:</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Use the product element instead of various forms of Oxygen unless
                  it is a link, legal reference, or a tag that does not allow the insertion of a
                  product element.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>UI Names</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Use uicontrol for specific names of UI or XML related names (i.e.
                  actions, preference options, attributes, elements, tags, etc.)</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Ellipses in UI Names</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Do not use elipses when naming a specific ui control action if it
                  has elipses in its name</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Syncro</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Syncro Soft: Use 'Syncro Soft' unless Syncro is defined as 'Syncro
                  Soft' in the document.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Content Completion</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Use 'Content Completion Assistant' for specific references to this
                  tool, or 'content completion assistance' for a general reference to the
                  subject.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Editing Modes</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> When referring to the editing modes use 'Grid editor mode', 'Text
                  editor mode', 'Author mode', 'Design mode' (or Grid editing mode, etc.) and bold
                  the words 'Grid', 'Text', 'Author', 'Design' </dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="punctuation-style-rules-section">
          <dt>Punctuation Style Rules</dt>
          <dd>The following <i>Style Rules</i> pertain to punctuation:<dl>
              <dlentry id="serial-comma-dlentry">
                <dt>Serial Commas</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Use a serial comma for 3 or more sentence elements. Do not use a serial comma
                  for 2 elements. In many cases, omitting the serial comma is ambiguous. Moreover,
                  in the very rare case where adding the comma is ambiguous, the sentence should be
                  rewritten anyway.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Inside Parenthesis (Brackets)</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Only place a full stop or comma inside the end bracket if whatever is inside the
                  bracket would require it even if it was not inside brackets. Here is an example
                  from the website where the first set of brackets correctly has the full stop
                  inside and the second set correctly has the full stop outside the brackets. ...and
                  special debugging views (Context, Call Stack, Trace History, XPath Watch,
                  Variables, etc.) All debugger capabilities are provided (step into, step over,
                  step out, run, run to cursor, run to end, pause, stop).</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Inside Quotations</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b> There are two conflicting style rules in regards to whether
                  punctuation goes inside or outside quotations, depending on whether you use
                  American or British English rules. Since we use very few quotation marks in our
                  documentation, it is unnecessary to go into extensive details about these rules.
                  Instead, in those rare instances where quotations are used, we will use a
                  simplified version of the American rules.</dd>
                <dd><b>Rules to follow:</b> Always place commas and periods inside the closing
                  quotations mark, while semicolons, colons, and dashes always go outside the
                  closing quotation mark. Avoid using other punctuation with quotations, or avoid
                  using quotations.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Hyphenate</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>pop-up, drop-down, as-you-type, ready-to-use (when used as an adjective or noun
                  ... however, do not hyphenate when used like this 'the product comes ready to
                  use...'), user-friendly, built-in, pretty-print, read-only, open-source, co-exist,
                  built-in, right-click, left-click, double-click</dd>
                <dd>Do not hyphenate: plugin, screenshot, checkbox</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Semi-Colons</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Avoid...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Exclamation Marks</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b></dd>
                <dd>Not necessary in UG</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
    <section id="website-style-rules-section"><title>Style Rules for the Website</title>This section
      includes some basic style rules specifically for documenting certain parts of the website.<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>What's New Section</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>The following <i>Style Rules</i> pertain to adding features in the What's New section
            of the website.<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Content of Features</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Whenever possible, the content of each feature should focus on its
                  actual benefit to the end user.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Links to the User Guide</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b> Add links to the User Guide for features in which users might want
                  more information.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Structured Markup</dt>
                <dd><b>Description:</b>
                </dd>
                <dd><b>Rules:</b><ul>
                    <li><b><codeph>emf</codeph></b> - Use <codeph>emf</codeph> elements for names of
                      UI controls.</li>
                    <li><b><codeph>strong</codeph></b> - Use <codeph>strong</codeph> elements when
                      referring to <uicontrol>Text</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>,
                        <uicontrol>Grid</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Design</uicontrol> modes.</li>
                    <li><b><codeph>italic</codeph></b> - Use <codeph>italic</codeph> elements for
                      content that would normally be wrapped in various code-related DITA elements
                      (such as <codeph>codeph</codeph>, <codeph>apiname</codeph>,
                        <codeph>filepath</codeph>, etc.)</li>
                    <li><b><codeph>product</codeph></b> - Use the <codeph>product</codeph> element
                      whenever referring to oXygen.</li>
                  </ul></dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
    <section id="writing-tips-section"><title>Writing Tips and Suggestions</title>The writing rules
      and tips listed in this section are more suggestions than concrete rules, but they are
      important to make documentation clear, concise, effective, absorbing, and comprehensible.
      These suggestions and guidelines are meant to help anyone improve their writing skills.  <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Good Documentation Requires Editing</dt>
          <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> If you <i>really</i> want to produce great documentation,
            it needs to be edited. No matter how talented a writer happens to be, it is nearly
            impossible to avoid mistakes on the first attempt. It is also a good idea to have
            someone else review your documentation because when you read something you wrote
            yourself, you know what you <i>meant</i> to write, so it is really easy to just skip
            over typos or missing words. If you are editing your own work, changing the indent
            structure or font size can help you recognize mistakes that were previously
            unnoticed.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Basic Writing Rules</dt>
          <dd>The following rules are suggestions in regards to general writing standards: <dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Redundancy</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Avoid ...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Topic Structure</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b>  flow  intro  specific content  conclusion (if
                  appropriate)</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Paragraph Structure</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Opening intro sentence  keep short as possible
                  without...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Transitions</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> ...each paragraph should transition smoothly from
                  the preceding paragraph. Without good transitions, the reader will end up
                  backtracking repeatedly</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Sentence Structure</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Try to avoid starting a sentence with one kind of
                  structure and then changing to another later in the sentence. Doing so can confuse
                  your readers.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Complete Sentences</dt>
                <dd>
                  <p><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Except in extraordinary circumstances, sentences
                    should always be complete. Proofread your work carefully to spot sentence
                    fragments that are written as if they are complete sentences.</p>
                </dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Run-on Sentences</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> A <term>run-on</term> sentence is one that joins
                  clauses that could each stand on its own as a sentence without any punctuation or
                  words to link them. Fused sentences must be either divided into separate sentences
                  or joined by adding conjunctive words or punctuation. Always consider the general
                  flow and the length of the sentences to decide whether to separate them or add
                  conjunctions.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Possession</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Avoid if possible...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry id="conjunctions-dlentry">
                <dt>Coordinating Conjunctions vs. Subordinating Conjunctions</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> There are two types of conjunctions (coordinating
                  and subordinating) and they both can be used to join clauses. Various rules for
                  conjunctions can become very complicated. <b>The most important things to remember
                    is how to punctuate both types and that subordinating conjunctions require more
                    than one clause to avoid a sentence fragment.</b>
                </dd>
                <dd>
                  <ul>
                    <li id="coordinating-conjunctions-li"><b>Coordinating Conjunctions</b> - A
                      coordinating conjunction joins two main clauses with equal emphasis, or
                      connects any other grammatical unit.<ul>
                        <li>The seven coordinating conjunctions: <i>"and"</i>, <i>"or"</i>,
                            <i>"but"</i>, <i>"nor"</i>, <i>"so"</i>, <i>"for"</i>, <i>"yet"</i></li>
                        <li>Punctuating coordinating conjunctions: There are three patterns:<ol>
                            <li>Connecting two main clauses - When you connect two main clauses with
                              a coordinating conjunction, use a comma before the conjunction. {[Main
                              Clause 1], [Coordinating Conjunction] [Main Clause
                                    2]}<p><b><i>Example:</i></b></p></li>
                            <li>Connecting two items (other than two main clauses) - Do not use a
                              comma. {[Item 1] [Coordinating Conjunction] [Item
                                    2]}<p><b><i>Example:</i></b></p></li>
                            <li>Connecting three or more items in a series - Use a comma after each
                              item (except for the last) and before the conjunction. {[Item 1],
                              [Item 2], [Coordinating Conjunction] [Item
                                  3]}<p><b><i>Example:</i></b></p></li>
                          </ol></li>
                      </ul></li>
                    <li id="subordinating-conjunctions-li"><b>Subordinating Conjunctions</b> - A
                      subordinating conjunction causes the clause that it appears in to become
                      dependent. Therefore, it will be a sentence fragment unless it is joined to an
                      independent clause.<p><i><b>Example of a fragment:</b> With this option in
                          effect, the referenced schema document is loaded. <u>Unless</u> the
                          absolute URI is the same as a schema document already loaded.</i>
                        <b>(The second sentence is a fragment)</b></p><p><i><b>Example of a complete
                            sentence:</b> With this option in effect, the referenced schema document
                          is loaded <u>unless</u> the absolute URI is the same as a schema document
                          already loaded.</i>
                        <b>(One complete sentence)</b></p><ul>
                        <li>Some examples of subordinating conjunctions: <i>"after"</i>,
                            <i>"although"</i>, <i>"as"</i>, <i>"because"</i>, <i>"if"</i>,
                            <i>"since"</i>, <i>"though"</i>, <i>"unless"</i>, <i>"whenever"</i>,
                            <i>"while"</i>.</li>
                        <li>Punctuating coordinating conjunctions: Generally, there are two patterns:<ol>
                            <li>The main clause followed by a subordinate clause. Typically, a comma
                              is not necessary. {[Main Clause] [Subordinate
                                    Clause]}<p><b><i>Example:</i></b></p></li>
                            <li>A subordinate clause followed by the main clause. Typically, use a
                              comma after the subordinate clause. {[Subordinate Clause], [Main
                                    Clause]}<p><b><i>Example:</i></b></p></li>
                          </ol></li>
                      </ul></li>
                  </ul>
                </dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>Basic Technical Writing Rules</dt>
          <dd>The following rules are suggestions in regards to technical writing standards:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Include Links to Other Documentation</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Include links to other pertinent sections of the
                  documentation (or other resources) whenever possible. You want to make it as
                  convenient as possible for the users to navigate to other sections, topics, or
                  resources that might help them to find the information they need.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Consistency</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> ...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Ambiguity</dt>
                <dd>
                  <p>
                    <b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> "this", "these", "it" Even if the item to which you
                    refer is explicitly mentioned in your paper, ask yourself whether there is any
                    chance that the reader might not know to which of several items you might be
                    referring.</p>
                </dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Teach</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Teach or guide ...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Audience</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> we to include... know your audience... identify who
                  its for and what they need to know</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Make Important Content Noticeable</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Use various structural elements to make the topics
                  more visually appealing and readable  contrast...labels...use concrete
                  language</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Sections</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> ...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Use Structure for Procedural or Task-Related Information</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Do not bury task-related information within dense
                  paragraphs. This will make your readers very frustrated when they are trying to
                  learn how to do a specific task. Use structured components to make your
                  instructions more visible and appealing. Follow the subsequent guidelines whenever
                  documenting procedures.</dd>
                <dd>
                  <p><b><u>Guidelines for documenting procedures:</u></b><ul>
                      <li>It is helpful to use titles for procedures, especially when the procedure
                        is surrounded by a large amount of content. This helps the reader to quickly
                        find the procedure that they are looking for amongst blocks of other
                        content.</li>
                      <li>Only use <term>unordered lists</term> (<codeph>ul</codeph>) when steps do
                        not need to occur in sequence.</li>
                      <li>Always use <term>ordered lists</term> (<codeph>ol</codeph>) when the steps
                        must occur in a sequence and make sure the items are in proper order.</li>
                      <li>Each step in a procedure should be an action in the sequence.</li>
                      <li>If possible, eliminate steps that lack action. Instead, put informational
                        content after the action within a step, or put it outside the step (for
                        example, in a <codeph>paragraph</codeph> or <codeph>step
                        result</codeph>).</li>
                      <li>Use sub-steps rather than putting too many tasks within one step.</li>
                      <li>Clearly identify optional steps. For example, put the word
                          <i>"optional"</i> in parentheses at the beginning of the step.</li>
                      <li>Identify conditional steps with words such as <i>"if"</i> and
                          <i>"then"</i>.</li>
                      <li>Use an additional list within a list for branching steps, such as
                        alternative methods.</li>
                      <li>Edit and rewrite ambiguous steps. Proofread the entire procedure, or
                        better yet, have someone else read the procedure, and if there is any
                        ambiguity in any of the steps, the procedure needs to be revised. </li>
                    </ul></p>
                </dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Contractions</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Avoid  Contractions are appropriate only for
                  conversational use and for informal writing, but never for technical writing.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Avoid Passive Voice</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> Particularly in technical writing, you should avoid
                  using a <term>passive voice</term> whenever possible. <term>Passive</term> writing
                  comes across as sounding weak and ambiguous, while using in an active voice makes
                  your writing seem more alive and clear. Basically, passive voice happens when the
                  object of a sentence is placed in the beginning of a sentence instead of the end.
                  In other words, the object becomes the subject. For example, <i>"I mailed the
                    letter"</i> becomes passive if it is changed to <i>"The letter was mailed by
                    me"</i>.<dl>
                    <dlentry>
                      <dt>How to recognize a <i>Passive Voice</i> sentence</dt>
                      <dd>The two most basic things to ask yourself are:<ul>
                          <li>Is the object in the subject position?</li>
                          <li>Can I add <i>"by [so-and-so]"</i> to the end?</li>
                        </ul></dd>
                      <dd>Also, keep this in mind: All passive sentences include a form of the verb
                          <i>"to be"</i> (such as <i>"was"</i>, <i>"were"</i> or <i>"is"</i>), BUT
                        not all sentences that have those verbs are passive. It is easy to recognize
                        sentences that include a form of <i>"to be"</i> but you need to ask yourself
                        the two questions above to determine if it is in the passive voice.</dd>
                    </dlentry>
                  </dl><dl>
                    <dlentry>
                      <dt><b><i>Examples from the UG:</i></b></dt>
                      <dd><i>Passive voice:</i> The New Document wizard allows you to select custom
                        templates that <b>were created in previous sessions by you or other
                          users</b>. [INCORRECT]</dd>
                      <dd><i>Active voice:</i> The New Document wizard allows you to select custom
                        templates that <b>you or other users created in previous sessions</b>.
                        [CORRECT]</dd>
                    </dlentry>
                  </dl></dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Avoid Unnecessary Words</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b>  "in order to"</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Avoid Qualifiers</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b>  Rather, very, little, pretty</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Avoid <i>Fancy</i> Words</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> ...</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt>Avoid Using Figures of Speech</dt>
                <dd><b>Rules or Suggestions:</b> ...</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></section>
  </body>
</topic>
