<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="reusables-tools">
  <title>Reusable Components in Tools</title>
  <body>
    <p>
      <!--Reusable components for the Compare Files tool-->
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="three-way-comparison-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/ThreeWayComparison24.png"/>Three-Way
              Comparison</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="three-way-comparison-ph">Toggle action that allows you to perform a three-way
              comparison between the two files displayed in the two editing panes and a base
              (ancestor) file.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-perform-files-diff">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffPerform20.png"/>Perform Files
              Differencing</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="files-perform-files-diff-ph">Looks for differences between the two files
              displayed in the left and right side panels.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-format-indent">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffPrettyPrint20.png"/>Format and Indent Both
              Files</uicontrol> (<uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_p"
            />)</dt>
          <dd><ph id="files-format-indent-ph">Formats and indents both files before comparing them.
              Use this option for comparisons that contain long lines that make it difficult to spot
              differences.</ph><note id="format-indent-note">When comparing two JSON files, the
                <uicontrol>Format and Indent Both Files</uicontrol> action will automatically sort
              the keys in both files the same to make it easier to compare. </note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-copy-right-left-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCopyRightToLeft20.png"/>Copy Change from Right
              to Left</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="files-copy-right-left">Copies the selected difference from the file in the
              right panel to the file in the left panel.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-copy-all-right-left-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCopyAllRightToLeft20.png"/>Copy All Changes from
              Right to Left</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="files-copy-all-right-left-ph">Copies all changes from the file in the right
              panel to the file in the left panel.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-next-block-changes">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffNextBlock16.png" id="image_vrq_3k3_tc"/>Next
              Block of Changes</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_period"/>)</dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the next block of changes. This action is not available when the cursor is
            positioned on the last change block or when there are no changes.<note>A change block
              groups one or more consecutive lines that contain at least one change.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-previous-block-changes">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffPreviousBlock16.png" id="image_lbz_hk3_tc"
              />Previous Block of Changes</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_comma"/>)</dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the previous block of changes. This action is not available when the cursor
            is positioned on the first change block or when there are no changes.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-next-change">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffNext16.png" id="image_lbp_jk3_tc"/>Next
              Change</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_period"/>)</dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the next change from the current block of changes. When the last change from
            the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the next block of changes. This
            action is not available when the cursor is positioned on the last change or when there
            are no changes.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-previous-change">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffPrevious16.png" id="image_vc1_hk3_tc"/>Previous
              Change</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_shift_comma"/>)</dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the previous change from the current block of changes. When the first change
            from the current block of changes is reached, it highlights the previous block of
            changes. This action is not available when the cursor is positioned on the first change
            or when there are no changes.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-copy-all-left-right-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCopyAllLeftToRight20.png"/>Copy All Changes from
              Left to Right</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="files-copy-all-left-right-ph">Copies all changes from the file in the left
              panel to the file in the right panel.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-copyl-left-right-dlentry">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCopyLeftToRight20.png"/>Copy Change from Left to
              Right</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="files-copy-left-right-ph">Copies the selected difference from the file in the
              left panel to the file in the right panel.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files_first_change">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffFirst16.png"/>First Change</uicontrol>
              (<uicontrol conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_b"/>)</dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the first change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-last-change">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffLast16.png"/>Last Change</uicontrol> (<uicontrol
              conkeyref="reusable-oxygen-shortcuts-list/ctrl_e"/>)</dt>
          <dd>Jumps to the last change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-ignore-whitespaces">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffIgnoreWhitespaces20.png" id="image_gmn_wk3_tc"
                placement="inline"/>Ignore Whitespaces</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Enables or disables the whitespace ignoring feature. Ignoring whitespace means that
            before performing the comparison, the application normalizes the content and trims its
            leading and trailing whitespaces.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-synchro-scrolling">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffSynchronizeScroll20.png" id="image_ygw_yph_tc"
                placement="inline"/>Synchronized scrolling </uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Toggles synchronized scrolling. When toggled on, a selected difference can be seen in
            both panels.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-show-word-level">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffWordDetails16.gif" id="image_kwp_4yh_5r"/>Show
              Word Level Details</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Provides a word-level comparison of the selected change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="files-show-char-level">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCharDetails16.gif" id="image_sjs_gyh_5r"/>Show
              Character Level Details</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Provides a character-level comparison of the selected change.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="ignore-nodes-by-xpath">
          <dt><uicontrol>Ignore Nodes by XPath</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>You can use this text field to enter an <xref
              href="../../topics/running-xpath-expressions.dita#running-xpath-expressions"
              product="author developer editor">XPath expression</xref><ph product="svnClient">XPath
              expression</ph> to ignore certain nodes from the comparison. It will be processed as
            XPath version 2.0. You can also enter the name of the node to ignore all nodes with the
            specified name (for example, if you want to ignore all ID attributes from the document,
            you could simply enter <userinput>@id</userinput>). This field is only available when
            comparing XML documents using the <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>XML
              Accurate</uicontrol> algorithms.<note>If an XPath expression is specified in the <ph
                product="author developer editor"><xref
                  href="../../topics/preferences-diff-files.dita#preferences-diff-files/xml-diff-section"
                    ><uicontrol>Ignore nodes by XPath</uicontrol> option</xref> in the
                  <uicontrol>Diff / File Comparison</uicontrol></ph><ph product="svnClient"><xref
                  href="../../topics/preferences-svn-diff.dita#preferences-svn-diff/xml-diff-section"
                    ><uicontrol>Ignore nodes by XPath</uicontrol> option</xref> in the
                  <uicontrol>Diff</uicontrol></ph> preferences page, that one is used as a default
              when the application is started. If you then enter an expression in this field on the
              toolbar, this one will be used instead of the default. If you delete the expression
              from this field, neither will be used.</note></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <section id="d2e227">
      <title>Diff Reusables</title>
      <sectiondiv id="highlighting-colors"><b>Highlighting Colors</b><p>The differences are also
          highlighted in several colors, depending on the type of change, and dynamic lines connect
          the compared fragments in the middle section between the two panes. The highlighting
          colors can be customized in the <xref
            href="../../topics/preferences-diff-appearance.dita#preferences-diff-appearance"
              ><uicontrol>Files Comparison / Appearance</uicontrol> preferences page</xref>, but the
          default colors and their shades mean the following:<ul>
            <li><b>Pink</b> - Identifies blocks of changes that include conflicts.</li>
            <li><b>Gray</b> - Identifies your outgoing changes that do not include conflicts.</li>
            <li><b>Blue</b> - Identifies incoming changes that do not include conflicts.</li>
            <li><b>Lighter Shade</b> - Identifies blocks of changes that can be merged in their
              entirety.</li>
            <li><b>Darker Shade</b> - Identifies specific changes within the blocks that can be
              merged more precisely.</li>
          </ul></p></sectiondiv>
      <sectiondiv id="editing-actions"><b>Editing Actions</b><p>You can edit the files directly in
          either editing pane. The two editors are constantly synchronized and the differences are
          refreshed when you save the modified document or when you click the <uicontrol><image
              href="../../img/DiffPerform16.png"/>Perform File Differencing</uicontrol>
          button.</p><p>A variety of actions are available on the <xref
            href="../../topics/file-compare-toolbar.dita#file-compare-toolbar">toolbar</xref> and in
          the <xref href="../../topics/files-comparison-main-menu.dita#files-comparison-main-menu"
            >various menus</xref> (these same actions are also available in the contextual menu in
          both editing panes). The tool also includes some inline actions to help you merge, copy,
          or remove changes. When you select a change, the following inline action widgets are
          available, depending on the type of change:<dl>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffAppendLeftToRight12.png" placement="inline"
                  />Append left change to right</uicontrol> and <uicontrol><image
                    href="../../img/DiffAppendRightToLeft12.png" placement="inline"/>Append right
                  change to left</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Copies the content of the selected change from one side and appends it on the
                other, according to the content of the corresponding change. As a result, the side
                where the arrow points to will contain the changes from both sides.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCopyLeftToRight12.png" placement="inline"
                  />Copy change from left to right</uicontrol> and <uicontrol><image
                    href="../../img/DiffCopyRightToLeft12.png" placement="inline"/>Copy change from
                  right to left</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Replaces the content of a change from one side with the content of the
                corresponding change from the other side.</dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry>
              <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffRemove12.png"/>Remove
                change</uicontrol></dt>
              <dd>Rejects the change on the particular side and preserves the particular content on
                the other side.</dd>
            </dlentry>
          </dl></p></sectiondiv>
      <sectiondiv id="navigate-differences"><b>Navigate Differences</b><p>To navigate through
          differences, do one of the following:<ul id="ul_lrm_q3f_lf">
            <li>Use the navigation buttons on the toolbar (or in the <uicontrol>Compare</uicontrol>
              menu).</li>
            <li>Select a block of differences by clicking its small colored marker in the overview
              ruler located in the right-most part of the window. At the top of the overview ruler
              there is a success indicator that turns green where there are no differences, or red
              if differences are found.</li>
            <li>Click a colored area in between the two text editors.</li>
          </ul></p></sectiondiv>
    </section>
    <p>
      <!--Reusable components for the Compare Directories tool-->
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="dir-perform-dir-diff">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffPerform20.png"/>Perform Directories
              Differencing</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="perform-dir-diff-ph">Looks for differences between the two directories
              displayed in the left and right side of the application window.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="dir-perform-files-diff">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffFiles24.png"/>Perform Files
              Differencing</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="compare-files-ph">Opens the <xref
                href="../../topics/file-comparison.dita#file-comparison"><uicontrol>Compare
                  Files</uicontrol> tool</xref> that allows you to compare the currently selected
              files.</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCopyRightToLeft16.png"/>Copy Change from Right
              to Left</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="dir-copy-right-left-ph">Copies the selected change from the right side to the
              left side (if there is no file/folder in the right side, the left file/folder is
              deleted).</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DiffCopyLeftToRight16.png"/>Copy Change from Left to
              Right</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd><ph id="dir-copy-left-right-ph">Copies the selected change from the left side to the
              right side (if there is no file/folder in the left side, the right file/folder is
              deleted).</ph></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <section id="options_menu">
      <title>Options Menu</title>
      <p>
        <dl id="options-dl">
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens the preferences dialog box that includes numerous pages of options that can be
              configured.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Menu Shortcut Keys</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Menu Shortcut Keys</uicontrol> option page where you can
              configure keyboard shortcuts available for menu items.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Reset Global Options</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Resets options to their default values. Note that this option appears only when the
              tool is executed as a stand-alone application.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Import Global Options</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Allows you to import an options set that you have previously exported.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Export Global Options</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Allows you to export the current options set to a file.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="help_menu">
      <title>Help Menu</title>
      <p>
        <dl id="help-dl">
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Help (<shortcut>F1</shortcut>)</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens a <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> dialog box that displays the User Manual at a
              section that is appropriate for the context of the current cursor position.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Use Online Help</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>If this option is selected, when you select Help or press F1 while hovering over any
              part of the interface, <ph keyref="product"/> attempts to open the help documentation
              in online mode. If this option is not selected or an internet connection fails, the
              help documentation is opened in offline mode.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Report problem</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows the user to write the description of a problem that
              was encountered while using the application. You can change the URL where the reported
              problem is sent by using the <codeph>com.oxygenxml.report.problems.url</codeph> system
              property. The report is sent in XML format through the
                <systemoutput>report</systemoutput> parameter of the POST HTTP method.</dd>
          </dlentry>
          <dlentry>
            <dt><uicontrol>Support Center</uicontrol></dt>
            <dd>Opens the <ph keyref="product"/> Support Center web page in a browser.</dd>
          </dlentry>
        </dl>
      </p>
    </section>
    <!--Diff Algorithms-->
    <ul id="algorithm-ul">
      <li id="auto">
        <uicontrol>Auto</uicontrol> - Selects the most appropriate algorithm, based on the compared
        content and its size (selected by default).</li>
      <li id="characters">
        <uicontrol>Characters</uicontrol> - Computes the differences at character level, meaning
        that it compares two files or fragments looking for identical characters.<ph
          product="author editor"> This algorithm is not available when the file comparison is in
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
      <li id="words">
        <uicontrol>Words</uicontrol> - Computes the differences at word level, meaning that it
        compares two files or fragments looking for identical words.<ph product="author editor">
          This algorithm is not available when the file comparison is in
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
      <li id="lines">
        <uicontrol>Lines</uicontrol> - Computes the differences at line level, meaning that it
        compares two files or fragments looking for identical lines of text.<ph
          product="author editor"> This algorithm is not available when the file comparison is in
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
      <li id="syntax-aware">
        <uicontrol>Syntax Aware</uicontrol> - Computes differences for the file types or fragments
        known by <ph keyref="product"/>, taking the syntax (the specific types of tokens) into
          consideration.<ph product="author editor"> This algorithm is not available when the file
          comparison is in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</ph></li>
      <li id="xml-fast">
        <uicontrol>XML Fast</uicontrol> - Comparison that works well on large files or fragments,
        but it is less precise than <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol>.</li>
      <li id="xml-accurate">
        <uicontrol>XML Accurate</uicontrol> - Comparison that is more precise than <uicontrol>XML
          Fast</uicontrol>, at the expense of speed. It compares two XML files or fragments looking
        for identical XML nodes. </li>
    </ul>
    <!--SDK reusables-->
    <ol product="author developer editor">
      <li>Pack the <xref keyref="glossentry_plugin"><term>plugin</term></xref> or <xref
          keyref="glossentry_framework"><term>framework</term></xref> as a <codeph>ZIP</codeph> file
        or a <xref keyref="glossentry_jar"><term>Java Archive</term></xref>. Note that you should
        pack the entire root directory not just its contents.</li>
      <li id="li2">Digitally sign the package. Note that you can perform this step only if you have
        created a <term>Java Archive</term> at the previous step. You will need a certificate signed
        by a trusted authority. To sign the <term>JAR</term> you can either use the <i>jarsigner</i>
        command-line tool inside Oracle's Java Development Kit.
          (<filepath>[JDK_DIR]/bin/jarsigner.exe</filepath>) or, if you are working with <xref
          keyref="glossentry_ant"><term>Apache Ant</term></xref>, you can use the <i>signjar</i>
        task (a front for the <i>jarsigner</i> command-line tool).<note>The benefit of having a
          signed add-on is that you can verify the integrity of the add-on issuer. If you do not
          have such a certificate you can generate one yourself using the <i>keytool</i>
          command-line tool. This approach is mostly recommended for tests since anyone can create a
          self signed certificate. </note></li>
      <li id="li3">Create a descriptor file. You can use a template that <ph keyref="product"/>
        provides. To use this template, go to <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> and select the <uicontrol>Oxygen add-ons update site</uicontrol> template.
        Once deployed, this descriptor file is referenced as <i>update site</i>.</li>
    </ol>
    <p id="p1" product="author developer editor">Alternatively, you can use the <uicontrol>Add-ons
        Packager</uicontrol> plugin by following this procedure:<ol>
        <li>Install the <uicontrol>Add-ons Packager</uicontrol> plugin following the procedure
          described in <xref keyref="install_add-ons">Installing Add-ons</xref>.</li>
        <li>Restart <ph keyref="product"/>. If the add-on is correctly installed, the
            <uicontrol>Add-ons packager</uicontrol> toolbar action is available.</li>
        <li>Invoke the <uicontrol>Add-ons packager</uicontrol> toolbar action and input the required
          information in the displayed dialog box.</li>
        <li>Press <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol> to complete the packaging process.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <section id="deploying_an_addon" product="author developer editor">
      <title>Deploying an Add-on</title>
      <p id="p2">To deploy an add-on, copy the <codeph>ZIP</codeph> or <xref keyref="glossentry_jar"
            ><term>Java Archive</term></xref> file and the descriptor file to an HTTP server. The
        URL to this location serves as the <i>Update Site URL</i>.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
