<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="reusables-webapp">
  <title>Reusable Components in The Web Author Chapter</title>
  <body>
    <!--Reusable components for the WepApp chapter-->
    <p>
      <ul id="paste-special-options">
        <li><uicontrol>Smart Paste</uicontrol> - <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> will paste the copied
          content while trying to preserve its structure and if the current location is invalid, <ph
            keyref="webappProduct"/> will attempt to find a possible solution.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Paste as Text</uicontrol> - The copied content will be pasted as text
          content.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Paste as XML</uicontrol> - Copied content that is considered to be valid XML
          will be pasted with its XML structure preserved.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <!--Actions-->
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="accept-changes">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/AcceptChange16.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_eb1_t5d_4v"/>Accept Change</uicontrol> (Available when invoked on a
            change)</dt>
          <dd>Available on changes when <term>Change Tracking</term> is enabled. It accepts the
            tracked change located at the cursor position. For an <i>insert</i> change, it means
            keeping the inserted text and for a <i>delete</i> change, it means removing the content
            from the document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="reject-changes">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/RejectChange16.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_fb1_t5d_4v"/>Reject Change</uicontrol> (Available when invoked on a
            change)</dt>
          <dd>Available on changes when <term>Change Tracking</term> is enabled. Rejects the tracked
            change located at the cursor position. For an <i>insert</i> change, it means removing
            the inserted text and for a <i>delete</i> change, it means preserving the original
            content from the document.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="add-comment">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/AddComment16.png" id="image_pmh_5jg_wr"/>Add
              Comment</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to insert a comment on a selected fragment of text. After you add a
            comment, the content where the comment was added is highlighted in the document and you
            can see the comment by hovering over the highlighted content or in the
              <uicontrol>Review</uicontrol> view.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="edit-comment">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/EditComment16.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_gb1_t5d_4v"/>Edit Comment</uicontrol> (Available when invoked on a
            comment)</dt>
          <dd>Opens the <uicontrol>Edit Comment</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you to edit the
            selected comment.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="remove-comment">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/RemoveComment16.png" placement="inline"
                id="image_hb1_t5d_4v"/>Remove Comment</uicontrol> (Available when invoked on a
            comment)</dt>
          <dd>Removes a selected comment.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <!--DITA actions-->
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry id="cross-reference">
          <dt><uicontrol>Cross Reference</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Used to insert a cross reference link to a DITA resource. Selecting this option opens
            a dialog box where you can select a target file and a target element (for any element in
            the target file with an <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute set). It inserts the target link
            as a DITA <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> element and points to the target using the
              <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> attribute. However, if the target reference is defined with a
            key, a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute is automatically inserted instead.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="file-reference">
          <dt><uicontrol>File Reference</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Used to insert a link to a non-DITA file resource. Selecting this option opens a
            dialog box where you can select a target file. It inserts the target link as a DITA
              <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> element and points to the target file using the
              <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> attribute, and also inserts a <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> attribute
            and detects the appropriate value based on the type of resource. If the target reference
            is defined with a key, a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute is automatically inserted
            instead.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="web-link">
          <dt><uicontrol>Web Link</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Used to insert a link to a web-related resource. Selecting this option opens a simple
            dialog box where you can enter the URL of the target web link. It inserts the target
            link as a DITA <xmlelement>xref</xmlelement> element and points to the target URL using
            the <xmlatt>href</xmlatt> attribute, and also inserts a <xmlatt>format</xmlatt> and
              <xmlatt>scope</xmlatt> attribute and detects the appropriate values (for example,
              <codeph>format="html" scope="external"</codeph>). If the target reference is defined
            with a key, a <xmlatt>keyref</xmlatt> attribute is automatically inserted instead.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-image">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/Image16.gif" id="image_lqj_f1z_tr"/>Insert
              Image</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box where you can browse for and select an image to be inserted into a
            DITA document at the cursor position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-section">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/Section16.gif"/>Insert Section</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>section</codeph> element in the document, depending on the
            current context.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-concept">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/InsertConcept16.gif"/>Insert
            Concept</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>concept</codeph> element, depending on the current context.
            Concepts provide background information that users must know before they can
            successfully work with a product or interface.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-task">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/InsertTask16.gif"/>Insert Task</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>task</codeph> element, depending on the current context. Tasks
            are the main building blocks for task-oriented user assistance. They generally provide
            step-by-step instructions that will help a user to perform a task.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-topic">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/InsertTopic16.gif"/>Insert Topic</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>topic</codeph> element, depending on the current context. Topics
            are the basic units of DITA content and are usually organized around a single
            subject.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-reference">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/InsertRef16.gif"/>Insert Reference</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new <codeph>reference</codeph> element, depending on the current context. A
            reference is a top-level container for a reference topic.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-paragraph">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/Paragraph16.png" id="image_glk_4lw_5r"/>Insert
              Paragraph</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Inserts a new paragraph at current cursor position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="reuse-content">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/Conref16.png" id="image_h2y_rwx_sr"/>Reuse
              Content</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>
            <p>This action opens a dialog box where you can select a target file and a target
              element (for any element in the target file with an <xmlatt>id</xmlatt> attribute
              set). It inserts the target as a DITA content reference (<xmlatt>conref</xmlatt>).
              However, if the target reference is defined with a key, it is automatically inserted
              as a <xmlatt>conkeyref</xmlatt> instead.</p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-table">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/Table16.png"/>Insert Table</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box where you can choose between a <uicontrol>CALS</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol>Simple</uicontrol> table and optionally enter a title. When you click
              <uicontrol>OK</uicontrol>, it inserts a table at the current position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="surround-with">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/SurroundWithTag16.png"/>Surround
            With</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to choose a tag to enclose selected content.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="insert-element">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/InsertElement16.png"/>Insert
            Element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a content completion window where you can choose an element to insert at the
            current position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="generate-ids">
          <dt><uicontrol>Generate IDs</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>
            <p><ph keyref="product"/> generates unique IDs for the current element (or elements),
              depending on how the action is invoked:<ul id="ul_ivr_nx1_gr">
                <li>When invoked on a single selection, an ID is generated for the selected element
                  at the cursor position.</li>
                <li>When invoked on a block of selected content, IDs are generated for all top-level
                  elements.</li>
              </ul><note id="generate-id-note">The <uicontrol>Generate IDs</uicontrol> action does
                not overwrite existing ID values. It only affects elements that do not already have
                an <codeph>id</codeph> attribute.</note></p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="IX-Paste_special">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/Paste16.png"/>Paste Special</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to choose how to paste copied content. You have to
            use the <uicontrol><shortcut id="ctrl_v_shortcut">Ctrl + V (Command + V on OS
                X)</shortcut></uicontrol> keyboard shortcut (or select <uicontrol>Paste</uicontrol>
            from the contextual menu) to paste the copied content into the preview window in this
              <uicontrol>Paste Special</uicontrol> dialog box and then you can choose to paste it
            into your document with one of the following choices:<ul>
              <li><uicontrol>Smart Paste</uicontrol> - <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> will paste the
                copied content while trying to preserve its structure and if the current location is
                invalid, <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> will attempt to find a possible solution.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Paste as Text</uicontrol> - The copied content will be pasted as text
                content.</li>
              <li><uicontrol>Paste as XML</uicontrol> - Copied content that is considered to be
                valid XML will be pasted with its XML structure preserved.</li>
            </ul></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="folding-submenu">
          <dt><uicontrol>Folding</uicontrol> Submenu</dt>
          <dd>
            <p>
              <dl>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/ToggleFold16.png" id="image_tvs_2vm_wr"
                      />Toggle Fold</uicontrol> (or simply click on the <image
                      href="../../img/Expanded16.png"/>/<image href="../../img/Collapsed16.png"/>
                    arrow in the editing panel)</dt>
                  <dd>Toggles the state of the current fold.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/CloseOtherFolds16.png" id="image_pz2_z5m_wr"
                      />Collapse Other Folds</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Folds all the elements except the current element.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/CollapseChildFolds16.png"
                        id="image_rlw_y5m_wr"/>Collapse Child Folds</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Folds the child elements that are indented one level inside the current
                    element.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/ExpandChildFolds16.png"
                        id="image_o5l_y5m_wr"/>Expand Child Folds</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Unfolds all child elements of the currently selected element.</dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                  <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/ExpandAll16.png" placement="inline"/>Expand
                      All</uicontrol></dt>
                  <dd>Unfolds all elements in the current document.</dd>
                </dlentry>
              </dl>
            </p>
          </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="IX-Rename_element">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/RenameElement16.png" id="image_z52_xxz_tr"/>Rename
              Element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a content completion window where you can choose an element to rename the
            element at the current position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="delete-element">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/DeleteElementTags16.png"/>Delete
            Element</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Deletes the tags of the closest element at the current cursor position.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="IX-Insert_special_char">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/WASpecChar16.png"/>Insert Special
              Character</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to select from a large variety of special
            characters to insert at the current cursor position. The various types of characters
            include symbols, emoticons, punctuation, and many more.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <!--misc notes-->
    <p><ph id="safari-note">On Safari Mobile versions 6 and 7, the copy/paste support ignores all
        text formatting, keeping only the content.</ph></p>
    <!--UI reusables-->
    <ul>
      <li id="help-li"><uicontrol><image href="../../img/ShowHelp16.png"/>Help</uicontrol> - Opens a
        WebHelp version of the <ph keyref="webappProduct"/> user manual.</li>
      <li id="report-problem-li"><uicontrol>Report Problem</uicontrol> - You can use this option to
        open a dialog box that allows you to write the description of a problem that was encountered
        while using the application. You can also select additional information to be sent to the
        technical support team in the various tabs.</li>
    </ul>
    <!--misc-->
    <p><ph id="side-panel-ph"> If it is not displayed, click the arrow button (<image
          href="../../img/WA_open_arrow.png"/>) on the far right side of the editor.</ph></p>
  </body>
</topic>
