<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="reusables-search-refactoring-actions">
  <title>Reusable - Searching and Refactoring Actions</title>
  <body>
    <p>
      <dl id="searchRefAndDeclarations">
        <dlentry id="search-references-li">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/SearchReferences16.png" id="image_or2_flq_2r"
              />Search References</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches all references of the item found at current cursor position in the defined
            scope, if any. If a scope is defined, but the current edited resource is not part of the
            range of resources determined by this, a warning dialog box is displayed and you have
            the possibility to define another search scope. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="search-references-in-li">
          <dt><uicontrol>Search References in</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches all references of the item found at current cursor position in the file or
            files that you specify when define a scope in the <uicontrol>Search
              References</uicontrol> dialog box.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="search-declarations-li">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/SearchDeclarations16.png" id="image_c3l_3lq_2r"
              />Search Declarations</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches all declarations of the item found at current cursor position in the defined
            scope if any. If a scope is defined, but the current edited resource is not part of the
            range of resources determined by this, a warning dialog box will be displayed and you
            have the possibility to define another search scope.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="search-declarations-in-li">
          <dt><uicontrol>Search Declarations in</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches all declarations of the item found at current cursor position in the file or
            files that you specify when you define a scope for the search operation.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="search-occurrences-li">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/OccurrencesInFile16.png" id="image_hwj_z51_5r"
              />Search Occurrences in File</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Searches all occurrences of the item at the cursor position in the currently edited
            file.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
      <!--Rename component-->
      <dl id="renameComponent">
        <dlentry id="rename-component-li">
          <dt><uicontrol>Rename Component</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Allows you to rename the current component (in-place). The component and all its
            references in the document are highlighted with a thin border and the changes you make
            to the component at the cursor position are updated in real time to all occurrences of
            the component. To exit the in-place editing, press the
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Esc</shortcut></uicontrol> or
                <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> key on your keyboard.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry id="rename-component-in-li">
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/RenameXSLResource16.png" id="image_zx4_kv1_5r"
              />Rename Component in</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Opens a dialog box that allows you to rename the selected component by specifying the
            new component name and the files to be affected by the modification. If you click the
              <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> button, you can view the files to be affected by the action.<p>
              <fig id="fig_bjd_ghb_lr" product="editor developer">
                <title>Rename Identity Constraint Dialog Box </title>
                <image href="../../img/sa_rename_component.png" id="image_qjd_ghb_lr"
                  placement="inline"/>
              </fig>
            </p><p>
              <fig id="fig_rjd_ghb_lr" product="editorEclipse developerEclipse">
                <title>Rename Identity Constraint Dialog Box</title>
                <image href="../../img/ec_rename_component.png" id="image_sjd_ghb_lr"
                  placement="inline"/>
              </fig>
            </p></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
  </body>
</topic>
