<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="reusables-webauthor-customization">
  <title>Reusable Components in WA Customization Chapters</title>
  <body>
    <p id="oxy-url-p-2">The allowed URL parameters are as follows:<ul id="ul_x1l_2x1_br">
        <li><b>url</b> - The <xref href="../../topics/oxy-url.dita" format="dita"
              ><term>OXY-URL</term></xref> that identifies the file to be opened.</li>
        <li><b>folderUrl</b> - You can use this parameter to navigate to the Dashboard with the
          corresponding repository tab open and the content of the specified folder
          displayed.</li>
        <li><b>userName</b> - The user name of the author.</li>
        <li><b>autoSaveInterval</b> - The interval of time (in seconds) to wait until an auto-save
          is performed. If set to <codeph>0</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>, the auto-save is
          disabled.</li>
        <li><b>ccOnEnter</b> - If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, the content completion popup window
          is displayed when the user presses <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol>. If
          set to <codeph>false</codeph>, the <uicontrol><shortcut>Enter</shortcut></uicontrol> key
          works similar to the behavior in a normal word processor application.</li>
        <li><b>hideBreadcrumb</b> - If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, the <i>breadcrumb</i> will not
          be displayed in the interface.</li>
        <li><b>lang</b> - You can use this parameter to impose a specific language for the <ph
            keyref="webappProduct"/> interface. The possible values are:<ul>
            <li><b>en_US</b> - English</li>
            <li><b>de_DE</b> - German</li>
            <li><b>fr_FR</b> - French</li>
            <li><b>ja_JP</b> - Japanese</li>
            <li><b>nl_NL</b> - Dutch</li>
            <li><b>zh_CN</b> - Chinese</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b>spell.check.language</b> - Specifies the default language used for spell checking in
          the document. The value must be in either a 2-digit or 4-digit language code format (for
          example, <codeph>en</codeph> or <codeph>en_US</codeph>).</li>
        <li><b>trackChanges</b> - Flag that controls whether or not the editor should track changes.
          The possible values are:<ul id="ul_bn3_jcf_11b">
            <li><b>default</b> - The status of change tracking is determined by the server's global
              options.</li>
            <li><b>enabled</b> - Change tracking is enabled but the user can disable it using a
              toolbar action.</li>
            <li><b>forced</b> - Change tracking is enabled and the user cannot disable it. The user
              can reject their own changes, but cannot accept or reject changes made by others.</li>
          </ul>If you use a value other than <codeph>default</codeph>, the server change tracking
          status (as configured in the <xref
            href="../../topics/webapp-admin-page.dita#webapp-admin-page">Administration Page</xref>)
          should not be "Stored in the document". For more information about this parameter, see
            <xref href="../../topics/wa-force-track-changes.dita#wa-force-track-changes"/></li>
        <li><b>ditamap</b> - (DITA-specific Parameter) The <xref href="../../topics/oxy-url.dita"
            format="dita"><term>OXY-URL</term></xref> of the DITA Map to use as a context for
          resolving keys.</li>
        <li><b>dita.val.url</b> - (DITA-specific Parameter) The <xref
            href="../../topics/oxy-url.dita" format="dita"><term>OXY-URL</term></xref> of a DITAVAL
          filter. It is used for resolving keys whose values depend on profiling conditions and it
          grays out content that is excluded by the DITAVAL filter.</li>
        <li>
          <p><b>KeyscopeStack</b> - (DITA-specific Parameter) Used for resolving keys when DITA 1.3
              <i>key scopes</i> are defined in the DITA map. The value looks like
            this:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">a b c,d e f</codeblock></p>
          <p>for a DITA map that has the key scope defined like
            this:<codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;topicref keyscope="a b c">&lt;topicref keyscope="d e f"/>&lt;/topicref></codeblock></p>
        </li>
        <li><b>expandTopicRefs</b> - (DITA-specific Parameter) If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, when
          a DITA map is opened in <ph keyref="webappProduct"/>, the content of all topics referenced
          in the map will be presented.</li>
        <li><b>contentType</b> - For cases where Web Author cannot open a document that has an
          unrecognized file extension, you can use this parameter as a loading option to pass a
          specific file type so that client-side editing support can be used for editing the
          document. You can also specify an encoding type. Examples for values:<ul>
            <li><b>image/png</b></li>
            <li><b>application/xml</b></li>
            <li><b>application/markdown;charset=utf-8</b></li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b>textModeReadOnly</b> - If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, the Web Author XML text
          editing mode will always be set to read-only.</li>
        <li><b>tags-mode</b> - You can use this parameter to specify the <uicontrol>Tags Display
            Mode</uicontrol> for the document. The possible values are:<ul id="ul_vhx_tpc_kjb">
            <li><b>full-tags-with-attributes</b> - Displays full tag names with attributes for both
                <term>block</term> and <term>inline</term> elements.</li>
            <li><b>full-tags</b> - Displays full tag names without attributes for both
                <term>block</term> and <term>inline</term> elements.</li>
            <li><b>block-tags</b> - Displays full tag names for <term>block elements</term> and
              simple tags without names for <term>inline elements</term>.</li>
            <li><b>inline-tags</b> - Displays full tag names for <term>inline elements</term>, while
                <term>block elements</term> are not displayed.</li>
            <li><b>partial-tags</b> - Displays simple tags without names for <term>inline
                elements</term>, while <term>block elements</term> are not displayed.</li>
            <li><b>no-tags</b> - No tags are displayed.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><b>compactTagsMode</b> - If the user has the <uicontrol>Tags Display Mode</uicontrol>
          option set to any value that shows the XML tags, setting this parameter to
            <codeph>true</codeph> will compact the tags (for example, multiple tags presented on the
          same line). If set to <codeph>false</codeph>, each tag of a block element is presented on
          a separate line.</li>
        <li><b>quickUpDownNavigation</b> - If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, horizontal cursor
          positions between block elements are avoided. It also forces tags of block elements to be
          displayed on separate lines, if visible.</li>
        <li><b>diffUrl</b> - (File Comparison Tool Parameter) This parameter can be used in
          conjunction with the <b>url</b> parameter to specify files to compare with each other.
          This parameter specifies the URL of the file to be opened in the right side of the file
          comparison tool while the <b>url</b> parameter specifies the URL of the file to be opened
          in the left side.</li>
        <li><b>diffBaseUrl</b> - (File Comparison Tool Parameter) This parameter can be used in
          conjunction with the <b>url</b> and <b>diffUrl</b> parameters to perform a 3-way file
          comparison. This parameter specifies the URL of the original base file, while the
            <b>url</b> parameter specifies the URL of the file to be opened in the left side of the
          file comparison tool (the local file), and the <b>diffUrl</b> parameter specifies the URL
          of the file to be opened in the right side (the remote file).</li>
        <li><b>leftEditorLabel</b> - (File Comparison Tool Parameter) This parameter can be used to
          specify the label used for the name of the file in the left side of the file comparison
          tool. Normally, the file name is used.</li>
        <li><b>rightEditorLabel</b> - (File Comparison Tool Parameter) This parameter can be used to
          specify the label used for the name of the file in the right side of the file comparison
          tool. Normally, the file name is used.</li>
        <li><b>schematron.imposed.phase</b> - This parameter can be used to impose the Schematron
          phase to use when validating with a Schematron file.</li>
        <li><b>schematronUrl</b> - (Markdown-specific parameter) This parameter can be used to
          specify the URL of a Schematron file that will be used to validate the Markdown
          document.</li>
        <li><b>showDitaMapView</b> - When set to <b>true</b>, the <uicontrol>DITA Map</uicontrol>
          view will automatically be displayed (and the <i>Show DITA Map View</i> action is no
          longer present on the toolbar).</li>
        <li><b>showTopicTitles</b> - When set to <b>true</b>, topic titles are resolved and
          displayed when a DITA map is opened (the same as if the <xref
            href="../../topics/WA-dita-map-doc-type.dita#WA-dita-map-doc-type/view-topic-titles"
              ><uicontrol>View Topic Titles</uicontrol> mode</xref> is selected in the <xref
            href="../../topics/WA-dita-map-doc-type.dita#WA-dita-map-doc-type/dita-map-display-mode"
            >DITA map display mode drop-down</xref>).</li>
        <li><b>inplaceReferenceEditingSupported</b> - Can be set to <b>true</b> if the CMS connector
          is prepared to save user changes in files referenced from the open document. When this
          option is enabled, the <xref
            href="../../topics/WA-dita-map-doc-type.dita#WA-dita-map-doc-type/edit-topic-content"
              ><uicontrol>Edit Topic Content</uicontrol> mode</xref> becomes available when opening
          a DITA Map.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
