<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="reusables-user-guide">
  <title>Reusable Components in User Guide</title>
  <body>
    <!--Reusable components for multiple chapters in the User Guide-->
    <p><term id="oxy-install-dir">[OXYGEN_INSTALL_DIR]</term></p>
    <p><term id="oxy-webapp-install-dir">[OXYGEN_WEBAUTHOR_INSTALL_DIR]</term></p>
    <p><term id="eclipse-install-dir">[ECLIPSE-INSTALL-DIR]</term></p>
    <p><!--Reusable components for the name of the folder used on OS X--></p>
    <p><filepath id="installMacFolder"><term product="editor">Oxygen XML Editor</term><term
          product="author">Oxygen XML Author</term><term product="developer">Oxygen XML
          Developer</term></filepath></p>
    <!--To reopen a view-->
    <p><ph id="reopen-view">If the view is not displayed, it can be opened by selecting it from the <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> menu.</ph></p>
    <p><ph id="reopen-view-parenthesis">(if the view is not displayed, it can be opened by selecting
        it from the <menucascade>
          <uicontrol>Window</uicontrol>
          <uicontrol>Show View</uicontrol>
        </menucascade> menu)</ph></p>
    <!--Adding a path in dialog boxes that include the Insert Editor Variable button and Browsing drop down list-->
    <p><ph id="specify-path-ph"
        product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">You can
        specify the path by using the text field, its history drop-down, the <xref
          href="../../topics/editor-variables.dita#editor-variables"><uicontrol><image
              href="../../img/InsertEditorVariables16.png"/>Insert Editor
          Variables</uicontrol></xref> button, or the browsing tools in the <uicontrol><image
            href="../../img/BrowseDrop.png"/>Browse</uicontrol> drop-down list.</ph></p>
    <p><ph id="specify-path-without-drop-down"
        product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">You can
        specify the path by using the text field, the <xref
          href="../../topics/editor-variables.dita#editor-variables"><uicontrol><image
              href="../../img/InsertEditorVariables16.png"/>Insert Editor
          Variables</uicontrol></xref> button, or the <uicontrol><image href="../../img/Open16.png"
          />Browse</uicontrol> button.</ph></p>
    <note type="tip" product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
      id="note-wildcards-in-path">The path can also contain wildcards (for example,
        <codeph>${framework}/lib/*.jar</codeph>).</note>
    <p><ph id="specify-path">You can specify the path by using the text field, the history
        drop-down, or the browsing tools in the <uicontrol><image href="../../img/BrowseDrop.png"
          />Browse</uicontrol> drop-down menu.</ph></p>
    <note type="tip" id="note2-wildcards"
      product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse">The path can
      also contain wildcards. For example, using <codeph>${frameworkDir}/templates/*</codeph> would
      add all the template folders found inside the <filepath>templates</filepath> directory.</note>
    <p>another note:</p>
    <note type="tip" product="author developer editor authorEclipse developerEclipse editorEclipse"
      id="note3-wildcards">You can specify the path to the resources using wildcards (for example,
        <codeph>${oxygenHome}/lib/*.jar</codeph>).</note>
    <!--Misc-->
    <p id="docbook-intro-p"><i>DocBook</i> is a very popular set of tags for describing books,
      articles, and other prose documents, particularly technical documentation. DocBook provides a
      vast number of semantic element tags, divided into three broad categories: structural,
        <term>block-level</term>, and <term>inline</term>. DocBook content can then be published in
      a variety of formats, including HTML, PDF, WebHelp, and EPUB.</p>
    <p id="tei-intro">The <i>TEI (Text Encoding Initiative)</i> document type is an international
      and interdisciplinary standard that enables libraries, museums, publishers, and individual
      scholars to represent a variety of literary and linguistic texts for online research,
      teaching, and preservation.</p>
    <!--Digital Signing notes-->
    <note id="exclusive-note">Exclusive Canonicalization just copies the namespaces you are actually
      using (the ones that are a part of the XML syntax). It does not look into attribute values or
      element content, so the namespace declarations required to process these are not copied. This
      is useful if you have a signed XML document that you want to insert into other XML documents
      (or you need self-signed structures that support placement within various XML contexts), as it
      will ensure the signature is verified correctly each time.</note>
    <note id="inclusive-note">Inclusive Canonicalization copies all the declarations, even if they
      are defined outside of the scope of the signature, and all the declarations you might use will
      be unambiguously specified. Inclusive Canonicalization is useful when it is less likely that
      the signed data will be inserted in other XML document and it is the safer method from the
      security standpoint because it requires no knowledge of the data that are to be secured to
      safely sign them. A problem may occur if the signed document is moved into another XML
      document that has other declarations because the Inclusive Canonicalization will copy them and
      the signature will be invalid.</note>
  </body>
</topic>
