<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="dg-editor-function">
  <title>The Form Control Function</title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <shortdesc/>
  <conbody>
    <p>A <term>form control</term> is a generic term that describes any type of user interface
      control that allows a user to interact with a document. Form controls include familiar user
      interface objects. For example, text boxes allow a user to input text in a document, while
      date pickers allow the user to select a date in a user-friendly manner.</p>
    <p>Currently <ph keyref="product"/> provides the following built-in form controls:<ul
        id="ul_rv2_kpl_rq">
        <li>Text Field - A graphical user interface box that allows you to enter a single line of
          text.</li>
        <li>Combo Box - A graphical user interface object that can be a drop-down list or a
          combination of a drop-down list and a single-line text field.</li>
        <li>Check Box - A graphical user interface box that you can click to select or deselect a
          value.</li>
        <li>Pop-up - A contextual menu that provides quick access to various actions.</li>
        <li>Button - A graphical user interface object that performs a specific action.</li>
        <li>Button Group - A graphical user interface group of buttons (such as radio buttons) that
          perform specific actions.</li>
        <li>Text Area - A box that allows you to enter multiple lines of text.</li>
        <li>URL Chooser - A dialog box that allows you to select the location of local or remote
          resources.</li>
        <li>Date Picker - A form control object that allows you to select a date in a specified
          format.</li>
        <li>HTML Content - A graphical user interface box that is used for rendering HTML
          content.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>For customization and backwards compatibility purposes, <ph keyref="product"/> also supports
      a custom form control, the <codeph>oxy_editor()</codeph> function.</p>
    <p>To watch our video demonstration in regards to form controls, go to <xref
        href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Form_Controls.html" format="html" scope="external"
        >http://oxygenxml.com/demo/Form_Controls.html</xref>.</p>
  </conbody>
  <related-links>
    <link
      href="../topics/api_faq_add_form_control_from_filter.dita#api-faq-add-form-control-from-filter"
    />
  </related-links>
</concept>
