<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="doc-type">
  <title>Document Type</title>
  <body>
    <p id="document-type-definition">A <i>document type</i> or <i>framework</i> is associated to an
      XML file according to a set of rules. It includes also many settings that improve editing in
      the <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode for the category of XML files it applies for. These
      settings include:<ul>
        <li>a default grammar used for validation and content completion in both
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode and Text mode;</li>
        <li>CSS stylesheet(s) for rendering XML documents in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
          mode;</li>
        <li>user actions invoked from toolbar or menu in <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode;</li>
        <li>predefined scenarios used for transformation of the class of XML documents defined by
          the document type;</li>
        <li>XML catalogs;</li>
        <li>directories with file templates;</li>
        <li>user-defined extensions for customizing the interaction with the content author in
            <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> mode.</li>
      </ul><note product="developer developerEclipse authorSDK">The <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol>
        mode allows WYSIWYG-like visual editing of XML documents and is available only in <ph><ph
            keyref="product"/></ph> Editor and <ph><ph keyref="product"/></ph> Author.</note></p>
    <p>The tagless editor comes with some predefined document types already configured when the
      application is installed on the computer. These document types describe well-known XML
      frameworks largely used today for authoring XML documents. Editing a document which conforms
      to one of these types is as easy as opening it or creating it from one of the predefined
      document templates which also come with <ph><ph keyref="product"/></ph>.</p>
    <p>To see our video demonstration about configuring a framework in <ph><ph keyref="product"
        /></ph>, go to <xref href="http://oxygenxml.com/demo/FrameworkConfiguration.html"
        format="html" scope="external"
      >http://oxygenxml.com/demo/FrameworkConfiguration.html</xref>.</p>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="../topics/predefined-document-types.dita#predefined-document-types">
      <desc>Description of the predefined document types</desc>
    </link>
  </related-links>
</topic>
