<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_ktv_xv1_chb">
  <title>Adding support for embedding LaTeX equations in DITA content</title>
  <body>
    <p>LaTeX is a high-quality typesetting system that includes features designed for the production
      of technical and scientific documentation. LaTeX can also be used to express mathematical
      formulas in a textual format. By default, web browsers and PDF readers do not have support to
      show mathematical equations written in LaTeX but there are open source projects that can read
      LaTeX and convert it to other image types.</p>
    <p>Adding support for writing LaTeX equations in DITA topics would imply three stages:<ul
        id="ul_kcm_jw1_chb">
        <li>Find a way to write the equation in the DITA XML content. You can either create a DITA
          DTD specialization and add a new element (for example, called
            <xmlelement>latex</xmlelement> and it extends the DITA <xmlelement>foreign</xmlelement>
          element). Alternatively, you can use the DITA <xmlelement>foreign</xmlelement> element
          with a specific <xmlatt>outputclass</xmlatt> attribute value directly:
          <codeblock outputclass="language-xml">&lt;!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
&lt;topic id="testEquation">
    &lt;title>Test equation&lt;/title>
    &lt;body>
        &lt;p>&lt;foreign outputclass="embed-latex">L' = {L}{\sqrt{1-\frac{v^2}{c^2}}}&lt;/foreign>&lt;/p>
    &lt;/body>
&lt;/topic></codeblock></li>
        <li> If you want Oxygen to properly present the LaTeX equation when editing in the
            <b>Author</b> visual mode, you need an Oxygen plugin that converts the equation content
          to an image. There is a sample plugin that does that here: <xref
            href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/wsaccess-javascript-sample-plugins/tree/master/latex-images-support"
            format="html" scope="external"/>. You can download and copy the plugin folder
            <b>latex-images-support</b> to the Oxygen <b>plugins</b> folder, then restart
          Oxygen.</li>
        <li>Publishing to HTML-based and PDF outputs. This DITA Open Toolkit plugin automatically
          converts LaTeX images to SVG when publishing: <xref
            href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/dita-latex" format="html" scope="external"/>.</li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
