<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="author-document-type-sharing">
  <title>Document Type Extension Sharing</title>
  <body>
    <p>Instead of copying an entire framework configuration folder (like <b>DITA</b> or
        <b>Docbook</b>), then modifying and distributing it, you can choose to extend that framework
      and distribute the extension. This way, you benefit from new functionality added to the base
      framework by newer Oxygen versions and you can still use your customizations.</p>
    <p>The steps below describe how to construct and share an extension of the <b>DITA</b> framework
      that removes certain elements from the content completion list:<ol id="ol_om1_xzp_zs">
        <li>Somewhere on your local disk (in a place where you have full write access), create a
          folder structure like: <filepath>custom_frameworks/dita-extension</filepath>. </li>
        <li>In the <b>Document Type Association / Locations</b> preferences page, add the path to
          your <filepath>custom_frameworks</filepath> folder in the <b>Additional frameworks
            directories</b> list. Click <b>OK</b> or <b>Apply</b> to save your changes.</li>
        <li>In the <b>Document Type Association</b> preferences page, select the <b>DITA</b>
          document type configuration and use the <b>Extend</b> button to create an extension for
          it.</li>
        <li>Give the extension a custom name (for example, <b>DITA - Custom</b>), then change its
            <b>Storage</b> to external, and save it to a path like:
            <filepath>path/to/.../custom_frameworks/dita-extension/dita-extension.framework</filepath>.</li>
        <li>Make changes to the extension (for example, go to the <b>Author->Content completion</b>
          tab and add elements that should not be presented to the end users in the <b>Filter -
            Remove content completion items</b> list).</li>
        <li>Click <b>OK</b> to close the dialog box and then either <b>OK</b> or <b>Apply</b> to
          save the preferences changes.</li>
      </ol></p>
    <p>After you perform the steps above, in the <filepath>dita-extension</filepath> folder you will
      have a fully functioning framework that can be shared with others.</p>
    <p>The framework can be shared with others in several ways:<ul id="ul_nsg_zbq_zs">
        <li>Copy it to their <filepath>[OXYGEN_DIR]/frameworks</filepath> directory. </li>
        <li>Somewhere on the local disk, create a <filepath>custom_frameworks</filepath> folder,
          copy the framework there, and then in the <b>Document Type Association / Locations</b>
          preferences page, add the path to your <filepath>custom_frameworks</filepath> folder in
          the <b>Additional frameworks directories</b> list.</li>
        <li product="author developer editor">
          Distribute the framework along with a project by following these steps:<ol
              id="ol_h4n_vpi_5m">
              <li>On your local drive, create a directory with full write access that contains the
                project files and a <filepath>custom_frameworks</filepath> folder that contains your
                  <filepath>dita-extension</filepath>.</li>
              <li>Start the application, go to the <xref
                  href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/17.0/ug-editor/#topics/using-the-project-view.html"
                  format="html" scope="external"><b>Project</b> view</xref>, and create a project.
                Save it in the newly created directory.</li>
              <li>In the <b>Document Type Association / Locations</b> preferences page, select
                  <b>Project Options</b> at the bottom of the page.</li>
              <li>In the <b>Additional frameworks directories</b> list, add an entry like:
                  <filepath>${pd}/custom_frameworks</filepath>.</li>
              <li>Add other resources to your project (for example, you can have all of your DITA
                content located inside the project folder).</li>
              <li>You can then share the new project directory with other users. For example, you
                can commit it to your version control system and have them update their working
                copy. When they open the customized project file in the <xref
                  href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/17.0/ug-editor/#topics/using-the-project-view.html"
                  format="html" scope="external"><b>Project</b> view</xref>, the new document type
                becomes available in the list of Document Types.</li>
            </ol>
        </li>
        <li product="author developer editor">Deploy the framework/document type configuration <xref
            href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/17.0/ug-editor/#topics/packing-and-deploying-addons.html"
            format="html" scope="external">as an add-on</xref>.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>After your team members install the framework, they can check in the <b>Document Type
        Association</b> preferences page (in the list of Document Types) to see if the framework is
      present and if it appears before the bundled <b>DITA</b> framework (meaning that it has higher
      priority).</p>
  </body>
</topic>
