<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="migrating_to_dita">
    <title>Migrating to DITA</title>
    <body>
        <p>Most companies do not start new DITA-based projects from zero, they already have content
      written in various other formats and somehow they need that content converted to DITA. In this
      blog post I will try to give some conversion advice depending on the format in which your
      current project has.</p>
    <section id="section_j23_k54_4gb">
      <title>Migrating DocBook content to DITA.</title>
      <p>Because DocBook content is XML migrating it to DITA is quite straight forward:<ol
          id="ol_rnd_t54_4gb">
          <li>You first convert the DocBook document to a single large DITA composite file and you
            can do that with the predefined transformation scenario bundled with Oxygen called
              <b>DocBook to DITA</b>.</li>
          <li>There is an utility XSLT stylesheet on the Oxygen XML GitHub account which can convert
            a DITA composite to a DITA Map with separate DITA topic files:<xref
              href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/old-userguide-docbookbased/blob/master/split-DITA-topic.xsl"
              format="xsl" scope="external"/></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_bfz_z54_4gb">
      <title>Migrating Microsoft Word content to DITA</title>
      <p>The Oxygen XML User's manual has a detailed topic enumerating the possibilities to convert
        Microsoft Word content to DITA: <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/20.1/ug-editor/topics/ooxml-to-dita.html?hl=migrate%2Cdita"
          format="html" scope="external"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_yx1_hv4_4gb">
      <title>Migrating Excel content to DITA</title>
      <p>You can use Oxygen's smart paste functionality to copy content from an Excel spreadsheet
        and paste it inside an opened DITA topic. Also as an alternate possibility the Oxygen
        resources converter-addon was updated to be able to batch convert Excel to DITA:<xref
          href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/oxygen-resources-converter" format="html"
          scope="external"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_p4y_nv4_4gb">
      <title>Migrating LibreOffice content to DITA</title>
      <p>LibreOffice documents can be saved in Word format so once you do that you can apply the
        Word to DITA conversion choices above. Or you can save the LibreOffice documents to DocBook
        and then apply DocBook to DITA conversions.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_gdg_tv4_4gb">
      <title>Migrating Markdown content to DITA</title>
      <p>The DITA Open Toolkit publishing engine bundled with Oxygen allows you to refer to Markdown
        files directly in a DITA Map and either publish directly or export the Markdown files to
        DITA one by one: <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/20.1/ug-editor/topics/markdown-dita-x-dita2.html"
          format="html" scope="external"/>. Or if you want batch conversions you can use the Oxygen
        Resources Converter add-on: <xref
          href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/oxygen-resources-converter" format="html"
          scope="external"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_ss1_gw4_4gb">
      <title>Migrating HTML content to DITA</title>
      <p>Using Oxygen's <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/20.1/ug-editor/topics/smart-paste-support.html"
          format="html" scope="external">smart paste</xref> functionality you can open the HTML
        documents in a web browser, then copy the contents and paste in a DITA topic opened in
        Oxygen in the Author visual editing mode. Or if you want batch conversions you can use the
        Oxygen Resources Converter add-on: <xref
          href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/oxygen-resources-converter" format="html"
          scope="external"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_imj_py4_4gb">
      <title>Migrating unstructured FrameMaker to DITA</title>
      <p>There is a FrameMaker plugin which can be used for this conversion: <xref
          href="http://leximation.com/tools/info/fm2dita.php" format="php" scope="external"/></p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_cry_wy4_4gb">
      <title>Migrating MadCap content to DITA</title>
      <p>Some recent MadCap versions seem to have facilities to export content directly to DITA.
        Otherwise you will need to convert XHTML content to DITA with a custom XSLT stylesheet to
        preserve variable references.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_zv4_hy4_4gb">
      <title>Migrating other formats to DITA</title>
      <p>You may find third party applications like <xref href="https://pandoc.org/" format="html"
          scope="external">Pandoc</xref> which can convert your content to HTML or to some kind of
        XML format like DocBook. Once you have HTML or DocBook content you can convert them to DITA
        using the advice above.</p>
    </section>
    </body>
</topic>
