<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_whr_nly_c5">
  <title>Sharing Application Settings</title>
  <body>
    <p>There are varios ways in the <b>Oxygen</b> standalone version through which a team of writers
      can share and use a set of common settings. Below I will try to list each of these
      possibilities along with useful links:<ul id="ul_m2f_sly_c5">
        <li>
          <p> Save the settings at project level and have all users use the same project
              <b>"projectName.xpr"</b> file in the Project view when editing. Most of the Oxygen
            Preference pages have a switch radio button which allows you to pass the settings to
            Project level and save them in the current project configuration file opened in the
            Project view. If you commit that Project configuration file to a version control system
            like <b>GIT</b> or <b>SVN</b>, all writers can open and use that project when working
            with the repository content. </p>
          <p>For example, when we work on the <b>Oxygen User's Manual</b> using our common
              <b>GitHub</b> repository, we all open in the <b>Project</b> view the
              <b>"userguide.xpr"</b> project which comes with various fixed options (eg: enabling
            automatic spell checking):<xref href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/userguide"
              format="html" scope="external"/></p>
          <p>You can find out more details about sharing projects here: <xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/17.1/ug-editor/#topics/sharing-projects.html"
              format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>Create and then provide a <b>default options XML document</b> to others. When placed in
            a specific place in the Oxygen installation or referenced via a specific property in the
            application startup script, this default options XML document will be used by the
            application to provide default values for certain settings. You can find out more about
            how default options work here:<xref
              href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/17.1/ug-editor/#topics/default-options.html"
              format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>Have others manually <b>import</b> an options XML document which you <b>exported</b>
          from Oxygen:<xref
            href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/17.1/ug-editor/#topics/import-export-preferences.html"
            format="html" scope="external"/>.</li>
        <li>
          <p>An Oxygen plugin could use our <b>Java API</b> to impose fixed options when the
            application starts using the API method:
              <b>PluginWorkspaceProvider.getPluginWorkspace().setGlobalObjectProperty(key,
              value)</b>. In our <xref href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/oxygen_sdk.html"
              format="html" scope="external">Maven-based SDK</xref> we have a sample plugin called
              <b>ImposeOptions</b> which imposes a fixed set of options when the application starts.
          </p>
        </li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>If you want to share <b>document type configurations</b> (for editing certain XML vocabulary)
      you can find more details in this older blog post: <xref
        href="http://blog.oxygenxml.com/2015/08/document-type-extension-sharing.html" format="html"
        scope="external"/>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
