<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_a3g_bsc_2z">
    <title>Useful DITA OT Plugins</title>
    <body>
        <p>The <b>DITA Open Toolkit</b> is the most commonly used engine for publishing <b>DITA</b>
      content to various output formats. It has a plugin-based architecture and it comes bundled by
      default with plugins for publishing to <b>XHTML</b>-based and <b>PDF</b> formats. There are
      other useful open-source plugins that can be installed in the <b>DITA Open Toolkit</b> and
      provide various publishing or reporting capabilities. Below is a list of my favorite open
      source plugins, many of which are bundled by default with <b>Oxygen XML Editor</b>:</p>
        <section id="section_f2h_qsc_2z">
            <title>DITA to MS Word</title>
            <p>This very useful plugin developed by Jarno Elovirta (the main DITA OT developer) can
        be used to publish <b>DITA</b> to <b>MS Word (OOXML)</b>: <xref
          href="https://github.com/jelovirt/com.elovirta.ooxml" format="ooxml" scope="external"/>.
        The plugin is robust and can handle large DITA projects.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_ft2_ttc_2z">
            <title>Convert MS Word to DITA</title>
            <p>The <xref href="https://github.com/dita4publishers/dita4publishers/releases"
          format="html" scope="external"><b>DITA For Publishers</b></xref> project developed by
          <b>Eliot Kimber</b> contains a plugin that can convert <b>MS Word (OOXML)</b> documents to
        DITA topics: <xref
          href="http://www.dita4publishers.org/d4p-users-guide/user_docs/d4p-users-guide/word2dita/word-to-dita-plugin.html"
          format="html" scope="external"/>. Useful advice and other ways to migrate from <b>MS
          Word</b> to <b>DITA</b> can be found here: <xref
          href="http://blog.oxygenxml.com/2016/05/how-to-migrate-from-word-to-dita.html"
          format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_iw1_ntc_2z">
            <title>DITA to EPUB</title>
            <p>The <xref href="https://github.com/dita4publishers/dita4publishers/releases"
          format="html" scope="external"><b>DITA For Publishers</b></xref> project developed by
          <b>Eliot Kimber</b> contains a plugin that can convert <b>DITA</b> content to
        <b>EPUB3</b>: <xref
          href="http://www.dita4publishers.org/d4p-users-guide/user_docs/d4p-users-guide/epub-plugin/generating-epubs.html"
          format="html" scope="external"/>. There are also plugins that can take the <b>EPUB3</b>
        output and generate <b>Kindle</b> or <b>Mobi</b> formats.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_pyq_dtc_2z">
            <title>Use Markdown content directly in DITA Maps</title>
            <p>This plugin developed by Jarno Elovirta can be used to publish hybrid DITA projects
        containing both DITA and Markdown topics to any output format: <xref
          href="https://github.com/jelovirt/dita-ot-markdown" format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_cn4_gvc_2z">
            <title>Embed video and audio resources in DITA topics</title>
            <p>This handy little plugin developed by <b>Oxygen</b> allows you to embed audio, video,
        or YouTube resources in <b>DITA</b> topics and properly display the embedded content in the
        XHTML-based outputs: <xref href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/dita-media-support"
          format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_bfz_tvc_2z">
            <title>Publish RelaxNG-based DITA topics</title>
            <p><b>RelaxNG</b> is the default schema type in which the <b>DITA</b> vocabulary is
                described by the specification developers. But the <b>DITA Open Toolkit</b> does not
                allow publishing RNG-based <b>DITA</b> content by default. Installing this plugin
                developed by <b>Oxygen</b> will make this possible: <xref
                    href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/dita-relaxng-defaults" format="html"
                    scope="external"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_c31_1wc_2z">
            <title>Present Oxygen track changes in the PDF output</title>
            <p>This useful plugin developed by <b>Oxygen</b> allows you to preserve <b>Oxygen</b>
                change tracking highlights in the PDF output: <xref
                    href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/dita-classic-pdf-review" format="html"
                    scope="external"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_qd1_fwc_2z">
            <title>Publish DITA to PDF using CSS</title>
            <p>The difficult thing about the default PDF output is the customization that involves
        modifying XSLT scripts and requiring knowledge of both <b>XSLT</b> and <b>XSL-FO</b>. This
        plugin developed by <b>Oxygen</b> allows you to use <b>CSS</b> to customize the <b>PDF</b>
        obtained from <b>DITA</b> content: <xref href="https://github.com/oxygenxml/dita-css"
          format="html" scope="external"/>. The plugin needs a commercial license of <b>RenderX
          XEP</b> or <b>Antenna House</b> in order to produce the PDF: <xref
          href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/doc/versions/18.1/ug-editor/topics/ditamap-pdf-css-x-dita2.html"
          format="html" scope="external"/>. But for <b>Oxygen XML Editor 19</b>, we are actively
        working on a <b>PDF CSS</b> engine (called <b>Chemistry</b>) that will allow the plugin to
        work from <b>Oxygen</b> without any additional licenses: <xref
          href="http://archive.xmlprague.cz/2017/files/presentations/css2pdf-xslfo.pdf" format="pdf"
          scope="external"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <p>A list with all open-source DITA OT plugins developed and shared by <b>Oxygen XML
                Editor</b> can be found on <b>GitHub</b>: <xref
                href="https://github.com/search?q=topic%3Adita-ot-plugin+org%3Aoxygenxml&amp;type=Repositories"
                format="html" scope="external"/>. My <b>DITA OT Day 2016</b> presentation covers
            most of these: <xref
                href="https://www.oxygenxml.com/events/2016/dita-ot_day.html#Seven_Open-Source_DITA-OT_plugins"
                format="html" scope="external"/>.</p>
    </body>
</topic>
