<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="selecting-combining-multiple-css-styles">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150108T113950+0200" comment="Reusable content marker"?>Selecting
    and Combining Multiple CSS Styles<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <!--Proofed-->
  <body>
    <p conref="../reusables/topics/reusable.cssStyles.dita#reusable.cssStyles/css.styles.intro"/>
    <p conref="../reusables/topics/reusable.cssStyles.dita#reusable.cssStyles/css.styles.example"/>
    <fig conref="../reusables/topics/reusable.cssStyles.dita#reusable.cssStyles/css.styles.image"
      id="fig_u12_cls_mq"/>
    <p>The main and alternate styles that are listed in the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down
      list can be controlled in the <xref
        href="../topics/preferences-document-type-association.dita#preferences-document-type-association"
          ><uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol> dialog</xref>. To access this dialog:<ol
        id="ol_fk5_32t_mq">
        <li><ph id="Open-the-preferences-page">
            <xref keyref="options.preferences">Open the <uicontrol>Preferences</uicontrol>
              dialog</xref>
          </ph>. </li>
        <li>Go to <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Document Type Association</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</li>
        <li>Select the appropriate document type and press the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol>
          button.</li>
      </ol>The CSS styles associated with the particular document type are listed in the
        <uicontrol>Author</uicontrol> tab. </p>
    <p>The names listed in the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down list match the values in the
        <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> column. The value in the <uicontrol>Alternate</uicontrol>
      column determines whether it is a main or alternate CSS. If the value is <i>no</i> it is a
      main CSS. If the value is <i>yes</i> it is an alternate CSS and the style can be combined with
      a main CSS or other alternate styles when using the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down
      list.</p>
    <p>A developer can add, edit, or delete styles from this dialog to control the main and
      alternate styles associated to the particular document type. Notice that the CSS styles shown
      in the following figure match the styles listed in the drop-down list in the previous figure.   </p>
    <p>
      <fig id="fig_fkw_x4m_mq">
        <title>Main and Alternate CSS Styles in the Document Type Association Dialog</title>
        <image href="../img/css_styles_doc_type.png"/>
      </fig>
    </p>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Enable multiple selection of alternate CSSs</uicontrol> box at the bottom of
      the pane must be checked in order for the alternate styles to be combined. If this option is
      disabled, the alternate styles are treated like main CSS styles and you can only select one at
      a time. By default, this option is enabled for DITA documents. There are also a few radio
      button options to specify how to handle the CSS if there are CSS styles specified in the
      document. You can choose to <i>ignore</i> or <i>merge</i> them. </p>
    <p>The selections from the <uicontrol>Styles</uicontrol> drop-down list are persistent, meaning
      that <ph keyref="product"/> will remember the selections when subsequent documents are opened.
      This is only true for newly opened documents. Previously opened documents will not be
      affected.</p>
    <note>The multiple alternate styles feature is also supported on LESS stylesheets.</note>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="../topics/the-css-sub-tab.dita#the-css-sub-tab"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
