<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="berkeley-container-level">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20160304T113056+0200" comment="Merged or no longer needed. Moved to not_used folder."?>Actions
    Available at Container Level<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <body>
    <p>In a Berkeley DB XML repository, the actions available at container level in the
        <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view are as follows:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/AddFile16.gif" id="image_jqz_d2w_sr"/>Add
            Resource</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Adds a new XML resource to the selected container.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Allows you to specify a new name for the selected container.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif" placement="inline"
            />Delete</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Removes the selected container from the database tree.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Edit indices</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens a <uicontrol>Container Indices</uicontrol> dialog box that allows you to configure
          indices properties for the selected container.<fig id="fig_rxr_wd3_2s">
            <title>Container Indices Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_berkeley_edit_indices_dialog.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_sxr_wd3_2s"/>
          </fig></dd>
        <dd>This dialog box allows you to configure the following properties:<ul id="ul_adq_wd3_2s">
            <li><uicontrol>Granularity</uicontrol> - A measure of the level of details of your data
              in the database. You can select one of the following:<ul id="ul_bdq_wd3_2s">
                <li><uicontrol>Document level</uicontrol> - Good option for retrieving large
                  documents.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Node level</uicontrol> - Good option for retrieving nodes from within
                  documents.</li>
              </ul></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Node</uicontrol> - The name of the node.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Namespace</uicontrol> - The index namespace.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Index type</uicontrol>: <ul id="ul_edq_wd3_2s">
                <li><uicontrol>Uniqueness</uicontrol> - Indicates whether or not the indexed value
                  must be unique within the container.</li>
                <li><uicontrol>Path type</uicontrol> - Drop-down menu that allows you to select from
                  the following: <ul id="ul_fdq_wd3_2s">
                    <li><uicontrol>node</uicontrol> - Indicates that you want to index a single node
                      in the path.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>edge</uicontrol> - Indicates that you want to index the portion
                      of the path where two nodes meet.</li>
                  </ul></li>
                <li><uicontrol>Node type</uicontrol> - Drop-down menu that allows you to select from
                  the following:<ul id="ul_gdq_wd3_2s">
                    <li><uicontrol>element</uicontrol> - An element node in the document
                      content.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>attribute</uicontrol> - An attribute node in the document
                      content.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>metadata</uicontrol> - A node found only in the metadata content
                      of a document.</li>
                  </ul></li>
                <li><uicontrol>Key type</uicontrol> - Drop-down menu that allows you to select from
                  the following:<ul id="ul_hdq_wd3_2s">
                    <li><uicontrol>equality</uicontrol> - Improves the performances of tests that
                      look for nodes with a specific value.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>presence</uicontrol> - Improves the performances of tests that
                      look for the existence of a node regardless of its value.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>substring</uicontrol> - Improves the performance of tests that
                      look for a node whose value contains a given sub-string.</li>
                  </ul></li>
                <li><uicontrol>Syntax</uicontrol> - The syntax describes the type of data the index
                  contains and is mostly used to determine how indexed values are compared. The
                  default value is <codeph>string</codeph>.</li>
              </ul></li>
          </ul></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Refresh16.png" id="image_dhn_y2w_sr"
          />Refresh</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Performs a refresh for the sub-tree of the selected node.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Properties</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Displays a dialog box with a list of properties of the Berkeley container (such as
            <term>container type</term>, <term>auto indexing</term>, <term>page size</term>,
            <term>validate on load</term>, <term>compression algorithm</term>, <term>number of
            documents</term>, etc.)</dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
    <p>The fields of the dialog box are as follows:</p>
  </body>
</topic>
