<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="check-out-working-copy">
  <title>Check Out a Working Copy</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Client<indexterm>check out a working copy</indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p><b>Check Out</b> means to make a copy of a project from a repository to your local file
        system. This copy is called a <term>working copy</term>. An <ph keyref="apacheSubversion"/>
        working copy is a specially formatted directory structure that contains additional
          <filepath>.svn</filepath> directories, which store Subversion information, as well as a
        pristine copy of each item that is checked out.</p>
      <p>To check out a working copy, go to the <xref href="../topics/repository-view.dita"
            ><uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol> view</xref> and follow these steps:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Locate and select the desired directory in the <uicontrol>Repositories</uicontrol>
          view.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Check Out...</uicontrol> action from the contextual menu, the
          toolbar, or the <uicontrol>Repository</uicontrol> menu.</cmd>
        <stepresult>
          <p>The <uicontrol>Check Out</uicontrol> dialog box is displayed:</p>
          <fig>
            <title>Check Out Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_svn_check_out_dialog.png"/>
          </fig>
        </stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Configure the options in the <uicontrol>Check out</uicontrol> dialog box:</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the depth to be used when checking out the working copy;</cmd>
        <info>This allows you to specify the recursion level into child resources. The depth is used
          if you want to check out only a part of the selected repository directory and bring in a
          future update the rest of the files and subdirectories. You can find out more about the
          check out depth in the <xref href="../topics/sparse-checkouts.dita">sparse
            checkouts</xref> section.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the revision number that is checked out.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>By default the last (HEAD) revision is checked out. If you need another revision, you
            have to specify the revision number or click the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> button
            which opens <xref href="../topics/history-dialog.dita#history-dialog" format="dita">the
                <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> dialog</xref>.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>After a check out, the new working copy will be added to the list in the <xref
        href="../topics/working-copy-view.dita"><uicontrol>Working Copy</uicontrol> view</xref> and
      loaded automatically.</result>
  </taskbody>
</task>