<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="convert-db-to-xml-schema">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150609T093613+0300" comment="Changed this to a task."?>Convert
    Database Structure to XML Schema<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>Tools Menu<indexterm>Convert DB Structure to XML Schema</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The <uicontrol>Convert DB Structure to XML Schema</uicontrol> dialog box allows you to create
      an XML Schema from the structure of a database. To open this dialog box, use the
        <uicontrol>Convert DB Structure to XML Schema</uicontrol> action that is available in the
        <uicontrol>Tools</uicontrol> menu. The dialog box includes the following:<dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Connections</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays a list of database source connections and includes the following two actions:<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Connect</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Click this button to establish a connection to the selected database
                  source.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Configure Database Sources</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>Opens the <xref href="../../topics/preferences-data-sources.dita#preferences-data-sources"
                      ><uicontrol>Data Sources</uicontrol> preferences page</xref> where you can
                  configure data sources and connections.</dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Select database tables</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Displays a tree-like representation of the tables of the database and you can select
            which tables you want to include in the conversion.<dl>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Criterion</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>You can choose to convert the selected tables with one of the following
                  criteria: <uicontrol>Element</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Attribute</uicontrol>, or
                    <uicontrol>Skipped</uicontrol>.</dd>
              </dlentry>
              <dlentry>
                <dt><uicontrol>Format for generated schema</uicontrol></dt>
                <dd>You can select one of the following two formats for the result of the generated
                    schema:<ul id="ul_eb1_4pl_hs">
                    <li><uicontrol>Flat schema</uicontrol> -  The generated schema will have a flat
                      structure that resembles a tree-like view of the database.</li>
                    <li><uicontrol>Hierarchical schema</uicontrol> -  The generated schema will
                      display the table dependencies visually, in a type of tree view where
                      dependent tables are shown as indented child elements in the content
                      model.</li>
                  </ul></dd>
              </dlentry>
            </dl></dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl></p>
  </body>
</topic>
