<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="create-topic-in-map">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="Steven" timestamp="20160919T153817+0300" comment="Converted to topic with same name"?>Creating
    a New DITA Topic<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>DITA<indexterm>Topics<indexterm>Create new
          topic</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>The basic building block for DITA information is the DITA topic. DITA provides a variety of
        specialized topic types, the most common of which are:<ul id="ul_omg_4rd_ts">
          <li><i>Concept</i> - For general, conceptual information such as a description of a
            product or feature.</li>
          <li><i>Task</i> - For procedural information such as how to use a dialog box.</li>
          <li><i>Reference</i> - For reference information.</li>
          <li>
            <i>Topic</i> - The base topic type from which all other topic types are specialized.
            Typically, it is used when a more specialized topic type is inappropriate.</li>
        </ul></p>
      <p>To add a new topic to a DITA map, follow these steps:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select a node of a map open in the <uicontrol>DITA Maps Manager View</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To insert the topic as a child of the selected node, right-click that node and choose <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Append Child</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>. To insert the topic as a sibling to the current node, choose <menucascade>
            <uicontrol>Insert After</uicontrol>
            <uicontrol>New</uicontrol>
          </menucascade>.</cmd>
        <stepresult>A dialog box is displayed that allows you to create a new DITA topic using
          various types of DITA file templates and provides some options that help you to configure
          the new topic.<p>
            <fig id="fig_x5w_wzd_ts" product="author editor">
              <title>New DITA File Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/sa_new_file_dialog.png" id="image_jvb_112_ts"/>
            </fig>
          </p><p>
            <fig id="fig_hdb_yzd_ts" product="authorEclipse editorEclipse">
              <title>New DITA File Dialog Box</title>
              <image href="../img/ec_new_file_dialog.png" id="image_rqk_b12_ts"/>
            </fig>
          </p>
          <note>The templates that appear in this dialog box include all templates that have an
            associated <codeph>.properties</codeph> file and the <codeph>type</codeph> property is
            set to <userinput>dita</userinput>, as well as templates that do not have an associated
            properties file or the <codeph>type</codeph> property is not defined. It will also
            include custom templates that you create using the procedures presented in <xref
              href="../topics/create-your-own-templates.dita#create-your-own-templates"
          />.</note></stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the appropriate DITA topic type from the list templates. You can use the
            <uicontrol>filter</uicontrol> text field to search for a template.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>You can use the following options to preconfigure some topic creation tasks:</cmd>
        <substeps id="substeps_rss_bb2_ts">
          <substep>
            <cmd><uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> - The text entered in this field will be used as the
              value of the root <codeph>title</codeph> element for the new topic. The title is set
              only if the selected template contains a root with a <codeph>title</codeph> element as
              its first child.</cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd><uicontrol>Use the title to generate the file name</uicontrol> - Select this option
              to use the text entered in the <uicontrol>Title</uicontrol> field to automatically
              generate a file name. By default, the generated name will transform spaces into
              underscores (<codeph>_</codeph>), all illegal characters will be removed, and all
              upper case characters changed to lower case (the generated name can be seen in the
                <uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> field). You can configure these rules by clicking the
                <xref href="../topics/preferences-dita.dita#preferences-dita/file-name-rules"
                  ><uicontrol>File name generation rules</uicontrol> link</xref>.</cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd><uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> - Select a file name and path in this field.</cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd><uicontrol>Use the file name as the value of the root ID attribute</uicontrol> -
              Select this option to use the file name (without the file extension) in the
                <uicontrol>Save as</uicontrol> field as the value of the root <codeph>id</codeph>
              attribute for the new topic.</cmd>
          </substep>
        </substeps>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click the <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol> button.</cmd>
        <stepresult>A reference (<codeph>topicref</codeph>) to the new topic is added to the current
          map and the new topic is opened in the editor.</stepresult>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <link href="../topics/eppo-first-dita-topic.dita#eppo-first-dita-topic"/>
  </related-links>
</task>