<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd">
<topic id="documentumcms-actions-at-file-level">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20160307T162328+0200" comment="Merged or no longer needed. Moved to not_used folder.  "?>Actions
    Available on Resources<?oxy_comment_end?></title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>Documentum (CMS) Support<indexterm>actions<indexterm>resources</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>The following actions are available on <ph keyref="documentumCMS"/> resources in the
        <uicontrol>Data Source Explorer</uicontrol> view:</p>
    <dl>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Edit16.gif" id="image_nq5_rxh_5r"/>Edit</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Checks out (if not already checked out) and opens the selected resource in the
          editor.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Edit with</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Checks out (if not already checked out) and opens the selected resource in the specified
          editor / tool.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Open (Read-only)</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens the selected resource in the editor. <ph product="editor author developer">The
            resources are marked as read-only in the editor using a lock icon on the file tab. If
            you want to edit those resources, enable the <xref
              href="preferences-editor.dita#preferences-editor/preferences_can_edit_read_only"
                ><uicontrol>Can edit read only files</uicontrol> option</xref>.</ph>
        </dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Open with</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Opens the selected resource in the specified editor / tool.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Check Out</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Checks out the selected resource from the repository. The action is not available if the
          resource is already checked out.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Check In</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Checks in the selected resource (commits changes) into the repository. The action is
          only available if the resource is checked out. <fig>
            <title>Check In Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_documentum_cms_checkin.png" placement="inline"/>
          </fig><p>The following resource properties are available: </p><ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The resource name in the repository.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Version</uicontrol> - Allows you to choose what version the resource will
              have after being checked in.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Version label</uicontrol> - The label of the updated version.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> - An optional description of the resource.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Keep Locks</uicontrol> - When this option is enabled, the updated
              resource is checked into the repository but it also keeps it locked.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Make this the current version</uicontrol> - Makes the updated resource
              the current version (will have the <i>CURRENT</i> version label).</li>
          </ul></dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Cancel Checkout</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Cancels the checkout process and loses all modifications since the checkout. Action is
          only available if the resource is checked out.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Export</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Allows you to export the resource and save it locally.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Rename</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Changes the name of the selected resource.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Copy</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Copies the selected resource to another location in the tree. This action is not
          available on virtual document descendants. This action can also be performed with drag and
          drop while holding the <uicontrol><shortcut>Ctrl (Meta on OS X)</shortcut></uicontrol> key
          pressed.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Move</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Moves the selected resource to another location in the tree. Action is not available on
          virtual document descendants and on checked out resources. This action can also be
          performed with drag and drop.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/RemoveSelected16.gif" placement="inline"
            />Delete</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Deletes the selected resource from the repository. Action is not available on virtual
          document descendants and on checked out resources.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Add Relationship</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Adds a new relationship for the selected resource. This action can also be performed
          with drag and drop between resources.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Convert to Virtual Document</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Allows you to convert a simple document to a virtual document. Action is available only
          if the resource is a simple document.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Convert to Simple Document</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Allows you to convert a virtual document to a simple document. Action is available only
          if the resource is a virtual document with no descendants.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol>Copy location</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Allows you to copy to clipboard an application-specific URL for the resource that can
          then be used for various actions such as opening or transforming the resources.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Refresh16.png" id="image_mst_5gw_sr"
          />Refresh</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Performs a refresh of the selected resource.</dd>
      </dlentry>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/DockableFrameProperties16.png" id="image_g5b_g5h_5r"
            />Properties</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Displays the list of properties of the selected resource.</dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
  </body>
</topic>