<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="lost-topics">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150511T160447+0300" comment="See comments in green. Questions for Adrian."?>Lost
    topics<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <body>
    <p>This is where we store content that was in the wrong place until we can find new home for
      it.</p>
    <section>
      <draft-comment author="Mark">This was in the instructions for the All Platforms installer, but
        it is obviously more general than this. However, it is not clear if this is the sort of
        information that needs to be presented for its own sake of if it is just a step in one or
        more troubleshooting procedures.</draft-comment>
      <title>Change the JVM that runs <ph keyref="product"/></title>
      <p>To change the version of the Java Virtual Machine that runs <ph keyref="product"/>, go to
        the Java command at the end of the script file and specify the full path to the Java
        executable of the desired JVM version, for example:
        <screen xml:space="preserve">"C:\Program Files\Java\jre<ph keyref="minimumJavaVersion"/>\bin\java" -Xmx256m -Dsun.java2d.noddraw=true ...</screen>
        on Windows,
        or<screen product="editor" xml:space="preserve">/System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/<ph keyref="minimumJavaVersion"/>/Home/bin/java "-Xdock:name=Oxygen" ...</screen><screen product="author" xml:space="preserve">/System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/<ph keyref="minimumJavaVersion"/>/Home/bin/java "-Xdock:name=Author" ...</screen><screen product="developer" xml:space="preserve">/System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/<ph keyref="minimumJavaVersion"/>/Home/bin/java "-Xdock:name=Developer" ...</screen><screen product="svnClient" xml:space="preserve">/System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/<ph keyref="minimumJavaVersion"/>/Home/bin/java "-Xdock:name=SyncroSVNClient" ...</screen>
        on OS X.</p>
    </section>
    <draft-comment author="Mark">This account of how Oxygen searches for a license key might be
      useful for troubleshooting licensing issues, if there were a troubleshooting topic on that
      subject. It does not belong in the licensing topic where it was found.</draft-comment>
    <p>At start-up, <ph keyref="product"/> looks for a valid license key in the following locations,
      in this order:<ul id="ul_j2v_fyy_x4">
        <li>in the XML file registration</li>
        <li>in the text file registration</li>
        <li>in its internal settings files created after you used the
            <uicontrol>Register</uicontrol> dialog box to validate a named-user or concurrent
          license.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <draft-comment author="steven_higgs">I moved the following information here in case it is needed
      when documenting the updated insert DITA content reference action. The insert content key
      reference action is now integrated into the insert conref action.</draft-comment>
    <dl>
      <dlentry>
        <dt><uicontrol><image href="../../img/Conkeyref16.png" id="image_cnp_swx_sr"/>Insert Content
            Key Reference</uicontrol></dt>
        <dd>Inserts a content key reference at the caret position. <p>As stated in the DITA 1.2
            specification the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute provides a mechanism for reuse of
            content fragments similar with the <codeph>conref</codeph> mechanism. Keys are defined
            at map level which can be referenced using <codeph>conkeyref</codeph>. The
              <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute contains a key reference to another element and
            is processed to replace the referencing element with the referenced element. The element
            containing the content key reference acts as a placeholder for the referenced element.
            The identifier for the referenced element must be either absolute or resolvable in the
            context of the referencing element.</p><p><ph keyref="product"/>
            <xref href="author-displaying-referenced-content.dita">displays the key referenced
              content</xref> of a DITA <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> if it can resolve it to a valid
            resource in the context of the current opened DITA map.</p><p>A content key reference is
            inserted with the action <uicontrol>Insert a DITA Content Key Reference</uicontrol>
            available on the toolbar <uicontrol>Author custom actions</uicontrol> and on the menu <menucascade>
              <uicontrol>DITA</uicontrol>
              <uicontrol>Insert</uicontrol>
            </menucascade>.</p><fig product="editor author" id="fig_ubq_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../../img/sa_dita_insert_conkeyref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_jfq_ggb_2r"/>
          </fig><fig product="editorEclipse authorEclipse" id="fig_zfq_ggb_2r">
            <title>Insert Content Key Reference Dialog Box</title>
            <image href="../../img/ec_dita_insert_conkeyref.png" placement="inline"
              id="image_ojq_ggb_2r"/>
          </fig><note>The <uicontrol>Insert Content Key Reference</uicontrol> dialog box is not
            modal. The dialog box is closed automatically if you switch to a different
            editor.</note><p>To reference target elements at sub-topic level just press the
              <uicontrol>Sub-topic</uicontrol> button and choose the target.</p><p>According to the
            DITA 1.2 specification the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> attribute can be used to specify
            content reference ranges. This is a very useful feature when referencing multiple
            consecutive steps or list items. If you use multiple contiguous sibling selection for
            IDs at sub-topic level the <codeph>conrefend</codeph> value will also be set to the
            value of the last selected ID path. <ph keyref="product"/> will present the entire
            referenced range as read-only content.<note type="important">All keys which are
              presented in the dialog box are gathered from the current opened DITA map. Elements
              which have the <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> attribute set are displayed by default with
              the target content expanded. The current opened DITA map is also used to resolve
              references when navigating <codeph>conkeyref</codeph> links in the Author
            mode.</note></p></dd>
      </dlentry>
    </dl>
  </body>
</topic>
