<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="managing-dita-webhelp-feedback">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="steven_higgs" timestamp="20150804T105849+0300" comment="The content in this topic was merged with &quot;manage-comments-webhelp-feedback.dita&quot; and therefore is no longer needed."?>Feedback
    System User Management<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>WebHelp with Feedback <indexterm>admin management</indexterm><indexterm>admin
            panel</indexterm><indexterm>administrator
            management</indexterm><indexterm>administration panel</indexterm></indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>Apart from the options available for a regular user, you can also use the administrative page
      for advanced customization and management. As an administrator, you have full access to all
      the features of the feedback-enabled WebHelp system. To access the administration page, select
        <uicontrol>Admin Panel</uicontrol> from the <uicontrol>Comments</uicontrol> bar. </p>
    <fig>
      <title>The Administrative Page</title>
      <image href="../img/webhelp-admin-page.png"/>
    </fig>
    <p>This page allows you to view all posts, export comments, and set the version of the WebHelp
      system. You can also view the details of each user and search through these details using the
        <uicontrol>Search User Information</uicontrol> filter.</p>
    <p>The upper part of the page contains the following actions:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Delete Orphan Comments</uicontrol> - Deletes comments that were attached to
          topics that are no longer available.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Delete Pending Users</uicontrol> - Deletes all unconfirmed users that
          registered more than a week ago.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>View All Posts</uicontrol> - Allows you to view all posts associated with a
          product and version.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Export Comments</uicontrol> - Allows you to export all posts associated with
          a product and version in XML format.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Set Version</uicontrol> - Use this action to display comments starting with a
          particular version.</li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>To edit the details of a user, click the corresponding row. Use the <uicontrol>Edit
        User</uicontrol> dialog box to customize all the information associated with an user:<ul>
        <li><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol> - The full name of the user.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Level</uicontrol> - Use this field to modify the privilege level of the
          selected user. You can choose from the following:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>User</uicontrol> - Regular user, able to post comments and receive e-mail
              notifications.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Moderator</uicontrol> - In addition to the regular
                <uicontrol>User</uicontrol> rights, this type of user has access to the
                <uicontrol>Admin Panel</uicontrol> where a moderator can view, delete, export
              comments, and set the version of the feedback-enabled WebHelp system.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Admin</uicontrol> - Full administrative privileges. Can manage
              WebHelp-specific settings, users, and their comments.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Company</uicontrol> - The organization name associated with the user.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>E-mail</uicontrol> - The contact email address for the user. This is also the
          address where the WebHelp system sends notifications. The following notification options
          can be selected:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>WebHelp Notification</uicontrol> - When enabled, the user receives
              notifications when comments are posted anywhere in the feedback-enabled WebHelp
              system.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Reply Notification</uicontrol> - When enabled, the user receives
              notifications when comments are posted as a reply to one of their comments.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Page Notification</uicontrol> - When enabled, the user receives
              notifications when comments are posted on a topic where they posted a comment.</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li><uicontrol>Date</uicontrol> - User registration date.</li>
        <li><uicontrol>Status</uicontrol> - Specifies the status of the currently edited user:<ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Created</uicontrol> - The user is created but does not yet have any
              rights for the feedback-enabled WebHelp system.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Validated</uicontrol> - The user is able to use the feedback-enabled
              WebHelp system.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Suspended</uicontrol> - The user has no rights for the feedback-enabled
              WebHelp system.</li>
          </ul></li>
      </ul></p>
  </body>
</topic>
