<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="ofb-configuring-managing">
  <title><?oxy_comment_start author="Steven" timestamp="20200521T124537-0400" comment="Duplicate"?>Administration
    Interface<?oxy_comment_end?></title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <indexterm>What is a site</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Administration interface</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Sites page</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Site configuration</indexterm>
        <indexterm>Dashboard</indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><ph keyref="product"/> features a user-friendly <i>administration interface</i> where you can
      moderate comments, manage users, view statistics, and configure various settings,
      notifications, and other components of the comment system. This administration interface is
      reached by logging in to your Feedback account in the <i>administration login page</i> (<xref
        href="https://feedback.oxygenxml.com/login" format="html" scope="external"/>).<note
        type="tip">You can also reach the <i>administration interface</i> from the comments area in
        any web page where it is installed by logging in and selecting <uicontrol>Home</uicontrol>
        from the drop-down menu to the right of your name.</note></p>
    <p>All the various pages within the <i>administration interface</i> have a common ribbon at the
      top with some actions to help you navigate through the interface.</p>
    <p><image href="../img/ofb-stripe.png" id="image_bqp_yst_flb"/></p>
    <p>The components in that ribbon include:</p>
    <p>
      <dl>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Feedback24.png" id="image_zfr_jtt_flb"/>Oxygen
              Feedback</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol><image href="../img/Feedback24.png" id="image_jkb_jtt_flb"
              />Oxygen Feedback</uicontrol> logo at the left side of the ribbon will navigate to the
              <xref href="ofb-dashboard.dita"><uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> action will navigate to the <xref
              href="ofb-dashboard.dita"><uicontrol>Dashboard</uicontrol> page</xref>.</dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> drop-down menu</dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol>Sites</uicontrol> drop-down menu displays a list of your site
            configurations, making it easy to navigate to a particular configuration from anywhere
            in the interface. It shows the 5 most recent sites, followed by 5 sites with pending
            comments, and there is a <uicontrol>View All Sites</uicontrol> action at the bottom of
            the list to see the rest of the site configurations. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt><uicontrol><image href="../img/Help20.png" id="image_j3h_j5t_flb"
            />Help</uicontrol></dt>
          <dd>Clicking the <uicontrol>Help</uicontrol> icon displays a menu where you can choose to
            open the <uicontrol>User Guide</uicontrol> or you can choose
              <uicontrol>About</uicontrol> to see information about the current version for the
            application. </dd>
        </dlentry>
        <dlentry>
          <dt>User drop-down menu</dt>
          <dd>Clicking this drop-down menu provides access to the <xref
              href="ofb-profile-management.dita">profile management page</xref>, <xref
              href="ofb-subscription.dita">subscription plans page</xref>, <xref
              href="ofb-usage-statistics.dita">usage statistics page</xref>, and <uicontrol>Log
              out</uicontrol> action.</dd>
        </dlentry>
      </dl>
    </p>
    
    
  </body>
</topic>
