<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="resolve-merge-conflicts">
  <title>Resolve Merge Conflicts</title><prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords><indexterm>SVN Branches/Tags<indexterm>merging<indexterm>resolve merge
            conflicts</indexterm></indexterm></indexterm></keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <taskbody>
    <steps>
      <step id="resolve-conflicts">
        <cmd>Optionally, resolve the conflicts that were created by the merge operation.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>After the merge operation is finished, it is possible to have some resources in
            conflict. This means that some incoming modifications for a resource could not be merged
            with the current modifications from the working copy. If there are such conflicts, the
            following dialog will appear, presenting you the resources that are in conflict. In this
            dialog you can choose a way in which every conflict should be resolved.</p>
          <fig>
            <title>Merge Conflicts Dialog</title>
            <image href="../img/sa_svn_merge_conflicts_dialog.png"/>
          </fig>
          <p>The options to resolve a conflict are:</p>
          <ul>
            <li><uicontrol>Resolve later</uicontrol> - Used for leaving the conflict as it is, to
              manually resolve it later.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Keep incoming</uicontrol> - This option keeps all the incoming
              modifications, discarding all current ones from your working copy.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Keep outgoing</uicontrol> - This option keeps all current modifications
              from your working copy, discarding all incoming ones.</li>
            <li><uicontrol>Mark resolved</uicontrol> - You should chose this option after you have
              manually edited the conflict. To do this, use the <uicontrol>Edit conflict</uicontrol>
              button, that will display a dialog presenting the conflicting resource's contents (for
              the working copy version versus the incoming version). After manually resolving the
              conflict, the resource will be marked as resolved.</li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>